<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10003" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai T-bill spot end mixed, repo rates down.</title>
<headline>Shanghai T-bill spot end mixed, repo rates down.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>-- Contracts on the T-bill spot market in Shanghai closed mixed on Thursday, with volume hitting a record high for the second day in a row on talk that the central bank would cut bank interest rates soon, traders said.</p>
<p>Of the nine contracts, three closed up, four down and two were untraded. Combined volume surged to 16.375 million lots from 13.71 million lots on Wednesday.</p>
<p>One lot is 1,000 yuan face value of treasury bills.</p>
<p>The most active ten-year bond that matures in June 2006 edged down to 124.59 yuan from 124.76 yuan after soaring about five percent on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Traders said that, with a bank rate cut, current T-bill spots were cheap and would continue to rise in the short term, attracting much liquidity back into the marekt.</p>
<p>Contracts on the treasury bill repurchase market in Shanghai ended down across the board due to the rate cut talk.</p>
<p>The annual rate for the most active three-day contract ended lower at 10.91 percent from 12.18 percent and the seven-day contract fell to nine percent from 10.50 percent.</p>
<p>Turnover surged to 11.57 million lots from 6.79 million because of a domestic A share issue in Shanghai today.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
