<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10002" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Ringgit losses limited by technicals, seen down.</title>
<headline>Ringgit losses limited by technicals, seen down.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ringgit ended lower in Kuala Lumpur, but the losses were limited by technical support at 2.4950 per dollar level, dealers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>They said the ringgit was likely to remain weak on covering of short dollar positions in the near term. Unwinding of ringgit/Sing was likely to depress sentiment further.</p>
<p>&quot;Sentiment is generally weak for the ringgit. People believe it has become expensive to swap into ringgit, though its yields are still higher,&quot; a local bank dealer said.</p>
<p>He said there was also some cross play against yen, which contributed to the ringgit's weakening.  </p>
<p>Dealers said ringgit was also affected by fear that the U.S. could impose sanctions against Malaysia because Petronas, the Malaysian oil company, has bought into an Iranian oil field.</p>
<p>&quot;There is reaction to the possibility of sanctions against Malaysia,&quot; said a dealer with a U.S. bank in Singapore.</p>
<p>He said there was support for the ringgit at 2.4950 per dollar, though cross play against Sing and yen was threatening to break that support level.</p>
<p>At 0900 GMT, the ringgit was at 2.4945/55 per dollar against 2.4926/31 on Wednesday. The Singapore dollar was at 0.5649/55 against 0.5661/68. - Madhav Reddy (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
