<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10043" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Perwaja rescuers given six months to provide plan.</title>
<headline>Perwaja rescuers given six months to provide plan.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Private firms picked to rescue ailing Perwaja Steel Sdn Bhd have six months to come up with a plan, Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The selected parties, Maju Holdings Sdn Bhd and Lion Corp Bhd, have briefed Mahathir on the problems faced by the government-owned steel products manufacturer, the national Bernama news agency reported.</p>
<p>&quot;We have given them six months to understand the problems and we will see how they plan to rescue Perwaja,&quot; Bernama quoted Mahathir as saying.</p>
<p>Perwaja, which operates two steel plants, has accumulated losses of more than 2.9 billion ringgit.</p>
<p>Under the preliminary rescue formula, Maju Holdings would hold 51 percent of the restructured equity of Perwaja Steel while Lion would hold 30 percent and the government the balance.</p>
<p>Lion has reportedly decided to step back from the rescue plan after failing to take management control of the effort from Maju.</p>
<p>Asked about this, Mahathir said: &quot;Lion Group will provide support but it may not take up the equity.&quot;</p>
<p>He added, &quot;It is a bit difficult for two parties to manage a business. We will look into that problem.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
