<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10061" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs end lower as buying back pressure recedes.</title>
<headline>JGBs end lower as buying back pressure recedes.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Key September Japanese government bond futures ended lower on Thursday, as buying back pressure ahead of a benchmark shift receded somewhat.</p>
<p>&quot;The bulk of the buying back rally ahead of a benchmark shift is over. Buying back probably will not push up the September from here on,&quot; a trust bank trader said.</p>
<p>Some traders said news reports about the Bank of Japan's 'tankan' corporate survey weighed on the September in the afternoon. &quot;Forecasts of the 'tankan' by the media were positive and caused the downturn,&quot; said a trader for a city bank's securities unit.  </p>
<p>The September ended at 120.66, down from Wednesday's 120.88, and moved within a range of 120.64 to 120.95 during the day. Turnover was 39,179 contracts.</p>
<p>Turnover for the December futures contract was 28,864.</p>
<p>When turnover of the December exceeds that of the September, the market considers the December the new benchmark.</p>
<p>Such a shift could take place as early as Friday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's taking a long time for the benchmark to change. The shift usually happens in the second or third week of the month,&quot; a trader for a major securities house said.  </p>
<p>In the morning, the September inched lower after an earlier rise to 121 failed.</p>
<p>The key contract's topside was capped just below 121 by a widespread belief that it saw a ceiling on Wednesday when it pierced a technical barrier at 121.00 and hit an eight-month high of 121.04, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a perception lingering from yesterday, that the September is heavy near 121.00,&quot; a city bank trader said.</p>
<p>The September remained stuck near the morning's range early in the afternoon, but edged gradually downwards later on.  </p>
<p>The benchmark 182nd cash JGB was yielding 3.115 percent as of 0714 GMT, up from Thursday's 3.095 percent.</p>
<p>-- Masayuki Kitano, Tokyo Treasury Desk (81-3-5473-3748)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
