<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10081" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Marubeni, Indian Oil forge broad business ties.</title>
<headline>Marubeni, Indian Oil forge broad business ties.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marubeni Corp and state-run Indian Oil Corp (IOC) signed an agreement on Thursday to cooperate in a broad range of business areas related to energy, the Japanese trading house said in a news release.  </p>
<p>Marubeni said it was the first time the IOC had forged such ties with a foreign company outside the oil refining and distribution industry.</p>
<p>A Marubeni spokesman said talks were already being held on the possible construction of a 200- to 240-megawatt thermal power plant in the state of Haryana in northern India.</p>
<p>The plant, to be built next to an IOC refinery, would be powered by the by-products from the refinery.</p>
<p>No agreement has been signed, and the spokesman could not provide a cost estimate for the project.  </p>
<p>Marubeni's news release said the two firms agreed to cooperate in a number of areas including the possible development of oil and gas fields in India as well as in a third country.</p>
<p>The two firms would also study the construction and operation of power plants and the construction of pipelines and export facilities for the transport of crude oil and oil products.</p>
<p>The Japanese trading company said the two firms would also cooperate in petrochemical and oil refining projects.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
