<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10114" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks lower by break on politics worry.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks lower by break on politics worry.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks were lower by the break on Thursday as a mid-week rally on foreign funds fizzled out and worry over political uncertainty once again set the market mood, brokers said.</p>
<p>The SET index was 5.77 points lower to 1,089.26 on thin 1.3 billion baht trade. Decliners beat gainers 168 to 81 with 93 unchanged. The SET-50 index was 0.47 points off to 83.08.</p>
<p>Brokers said a 2.2 percent rally on Wednesday was on hopes that a local support fund was beginning to kick in and on Japanese buying, but the prevailing mood in other centres such as Hong Kong, Singapore and London was still negative.  </p>
<p>&quot;People are saying nothing has really changed on the economic front and with the political uncertainty, they would rather wait a couple of weeks to see what happnes,&quot; said a foreign analyst.</p>
<p>The first part of a 21 billion baht local support fund entered the market earlier this week, pulling in some Japanese funds on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But political worry has dominated the market mood since one of the partners in Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa's coalition pulled out last week. Unease has continued due to a planned no-confidence attack on the premier due next month.  </p>
<p>Brokers said they expected the market to move sideways or down for the rest of the week on a lack of any positive factors to spark interest.</p>
<p>The finance sector was 0.41 percent lower on 361.5 million baht trade while the bank counter shed 0.49 percent on 236.3 million baht turnover.</p>
<p>Bangkok Bank was most active, unchanged at 212 baht. Finance One was one lower to 109, Thai Farmers Bank gained one to 173.</p>
<p>-- Robert Birsel (662) 252-9950</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
