<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10127" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan stocks close weaker amid profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Taiwan stocks close weaker amid profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Profit-taking pulled Taiwan stocks to a lower close on Thursday and sentiment was cautious as investors awaited Taipei's reaction after China issued rules governing direct shipping links between the two sides.</p>
<p>Early interest focused on firms with investments in China but profit-taking pulled share prices down in late trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Players are cautious as they don't know how the government will react to mainland China's offers, but overall sentiment was not bad,&quot; said George Hou of Jardine Fleming.</p>
<p>The weighted index slipped 16.96 points or 0.27 percent to close at 6,160.82. Turnover was T$29 billion.  </p>
<p>The market also was eager to hear Taipei's reaction after China said it was time to resume political talks after a year's impasse, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever the government says (toward China's offers) in the near term will affect the market,&quot; said Wang Jieh of Foremost Investment Services.</p>
<p>Brokers noted little impact from Vice-President Lien Chan's secretive trip to Ukraine although the trip has riled China, which sees Taiwan as a Chinese province not entitled to foreign ties. Ukraine recognises China, not Taiwan.  </p>
<p>The construction sector outperformed the market to rise 0.84 percent on expectations of an industry recovery while profit-taking hit shipping stocks, which had posted gains on Wednesday on hopes for direct shipping links with China.</p>
<p>Yang Ming Marine, which gained T$1.8 on Wednesday, lost 10 cents to end at T$37.7 after minor gains early in the session.</p>
<p>The market was likely to focus on companies with investments in China, such as plastics, foods and petrochemical firms, brokers said. Initial support was seen at 6,100 points.</p>
<p>-- Joyce Liu (2-5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
