<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10125" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Yuan ends up against dollar amid rate talk.</title>
<headline>Yuan ends up against dollar amid rate talk.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chinese yuan closed up at a year-high of 8.3050 on Thursday, from Wednesday's 8.3072 against U.S dollar on the Shanghai-based interbank foreign exchange market, traders said.</p>
<p>The yuan ended at an intra-day high on a sudden rise in late trading but its uptrend was checked by expectations of an imminent cut in interest rates which is seen cutting demand for yuan, dealers said.</p>
<p>The yuan opened little changed at 8.3073 and consolidated around 8.3070 for most of the session, hitting an intra-day low of 8.3075 in midsession before closing at a high of 8.3050.  </p>
<p>Trading was less active than on Wednesday, with most done at 8.3070, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The rumours of a cut in bank interest rates this week checked the yuan's rise at about 8.3070,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Shanghai brokers said that the People's Bank of China would cut interest rates on both loans and deposits by more than one percentage point as early as this weekend.</p>
<p>Dealers expect the yuan to fall back to 8.3070 on Friday.</p>
<p>The yuan closed little up at 7.6600 from 7.6552 against 100 Japanese yen and up slightly at 1.0730 from 1.0735 against the Hong Kong dollar.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
