<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10144" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: TRIS lowers Int'l Engineering rating.</title>
<headline>TRIS lowers Int'l Engineering rating.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai Ratings and Information Services (TRIS) said on Thursday it had downgraded to BBB from BBB+ its rating for International Engineering Plc's 1.2 billion baht in convertible debentures, reflecting lower cash flow.</p>
<p>&quot;The new rating reflects IEC's lower-than-expected cash inflow resulting in a distressed financial profile,&quot; TRIS said.</p>
<p>IEC has recently suffered some financial difficulty as a digital mobil phone system service provider of Total Access Communication Plc. IEC recorded a significant loss due to a slower-than-expected digital market, TRIS said.</p>
<p>TRIS said the firm's rating was likely to improve after it reorganises and sets up a subsidiary Wirelss Communications Service Co Ltd, in which it will initially hold 55 percent.</p>
<p>IEC will concentrate on trading cellular telephone hand sets and customer service while leaving network operations to Wireless Communications Service.</p>
<p>&quot;IEC stands to benefit from this because it will share a certain percentage of airtime revenue from (Wireless Comminications) without the investment burden. This eases its financial position and ensures its future earnings,&quot; TRIS said.</p>
<p>TRIS said it expected IEC's financial position to improve from 1998 onwards.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
