<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10142" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Golden Hope year profit beats forecasts.</title>
<headline>Golden Hope year profit beats forecasts.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Golden Hope Plantations Bhd's full-year net earnings of 209.3 million ringgit or 20.9 cents a share beat market expectations, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The plantations and property concern on Wednesday reported an 11 percent rise in net profit for the year ended June 30, 1996. Providing a boost to results was a 79 percent surge in investment income to 48.66 million, analysts noted.</p>
<p>In a research note on Thursday, Jupiter Securities said Golden Hope's earnings per share of 20.9 cents were 7.7 percent above consensus estimates.</p>
<p>Mohaiyani Securities said in a research note on Thursday that it has upgraded its Golden Hope rating to &quot;buy&quot; from &quot;switch&quot; based on the results and the valuation of the stock.</p>
<p>&quot;The bulk of Golden Hope's earnings in the next two years will continue to come from its plantation division,&quot; Mohaiyani said. About 60 percent of group pretax profit for the year was from that division.</p>
<p>Golden Hope's shares were up two cents at 3.90 ringgit in late morning trading Thursday.</p>
<p>HLG Securities said in a research note that Golden Hope's net profit was 12 percent above its forecast of 184.1 million ringgit. Golden Hope's property and plantation divisions should record double-digit growth in pretax profits over the next two years, HLG said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
