<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10179" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China says conditions ripe for interest rate cut.</title>
<headline>China says conditions ripe for interest rate cut.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Conditions are ripe for a second cut in bank interest rates this year, the China Securities newspaper said on Thursday.</p>
<p>In the clearest official indication that a cut is imminent, a front-page commentary in the official newspaper said that a cut was needed to stimulate flagging demand, provide state firms with much needed capital, reduce the debt burden of banks and play a role in overall monetary policy.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking at the current situation of the economy, conditions for a second interest rate cut are certainly ripe,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Rumours of a rate cut pushed up the A and B share markets and most contracts on the T-bill spot market in Shanghai on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Shanghai brokers expect a cut of more than one percentage point to be announced late on Friday and implemented from Saturday.  </p>
<p>Overall demand in China is insufficient, with weakness in investment and consumer demand leading to an imbalance between supply and demand, the commentary said.</p>
<p>&quot;Stimulating an increase in social demand is an important duty of current macroeconomic management and cutting interest rates is one effective way to reach this objective,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>A shortage of working capital is a problem of state companies that needs to be resolved, it said.</p>
<p>Solving this capital shortage, especially for efficient companies with a market for their products, is an urgent task, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Cutting interest rates would channel capital from society to industrial and commercial enterprises, reduce the cost of capital for companies and would certainly help to relieve their financial difficulties to some extent,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>The third reason for a rate cut is to reduce the burden on banks, the commentary said.</p>
<p>At the end of the first half of 1996, the outstanding level of savings in banks reached 3.5458 trillion yuan, it said.</p>
<p>After a cut in interest rates on May 1, the rate of increase in new bank savings slowed down but the total sum remains very large, it said.</p>
<p>The main customers for bank loans are state companies and the level of bad debts they owe is high, leading to an increase in the management risk of banks, it said.</p>
<p>Central bank policy is to spread this risk by encouraging companies to raise capital directly from the public and not concentrate all the risk on banks, it said.  </p>
<p>A cut in interest rates is also an important part of monetary policy, the commentary said.</p>
<p>In the first half of 1996, the level of new loans was 390 billion yuan and in the second half state bank loans will be concentrated on 300 key companies, it said.</p>
<p>To meet this sharp increase in demand for capital, a cut in rates is a suitable instrument, it said.</p>
<p>Another factor in the decision is the fall in inflation, which grew an annual 7.1 percent in the first half of 1996, 5.8 percent in July and is likely to hit eight percent for the whole year, it said.</p>
<p>An interest rate cut is in the long-term interests of the stock markets, it said.</p>
<p>It should not be seen as a short-term instrument but the start of a new economic cycle, to channel some of the huge and in the past static bank savings into the securities market, it added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
