<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10188" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: July durable orders up, little slowing seen.</title>
<headline>July durable orders up, little slowing seen.</headline>
<byline>Glenn Somerville</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Orders for costly manufactured goods staged a broad-based surge in July, the Commerce Department reported on Friday, surprising financial markets and raising questions as to whether the economy is indeed slowing, as analysts had thought.</p>
<p>Orders for costly durable goods, ranging from communications equipment to computers, climbed 1.6 percent last month to a seasonally adjusted $172.7 billion after a revised 0.2 percent fall in June and a robust 4.2 percent May increase.</p>
<p>Analysts said manufacturing industries were headed into the second half of the year on a much stronger note than anticipated, freed of bulging inventories by brisk demand.</p>
<p>&quot;The manufacturing sector had a rough patch but it now seems to be over,&quot; said Pierre Ellis, an economist with Lehman Brothers in New York. &quot;Demand clearly is there and what is striking is the breadth of the increase in it.&quot;</p>
<p>Every category of durable good except transportation equipment reflected stronger orders in July. Weakness in demand for ships and for military tanks left overall transportation orders flat, but new cars and parts orders increased from June.</p>
<p>Not only were total July orders up, but shipments of finished products gained solidly and order backlogs fattened for the 10th month out of the past 11, primarily because of more orders for new commercial aircraft and parts.</p>
<p>The durables report renewed inflation worries and sent bond prices sharply lower.</p>
<p>The 30-year U.S. Treasury bond fell 1-1/4 points, sending its yield climbing to 6.94 percent from 6.83 percent late Thursday. The decline in the bond market put stocks under pressure, and the Dow Jones industrial average fell 10.73 points to 5,722.74.</p>
<p>&quot;This number fits into the story of the economy retaining momentum in the summer,&quot; said economist Russell Sheldon of Mellon Bank in Pittsburgh.</p>
<p>It was widely thought that the Federal Reserve decided this week to keep interest rates unchanged because of signs the economy was losing steam in the second half of the year so that inflation pressures were abating on their own.</p>
<p>Lehman Brothers' Ellis said Fed policymakers, like private economists, may be uncertain what represents &quot;too strong&quot; growth that would risk fuelling inflation.</p>
<p>He said it also was unclear whether manufacturing was simply regaining its trend of expansion or whether demand was heating up to a degree that threatens to outstrip supply and send prices spiraling upward.</p>
<p>Durable goods are products like cars and home appliances that are intended to last at least three years. Rising orders and shipments are an indicator of the health of the manufacturing sector, which generates many of the better-paying jobs that keep incomes rising.</p>
<p>The national economy grew at a sharp 4.2 percent annual rate in the second quarter, exceptionally strong in the sixth year of expansion from the 1990-91 recession.</p>
<p>However, Ellis said the Lehman Brother Global Economics model still showed the pace of growth easing down to 2.5 percent in the third quarter and to 2.5 percent to 3 percent in the final quarter.</p>
<p>Previously, the Commerce Department said durable goods orders had fallen 0.6 percent in June. But it revised that to show only a 0.2 percent decline.</p>
<p>The sole weakness in the July report was for transportation equipment, with orders flat after a 1.2 percent drop in June. Excluding transportation, durables orders rose 2.1 percent after a 0.2 percent rise in June and a 1.1 percent rise in May.</p>
<p>Orders for electronic and electrical equipment jumped 4.7 percent to a seasonally adjusted $28.1 billion in July after a 3.9 percent gain in June. The department said there were widespread increases in this category, led by communcications equipment.</p>
<p>Orders for industrial machinery, which includes computers, rose 2.1 percent in July to $32.3 billion following a 0.2 percent increase in June.</p>
<p>Orders for non-defence capital goods, used as an indicator of business investment in new production equipment, climbed a brisk 7.2 percent to $46 billion after a 4.6 percent fall in June.</p>
<p>Shipments of durable goods, an indication of current demand, climbed 0.7 percent to $168 billion after dropping 0.4 percent in June.</p>
<p>Unfilled orders were up strongly, by 1 percent, to $480 billion in July after a 0.7 percent gain in June. It was the 10th increase in the past 11 months for order backlogs, pointing to underlying strength in manufacturing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
