<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10190" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India police raid tycoon's home in phone scandal.</title>
<headline>India police raid tycoon's home in phone scandal.</headline>
<byline>Narayanan Madhavan</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian police said on Friday they raided the home of a company executive whose firm has been linked to a growing scandal involving the privatisation of the nation's telecommunications sector.</p>
<p>The raid followed a search of two homes belonging to former communications minister Sukh Ram during which police seized more than $1 million in cash and the arrest of a civil servant.</p>
<p>The Central Bureau of Investigation (CBI) said it raided on Thursday the home of Mahendra Nahata, chairman of Himachal Futuristic Communications Ltd (HFCL), a little-known firm that won lucrative licences earlier this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Searches were conducted at his home,&quot; CBI spokesman S.M. Khan told Reuters. &quot;Some documents were seized and are being scrutinised.&quot; The Press Trust of India (PTI) said his offices were also raided on Friday.</p>
<p>Neither Nahata nor company officials could be reached for comment. &quot;Some CBI officials did visit the house of Mr Nahata and held discussions with him,&quot; PTI quoted a senior company official, Arvind Kharbanda, as saying.</p>
<p>Last week, the CBI seized cash worth over $1 million from two homes belonging to Sukh Ram. He was abroad during the raids last week and was located on Friday in London.</p>
<p>His relatives told the Indian high commission in London he was unwell and planned to return to India within a week, PTI said. He was earlier in the United States as part of a trip which media reports said was for treatment linked to heart problems.</p>
<p>Khan confirmed police searches of Nahata's home were linked to last week's corruption case against Sukh Ram.</p>
<p>Former Prime Minister P.V. Narasimha Rao's Congress party, defeated in April-May general elections this year, suspended Sukh Ram from its membership this week after the raids.</p>
<p>No formal charges have been laid by the CBI but a senior telephone department official has been arrested in the case. On Friday, police arrested the owner of a radio equipment firm alleged to have been favoured by Sukh Ram, PTI said.</p>
<p>Sukh Ram oversaw a yet-unfinished privatisation process that began in 1994 and was accused by the opposition of unfairly favouring the HFCL in an auction of licences under an economic reform programme started in 1991. He has denied the accusations.</p>
<p>Although the raids on his homes were not linked to the privatisation of telephone services, they revived simmering charges that Sukh Ram mishandled the tendering process for licences in the privatisation scheme.</p>
<p>Opposition parties protesting against Sukh Ram and the licensing process virtually paralysed parliament during a month-long session last December.</p>
<p>On Monday, new Communications Minister Beni Prasad Verma ordered an overhaul of the committee which awards the licences.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
