<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10195" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Recreational vehicles haul up Honda profits.</title>
<headline>Recreational vehicles haul up Honda profits.</headline>
<byline>Mitsuo Suzuki</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Honda Motor Co Ltd announced on Friday that its first-quarter profits jumped by nearly 300 percent from a year earlier thanks to booming demand for recreational vehicles and a weaker yen.</p>
<p>The increase prompted the automaker to raise its profit forecasts for the current business year.</p>
<p>Honda's group net profit in the first quarter of the business year that started on April 1 jumped 283.4 percent from a year before to 45.71 billion yen ($423 million).</p>
<p>&quot;The main reason for the profit increase was strong demand for recreational vehicles,&quot; managing director Kunihiro Chujo told Reuters.</p>
<p>He also said group profits in the first quarter were pushed up by 25 billion yen ($231 million) due to the weaker yen, which averaged 107 yen to the dollar compared with 84.45 yen to the dollar a year earlier.</p>
<p>Booming sales of recreational vehicles boosted operating profits by 50.6 billion yen ($468 million), the company said.</p>
<p>But Chujo said the robust sales also increased sales costs by 37.1 billion yen ($343 million) in the quarter.</p>
<p>Honda sold almost three times the number of CR-V recreational vehicles in Japan -- 26,492 -- it had targeted.</p>
<p>Other recreational vehicles, such Step Wagons and Odysseys, exceeded their sales targets by 100 to almost 200 percent.</p>
<p>Encouraged by the quarterly result, Honda raised its parent and group profit forecasts for the 1996/97 business year.</p>
<p>It raised its forecast for group net profit to 160 billion yen ($1.48 billion) from its May forecast of 120 billion yen ($1.11 billion).</p>
<p>In 1995/96, Honda posted actual parent current profit of 47.18 billion yen ($436 million) and group net profit of 70.8 billion yen ($655 million).</p>
<p>Honda also announced that domestic production in July was up 18.5 percent from the same month a year ago while domestic sales were up 22.5 percent.</p>
<p>It said in a statement said that its exports in July rose 14.7 percent year-on-year, and its overseas production was up 30.1 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Its production is exceeding projected levels, its U.S. sales are strong now and it will start exporting its CR-V to the U.S. That will contribute to its profit in the second half,&quot; Nomura Research analyst Seiji Sugiura said.</p>
<p>&quot;Domestic demand for Honda cars has been so strong that I believe group profits could be larger than the already revised-up figure of 160 billion yen ($1.48 billion) this year,&quot; Sugiura said.</p>
<p>Honda will start selling CR-Vs in the United States early next year and will resume exporting four-door Civics there later this year, another Honda official said.</p>
<p>He said the Civic exports are needed because Honda's Ohio plant is operating at full capacity and cannot meet demand.</p>
<p>Honda's sales in North America rose 14.6 percent from a year earlier to 457,912 in the January-July period due to strong demand for almost all its models, including U.S.-made Civics and the Japan-produced Acura TL luxury car.</p>
<p>Overall North American automobile demand rose 3.9 percent to 8.41 million units in the same period. ($1=108 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
