<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10198" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Rally in UK shares seen fading despite record.</title>
<headline>Rally in UK shares seen fading despite record.</headline>
<byline>Simon Cowell</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>As the shackles of interest rate worries dropped from financial markets, London shares leapt through 3,900 for the first time on Friday.</p>
<p>But as the next big target -- 4,000 -- for the FTSE 100 index of Britain's leading companies comes into view, market strategists were questioning whether the surge is sustainable.</p>
<p>The gains of the past month have certainly been dramatic -- a near 300 point rise since July 16 and a rebound from the year's low to its high within the space of five weeks.</p>
<p>The latest push to shares came on Thursday from interest rate cuts across Europe in the wake of an easing in monetary policy by Germany's Bundesbank.</p>
<p>That move followed a stream of welcome data for markets through August which calmed fears about overheating economies and inflation in both Britain and the U.S.</p>
<p>Even after August's rise, valuations on the stock market are not stretched, say strategists. But identifying the factors that might provide the impetus to continue the rally are difficult.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not that far away but I would be moderately surprised to see 4,000 in the ultra short term. The market has rallied very quickly from the sell-off in the early part of July when Wall Street was under pressure,&quot; said UBS strategist Tim Brown.</p>
<p>Another quick surge forward is unlikely, particularly with the prospect of downbeat comments and disappointing results from the looming manufacturing sector's results season, says Brown.</p>
<p>And uncertainty about U.S. and British interest rates, a fast-approaching British election and November budget are all likely to play a part in capping the soaring stock market.</p>
<p>The gains in the market this week, with new highs on five out of six days, came as markets took heart from the larger than expected German rate cut and the U.S. Federal Reserve's decision to leave rates there unchanged.</p>
<p>But Brown said it is difficult to see interest rates driving shares much further, and another cut in British rates -- normally taken as good news -- may not please markets this time.</p>
<p>&quot;There's sufficient uncertainty between the view of the politicians and the Bank of England -- and quite a few economists -- that the market will see it as a worrying sign because of the risk of overheating,&quot; said Brown.</p>
<p>Yet the recent rally in the bond market has helped provide leeway for August's advance in share prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Whenever equities have tried to rally in the past it's been constrained by tight domestic valuations relative to gilts. This time there's been no trigger saying hang on, equities look expensive to gilts',&quot; said BZW strategist Steve Wright.</p>
<p>A slowing in the flow of new issues, privatisations and rights issues, switching into cyclical stocks and continuing bid speculation have provided other boosts.</p>
<p>&quot;We could see the market move a little forward but we have a year end target of 3,750 and if the market were to get to 4,000 it would probably be an ideal selling opportunity,&quot; said Wright.</p>
<p>The long holiday weekend period in Britain, where financial markets are closed on Monday, gives investors a chance to catch their breath and a period of consolidation is likely.</p>
<p>British economic and company news is thin on the ground next week and attention is set to shift back to the U.S.</p>
<p>But with levels of cash held by institutional investors relatively high, pressure to put money back into the market may yet provide further fuel to the rally.</p>
<p>&quot;There's quite a lot of cash out there and quite a lot of people will be nervous. All the data through August has been one way...and the turnaround in interest rate sentiment, if it's sustained, will add to that pressure (to put money into market),&quot; said SBC Warburg strategist George Hodgson.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
