<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10194" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. durable goods orders up strongly in July.</title>
<headline>U.S. durable goods orders up strongly in July.</headline>
<byline>Glenn Somerville</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Orders for costly manufactured goods posted broad-based gains in July, the Commerce Department said Friday, led by a jump in demand for communications equipment.</p>
<p>Total new orders for durable goods climbed 1.6 percent last month to a seasonally adjusted $172.7 billion -- a much more robust increase than anticipated by Wall Street economists, who had forecast orders would rise only 0.3 percent.</p>
<p>The July surge in orders followed a revised 0.2 percent decrease in June orders. It was the second big increase in the past three months, including a 4.2 percent surge in May orders, and was likely to raise questions as to whether the economic expansion was decelerating as rapidly as some analysts thought.</p>
<p>Not only did July orders increase, but shipments of finished products rose solidly and order backlogs fattened last month, primarily because of more orders for new commercial aircxraft and parts.</p>
<p>Wall Street analysts took a mixed view of the report, which sent the inflation-sensitive 30-year U.S. Treasury bond off half a point. Its yield climbed to 6.89 percent from 6.83 percent late Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there's a lot of subjectivity in these numbers, but on its face the numbers are clearly strong and point to a beginning strong period for the third quarter at least at the manufacturing level,&quot; said Vincent Malanga, president of Fundamental Funds at Lasalle Economics in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;We got a good 2.1 percent rise ex-transport, which suggests we've got quite a healthy manufacturing sector,&quot; added David Sloan, senior economist at I.D.E.A. Inc. &quot;I think it's reasonably broad-based gains. It suggests the underlying economy looks fairly healthy.&quot;</p>
<p>Durable goods are products like cars and home appliances that are intended to last at least three years. Rising orders and shipments are an indicator of the health of the manufacturing sector, which generates many of the better-paying jobs that keep incomes rising.</p>
<p>The only major category of durable goods that failed to register an orders increase in July was transportation equipment. July's flat performance followed a 1.2 percent drop in June orders.</p>
<p>Excluding transportation, durables orders shot up 2.1 percent last month after a 0.2 percent rise in June and a 1.1 percent rise in May.</p>
<p>Orders for electronic and electrical equipment jumped 4.7 percent to a seasonally adjusted $28.1 billion in July after a 3.9 percent gain in June. The department said there were widespread increases in this category, led by communcications equipment.</p>
<p>Industrial machinery orders, which include computers, rose 2.1 percent in July to $32.3 billion following a 0.2 percent increase in June.</p>
<p>Orders for defence goods, which experience wide monthly swings, dropped 36.5 percent last month to $5.1 billion after a 26.4 percent increase in June.</p>
<p>But orders for non-defence capital goods, an indication of business investment in new equipment, increased briskly, by 7.2 percent, to $46 billion after a 4.6 percent decrease in June.</p>
<p>Shipments of durable goods, an indication of current demand, climbed 0.7 percent to $168 billion after dropping 0.4 percent in June.</p>
<p>Unfilled orders were up strongly, by 1 percent, to $480 billion in July after a 0.7 percent gain in June. It was the tenth increase in the past 11 months for order backlogs, pointing to underlying strength in manufacturing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
