<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10202" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Buba cut does nothing for dollar, outlook gloomy.</title>
<headline>Buba cut does nothing for dollar, outlook gloomy.</headline>
<byline>Phil Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar's failure to get above technical resistance pegged around 1.4950-60 marks in the wake of the Bundesbank's money market interest rate cut is disappointing and the general feeling is that it will remain lifeless, foreign exchange analysts said on Friday. &quot;The dollar has failed to gain any meaningful momentum on the back of the Bundebank's larger than expected rate cut and is unlikely to do so in the near future,&quot; said Klaus Baader, senior currency economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>&quot;In our view the short-term risks are now very much skewed to the downside for dollar/mark.&quot;</p>
<p>At 0730 GMT the dollar was at 1.4900 marks, half a pfennig off Thursday's European close of 1.4960. On the yen it was little changed at 108.40 against Thursday's 108.46 with the focus firmly on dollar/mark. The Bundesbank's 30 basis point cut in the 3.30 percent repo rate came as a total surprise to the market where the most bullish forecasts, anyway thin on the ground, had looked for a maximum 20 basis point cut. The dollar shot up to 1.4950 marks in immediate reaction to the rate cut but failed to break above and quickly fell back.</p>
<p>So in the near-term everything seems to depend on a break above 1.4950 marks and analysts say if a German rate cut cannot do it, it is difficult to see what will. Further out the outlook for the dollar is also somewhat gloomy.</p>
<p>&quot;Long term the dollar is still going to be vulnerable,&quot; said James Montier, currency economist at Kleinwort Benson.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. still has problems both on the fiscal side and the trade side so I don't see much strength coming through for the dollar.&quot; He noted that on top of that portfolio outflow were continuing as yields remain much more attractive outside the U.S., and as domestic investors on Wall Street start to suffer from vertigo.</p>
<p>Klienwort's end year forecast for dollar/mark is 1.45</p>
<p>There is also U.S. industry in the background, and with an election coming up the exporters will be lobbying hard for a weaker dollar. &quot;There will be pressure from the exporters, and the politicians wouldn't want to upset such a powerful lobby group,&quot; Kleinwort's Montier said. Back in early July when dollar/yen hit 110, the Detroit auto industry became quite vocal in calling for action to halt the dollar's rise against the yen. The Chrysler chief economist said at the time that 110 was &quot;at the top end of the range we're comfortable with...the dollar and the yen are more or less appropriately valued somewhere around 105.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
