<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10216" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Blue-chip stocks now the dream team on Wall Street.</title>
<headline>Blue-chip stocks now the dream team on Wall Street.</headline>
<byline>Pierre Belec</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue-chip stocks have become the dream team on Wall Street as investors, burnt by the recent rout of small stocks, run to the safety of companies with proven records.</p>
<p>In what may go down on record as the shortest market correction ever, the Dow Jones industrial average this week came within a skip and a jump of its all-time high after plunging in late May and July.</p>
<p>The world's most closely-watched index of 30-blue chip stocks rallied Thursday to within 45 points of its record close of 5,778.00 reached on May 22. On Friday, the market slipped on profit-taking to end at 5,722.74, off 10.73 points. For the week, it was up 33.29 points.</p>
<p>The sell-off that swept across Wall Street wiped out all of the Dow's gain for the year as stocks were hit hard by the one-two punch of rising long-term interest rates and disappointing earnings by high profile companies.</p>
<p>The correction ended with the index settling at 5,346 on July 23, though it ticked down to intra-day low of 5,182 on July 16. It was the biggest setback since the bull market began six years ago.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq composite lost nearly 9 percent in July and the average stock mutual fund shrank more than 5 percent.</p>
<p>Ralph Acampora, director of technical research at Prudential Securities says the new motto on Wall Street is &quot;Big is Better&quot; and he suggested that investors stay with blue-chip stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;These issues on balance went down the least during the May-July sell-off,&quot; he said. &quot;Now many of them are either at or about to make new 52-week highs.&quot;</p>
<p>The blue chips -- AT&amp;T, International Business Machines Corp., Exxon Corp. Eastman Kodak and General Electric -- have regained nearly all of last month's losses, while the Nasdaq market, which is studded with smaller companies, has bounced back only 50 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said a bullish bias is again underpinning the market, as investors realise that while the economy may slow in the second half, it is not going to fall off the cliff.</p>
<p>They said the market's shakeout came at a time when unpleasant surprises tend to have an exaggerated effect as trading activity slows during Wall Street's summer doldrums.</p>
<p>Although stocks are again showing an upward bias, the experts said they doubted that the market will resume the type of fast-paced rise seen in 1995 and the first few months of 1996.</p>
<p>The mood on Wall Street has changed, they said, and what previously was a stock market that could only put a positive spin on just about every situations, is now more realistic and sees both the good and the bad.</p>
<p>The confirmation that stocks are back in their bullish track could come in September when the market-making portfolio managers return from their vacations after the Labour Day holiday, analysts said.</p>
<p>Wall Street's worries about higher interest rates started to fade into the background after this week's decision by the German central bank to slash a key money market interest rate, a move that was quickly matched by other European central banks and Canada.</p>
<p>They said the Bundesbank's deep rate cut to 3.00 percent from 3.30 percent and the chances of even lower interest rates may take some pressure off the Federal Reserve to raise interest rates in the coming months.</p>
<p>At a policy-setting meeting this week, the Fed opted to keep short-term interest rates unchanged amid signs that sectors of the economy such as housing, retail and manufacturing have slowed recently.</p>
<p>But some experts still see danger ahead for stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;Some measure of market strength are truly troubling,&quot; says Byron Wien, managing director of Morgan Stanley.</p>
<p>&quot;The number of stocks able to make new highs has declined dramatically in spite of the indexes moving back toward their all-time highs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;A peak in this indicator usually anticipates a decline in the market, and according to historical precedent, the time for a top formation is now,&quot; Wien said.</p>
<p>Prudential's Acampora said the Dow Jones index can still make new highs even while other stock market barometers are backpedalling.</p>
<p>&quot;If you go back in time, there were periods when the Dow kept going up and the other indexes were not confirming the trend,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Between 1963 and 1964, the NYSE advance/decline line failed to make a new high, while the DJIA gained over 20 percent,&quot; Acampora said. &quot;I believe that this time around we will witness a similar occurrence -- new Dow highs without breadth confirmation.&quot;</p>
<p>Breadth is Wall Street jargon for the number of shares moving up or down.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq composite index closed 0.91 of a point lower Friday at 1,143.05. For the week, it was up 9.40 points.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's index of 500 stocks was off 3.65 points to 667.03, up 1.82 points for the week. The American Stock Exchange index was up 0.62 of a point at 560.94, and was up 4.80 for the week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
