<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10222" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London stocks hit record, Tokyo's Nikkei falls.</title>
<headline>London stocks hit record, Tokyo's Nikkei falls.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here is how major stock markets outside the United States ended Friday.</p>
<p>LONDON - Shares finished the week as they began, setting record highs, after the Bundesbank's decision to ease monetary policy triggered cuts in interest rates across Europe on Thursday.</p>
<p>Stronger-than-expected U.S. data took the shine off the market briefly before shares recovered to end at a record close of 3,907.5 on the FTSE index, a rise of 16.4 points on the day and 34.6 since last Friday.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Stocks ended almost unchanged as a weaker dollar and softer German bonds weighed on trading sentiment.</p>
<p>At the end of bourse trade the DAX index was down 2.10 points at 2,555.16 points but up 6.8 from last week. The IBIS DAX index, which measures all-day electronic trade in German blue-chips, ended the day at 2,562.12.</p>
<p>PARIS - Shares ended slightly higher after spending most of the day in the red on profit-taking after a big rise on Thursday on unexpected interest rate cuts.</p>
<p>Wall Street's recovery from a lower start on higher than expected July durable good data pulled shares back. The blue-chip CAC-40 index closed up 3.06 points at 2,020.82, a rise of 41.30 from last Friday.</p>
<p>ZURICH - Shares closed slightly higher although they retreated from early morning highs.</p>
<p>U.S. durable goods data put shares under pressure but good performance in a few blue-chip stocks bolstered prices. The broad SPI gained 5.70 to 2,382.20 points, up 30.39 on the week.</p>
<p>TOKYO - The stock market's rally ended after gains over the past four days. The key Nikkei index made a strong start after the German Bundesbank's repo rate cut but profit-taking later took hold, erasing gains.</p>
<p>The Nikkei 225 average closed down 134.44 points at 21,228.80 but showed a net rise of 394.80 on the week.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - The week's rally in stocks came to a halt with prices ending lower as investors took profits ahead of a long weekend.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index fell 54.13 points to 11,424.64 but was up 248.66 from a week ago.</p>
<p>SYDNEY - Shares had a firmer session, closing near the highs after getting strength from Wall Street's gains on Thursday.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index finished up 18.3 points at 2,292.9, just off its intra-day high of 2,293.7, for a gain of 59.6 since last Friday.</p>
<p>JOHANNESBURG - Shares shook off some of the gloom seen earlier in the week but dealers cautioned that it was too early to talk about a turn in sentiment.</p>
<p>The industrial index ended 52.2 points higher at 7.733.8, a fall of 2.7 from last Friday. The gold index rose 36.4 points to 1,740.2, up 6.1 on the week, and the all share index was up 85.2 points at 6,564.2, up 36.8 from last Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
