<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10228" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain says it complied with Europe's BSE checks.</title>
<headline>Britain says it complied with Europe's BSE checks.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain on Friday denied a report that it had secretly avoided implementing European Union (EU) rules to stop mad cow disease spreading to the continent.</p>
<p>The Guardian newspaper said almost two million cattle were sold to Britain's EU partners without adequate controls to see if they had been born to cows infected with bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE), or mad cow disease.</p>
<p>The paper alleged that the Ministry of Agriculture issued secret orders to its officials that they need carry out computer checks on only 10 percent of calves exported to the continent.</p>
<p>EU rules required 100 percent verification.</p>
<p>But the ministry said Britain had always met its obligation not to send to other EU countries the calves of cows in which BSE was known or suspected.</p>
<p>&quot;A 1990 EU ruling required the UK to make full use of computer records to guarantee the identification of animals and these procedures were twice scrutinised by two visiting European Commission missions in 1994 and 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;On both occasions they expressed complete satisfaction with the UK measures,&quot; the ministry said in a brief statement.</p>
<p>Earlier the Brussels-based Commission said it was checking The Guardian story.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is a problem, we shall demand an explanation from the British government,&quot; Commission spokesman Thierry Daman told a news briefing.</p>
<p>The implications of any such illegal exports have become more serious following recent confirmation by the British government that BSE can be passed from cow to calf.</p>
<p>Daman said EU inspectors found in August 1995 that the Ministry of Agriculture was carrying out computer checks in line with agreed EU rules. The Commission was now checking reports from earlier inspections, he added.</p>
<p>Veal calves accounted for nearly all live cattle exports to the continent before exports were banned by the EU in March 1996 due to fears that BSE could spread to humans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
