<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10221" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton approves FDA curbs on teen smoking.</title>
<headline>Clinton approves FDA curbs on teen smoking.</headline>
<byline>Laurence McQuillan</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton, endorsing a plan broadening the Food and Drug Administration's (FDA) powers, approved rules to curb teen smoking by restricting the sale and advertising of tobacco, the White House said on Friday.</p>
<p>Against a backdrop of election-year politics, Clinton publicly embraced a controversial plan that has been softened from a more stringent approach unveiled last August.</p>
<p>&quot;The president has accepted and authorized&quot; the FDA action after an internal administration review, White House Press Secretary Mike McCurry said.</p>
<p>The restrictions include limiting vending machine sales and curbing advertising aimed at young people.</p>
<p>McCurry said Clinton &quot;in essence has accepted ... that cigarettes and smokeless tobacco are delivery devices&quot; for nicotine, which the administration believes qualifies them to fall under the authority of the FDA.</p>
<p>Clinton planned to make a formal announcement of details of the new federal regulation at the White House during a 1:30 p.m. EDT (1730 GMT) ceremony.</p>
<p>Underscoring the political implications of the decision, Joe Lockhart, the president's campaign spokesman, said Republican rival Bob Dole &quot;faces a big decision today -- protect children or protect the tobacco lobby.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole has been criticized by Democrats for accepting contributions from tobacco interests and saying no link has been made between smoking and cancer. His spokesman, Nelson Warfield, dismissed the announcement as an &quot;election-year gimmick&quot; that could delay a teen-smoking crackdown because of lawsuits.</p>
<p>The new regulations, which will be phased in gradually starting in six months, outlaw a wide variety of advertising aimed at enticing youths to take up tobacco -- including hats and T-shirts with a cigarette brand name.</p>
<p>Advertising near schools will also be restricted, with a ban on tobacco billboards within 1,000 feet (300 metres) of a school site. Magazines with a more than 15 percent youth readership will be limited to text-only tobacco ads.</p>
<p>The final regulations, however, fall short of the administration's initial bid to outlaw all sales of cigarettes in vending machines or through the mail.</p>
<p>Under the revised language, vending machine sales will be permitted in places where minors are not legally permitted, such as bars and nightclubs. There will be no limit on mail-order sales.</p>
<p>Clinton, who first called for curbs last August, has advocated limiting advertising of tobacco products aimed at children and called for steps to make it more difficult for them to buy such items.</p>
<p>&quot;We assume ... that it will be litigated,&quot; McCurry said of the decision. Tobacco companies have made clear they will fight the regulations in court by claiming the FDA does not have the authority to regulate nicotine.</p>
<p>The advertising industry also took exception to the limits, calling such curbs an unconstitutional breach of free speech that would cost $1.1 billion annually in lost revenues.</p>
<p>Hal Shoup, executive vice president of the American Association of Advertising Agencies, said there was no dispute that children's access to tobacco should be limited. But he added, &quot;Our quarrel is with the violation of the right to speak truthfully about legal products.&quot;</p>
<p>The National Center for Tobacco-Free Kids, however, denied that the proposed restrictions were unconstitutional.</p>
<p>The new regulation &quot;is entirely consistent with the First Amendment and with Supreme Court decisions interpreting the right of government to restrict commercial speech in order to protect important governmental interests,&quot; the center said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
