<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10229" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey says Shell LNG deal move shows confidence.</title>
<headline>Turkey says Shell LNG deal move shows confidence.</headline>
<byline>Ercan Ersoy</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish officials hailed on Friday a move by Royal Dutch/Shell Group to build a gas terminal and power plant complex worth $2.4 billion in Turkey as a return of foreign confidence to the country hit by political and economic instability over the past year.</p>
<p>&quot;The Shell investment intention shows the level of confidence in Turkey from foreign investors,&quot; said a senior energy official, who declined to be named.</p>
<p>The Turkish arm of the Anglo-Dutch oil giant said on Friday it had applied to the energy ministry to build a liquefied natural gas (LNG) terminal and power plant complex that would have a total power capacity of 2,000 megaWatts (MW).</p>
<p>&quot;We have expressed our intention to the energy ministry to build an LNG terminal and a power generation unit with a total capacity of 2,000 MW,&quot; a statement from the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;The first power unit will be of 650 to 700 MW capacity,&quot; the statement said. Shell would carry out the project with two other companies which the statement did not identify.</p>
<p>The statement said a feasibility study would begin immediately if the government gave permission for the project, presently under consideration at the energy ministry.</p>
<p>A nine-month-long political crisis in Turkey ended in June when the election-winner Islamist Welfare Party (RP) and conservative True Path Party (DYP) set up a coalition to tackle the nation's political and economic ills.</p>
<p>Turkey, in urgent need of electricity, has been seeking ways including electricity imports to solve its power shortage problem expected to hit the country from later this year.</p>
<p>The Shell-led project will be the second plant to use LNG to produce power in Turkey. Several European and Japanese companies will build stages of a 480-MW gas-fired plant at Marmara Ereglisi, 150 km (90 miles) west of Istanbul where there is already an LNG conversion terminal.</p>
<p>Turkey consumes about nine billion cubic metres (318 billion cubic feet) of imported natural gas, including LNG equivalent to two billion cubic metres (70 billion cubic feet) imported from Algeria and processed at Marmara Ereglisi.</p>
<p>Last week Turkey struck a $23-billion deal to buy gas from Iran for 23 years from 1999 through a pipeline to be built from the Iranian city of Tabriz to Ankara.</p>
<p>The government said it would revive plans to build a nuclear power plant on the southern coast that would have a capacity of up to 1,400 MW.</p>
<p>Turkey expects to produce 93.1 billion kiloWatt-hours (kWh) of electricity this year against an expected consumption of 97.5 billion kWh. It will soon begin electricity imports from Iran.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
