<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10231" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German building sector urges new minimum wage deal.</title>
<headline>German building sector urges new minimum wage deal.</headline>
<byline>Catherine O'Mahony</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German construction industry on Friday launched a fresh attempt to set a minimum wage for the sector and urged other industry groups not to block the initiative as they have in the past.</p>
<p>The building workers' union IG Bau and the two leading industry associations revealed a new agreement for a minimum hourly wage of 17 marks for west Germany and 15.64 marks for workers in the east -- considerably below levels they tried, but failed, to establish nationwide earlier this year.</p>
<p>In a statement, the union said it had agreed to compromise on a lower minimum wage because of the increasing urgency of getting legislation in place to ward off competition from low-paying foreign contractors.</p>
<p>&quot;Both sides declared unanimously during the talks that there was an urgent need to act on a minimum wage. Drawing in foreign workers into the domestic wage system ... could no longer be delayed,&quot; IG Bau said.</p>
<p>A previous minimum wage agreement -- envisaging minimum hourly rates of 18.60 marks for the west and 17.11 marks for the east -- foundered in April when the BDA umbrella employers' federation vetoed the deal during its final negotiating stages.</p>
<p>The BDA complained that the original deal exceeded lowest wages in other sectors and could carry an inflationary risk.</p>
<p>IG Bau and construction industry groups, who were incensed at the BDA's abrupt turnabout on their first deal, say the compromise rates represent just 82 percent of the current lowest wage in the building sector and should therefore be acceptable to all.</p>
<p>IG Bau and building firms blame surging unemployment levels in the German building sector on a big influx to the country of foreign contractors, mainly English and Portuguese, employing foreign workers at cut-price rates.</p>
<p>The building industry estimates that around 200,000 foreign building workers are currently employed by low-paying foreign firms in Germany.</p>
<p>At the same time, the number of German building workers unemployed in June was 186,500, around a third higher than in the year-earlier period.</p>
<p>&quot;A generally binding minimum wage ... could at least slow down further employment losses,&quot; the two leading industry associations, the Hauptverband der Deutschen Bauindustrie and the Zentralverband des Deutschen Baugewerbes said.</p>
<p>IG Bau said the wage agreement could become law as early as October 1 if approved by the Labour Ministry's wage committee.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
