<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10234" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Netanyahu targets illegal foreign workers.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu targets illegal foreign workers.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Heller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's government on Friday considered for the first time ways to cut a growing dependence on foreign workers who have taken jobs which are off-limits to Palestinians and unwanted by Jews.</p>
<p>&quot;We will act to reduce drastically the presence of illegal foreign workers as well as cut the scope of foreign labourers who enter the country with a permit,&quot; a cabinet statement quoted Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu as saying.</p>
<p>The communique said the cabinet would take a &quot;practical decision&quot; next week.</p>
<p>&quot;We will propose expelling about 1,000 illegal foreign labourers from Israel a month,&quot; Labour and Welfare Minister Eli Ishai told Israel Radio before Friday's debate.</p>
<p>But Ishai's plan was no blueprint for a mass exodus from Israel of workers from countries such as Romania, Thailand, Turkey and China who now do the low-paying manual labour of Palestinians barred from the Jewish state for security reasons.</p>
<p>It would take authorities more than eight years to expel all of the 100,000 foreigners he said were working in Israel without a permit -- assuming police could round all of them up and no new illegal labourers slipped into the country.</p>
<p>Ishai said another 100,000 foreigners had valid work papers.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a problem here. (Hiring foreigners) pays -- it is good for building contractors....We may have to keep a quota of foreign workers. The question is how many,&quot; Ishai said.</p>
<p>Many Israelis initially welcomed the blue-collar foreign influx at the height of the six-year-long Palestinian uprising that began in 1987, during the course of which Arab guerrillas knifed Jews in Israeli cities.</p>
<p>But while Israeli law required Palestinian workers to return to their homes in the occupied territories each evening, foreigners remain overnight in squalid housing.</p>
<p>&quot;Go look at the old central bus station area (in Tel Aviv). It has all the things you see in the Bronx,&quot; legislator Ran Cohen told the radio, comparing the foreign workers' slum area to the New York borough known for poverty and crime.</p>
<p>Cohen called for the establishment of &quot;transit camps&quot; to hold illegal immigrants for several days before expulsion, a proposal which his left-wing Meretz party colleague Amnon Rubinstein said would hurt Israel's image.</p>
<p>&quot;It won't be a concentration camp,&quot; Cohen snapped.</p>
<p>The cabinet communique quoted Netanyahu as saying that while &quot;strong action&quot; was needed to stop foreign workers staying in Israel illegally, &quot;we are talking about human beings and therefore must treat them accordingly&quot;.</p>
<p>Israel's Channel Two television showed on Thursday six Turkish workers locked in a shack on an Israeli farm by their employer, apparently over a financial dispute.</p>
<p>&quot;It is just like a ghetto,&quot; said an incredulous police officer at the scene.</p>
<p>Nigerians cleaning apartments, Thais picking flowers in greenhouses, Chinese building workers and Filipina nannies have become permanent fixtures in the Jewish state.</p>
<p>The Palestinian Authority has demanded Israel allow more of its people in to work, saying an Israeli closure had crippled the economy in the self-ruled areas.</p>
<p>Before the Palestinian uprising, as many as 160,000 Arabs from the West Bank and Gaza worked in Israel.</p>
<p>Israel sealed off the territories and stopped Palestinians from entering in February after the first in a series of Moslem suicide bombings that killed 59 people -- including seven Romanian workers. Today some 30,000 Palestinians work in Israel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
