<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10230" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Recreational vehicles boost Japanese automaker profits.</title>
<headline>Recreational vehicles boost Japanese automaker profits.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Honda Motor Co. Ltd. said Friday its first-quarter profits nearly quadrupled from a year earlier, thanks to booming demand for recreational vehicles and a weaker yen.</p>
<p>Separately, Toyota Motor Corp., Japan's biggest carmaker, and Nissan Motor Co. Ltd., its closest rival, said robust demand for recreational vehicles also boosted their domestic production in July.</p>
<p>Honda's group net profit in the first quarter of the business year that began April 1 jumped 283.4 percent from a year before to 45.71 billion yen ($423 million), mainly due to strong demand for recreational vehicles.</p>
<p>Managing Director Kunihiro Chujo said group profits in the first quarter were pushed up by 25 billion yen ($231 million) due to the weaker yen, which averaged 107 yen to the dollar compared with 84.45 yen to the dollar a year earlier.</p>
<p>Booming sales of recreational vehicles boosted operating profits by 50.6 billion yen ($468 million), the company said.</p>
<p>But Chujo said the robust sales also increased sales costs by 37.1 billion yen ($343 million) in the quarter.</p>
<p>Honda sold almost three times the number of CR-V recreational vehicles in Japan -- 26,492 -- it had targeted.</p>
<p>Other recreational vehicles, such Step Wagons and Odysseys, exceeded their sales targets by 100 to almost 200 percent.</p>
<p>Honda raised its parent and group profit forecasts for the 1996/97 business year to 160 billion yen ($1.48 billion) from its May forecast of 120 billion yen ($1.11 billion).</p>
<p>In 1995/96, Honda posted actual parent current profit of 47.18 billion yen ($436 million) and group net profit of 70.8 billion yen ($655 million).</p>
<p>Domestic production in July rose 18.5 percent from a year ago while domestic sales grew 22.5 percent, it said. Exports in July rose 14.7 percent, and overseas production was up 30.1 percent.</p>
<p>Honda's sales in North America rose 14.6 percent from a year earlier to 457,912 in the January-July period due to strong demand for almost all its models, including U.S.-made Civics and the Japan-produced Acura TL luxury car.</p>
<p>Toyota, which has 39.5 percent of the domestic market, said its domestic production in July rose 16 percent from the year before. Its exports in July jumped 37.3 percent and overseas production grew 15.8 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;In July last year, our exports to the Middle East were small due to the high yen, and the U.S.-Japan car dispute had a negative impact on our exports to the United States,&quot; the Toyota spokeswoman said. Exports to Asia rose this July.</p>
<p>Nissan also said active demand for recreational vehicles pushed up its production in July. Demand for luxury cars was also robust, a company spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Nissan said its July domestic production was up 5.4 percent from the previous year. Exports were down 1.1 percent but overseas production was up 14.8 percent.</p>
<p>In contrast with its bigger rivals, domestic production at Mitsubishi Motors Corp., Japan's third-largest car maker, rose only 0.1 percent year-on-year in July.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
