<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10238" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Icahn lifts RJR stake, repeats spin-off call.</title>
<headline>Icahn lifts RJR stake, repeats spin-off call.</headline>
<byline>Gene Ramos</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investor Carl Icahn said Thursday he raised his stake in RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp. to 5.8 percent and repeated his call for an immediate spin-off of its Nabisco Holdings Corp. food unit.</p>
<p>In a filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission, Icahn said he and his companies bought 1.27 million additional shares of the tobacco and food company between Aug. 12 and 22 at prices ranging from $25.25 to $28.625 a share.</p>
<p>That raised his stake to 15.9 million, which were purchased for a total of $489.3 million, according to the filing. He previously held about a 4.8 percent stake.</p>
<p>Icahn said he and his companies bought the stock &quot;for investment since they believe that the shares are undervalued.&quot;</p>
<p>He said his group thought that RJR should take all steps necessary to carry out a spin-off of RJR's non-tobacco operation to raise the value of its component parts and maximize value to shareholders.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Icahn, teaming up with investor Bennett LeBow, failed in an attempt to bring about a separation of the Nabisco Holdings from the tobacco business.</p>
<p>Icahn said his group has held a meeting with RJR management at which they discussed their position about the spin-off but were told that such a move should not be undertaken now.</p>
<p>&quot;Registrants believe that, especially after the recent loss by another tobacco company in a smoking damage case ... shareholders would be best served if the spinoff was accomplished immediately rather than waiting for some future date or event,&quot; the group's filing said.</p>
<p>Icahn was apparently referring to a Florida jury verdict earlier this month against Brown &amp; Williamson Tobacco Corp. and in favour of a smoker who sued alleging he contracted cancer because of cigarette smoking.</p>
<p>Icahn and LeBow parted ways in June after they differed over whether the tobacco litigation settlement offered by Liggett Group Inc., a unit of LeBow's Brooke Group Ltd., would entice RJR shareholders to vote for a spin-off.</p>
<p>According to a statement then issued by the two, Icahn did not believe RJR shareholders would support a tobacco litigation settlement that was not industrywide. LeBow, meanwhile, was committed to pursuing its litigation settlements.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
