<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10240" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British rock band Oasis plays secret concert.</title>
<headline>British rock band Oasis plays secret concert.</headline>
<byline>Merissa Marr</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Just a week after performing in front of 250,000 at one of Britain's largest rock events, superstars Oasis played for a select few at a top secret concert.</p>
<p>Four hundred excited fans who had won tickets for Friday's intimate concert sat on the edge of their seats ready to hear the British band, often described as the Beatles of the nineties, perform their chart-topping favourties.</p>
<p>But the fortunate few were left disappointed when controversial lead singer Liam Gallagher failed to appear on stage. Instead, he watched the show from a private box.</p>
<p>&quot;Liam is not going to be with us tonight. He's got a sore throat,&quot; brother Noel Gallagher told the selected audience at the Royal Festival Hall in London.</p>
<p>The concert was recorded as part of music channel MTV's Unplugged series, but the company was highly unimpressed by Liam's absence from the stage.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very disappointed,&quot; said spokesman Ian Renwick, adding that the music channel had yet to decide whether the concert would be broadcast after all.</p>
<p>Billed as Britain's rock event of the year, the concert had been shrouded in secrecy. Competition winners were not informed about the location until the last minute.</p>
<p>The exclusive performance was a great contrast to last weekend when the band performed before a quarter of a million fans, one of the biggest audiences for a single act in Britain.</p>
<p>Noel, the band's song-writer and singer, took the lead for the 90-minute performance as Liam looked on.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a real shame Liam couldn't play,&quot; said David Mootatamby, a fan from London.</p>
<p>Despite the lead singer's absence, the audience rewarded the band at the end with cheers and a standing ovation.</p>
<p>&quot;It was blinding. They really are a small venue band and should play more intimate venues,&quot; said fan Steve Johnson. &quot;It's almost better without Liam.&quot;</p>
<p>The band is about to embark on a world tour to include the United States, Europe and Australia, on which it hopes to repeat the success it has achieved in Britain.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
