<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10242" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Birt vows to safeguard BBC World Service.</title>
<headline>Birt vows to safeguard BBC World Service.</headline>
<byline>Keith Weir</byline>
<dateline>EDINBURGH 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>BBC Director General John Birt vowed on Friday to safeguard the corporation's much-praised World Service.</p>
<p>Birt's plans for closer integration of radio's World Service with domestic programme production have sparked fears that the quality and breadth of its news coverage will suffer.</p>
<p>But he told the Edinburgh International Television Festival that the World Service was safe in his hands.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue to fight for and to safeguard the quality, distinctiveness and independence of the World Service and all our global journalism,&quot; he said in a speech.</p>
<p>&quot;And it is extraordinary that anyone should suggest otherwise,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>With their distinctive opening theme tune, Lillibulero, World Service news broadcasts have won respect around the world for their even-handed treatment of global issues.</p>
<p>Birt's reforms, part of a broader reorganisation at the BBC, have provoked howls of anguish both in Britain and among the World Service's estimated 140 million listeners worldwide.</p>
<p>More than 200 parliamentarians have signed a motion of protest over the changes at the World Service. Flowers have been left as a sign of mourning at World Service's Bush House headquarters in central London.</p>
<p>Birt said the BBC's independent reporting had brought it into conflict with a number of governments around the world.</p>
<p>He said China and Saudi Arabia had effectively forced it to end transmission of its satellite television news services while he added that Burma continued to jam the World Service.</p>
<p>But Birt said the BBC would not bow to political pressure.</p>
<p>&quot;We will outlast the world's totalitarian regimes. We will remain a beacon in an uncertain world,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EDINBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
