<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10248" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Rampant demand keeps oil price buoyant.</title>
<headline>Rampant demand keeps oil price buoyant.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>World oil prices on Friday remained close to four-month highs, propped up by rising demand for energy ahead of the northern hemisphere winter and to fuel the booming economies of developing nations.</p>
<p>London October futures for international benchmark Brent crude were 11 cents down at $20.66 a barrel at 1550 GMT, leaving the market little changed on the week.</p>
<p>Brent so far this year has averaged $2 a barrel more than 1995's $16.94, defying analysts' expectations that a surge in supplies would outweigh extra demand.</p>
<p>Analysts cited stronger than expected demand growth for oil products this year from China, other developing Asian nations, Latin America and the U.S.</p>
<p>&quot;It's all down to demand,&quot; said one London-based energy market analyst. &quot;There are lot of hidden pockets of extra demand.</p>
<p>Heating oil and diesel prices have underpinned oil market strength from Asia to the U.S.</p>
<p>U.S. stocks of distillate fuel, which includes diesel and heating oil, were 18.5 million barrels below one year ago, according to the latest American Petroleum Institute report.</p>
<p>Chinese oil products in the first seven months of the year soared 56 percent compared to the same period of 1995, official figures released this week showed.</p>
<p>European oil traders said Brazil bought 300,000 tonnes of European gas oil in August, and was looking for more supplies in September. This compares to a total of 700,000 tonnes imported over the whole of 1995, they added.</p>
<p>Asian refiners have continued to plunder West African crude markets, buying another 500,000 barrels per day (bpd) for September on top of 500,000 bpd in August and 800,000 bpd in July.</p>
<p>In previous years Asian purchases from Atlantic Basin producers have been limited to the period October-April.</p>
<p>Crude markets on Friday also found support from a New York Times report that investigators had found evidence that TWA Flight 800 was downed by an explosive device.</p>
<p>The paper said chemists at the Federal Bureau of Investigation had found traces of plastic explosives on a piece of wreckage retrieved from the jet, which crashed off New York's Long Island on July 17.</p>
<p>Earlier this month the U.S. said Iran was the leading sponsor of terrorism against its interests. Oil dealers are concerned that proof of Iranian involvement could provoke retaliation and destabilise the Middle East.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>						    Aug 23	 Aug 22</p>
<p>						  (1550 GMT)     (close)</p>
<p>    Dated Brent				 $21.22	 $21.25</p>
<p>    IPE London Brent futures (Oct)	$20.69	 $20.73</p>
<p>    NYMEX light crude futures (Oct)     $22.16	 $22.30</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
