<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10243" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil is in demand, other commodities see dull trade.</title>
<headline>Oil is in demand, other commodities see dull trade.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>World commodity prices mostly ended a dull week little changed on Friday but with crude oil close to its highest level for four months on signs of firm demand.</p>
<p>London October futures for the international benchmark Brent Blend of crude were trading in London at around $20.60 per barrel.</p>
<p>Analysts said Brent so far this year has averaged $2 a barrel more than 1995's $16.94, defying expectations that a surge in supplies would outweigh extra demand.</p>
<p>They cited stronger-than-expected demand growth for oil products this year from China, other Asian nations, Latin America and the United States.</p>
<p>The industrial metals on the London Metal Exchange had an uncertain week with the flagship copper contract trading in a narrow range between $1,900 and $1,970 per tonne.</p>
<p>Copper was helped higher on Friday by book-squaring ahead of a three-day British holiday weekend.</p>
<p>Traders said bouts of short covering lifted copper from a low of $1,932 to $1,949, a $14 gain from Thursday, but the market never seriously attempted to break from its range.</p>
<p>Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) wheat futures were scarcely changed from a week ago around $4.50 per bushel.</p>
<p>London robusta coffee futures closed easier with the nearby September contract down $24 per tonne from Thursday at $1,685 after edging above $1,700 a week ago on prospects of tighter supply.</p>
<p>Producers have sold into the rally but technical analysts do not rule out a fresh advance next week.</p>
<p>Critical resistance over $1,700 has now seen a more serious challenge and there is an increasing possibility it will be cleared,&quot; said Elli Gifford in the latest weekly futures summary from Investment Research in Cambridge.</p>
<p>Some key commodity prices at 1600 GMT</p>
<p>						 Friday	    Thursday</p>
<p>    Gold ($/ounce)			 386.95	    386.95</p>
<p>    IPE Brent ($/barrel) (Oct)	  20.62	     20.62</p>
<p>(Ldn Metal Exchange)</p>
<p>    COPPER (three months/tonne)    1,948.00	  1,936.00</p>
<p>    ALUMINIUM			    1,478.00	  1,487.00</p>
<p>(Ldn futures)</p>
<p>    COFFEE ($/tonne) (Sep)	   1,685.00	  1,709.00</p>
<p>    COCOA (sterling/tonne) (Dec)   1,019.00	  1,032.00</p>
<p>    WHITE SUGAR ($/tonne) (Oct)	352.50	    353.00</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
