<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10257" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Europe grateful for rate cuts, but won't last long.</title>
<headline>Europe grateful for rate cuts, but won't last long.</headline>
<byline>Kate Kelland</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>European debt markets may well thank the Bundesbank for its lead in easing monetary policy, but the relief will not last long, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>A season of political bickering about budgets will begin to undermine confidence, and unless the dollar starts to pick up, European currencies and bonds will suffer, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank's cut is a help, but it's not a solution,&quot; said David Brickman, European economist at Yamaichi International in London. &quot;It may give (European) markets a temporary breather, but not much more than that.&quot;</p>
<p>The German central bank sparked off a frenzy of interest rate easings with a surprisingly hefty cut in its main money market, or repo, rate to 3.00 percent from 3.30 on Thursday. French, Dutch, Belgian, Finnish, Danish and Austrian authorities were swift to follow.</p>
<p>But analysts said that monetary policy is fading into the background and other factors are stepping into the spotlight.</p>
<p>&quot;We have reached a threshold where monetary policy is becoming less of a factor and we're turning to much more structural issues,&quot; said Kirit Shah, chief strategist at Sanwa International in London.</p>
<p>Two main issues for European debt to contend with now are domestic budgets and foreign exchange rates, analysts said.</p>
<p>Budget matters will be crucial as 1997 balance sheets will determine which countries meet the Maastricht criteria for European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) due to start in 1999.</p>
<p>France and Italy in particular are likely to face problems pushing their packages through and analysts said the air of nervousness is likely to pervade European debt markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors remain exceedingly sceptical of France's ability to cut its budget deficit in a credible fashion and in order to meet the Maastricht criteria,&quot; Brickman said.</p>
<p>&quot;And Italy has its own political worries. The political wrangling surrounding the budget is likely to cause problems for the market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said investors would be wise to hold off on trades seeking to take advantage of convergence between European bonds yields until budgets have been passed.</p>
<p>Then the focus would return to EMU, and with budgets in place, markets can start again to reflect the view that the union will go ahead in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;We still think EMU will happen,&quot; said Brickman. &quot;I'm just not convinced that the markets will be so sure over the autumn period -- there is a lot of uncertainty out there.&quot;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, currency worries will also play on market nerves.</p>
<p>&quot;The critical thing here is the dollar/deutschmark exchange rate,&quot; said Andrew Bevan, senior bond economist at Goldman Sachs in London. &quot;We really need to see the dollar trading higher against the mark, and see that leading to some strength in other European currencies (versus the mark).&quot;</p>
<p>While the Bundesbank's 30 basis point easing on Thursday pushed the mark sharply lower in Europe, the currency started to fight its corner again on Friday.</p>
<p>The dollar's performance on the back of the easing was not as impressive as it could have been, analysts said. While the dollar rose against the mark, it failed to hold above key resistance and was back below 1.49 marks by Friday's midsession.</p>
<p>&quot;What the Bundesbank did yesterday definitely helped, but we probably need something from the U.S. side,&quot; Bevan said.</p>
<p>Further signs of economic growth in the U.S. coupled with an interest rate rise by the Federal Reserve would be enough to push the dollar up, analysts said, but markets will probably have to wait for that until late this year or early next.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
