<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10250" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: WEEK AHEAD-Japan data, U.S. politics up for review.</title>
<headline>WEEK AHEAD-Japan data, U.S. politics up for review.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Thorpe</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese statistics, including the influential Tankan survey, will feature heavily on the data menu for financial markets in the week ahead, analysts said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Democratic convention may also draw some attention in a fairly light week for U.S. figures. In Europe, budget preparations and French data will be the focus.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly, speculation about a BOJ (Bank of Japan) tightening has tended to dwindle somewhat, and now it has reached the stage where the markets have taken the view the Tankan will be relatively soft,&quot; said Jeremy Hawkins of BankAmerica.</p>
<p>&quot;So there is a risk that we may get something stronger than expected, which will renew downward pressure on dollar/yen,&quot; said Hawkins, senior economic advisor at the U.S. bank.</p>
<p>The quarterly Tankan report on Japanese corporate sentiment is due on Wednesday. It is a key indicator for the BOJ, but with the economy still only showing a faint pulse, it should not throw up many surprises for markets, analysts said.</p>
<p>A clutch of Japanese numbers on Friday, including consumer prices, July unemployment and industrial production, will also show at most only modest improvements, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no risk of the ODR (official discount rate) going up, but perhaps they may allow call money to trade a bit firmer,&quot; said Hawkins.</p>
<p>In the U.S., official releases will be scant, though July existing home sales on Monday, August consumer confidence on Tuesday and more importantly, the Chicago Purchasing Managers Index (PMI) on Friday will give markets something to chew on.</p>
<p>Graham McDevitt, senior analyst at Paribas Capital Markets in London, said supply in the two- and five-year sector for the U.S., plus a weak technical backdrop for Treasuries would be a focus in the absence of more riviting financial news.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, $18.75 billion of two-year paper and on Wednesday $12.5 billion of five-year debt is up for sale.</p>
<p>Markets might also begin to zero in on U.S. politics as presidential elections in November draw closer. The Democratic nominating convention in Chicago starts next week.</p>
<p>&quot;All those things will get attention because there's no important data,&quot; McDevitt said.</p>
<p>Republican Bob Dole appears to have narrowed the opinion poll lead against President Bill Clinton but largely on the back of income tax cut proposals, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is going to be the risk that at the end of the day the White House starts panicking, and we see a similar sort of response coming from Clinton himself,&quot; said Hawkins.</p>
<p>In Europe, budget planning will provide fodder for markets as countries begin to discuss plans for 1997, analysts said.</p>
<p>French Prime Minister Alain Juppe and President Jacques Chirac were due to meet in a riviera fortress over the weekend to begin thrashing out their plans.</p>
<p>Denmark will also release a 1997 draft budget while Belgian authorities are set to resume budget negotiations next week, said Adrian Schmidt, international economist at Chase in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Political and budget talks in Europe will probably mean the mark will regain some strength,&quot; said Schmidt. &quot;And while I wouldn't say that the franc will go immediately back down to its recent lows, there will be some selling pressure there.&quot;</p>
<p>To add a little spice to the French discussions, French public sector unions will meet on Tuesday to prepare a plan of action against budget cuts and unemployment.</p>
<p>The French also release key data during the week. July housing starts are due for release on Tuesday, June industrial production on Wednesday and on Friday, July unemployment -- probably the most crucial politically, analysts said.</p>
<p>--International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6784</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
