<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10252" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British broker offers alien-impregnation insurance.</title>
<headline>British broker offers alien-impregnation insurance.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Worried about sex with space aliens, perhaps after a trip to the nerve-rattling American movie &quot;Independence Day&quot;?</p>
<p>A British broker claimed on Friday to have become the first insurer in the world to offer a policy against impregnation by beings from another planet.</p>
<p>It took a nuclear strike by Earth's American-led forces to beat off the aliens in the blockbuster film, but earthlings now can buy financial compensation for the alien sexual embrace.</p>
<p>Specialist broker Goodfellow Rebecca Ingrams Pearson (GRIP) said for 100 pounds ($155) a year adults living in Britain could insure against two sorts of extraterrestrial interference.</p>
<p>Abduction by aliens would net the victim 100,000 pounds and impregnation -- a risk against which both men and woman can insure -- double that sum.</p>
<p>&quot;I personally would not buy a policy of this nature, because I don't think the risk is commensurate with the premium,&quot; said GRIP managing director Simon Burgess.</p>
<p>&quot;But if there is the fear of these things out there, we are justified in offering to cover people against them.&quot;</p>
<p>Some U.S. insurers, cashing in on &quot;Independence Day&quot; fever, and on recent evidence that life may have existed on Mars, have offered policies covering abduction by aliens.</p>
<p>But until now, Burgess said, it has been impossible to insure against being impregnated by a being from another planet.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
