<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10254" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Furious lobby for UK's KEPIT as Merrill sifts bids.</title>
<headline>Furious lobby for UK's KEPIT as Merrill sifts bids.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Allen</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ten fund management groups are furiously lobbying behind the scenes for the mandate to manage KEPIT, the UK's biggest ever investment trust, knowing only three or four names will go forward to the independent board.</p>
<p>Fund managers say that by the end of August, Merrill Lynch, advisors to the Board of the 500 million stg Kleinwort European Privatisation Trust, will have sifted through the offers.</p>
<p>The 10 contenders are the current manager, Kleinwort Benson Investment Management (KBIM), Baring Asset Management (BAM), Fidelity, Flemings, Guinness Flight, TR European Growth Fund (TREG), M&amp;G, Deutsche Morgan Grenfell, Old Mutual Portfolio Managers and Lazard Brothers.</p>
<p>Mercury Asset Management (MAM), which raised as much as KBIM with its own European Privatisation trust has made no approach to the KEPIT board.</p>
<p>Among groups thought to have taken a look but pulled out for one reason or another are Invesco, Singer &amp; Friedlander, Gartmore and Foreign &amp; Colonial.</p>
<p>So far there have been three &quot;bids&quot; identified by the U.K. Takeover Panel, from M&amp;G, TREG and KBIM. It is not compulsory for approaches to be submitted to the Panel but it has seen all proposals made to the Board.</p>
<p>Among the issues shareholders have to consider are whether the fund should be open or closed end, whether to remain a specialist privatisation fund or broaden to general Europe and even eastern Europe; fee structures and management contracts and arrangements for a cash exit (demanded mainly by institutions).</p>
<p>For contenders, a main concern will be costs. Among those they will have to meet are the termination fee for the current manager KBIM; fees for advisors and the costs of liquidating the huge KEPIT portfolio. There are also substantial costs associated with merely preparing an offer, both in terms of administration and management time.</p>
<p>The following are outlines of confirmed approaches so far : *** BAM's proposal does not involve unitisation (converting from a closed to open-end fund) and it is prepared to go along with any structure the Board prefers. They consider the European privatisation mandate &quot;very liveable&quot; but believe there is scope to expand into Eastern Europe. BAM manages three European funds and plans to launch a fourth, the Barings Emerging Europe fund, shortly. *** FIDELITY declined to comment on its approach but it is not classified as a bid and it is believed not to involve unitisation. *** FLEMINGS confirms it has approached the Board but would give no details. Its European Fledgling Investment Trust is at a 6.3 percent discount at the moment and its Continental European Investment Trust is at a 4.95 percent discount. *** GUINNESS FLIGHT declined to elaborate on its bid. They are believed to want to keep KEPIT as a privatisation fund and have a worldwide privatisation fund already, but this would not be eligible to be included in Personal Equity Plans for UK retail investors. *** TREG has proposed liquidating the fund with payouts based on a percentage of formula asset value, rather than actual asset value, and a switch to TREG's own fund, which started two weeks ago at a premium but is now at a discount. That is expected to widen if more shares are issued as proposed.</p>
<p>TREG has already increased its bid, mainly by slicing fees but the KEPIT board has already described both offers as &quot;unattractive&quot;. Fund managers say TREG might suffer from having been the first in the ring with a hostile bid rather than an approach to the Board, and that liquidation costs will be higher than unitisation. *** KBIM is the current fund manager. Last year its contract was shortened and its management fee reduced but the Board two weeks ago gave nine months notice to terminate the contract. It says its unitisation deal will offer the best cash exit and allow those who want to stay with the Euro privatisation theme to remain. It has the advantage of not having to meet the management termination fee. *** M&amp;G has proposed unitising the fund and is classified as a bid. It has said it will take a hit on KBIM's fee if necessary to secure the mandate. *** DEUTSCHE MORGAN GRENFELL declined to comment on the approach it has made but is believed to want to broaden KEPIT to a general European fund. Its own European funds have performed well over five years but much of this is down to former manager John Armitage, who left two years ago. Since then performance has slipped due to one or two poor stock picks. *** OLD MUTUAL is prepared to offer the board any structure it wants and to separate management and administrative functions to satisfy corporate governance. It has no experience with investment trusts but its unit trust has performed very well in its sector. It also has a network of IFA (Independent Financial Advisors) contacts which would help it handle the 77,000 small retail investors in KEPIT. *** LAZARD INVESTMENT MANAGEMENT was a late name thrown in the ring. Its approach is not classed as a bid and unitisation is not thought to be part of the plan. It believes Europe is an attractive area to be in and that it has a strong performance record to offer.</p>
<p>-- Caroline Allen, London Investment desk +44 171 542 6414</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
