<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10251" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FUND VIEW-Old Mutual sets out to win KEPIT.</title>
<headline>FUND VIEW-Old Mutual sets out to win KEPIT.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Allen</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Old Mutual Portfolio Managers, one of 10 groups competing for the mandate to run the Kleinwort Benson European Privatisation Trust (KEPIT), says its good performance history with European funds and its offer of a flexible structure should secure it the contract.</p>
<p>Old Mutual European fund manager Talal Shakerchi said his group had been looking at the investment trust area for some time and was ready once TR European Growth fund opened the field with its hostile bid.</p>
<p>According to data from Micropal, Old Mutual European Unit Trust has never ranked lower than fifth place in any three year period from February 1, 1991, when Shakerchi became fund manager, to end-July 1996. The sector comprises some 119 funds.</p>
<p>Old Mutual sees its main competitor as Deutsche Morgan Grenfell, which has also produced excellent performance over the last five and three years, although this has slipped in the last year due to one or two poor stock-picks.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch, the advisor to the KEPIT board, is currently sifting through all the proposals. They are expected to put forward their recommendations by the end of August.</p>
<p>Speaking in an interview of how Old Mutual, not one of the London Establishment houses, came to enter the race for what is considered one of the biggest prizes in fund management, Shakerchi said they had checked the contest was truly open.</p>
<p>&quot;I can say we have confidence the Board will act in shareholder interest and this process is not a charade,&quot; he added. They assessed what the Board would want to satisfy two main groups of shareholders -- those seeking a cash exit (mostly institutions) and those who will stick with a European fund but not necessarily privatisation (mainly retail investors).</p>
<p>Some 77,000 small retail investors make up around 50 percent of KEPIT shareholders and Old Mutual believes their interest and vote will be crucial to the award of the mandate.</p>
<p>Shakerchi says the small investors are broadly disillusioned with the idea of privatisation, but are prepared to stick with a European fund as long as it can be included in Personal Equity Plans (PEPs), which offer them tax advantages. A PEPable fund must have at least 50 percent invested in the European Union.</p>
<p>Asked if he would broaden the fund to eastern Europe, Shakerchi noted that an overall focus there might exclude the fund from PEPs, and that the Board in the last annual report had wanted a limited exposure to that area for the time being.</p>
<p>A key issue for contenders is various costs, and these are highest in a bid or unitisation. &quot;We think a closed end fund is in shareholders' best interests but if the Board feels a unitised fund is better we would consider that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Old Mutual's approach also aims to satisfy corporate governance guidelines. &quot;We would not be demanding we fill the board with our directors or the kinds of excessive termination clauses common in the sector,&quot; Shakerchi said.</p>
<p>He believes the group's superior performance record and experience with unit trusts has given it an edge.</p>
<p>&quot;Unit trusts are much more competitive than investment trusts,&quot; Shakerchi noted. &quot;There is nothing like a guaranteed management contract for three years. If people don't like your fund, they redeem and the money goes.&quot;</p>
<p>-- London Investment desk +44 171 542 6414</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
