<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10256" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - KEPIT tells shareholders to reject TR.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - KEPIT tells shareholders to reject TR.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kleinwort European Investment Trust (KEPIT) on Friday rejected for a second time an offer from TR European Growth Trust's (TREG) to buy the company.</p>
<p>Earlier, TREG sweetened its offer for all of the issued ordinary shares and warrants of KEPIT, with 500 million pounds ($777 million) under management. KEPIT was seen as a big target as a result of the poor performance of its fund.</p>
<p>TREG said the improved offer valued KEPIT on August 19 at 96.2 pence per share on all cash election and 28.9 pence per warrant on the same basis.</p>
<p>The cash offer for each unit of five KEPIT shares and one KEPIT warrant was 509.9 pence.</p>
<p>But KEPIT received ten other proposals earlier this week from third parties and was still studying them.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the number of proposals received, it is not yet possible to indicate when KEPIT's board will be in a position to make a recommendation, but the review will be completed as quickly as practicable,&quot; said the trust in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;In the meanwhile, shareholders and warrantholders are recommended not to accept TREG's offer.&quot;</p>
<p>The future of KEPIT was thrown open when TREG made a bid for it after incumbent managers at Kleinwort Benson Investment Management presented plans to turn up to 60 percent into loan stock which it could repurchase to reduce the discount at which the shares trade to the value of the assets. ($1=.6436 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
