<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10258" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-BSkyB boosted by Internet link-up report.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-BSkyB boosted by Internet link-up report.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in satellite broadcaster British Sky Broadcasting Group Plc rose sharply on Friday following reports on the company's aim to link its planned digitial TV services to the Internet.</p>
<p>BSkyB shares were up 18-1/2 pence to 575-1/2p by early afternoon after the Financial Times newspaper said the firm planned to offer fast access to the Internet global computer network via conventional television sets fitted with a decoder.</p>
<p>The service would be in addition to home banking, home shopping and other interactive services, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>Noone at BskyB was immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>BSkyB, 40 percent-owned by Rupert Murdoch's News Corp, has been the centre of a wave of market speculation as it prepares to launch digital satellite television next year and is rumoured to be talking to a number of partners about promoting and subsidising the start-up.</p>
<p>Digital technology allows a much greater amount of information to be beamed from satellites and could potentially open up many new applications for current communications and broadcasting systems.</p>
<p>On August 20, BSkyB chief executive Sam Chisholm said the firm was considering a link-up with British Telecommunications Plc to supply interactive services. &quot;That is a possibility,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said it was likely the company would seek to expand into these fast-growing and hi-tech areas.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a logical extension of service considering the equipment and the band-width that they will have,&quot; said Robert Jolliffe, media analyst at ABN Amro Hoare Govett.</p>
<p>&quot;They are probably about 18 months ahead (of the competition),&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Dealers said the shares were also marked higher ahead of the company's shares trading ex-dividend on Monday. &quot;There is a defensive mark-up, people are short of stock,&quot; one trader said. &quot;Trade is pretty thin.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
