<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10259" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Lost TS Eliot works throw bawdy light on aloof poet.</title>
<headline>Lost TS Eliot works throw bawdy light on aloof poet.</headline>
<byline>Giles Elgood</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A collection of lost works by T.S. Eliot, including bawdy verses likely to explode any perception of the great poet as a dry academic figure, will be published for the first time next month.</p>
<p>The American-born Thomas Stearns Eliot spent much of his life in Britain as a poet-publisher with an austere reputation, reflecting his royalist, conservative, High Anglican church view.</p>
<p>The poems come from a notebook which Eliot sold to his patron, the New York lawyer John Quinn, in 1922, a few months before his most famous work &quot;The Waste Land&quot; was published.</p>
<p>Quinn paid $140 for the leather-bound notebook, which Eliot bought for 25 cents in 1909 while he was on holiday in New England.</p>
<p>Eliot said the verses &quot;ought never to be printed&quot; and the notebook disappeared until 1968, three years after the poet's death, when it surfaced in the Berg Collection of the New York Public Library.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Faber and Faber, the London publishing house where Eliot was once poetry editor, said publication of the &quot;lost&quot; works had now been approved by the poet's widow, Valerie.</p>
<p>The early poems, two of them written in French, cover a range of subjects including love, city life, boredom and social nuance. There is also an early version of &quot;The Love Song of J. Alfred Prufrock.&quot;</p>
<p>Part of the new book is taken up with a selection of lewd poems, including verses about a jolly tinker with an outsized sexual organ and a salacious poem about the voyage of Christopher Columbus.</p>
<p>One critic described this as being &quot;so packed with sexual incident that it's remarkable he ever survived to discover America&quot;.</p>
<p>The poem also contains references to blacks likely to reawaken charges of racism levelled at Eliot.</p>
<p>The new book is published at a time when the poet is already under attack for alleged anti-Semitism in a book by Anthony Julius, the British lawyer who is handling the divorce of Princess Diana and heir to the throne Prince Charles.</p>
<p>The hitherto unpublished poem &quot;Bleistein with a Cigar&quot; contains the lines: &quot;...On the Rialto once./ The rats are underneath the piles./ The Jew is underneath the lot./ Money in furs. The boatman smiles.&quot;</p>
<p>Eliot was born in St Louis, Missouri, in 1888, but in 1915 he moved to London where he worked as a teacher and a bank clerk.</p>
<p>Apart from his modernist poems, he also published &quot;Old Possum's Book of Practical Cats,&quot; a children's work on which Andrew Lloyd Webber's hit musical &quot;Cats&quot; is based.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
