<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10269" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Hopes rise of Bass Allied Domecq deal today.</title>
<headline>Hopes rise of Bass Allied Domecq deal today.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sources close to British brewer and leisure group Bass Plc and Allied Domecq said the two are close to unveiling an agreed deal over Allied's half share in brewer Carlsberg-Tetley, possibly later  on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd say there is an 80 percent chance of it coming later on today,&quot; said one source close to the deal.</p>
<p>Both companies confirmed they were in talks on July 29 and many analysts and newspapers then expected an announcement of the agreed terms in a matter of days.</p>
<p>Bass is widely expected to pay some 200 million pounds ($310 million) for Allied's stake while Danish brewer Carlsberg A/S is seen taking 20 percent of Bass's enlarged British brewing business.</p>
<p>The deal is also believed by analysts and investors to include a fall-back clause whereby, if the sale is blocked by Britain's competition authorities, Carlsberg will raise its stake in C-T.</p>
<p>Sources said management agreed in principle on a deal some three weeks ago but it has since been delayed by company lawyers who have to draw up separate contracts for each of the beer brands being sold and tackle the vexed question of an escape clause.</p>
<p>The Financial Times reported on Friday that if Bass was unhappy with any conditions imposed by Britain's Department of Trade and Industry, Carlsberg would buy Allied Domecq's share of C-T for 100 million pounds, while Allied would repay Bass 30 million.</p>
<p>Bass would also be entitled to 50 percent of C-T profits from the date of the deal to the date when any competition requirements are announced, said the paper.</p>
<p>Noone at either company was immediately available to comment. ($1=.6458 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
