<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10266" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INTERVIEW-TREG urges KEPIT holders to accept offer.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-TREG urges KEPIT holders to accept offer.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>TR European Growth Trust Plc (TREG) on Friday urged shareholders and warrantholders in Kleinwort European Privatisation Investment Trust Plc (KEPIT) to accept its improved offer for the fund.</p>
<p>&quot;I think KEPIT shareholders should get on and accept our offer,&quot; James de Sausmarez, retail managing director of Henderson, which runs TREG, told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>TREG's increased offer for the 500 million stg fund was &quot;very generous&quot;, he added.</p>
<p>KEPIT's future was thrown into play when TREG first made an offer for it late last month. Others are considering bids.  </p>
<p>Sir Geoffrey Littler, chairman of TREG, told Reuters the rationale behind the original offer for KEPIT had not changed, adding it offered cash for shareholders &quot;in the near future&quot;.</p>
<p>He said the new offer had been improved in several ways.</p>
<p>TREG's proposed fees from the deal had been reduced to half a percent from three quarters of a percent, providing a &quot;direct uplift to KEPIT shareholders&quot;, and there would now be a new bonus issue for those electing to buy new TREG &quot;C-shares&quot;.</p>
<p>This would be on the basis of one warrant for every seven TREG ordinary shares held.</p>
<p>Henderson's management fee will also be marginally reduced.  </p>
<p>The combined effect of these changes meant a marked reduction in TREG's costs, he added.</p>
<p>Littler said TREG was offering cash at a discount of 2.9 percent to the KEPIT net asset value on August 19.</p>
<p>De Sausmarez said that the scene was set in TREG's favour.</p>
<p>&quot;We have made an offer and it is the only one on the table at the moment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the KEPIT board should begin to sell some of the more illiquid stocks in the portfolio and was pleased it had already served notice on Kleinwort Benson Investment Management (KBIM), which currently has the management agreement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
