<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10262" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London gold stronger, but seen capped at $388.</title>
<headline>London gold stronger, but seen capped at $388.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Precious metals prices hovered near the top of recent ranges on Friday, but summer lethargy would prevent them breaking higher near term, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold's been in a narrow range and I don't think anyone sees it moving up in the next few days,&quot; a dealer said, adding that Monday's market holiday in Britain and Hong Kong would also slow down trading.</p>
<p>Bullion fixed at $387.50 an ounce, compared to $387.00 on Thursday afternoon and $386.90 in the morning.</p>
<p>Some analysts predicted that if support at $386 held, gold could test the $388 and then $390 resistance levels next week.</p>
<p>Gold and silver popped a little higher on Thursday afternoon in a burst of buying by investment funds in New York. But neither metal made much progress and quickly came off highs.</p>
<p>Their rise followed the German Bundesbank's cut in a key money market rate. Some analysts said an easier global monetary policy may eventually encourage demand for precious metals.</p>
<p>But most dealers agreed that, at least immediately, gold had ignored the rate cut. &quot;I don't think it's had any effect on the precious metals,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Silver was steady at $5.23 an ounce, unchanged from Thursday's London close.</p>
<p>Like gold, it was expected to remain range-bound after failing to conquer the key resistance at $5.25 on Thursday.</p>
<p>But silver's rally at the start of the week, which took it well above previous resistance around $5.15, was keeping the market slightly on edge.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is a little nervous,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;It's high enough to have to come back. There's a slimmer chance of it going up, and if we break through $5.27, we'll see $5.35.&quot;</p>
<p>Platinum was a touch firmer at $399.75, while its sister metal palladium firmed by $1.25 to $125.00.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
