<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10280" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe strikers defy threats of dismissal.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe strikers defy threats of dismissal.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwean civil servants defied threats by the government to dismiss them on Friday if they did not end a four-day strike over pay that has severely hurt some of its essential social services.</p>
<p>Thousands of strikers -- including junior state doctors, nurses and magistrates -- stayed on the streets, vowing not to return to their jobs until President Robert Mugabe's government met their demands for wage rises of between 30 and 60 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no question of us going back to work before the government addresses our grievances. We are not going back and we will not respond to any threats to dismiss us,&quot; Frank Chamunorwa, vice-president of the Public Service Association (PSA) union, told state radio.</p>
<p>His comments followed a statement by Public Service, Labour and Social Welfare Minister Florence Chitauro, also on state radio and television, that she had instructed senior officials to sack all those who did not report for work on Friday.</p>
<p>The strike has left many state hospitals stretched to the limit, handling only emergencies under senior doctors and nurse administrators with the assistance of army and Red Cross medical personnel.</p>
<p>On average, civil servants earn Z$1,000 (U.S.$99) a month and PSA union leaders justify their 60 percent pay rise demand on grounds salaries in the public service have fallen way below the cost of living over the years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
