<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10289" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak major share losses drag BSE lower.</title>
<headline>Slovak major share losses drag BSE lower.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovak blue chips closed mixed in heavier trading on the Bratislava Stock Exchange (BSE) on Friday, with losses to several major shares pulling the SAX index down 0.96 points to 222.89.</p>
<p>Oil and gas storage company Nafta lost 76 crowns to 1,954, with its average price -- according to which the index is calculated -- easing by 3.42 percent.</p>
<p>But brokers said it was hard to predict future development with the share, as investors remanined cautious over Nafta issue due to the recent controversial privatisation of a major stake in the firm.</p>
<p>Oil refiner Slovnaft also lost ground, shedding 35 crowns to close at 950 -- with its average price down 1.73 percent -- though dealers said the fall was a &quot;normal correction in the price&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The fluctuation of Slovnaft is not a dramatic decline, the price is oscillating within the range of normal corrections,&quot; said Libor Briska of Creditanstalt.</p>
<p>Briska said, however, that it seemed as though investor interest in Slovnaft shares was waning.</p>
<p>VUB bank, which closed up 50 at 2,250 crowns, led the day's floor trading with 45,204 shares matched.</p>
<p>&quot;This was probably the last large package of VUB shares for one unspecified investor, which seemed to have already satisfied its interests, and the logical trend next week should be a slightly lower price of the shares,&quot; Briska said.</p>
<p>Overall volume increased to 1,754,523 shares, from 333,229 shares traded on Thursday, while turnover rose to 884.87 million crowns from 244.56 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
