<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10295" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Ameritech blames Polish TPSA over joint venture.</title>
<headline>Ameritech blames Polish TPSA over joint venture.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ameritech Corp accused Polish state-owned telecom firm Telekomunikacja Polska SA (TPSA) of blocking development of their joint PTK Centertel SA mobile phone network, but said it remained committed to the venture.</p>
<p>&quot;Ameritech is -- and always has been -- committed to Centertel,&quot; Ameritech International's President Walter Catlow said in a statement issued in Warsaw late on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope to continue our strong and successful relationship, despite the unfortunate actions and misunderstandings that have taken place,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But in &quot;background information&quot; issued with the statement from the U.S. firm's Chicago base, Ameritech accused TPSA, which effectively controls Poland's telecommunications, of acting in a way that threatened the future of Centertel.</p>
<p>TPSA spokesman Krzysztof Bartnicki declined comment on Ameritech's statement on Friday, saying he wanted to avoid a row through the media.</p>
<p>In 1991 Ameritech and France Telecom joined state-owned telephone operator TPSA in setting up Centertel as Poland's first nationwide cellular telephone operator, using a dated analog system, which now has 100,000 customers.</p>
<p>They provided all the capital and each had 24.5 percent of the joint venture, with TPSA holding 51 percent.</p>
<p>They invested on an understanding with the then Polish government that they would later get a licence for a GSM digital network, but a tender last year led to licences going to two other groups, which are preparing to start operating.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately, the expansion and future operation of this national asset (Centertel) is in jeopardy due to the denial of the previously-agreed-upon GSM licence and TPSA's opposition to Centertel's expansion into digital telephony,&quot; Ameritech said.</p>
<p>&quot;Additionally, TPSA has taken steps that appear to have as their goal either the removal of the foreign partners from the joint venture, or the destruction of the company's business,&quot; the notes issued by Ameritech said.</p>
<p>It accused TPSA of blocking approval of Centertel's operating budgets and previously planned capital investments to expand and improve the network to meet its licence obligations.</p>
<p>Ameritech said TPSA had blocked a management change at Centertel and had unilaterally terminated a vital agreement on fees for interconnection to TPSA's ground network, demanding terms under which Centertel could not operate profitably.</p>
<p>The Polish government's Anti-Monopoly Office (UAM) said earlier this week it might launch an action against TPSA over the price it wanted to charge Centertel for connections with the ground telecommunications network.</p>
<p>Bartnicki said talks on renegotiating the agreement on fees were under way, adding: &quot;I have a feeling that the sides will reach agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>He said TPSA was not interested in running a mobile phone business itself or taking over Centertel because it did not want to be accused of extending its monopoly. It was committed to keeping Centertel in business, he said.</p>
<p>-- Anthony Barker +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
