<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10292" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo IBP plans 55 mln litres of Coca-Cola in 1996.</title>
<headline>Yugo IBP plans 55 mln litres of Coca-Cola in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Soft-drinks producer IBP Beograd, exclusively licensed to bottle Coca-Cola brand drinks in Yugoslavia, said on Friday it planned to produce 55 million litres of Coca-Cola and Fanta this year.</p>
<p>The IBP's bottling plant, however, will fall short of its original 60 million litre target for 1996, the plant's production manager said.</p>
<p>&quot;We would have to revise down our 1996 target due to some production limitations,&quot; Zorica Kljajic-Vukcevic told Reuters.</p>
<p>The plant operates four bottling lines with a total annual capacity of 80 million litres but only one PET bottle blowing line.</p>
<p>&quot;We bottled 27.5 million litres of Coca-Cola and Fanta from January to July -- 23-24 percent more than in the same period last year,&quot; Kljajic-Vukcevic said.</p>
<p>Production in 1995 totalled 36 million litres.</p>
<p>Kljajic-Vukcevic expected the plant to get extracts needed to start producing Sprite soon.</p>
<p>Customers in Yugoslavia can expect new 0.5 and 2 litre PET bottles of Coca-Cola in a few months, but not the canned drink.</p>
<p>&quot;The can-filling lines will not come to Yugoslavia soon because they are beyond our financial means,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Production costs in Yugoslavia ran at four dinars (1.21 German marks) per one litre, Kljajic-Vukcevic said. Ideally, production costs should not exceed one German mark, she said.</p>
<p>She blamed the higher than usual costs on the prices of sugar, industrial water and electricity.</p>
<p>-- Gordana Filipovic, Belgrade newsroom, +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
