<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10290" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares extend gains, seen up on Monday.</title>
<headline>Polish shares extend gains, seen up on Monday.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares on Friday rose for the seventh consecutive session and analysts said the stronger buying after price fixing signalled the market should rise on Monday and could soon test its recent high.</p>
<p>The main market has risen 11.6 percent over the last seven sessions to 13,888.2 points, partly spurred by firms' better July earnings reports, and is now in sight of this year's 27-month, July 5 high at 14,282.2 points.</p>
<p>&quot;We could soon pierce our latest high but if it doesn't happen in higher turnover we could soon have falls,&quot; said Ryszard Wojnowski, an analyst at Bank Gdanski brokerage.</p>
<p>The main market's all-share WIG index rose 2.1 percent on Friday to 13,888.2 points and turnover fell 9.4 percent to 108.5 million zlotys ($39.6 million) on both markets. Gainers led losers by 40 to 25 with 12 stocks flat.</p>
<p>Top gainer aluminium plant Kety rose by the daily maximum 10 percent, possibly helped by reports on Thursday it would invest 50 million zlotys ($18.2 million) this year, analysts said. The stock was not traded after price fixing due to excess demand.</p>
<p>Continuous trade turnover was at 0.8 million zlotys ($0.3 million) with top mover bank BPH up one percent. Mass privatisation NFI units fell 1.1 percent to 89 zlotys and fell 2.2 percent to 88 zlotys in live trade.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
