<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10296" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: IMF mission backs Ukraine tranche payment.</title>
<headline>IMF mission backs Ukraine tranche payment.</headline>
<byline>Irene Marushko</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>International Monetary Fund experts have backed the latest tranche of a standby credit to Ukraine but talks are continuing on a loan to support a new currency, the Fund's resident representative said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The performance criteria to the end of July were fully met and we are faxing our approval of the next tranche to Washington,&quot; Alex Sundakov told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still discussing the stabilisation fund,&quot; he said at the conclusion of a two-week mission.</p>
<p>The July tranche is for $100 million, part of a $867 million standby credit being paid out over this year and early 1997.</p>
<p>Sundakov would not say when he expected a decision to be made on Ukraine's request for $1.5 billion to back the permanent hryvna currency. &quot;Conversations are continuing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Speculation has revived that Ukraine will shortly introduce the hryvna to replace the temporary karbovanets currency, which has stabilised in recent months. It was trading at 176,100 to the dollar on Friday.</p>
<p>Some bankers believe the authorities could introduce the hryvna in the next few days, as Ukraine marks its fifth fifth anniversary of independence on Saturday.</p>
<p>President Leonid Kuchma told a news conference he would announce the new currency in the near future, Interfax news agency said.</p>
<p>The mission also discussed granting Ukraine a three-year Extended Fund Facility of between $2.5 and $3 billion, but Sundakov said this would probably not be decided until the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no intention on either side to settle this now. There were no negotiations as such,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sundakov said a mission would return next month to review Ukraine's economic progress. IMF missions have been visiting Ukraine monthly since the Fund body suspended payments of an earlier loan in January after Kiev overshot spending targets.</p>
<p>The Fund approved the current standby loan in May.</p>
<p>Ukraine achieved record-low inflation rates of 0.1 percent in June and July, but the tight economic policy agreed with the Fund has also been blamed for the government's failure to pay $1.7 billion in wages. The government has promised to clear these arrears next month.</p>
<p>Sundakov said Ukraine met requirements when it increased to 80 percent the share of electricity, water and natural gas tarrifs charged to consumers and industry last month.</p>
<p>Ukraine had previously planned to eliminate all subsidies and charge consumers the full cost, but desisted for fear of increasing social tension.</p>
<p>The IMF has so far provided about $2 billion to Ukraine since Kuchma secured approval for the first market reform programme three years after the 1991 collapse of Soviet rule.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
