<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10291" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: MOL ends lower on delayed energy price rise.</title>
<headline>MOL ends lower on delayed energy price rise.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian share prices closed mixed on the Budapest Stock Exchange on Friday when oil company MOL was a heavy loser after the government's Thursday announcement that it will postpone the energy price increase until January 1, 1997 from October 1.</p>
<p>&quot;The overall athmosphere was downcast but this is really only valid for MOL and (chemical company) TVK as all other shares were mostly stagnant or firmer,&quot; said Kalman Schuszter of New York Broker Budapest.</p>
<p>The BUX ended at 3,357.09 points, down 13.14. BUX index futures dropped for all maturities, by 38.00 to 86.00 points.</p>
<p>&quot;MOL's fall was evidently the result of the delay in energy price increase,&quot; Schuszter said, adding its fall was expected after its decline on London's SEAQ. MOL slid to a daily low of 1,540 forints but layter rebounded to end at 1,595, down 165.</p>
<p>TVK closed at 1,330 forints, down 20, in what traders said was a continuous supply of foreign investors.</p>
<p>Hotelier Danubius soared to a daily peak of 2,850 forints but later retreated to end at 2,720 forints, up 130, after it a suspension on Thursday, prior to the privatisation agency's announcement that Danubius won the tender for Hungaria Szalloda Rt.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
