<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10302" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romanian atom reactor fully operational by Q4 '96.</title>
<headline>Romanian atom reactor fully operational by Q4 '96.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's first nuclear reactor will be fully operational by the fourth quarter of 1996 and will switch to local fuel sources next year, an electricity authority official said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have final tests, with the reactor working at 100 percent capacity, late in September. After those tests, the reactor will start commercial operation,&quot; Teodor Chirica, of Renel RA told Reuters.</p>
<p>The 700-MW reactor at the plant at Cernavoda, on River Danube, began operating in April. The reactor, already connected to the national grid, has undergone tests since, and is being gradually taken to full capacity.</p>
<p>A carryover from the communist era of projects masterminded by late dictator Nicolae Ceausescu, Cernavoda has been plagued by repeated delays, taking 16 years and $10 billion to build.</p>
<p>Only one of a planned five CANDU-type reactors has been completed and there is little money to continue construction, although heavily energy-dependent Romania needs the power.</p>
<p>The project has been coordinated by Renel with assistance from a consortium grouping Atomic Energy of Canada Ltd and Italy's Ansaldo SpA.</p>
<p>The Cernavoda plant will use Romanian nuclear fuel for future operations, Chirica said, adding that the reactor needs some 100 tonnes a year.</p>
<p>Romania has a nuclear fuel plant at Pitesti, 113 km west of Bucharest, which is the licensed supplier for the five reactors. The country also produces heavy water -- used as a coolant in the reactors -- at a plant at Halanga in the south, with an annual capacity of 90 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;When the reactor was first loaded we imported fuel from Canada, in line with contract signed in 1979. Anyway, at that time the plant in Pitesti had only 4.0 tonnes of fuel in stock,&quot; Chirica said.</p>
<p>The imports came from Canada's private nuclear fuel manufacturer Zircotec.</p>
<p>&quot;The raw material will be natural uranium which Romania has enough of to allow five CANDU-type units to operate for 30 years,&quot; Chirica said.</p>
<p>The first reactor is expected to add some 660 megawatts to Romania's electric grid, which has an installed generating capacity of 21,701 megawatts. It is currently estimated to be running at 50 percent capacity.</p>
<p>-- Luli Popescu, Bucharest Newsroom +40 1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I15000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
