<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10318" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-News shares firm after strong forecast.</title>
<headline>RTRS-News shares firm after strong forecast.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Both the ordinary and converting preference shares in Rupert Murdoch's News Corp Ltd firmed about two percent in busy Friday morning trade after News Corp issued a bullish forecast on Thursday of at least 20 percent profit growth in the current year.</p>
<p>&quot;The analysts have had a chance to have a look at it (the 1995/96 result) and the company is looking at a 20 percent growth this year. Our analyst is forecasting A$1.6 billion for this year and that's given the boys a bit of heart,&quot; said one Sydney dealer.  </p>
<p>News Corp ordinary shares were up 15 cents at A$6.55 by 11.00 am (0100 GMT) while its converting preference shares were up 12 cents at A$5.34.</p>
<p>&quot;There's also been some speculation in the press that Rupert may be interested in increasing his family holdings -- that may have something to do with it,&quot; said another Sydney dealer.</p>
<p>The Australian Financial Review newspaper's Chanticleer columnist said on Friday that Murdoch's family companies may be ready to buy a larger stake in News Corp and more preference shares in particular.  </p>
<p>The newspapers said Murdoch believed the preference shares were undervalued and his family companies had taken on more debt recently, possibly to buy up more of these shares.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
