<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10310" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Japanese leader meets Chile's Frei for trade talks.</title>
<headline>Japanese leader meets Chile's Frei for trade talks.</headline>
<byline>Roger Atwood</byline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese Premier Ryutaro Hashimoto met Chile's President Eduardo Frei for talks on Friday aimed at bolstering trade and investment ties between Japan and one of Latin America's most dynamic economies.</p>
<p>The two met for 90 minutes of talks that officials said would include prospects for increasing Japan's paltry investments in Chile, which lag well behind those by U.S., Canadian and European interests.</p>
<p>Hashimoto arrived in Chile from Mexico on Thursday on the second leg of a Latin American tour aimed at raising Japan's profile in a region it used to associate with political turmoil and disasters.</p>
<p>&quot;We are paying more attention to Latin America now, as it has moved toward stability and progress. It used to be thought of as a dangerous place,&quot; a high-ranking member of Hashimoto's delegation said.</p>
<p>&quot;Specifically with Chile, we want to set priorities for our future relationship,&quot; the official told reporters.</p>
<p>Chile, with a relatively small population of 14 million, still hopes to become Japan's gateway to the vast markets of Brazil and Argentina by attracting Japanese exporters to its long Pacific coast studded with modern ports.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a certain revaluing of Latin America by the Japanese, and we want them to know that we offer the best conditions to be their bridge into this continent,&quot; a top Chilean official said.</p>
<p>He said the Japanese wanted to make their presence felt in Latin America, in part because they were concerned the continent's new prosperity could lead to protectionism later.</p>
<p>&quot;They're not sure where this economic progress is going to lead, so they want to make some commitments now,&quot; the official, who asked not to be identified, said.</p>
<p>Although Japan is Chile's second-largest trading partner, it is a distant seventh in the ranking of foreign investors by country, with about $500 million invested. The United States is No. 1 in both categories.</p>
<p>The two nations have a couple of points of friction. Chile backs a worldwide moratorium on whaling, opposed by Japan, and has also strongly protested shipments of nuclear wastes through Chilean waters on their way to Japan from Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;Both are areas of disagreement, but we have a civilised dialogue on them. I wouldn't call them real conflicts,&quot; the Chilean official said.</p>
<p>Hashimoto was due to leave early on Saturday for Brazil.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
