<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10314" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Mixed bag of earnings seen for NZ's Fletcher.</title>
<headline>Mixed bag of earnings seen for NZ's Fletcher.</headline>
<byline>James Gray</byline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fletcher Challenge, reporting for the first time as four separately listed divisions, is expected to produce a mixed bag of results when it reports next week, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>FCL Paper and FCL Building were both expected to report stronger earnings, but FCL Energy and FCL Forest were expected to show declines.</p>
<p>Paper's result was also likely to mask a dismal picture in its key areas of pulp and paper.</p>
<p>Paper's last four halves show how highly cyclical its business is. In the six months to December 1994, FCL paper earned NZ$21 million (US$14.5 million).</p>
<p>The result swelled to NZ$151 million in the ensuing six months and to $186 million in the third.</p>
<p>In contrast, analysts expect the half to June 30, 1996 to show just a few million in earnings. Some expect Paper to break even and others see a loss over the half.</p>
<p>&quot;What that shows is the impact of a very short upswing in pulp and paper prices and a very rapid downswing,&quot; David Stanley at Doyle Paterson Brown said.</p>
<p>Furthermore, there was little to suggest an improvement in commodity prices in the year ahead.</p>
<p>Paper made NZ$172 million in the year to June 1995 and analysts expect a profit for 1996 of around $190 million. The range of most analysts' expectations is $175-$210 million.</p>
<p>Paper has underperformed the market since the energy, building and paper divisions were split from the group in March, which coincided with a sharp downturn in pulp and paper markets.</p>
<p>Abysmal log prices and other factors are likely to combine to drag Forest's earnings down to around NZ$65 million in the year to June against $68 million a year ago, but the market will not be too concerned.</p>
<p>Forest has been riding the crest of a wave after successfully bidding, along with Brierley Investments Ltd and China's Citic, for Forestry Corp of NZ on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The stock has been powering ahead since the sale announcement, and closed on Friday at NZ$2.03, up nine cents.</p>
<p>The move almost doubles Forest's estate to around 300,000 hectares.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think people care about the result because they are focusing far more on the implications of the acquisition of Forestry Corp,&quot; Stanley said.</p>
<p>Forest itself had been assisted by the price the consortium was prepared to pay -- NZ$2.026 billion -- in that it improves the valuation of Forest's existing estate.</p>
<p>Building, fresh from cost cutting measures and a move out of unprofitable businesses, is expected to produce a healthy improvement in annual earnings.</p>
<p>Analysts expect a result in the region of NZ$137-8 million before abnormals, up substantially from $117 million a year earlier, and are generally positive about prospects.</p>
<p>Energy is expected to report a decline in annual profit before abnormal items, largely due to the operation of its Maui B platform.</p>
<p>Energy made a NZ$32 million profit on the sale of its interest in Bay of Plenty Electricity, but the sale happened after balance date and was unlikely to be included.</p>
<p>Analysts expect a net profit of around NZ$45-6 million, down from $64 million last June year.</p>
<p>Paul Richardson, energy analyst at SBC Warburg, said earnings before interest and tax would be around NZ$120 million, but the underlying profit was going to be lower than last year's. He expects a fall to around NZ$50 million.</p>
<p>US$1 = NZ$1.445</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
