<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10317" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FORECAST-Burns Philp braces for fall.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FORECAST-Burns Philp braces for fall.</headline>
<byline>Ian Pemberton</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Food ingredients group Burns Philp and Co Ltd will confirm next Wednesday that its 1995/96 (June 30) net profit was underdone, the worst result for five years and another disappointment for investors who have watched the stock slump in recent months.</p>
<p>The company, a spices and yeast manufacturer with operations in Australia, the United States, Europe and Asia, said in July that net profit before abnormals would be about 20 percent below the 1994/95 result of A$104.1 million pre-abnormals.  </p>
<p>&quot;It will just be another disappointing result, but it is probably reasonably well known in the market already,&quot; said one brokerage firm analyst, who forecast A$81.6 million before abmornals.</p>
<p>She said the consumer division in the key United States market, where Burns Philp has fought a price war with the world's number one spices firm McCormick and Co Inc, continued to perform poorly in the fourth quarter.  </p>
<p>While the price war is now off the boil, its impact continues to affect the company which has had to pay significant placment, or &quot;slotting&quot; fees, to U.S. supermarkets to ensure that its products caught the consumer's eye.</p>
<p>These payments will be included in an abnormal loss of up to A$100 million for 1995/96 which will also include rationalisation charges and other write-offs.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there is a possibility the abnormals will actually be worse than the A$100 million they have announced,&quot; the analyst said, citing this as the only possible surprise next week.  </p>
<p>The company may also announce its choice to lead the industrial and food service division next week, the one position still to be filled since the company was restructured from a geographic to a product-based operation in May.</p>
<p>Another analyst, who predicted a 1995/96 net profit of profit about A$80 million, said he had not changed his forecast or sell recommendation on the stock since the company released its surprisingly poor nine month result on May 10.</p>
<p>Burns Philp then revealed that nine month net profit had fallen by 22 percent to A$59.6 million mainly due to the weak U.S. division and that the full year result would fall.  </p>
<p>Investors, who had been expecting at least a steady result, began the process of marking the stock down to a 1996 low of A$1.90.</p>
<p>Its year high of A$3.35 was reached at the start of the year when investors and analysts were hoping for an improved result.</p>
<p>The stock was one cent higher at A$2.14 at 11.00 a.m. (0100 gmt) on Friday.</p>
<p>A third analyst said he expected a net profit of A$80 million. &quot;They should start to stabilise next year and probably 1998 is a big year, if they can do it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
