<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10326" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Tokyo, Hong Kong slide, other Asian markets up.</title>
<headline>Tokyo, Hong Kong slide, other Asian markets up.</headline>
<byline>Jason Szep</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Profit-taking belted Japanese and Hong Kong stock markets on Friday after recent rallies, while most other Asian markets gained ground.</p>
<p>Tokyo got off to a strong start after the German Bundesbank slashed its key money market rate, but investors later took profits, erased gains and were expected to remain sidelined until next week's Bank of Japan's corporate sentiment survey.</p>
<p>The key Nikkei 225 average closed down 134.44 points or 0.63 percent at 21,228.80.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though the market had advanced for four days, it still lacked a clear direction,&quot; said Chisato Takahashi, fund manager at Credit Suisse Investment Advisory.</p>
<p>Profit-taking also halted a week-long rally in Hong Kong stocks as prices slid ahead of a long weekend.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index, which had climbed 249 points this week on optimism over corporate earnings and hopes of an interest rate cut in China, fell 54.13 points to 11,424.64.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a long weekend so investors just took profits and there are a lot of profits to take,&quot; said Frederick Tsang, head of research at PrimeEast Securities.</p>
<p>Philippine stocks, encouraged by a recovery in the local currency from a speculative attack on Thursday, continued a solid advance. Manila's key index rose 38.68 points, or 1.21 percent, to 3,226.46 after a 2.45 percent rise on Thursday.</p>
<p>Recent losses in Thailand enticed investors into the Bangkok market on Friday, driving the SET index up 1.47 percent, or 16.02 points, to 1,106.73. Volumes, however, were light.</p>
<p>Bombay shares also performed strongly as investors squared their recent oversold positions in leading blue chips. The 30-share index of the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) closed 44.61 points, or 1.32 percent, higher at a provisional 3,433.41.</p>
<p>The New Zealand market finished at a two-and-a-half year high, surging one percent and brushing aside a political opinion poll which appeared negative for the ruling conservative government just seven weeks ahead of a general election.</p>
<p>The top 40 index ended 23.05 points ahead at 2,222.59, its highest level since March 1994.</p>
<p>Taiwan managed modest gains, closing up 39.40 points, or 0.64 percent, at 6,200.22. Dealers said the market remained concerned over Taiwan-China ties after China set rules on direct shipping links across the Taiwan Strait earlier this week.</p>
<p>Rumours of takeovers and talk of a possible initial public offering drove Singapore shares to a firm close on light volumes. The 30-share Straits Times Industrials Index climbed 18.79 points, or 0.87 percent, to 2,181.52.</p>
<p>An easing in Indonesia's political tensions saw active local and offshore buying in local shares, pushing Jakarta's composite index up 4.93 points, or 0.91 percent, at 549.21 points.</p>
<p>Seoul ended firmer, rising 1.79 points, or 0.23 percent, to a provisional 781.42 after a day of fluctuations on selective buying on small-sized shares, brokers said.</p>
<p>Australian shares had a firmer session in solid turnover, the market closing near its highs on strength from Wall Street. The All Ordinaries index finished up 18.3 points, or 0.80 percent, at 2,292.9, just off its intra-day high of 2,293.7.</p>
<p>Kuala Lumpur shares closed mixed as blue chips continued to consolidate after sharp gains earlier in the week. The benchmark composite index ended at 1,119.48, down 1.28 points.</p>
<p>In late Tokyo trade, the dollar erased early small losses against the mark on short-covering while steadying against the yen in directionless trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>It ended at 108.28/38 yen from New York's close on Thursday at 108.24/34 and at 1.4912/17 marks from 1.4919/26.</p>
<p>On SIMEX, October Brent futures traded at $20.75 per barrel in late business, up three cents from the London settlement Thursday of $20.72.</p>
<p>Bullion ended at US$387.50/388.00 an ounce in Hong Kong against New York's US$387.20/70 close on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
