<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10333" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai B shares end down despite rate cut.</title>
<headline>Shanghai B shares end down despite rate cut.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai B shares closed down on Friday after two major listed firms posted worse-than-expected interim results, despite the bullish news that the central bank had cut bank interest rates, brokers said.</p>
<p>The index fell 0.331 points or 0.63 percent to 52.029 points, on volume of 10.3 million shares worth $5.1 million. Of 41 B shares, 35 traded, with 14 down, 16 flat and five up.</p>
<p>Six B share firms posted their interim results on Friday, including Shanghai Shangling Electric Appliance which reported a fall of 53.26 percent in net profit and Shanghai Yaohua Pilkington Glass which reported a drop of 61.55 percent.</p>
<p>Brokers said that the fall in net profits of these two blue chip stock brought down the whole index.</p>
<p>Shanghai Shangling fell $0.022 or 4.15 percent to $0.508, on volume of 23,300 shares. Shanghai Yaohua followed, down $0.024 or 4.10 percent to $0.560, on volume of 95,900 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors were more interested in firms' interim results today than the rate cut which had already been partly digested over the past few days,&quot; one broker said. &quot;But the market will benefit greatly from the rate cut in the long run.&quot;</p>
<p>The central bank announced on Thursday a cut in bank despoite and lending rates by an average 1.5 and 1.2 percentage points respectively as from Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The index will consolidate around 52 points next week, with investors waiting for other interim results due by the end of this month,&quot; a second broker said.</p>
<p>Shanghai Goods &amp; Material was the biggest loser, falling $0.012 or 8.95 percent to $0.122, on volume of 17,000 shares.</p>
<p>Eastern Communications traded the most, thanks to institutional buying of stocks listed this year. It ended flat at $0.800, on volume of 2.5 million shares.</p>
<p>Shanghai A shares fell as the news of the interest rate cut had already been digested, brokers said.</p>
<p>The index closed down 15.428 points or 1.80 percent to 840.226 points, on volume of 320.3 million shares worth 2.8 billion yuan.</p>
<p>The SSE 30 index fell 19.100 points or 0.90 percent to 2112.968 points.</p>
<p>Shanghai Yaohua Pilkington Glass was the biggest loser on sharp fall of its net profit, plunging 1.57 yuan or 13.99 percent to 9.65 yuan, on volume of 1.1 million shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
