<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10342" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks end off, pause after week's rally.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks end off, pause after week's rally.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>This week's rally in Hong Kong stocks came to a halt on Friday, with prices ending lower as investors took profits ahead of the long weekend.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index fell 54.13 points to 11,424.64. Turnover was HK$4.93 billion compared to HK$4.89 billion on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a long weekend so investors just took profits and there are a lot of profits to take,&quot; said Frederick Tsang, head of research at PrimeEast Securities.</p>
<p>The market will be closed on Monday for Liberation Day.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index rose 249 points this week, boosted by expectations of solid earnings from Cheung Kong (Holdings) and hopes of an interest rate cut in China.</p>
<p>Analysts said Thursday's higher-than-expected results from Cheung Kong and China's cuts in both its deposit and lending rates had been discounted by the market and investors sold after the fact. Cheung Kong (Holdings) posted first-half net profit of HK$8.16 billion compared to HK$5.95 billion on Thursday.</p>
<p>Slightly lower-than-expected interim earnings from Hutchison Whampoa also weighed on share prices, analysts said. The company reported profit of HK$7.84 billion compared to HK$4.48 billion in the same period last year.</p>
<p>&quot;There were high expectations built into Cheung Kong and Hutchison prices and after the results the market started to react,&quot; said Tsang</p>
<p>Cheung Kong ended the session HK$0.75 lower at HK$56.75 and Hutchison Whampoa fell HK$1.10 to HK$48.20.</p>
<p>Kelvin Tang, analyst at ImPac Asset Management, said despite the drop in Cheung Kong shares, other property stocks had moved higher. New World Development added HK$0.30 to HK$38.60 and Hysan Development rose HK$0.10 to HK$24.80.</p>
<p>&quot;On the whole the property sector still performed quite OK with the expectation that first-half results will be quite good. I think that given no negative news from the States, the market will still be led by the property sector.&quot; said Tang.</p>
<p>Shares in Sino Land rose HK$0.20 to HK$8.35. The company said it was in preliminary discussions with bankers about securitising the rental income from a major property investment project.</p>
<p>Trading in Shanghai Petrochemical shares was suspended. The company said it would place 500 million H-shares at HK$2.075 each with institutional and professional investors. The stock closed at HK$2.25 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Trading in Recor Holdings shares was also suspended. The stock closed at HK$0.155 on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
