<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10348" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks hamstrung until parliamentary debate.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks hamstrung until parliamentary debate.</headline>
<byline>Suthep Chawla</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks are expected to stagnate until parliament votes on an opposition no-confidence motion against Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa next month, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>They said the political cloud hanging over the market is then expected to clear, whichever way the voting goes.</p>
<p>The market hit its lowest level this year on July 31 when the Stock Exchange of Thailand (SET) index dived to 1,064.04 points.</p>
<p>The volatile index finished 4.32 points lower at 1,090.71 on Thursday. It tumbled 15 percent in July alone.</p>
<p>Analysts said key factors affecting the market were a perception among foreigners that the government may be unable to handle the slowing economy, withdrawal of the Palang Dharma Party from Banharn's seven-party coalition last week and this week's no-confidence motion against the prime minister.</p>
<p>Some said Banharn's administration had failed to stem a ballooning current account deficit, caused a significant economic slowdown and been unable to liven up slowing exports.</p>
<p>Debate on the no-confidence motion, accusing Banharn of mismanagement and inefficiency, is due to start on September 11.</p>
<p>Political analysts said voting could go either way as Banharn tries to keep his troubled coalition, which has 209 seats in the 391-seat parliament, intact.</p>
<p>&quot;Negative feeling continues to prevail in the market and the SET index is expected to move sideways down at least until the censure motion against Banharn is over,&quot; James Landi of Nithipat Capital told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors should get clearer views on the political scene after the no-confidence debate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Somchai Trairattanapirom of Sitca Investment and Securities said the index could fall below the psychologically important 1,000-point level unless there was a change in the government and the economic picture cleared.</p>
<p>Analysts said cheap stock prices alone were not sufficient to bring back foreign investors to the SET, still considered as one of the most attractive markets in Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;The overall prices of stocks had fallen between 15 and 20 percent by the end of July from a year ago but investors are not enthusiastic in buying them. Long-term investment of more than six months is now preferable as it poses not too much risk for the investors,&quot; Somchai said.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody wants to see a new and efficient government with comprehensive plans to tackle economic problems. Chances are very small for the SET index to rise if there's no change in the government,&quot; said Landi.</p>
<p>Others said even if Banharn won the the no-confidence vote there was a chance the market could stabilise as there were expectations that the fourth quarter could see healthier economic fundamentals such as lower interest rates.</p>
<p>Analysts said it would not be as risky for investors to start buying large capitalised bank and energy issues now as there were priced attractively.</p>
<p>&quot;Major banks are expected to maintain their profits between 10 to 15 percent this year,&quot; Somchai said. &quot;Investors should not worry.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
