<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10345" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Argentina urges Latin America links to ASEAN.</title>
<headline>Argentina urges Latin America links to ASEAN.</headline>
<byline>Bill Tarrant</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine President Carlos Menem on Friday called for trade links between the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) and the fledgling South American common market, Mercosur.</p>
<p>In an address to Malaysian businessmen, Menem said Mercosur -- formed last year when Argentina, Brazil, Uruguay and Paraguay agreed to set up a common market -- had recently signed a framework accord with the European Union for a free trade area.</p>
<p>&quot;And I would very much like to ask Malaysian and Argentine businessmen to arrive at a similar agreement with ASEAN countries...making it possible to expand trade,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chile and Bolivia have also signed agreements with Mercosur, creating a market of 220 million people representing a combined gross domestic product of $950 billion and covering two-thirds of the South American land mass, Menem said.</p>
<p>ASEAN -- Malaysia, Indonesia, Brunei, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam -- groups some of the world's fastest growing countries. ASEAN is also implementing a free trade area in stages over the next decade.</p>
<p>Menem discussed ties between the two regional groups with Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad earlier on Friday.</p>
<p>Malaysian Foreign Minister Abdullah Badawi, briefing reporters on the meeting, said both leaders stressed the importance of establishing relations between the two groups.</p>
<p>&quot;I informed the meeting that ASEAN Foreign Ministers have already discussed this and we are now looking on how to further develop relations,&quot; Badawi said.</p>
<p>Mercosur would also discuss its relations with ASEAN at a meeting this year in Brazil, Badawi added.</p>
<p>Trade between Malaysia and Argentina has rocketed over the past five years. Last year, trade rose to $321 million, a 122 percent increase over the previous year, according to Argentine officials.</p>
<p>Argentina exported about $260 million worth of agricultural products, oil seeds, animal foodstuff and vegetable fats and imported $61 million worth of rubber, electrical equipment and industrial machinery.</p>
<p>Trade will get a further boost from agreements signed between Argentine metal equipment and turbine maker IMPSA and Malaysian firms to supply equipment to the 13.6 billion ringgit ($5.5 billion) Bakun dam.</p>
<p>Dam builder Ekran Bhd on Friday awarded a contract to IMPSA to supply turbines, hydraulic equipment and other machinery for the dam in Malaysia's Borneo state of Sarawak.</p>
<p>Ekran executive chairman Ting Pek Khing declined to give an exact figure for the contract at the signing ceremony except to say it was a multi-million ringgit one.</p>
<p>IMPSA signed a second agreement to form a joint venture, IMPSA Malaysia Sdn Bhd, with Malaysia's Hicom Holdings, state investment company Permodalan Nasional Bhd, Kumpulan Pinang holdings and Emir Equity Corporation.</p>
<p>The joint venture is to supply 40 million ringgit worth of equipment for Bakun's hydroelectric turbines and to make container cranes to sell regionally, Argentina officials told reporters.</p>
<p>Menem leaves for Indonesia on Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MRCSL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
