<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10344" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China rate cuts seen boosting gold consumption.</title>
<headline>China rate cuts seen boosting gold consumption.</headline>
<byline>Mishi Saran</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's second interest rate cut in four months, announced Thursday, will boost the country's gold consumption as the economy prospers, World Gold Council Hong Kong and China manager Emily Li said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;After the last interest rate cut in May, we have already seen some increases in the gold consumption in Shanghai and Guangzhou,&quot; Li said.</p>
<p>&quot;Starting in September and October, gold consumption in the China market enters its annual peak and that will also help generate more gold demand,&quot; Li added.</p>
<p>Emboldened by falling inflation and still worried about its flagging state-owned sector, China's central bank announced on Thursday it would slice an average 1.2 percentage points off lending rates and 1.5 percentage points off deposit rates.</p>
<p>Long term savings rates were slashed the deepest, with the five-year deposit rate cut by 3.06 percentage points to 9.0 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;I think, of course, gold will benefit from this action,&quot; Li said, noting that a thriving economy meant more disposable income available to buy gold.</p>
<p>&quot;When looking at the gold market, we have to look at the affluency and the economic development of the country, income levels and the population,&quot; Li added.</p>
<p>Some analysts said that as China's economy grew, other, more attractive investments were available to the general public and gold might suffer as a result.</p>
<p>&quot;With the drop in interest rates, people might well choose to put their money in property and stock markets,&quot; said a source at a Hong Kong-based jewellery house.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, in the second quarter of this year, higher consumer confidence and spending, partly in response to credit-easing measures, swelled China's gold consumption by two percent to 58 tonnes, according to figures released by the World Gold Council earlier this month.</p>
<p>Despite the official -- albeit thinning -- mist of secrecy surrounding China's gold industry, trade sources say that a healthy gold to-and-fro exists between Hong Kong and China.</p>
<p>&quot;We know that some of our customers are shipping gold back to China or have strong links to the mainland, but it's not our business to probe,&quot; said one gold trader.</p>
<p>&quot;It happens,&quot; said the World Gold Council's Li.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very difficult to say how, but it's not just Hong Kong companies taking gold to China -- it happens the other way around as well,&quot; she said, noting this was mainly spurred by the difference in gold prices across the colony's porous borders.</p>
<p>&quot;This is in addition to the millions of tourists from the mainland buying gold in Hong Kong each year to take back to China,&quot; Li said, noting this was a very direct channel.</p>
<p>As trade and financial links between Hong Kong and China thicken in the run-up to 1997, when the British territory's sovereignity will be handed back to China, movements in Hong Kong's gold market reflect more and more fluctuations in the Chinese gold market, analysts say.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
