<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10350" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Brokers cool to Tsingtao results.</title>
<headline>Brokers cool to Tsingtao results.</headline>
<byline>Mark O'Neill</byline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tsingtao Brewery Co on Friday announced a slight increase in interim profits, but brokers were unimpressed, saying it needed to do more to hold its position in an increasingly competitive market.</p>
<p>Tsingtao, which makes China's premium brand, produced 203,150 tonnes of beer in the first half ended June 30, up 7.25 percent on the same 1995 period and accounting for 2.4 percent of national output of 8.32 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The brewery is China's third largest beer producer.</p>
<p>It posted net profit of 76.99 million yuan ($9.28 million), up from 69.39 million, on turnover of 884.818 million yuan, up from 773.157 million, with long-term debt rising to 274.25 million yuan from 194.446 million.</p>
<p>The results were calculated using domestic accountic standards.</p>
<p>&quot;For me, this company is a sell,&quot; said an analyst at one foreign brokerage. &quot;It is not reacting fast enough to a very competitive market. It does not advertise enough and is not expanding production capacity quickly enough.</p>
<p>&quot;Its output has been growing more slowly than the market in the past few years,&quot; he added. &quot;Its market strategy is wrong.&quot;</p>
<p>China's beer market is one of the fastest growing in the world. National output in 1995 was 15.46 million tonnes and China is expected eventually to overtake the United States as the world's biggest beer drinker.</p>
<p>At the end of 1995, China had 640 breweries, 73 of which produce more than 50,000 tonnes a year, down from 800 several years ago. About 50 of these larger breweries are or will become joint ventures.</p>
<p>A second analyst recommended a hold on the stock, saying that Tsingtao's production in 1997 was expected to rise to 700,000-800,000 tonnes from 500,000 in 1996, because of expansion and the acquisition of two breweries.</p>
<p>The best strategy for the company was to acquire breweries in different regions, given China's fragmented beer market, he said.</p>
<p>A company spokeswoman said that it had no plans for new acquisitions in the short term. &quot;There are many ways to raise output. There is no single model. We act according to market demand.&quot;</p>
<p>She said that there had been no progress in talks with Anheuser-Busch on setting up a joint venture brewery.</p>
<p>The company statement said that establishment with a Hong Kong partner of a joint venture brewery in the southern city of Shenzhen had not progressed after more than three years of talks because of disagreements over its scale and other commercial issues.</p>
<p>But, on the positive side, it said the firm was among 300 companies chosen in June by the central bank and the State Economic and Trade Commission to receive support.</p>
<p>Tsingtao is also one of 10 domestic brewing groups that will receive preferential loans and conditions from the government to help them compete with joint venture breweries, the official press announced last month.</p>
<p>The 60 joint venture breweries in 1995 produced three million tonnes of beer, 20 percent of the national total. The foreign brands they produce account for just 2.6 percent of the market.</p>
<p>($1=8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
