<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10358" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Worst year for Malaysian cocoa, growers say.</title>
<headline>Worst year for Malaysian cocoa, growers say.</headline>
<byline>Barani Krishnaan</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's current mid-year cocoa crop is the worst in the nation's history and is unlikely to improve by the year-end harvest, growers said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;What I made this month is barely enough to pay one man's wages,&quot; Anthony Tsen, a grower in Tawau in the east Malaysian state of Sabah, lamented in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Tsen, who owns Landquest Sdn Bhd, a Tawau-based cocoa and oil palm grower, said he had obtained 320 kg of cocoa in August against 7.1 tonnes in August 1995 -- a 22-fold drop.</p>
<p>Dry beans from the current month totalled 112 kg. At an average price of 3,280 ringgit ($132) a tonne, that means a bottomline of 367 ringgit, said Tsen.</p>
<p>&quot;My workers earn around 400 (ringgit) each. Luckily I have some palm oil to survive,&quot; he said, echoing a sentiment all too common in Tawau these days, where growers have been chopping down cocoa trees almost every day and replanting with oil palm.</p>
<p>Tsen blamed the poor mid-year crop on floods that ravaged Tawau between December and February. &quot;The floods came during the fruit-setting period and wiped out the whole setting.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Fleshing of leaves for the third crop season between October and December has begun but rains are falling, too,&quot; said another grower in Tawau. &quot;So it looks like the year-end crop will also be bad.&quot;</p>
<p>Malaysia's first cocoa harvest is between April and June and the second between July and September.</p>
<p>Sabah, located on jungle-draped Borneo island, accounts for more than 80 percent of Malaysia's cocoa production, with the bulk of the output coming from Tawau in the northeast.</p>
<p>BAL Plantations, the largest cocoa producer in Sabah contributing about four percent of the nation's output, has also begun switching to oil palm, industry sources said.</p>
<p>BAL, taken over by Golden Hope Plantations Bhd earlier this year, will only hold about 5,800 hectares (14,330 acres) of cocoa in Tawau by June next year after chopping down 1,600 hectares (3,950 acres), said sources familiar with the workings of the company.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, there's no cocoa at all in BAL's warehouse. On a good year, BAL could produce 10,000 to 12,000 tonnes. Now seven to eight (thousand) is considered good,&quot; said a source.</p>
<p>The country's 12 cocoa grinders, with a total capacity to grind 120,000 tonnes, were only processing about 60,000 to 80,000 tonnes yearly, said industry officials.</p>
<p>The Malaysian Cocoa Board (MCB) has forecast 1996 output at 122,000 tonnes by the end of the third harvest in December -- against its earlier estimate of 130,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;We made the forecast in June,&quot; an MCB spokesman said by telephone from Kota Kinabalu, the capital of Sabah. He did not elaborate. Last year's production totalled 131,475 tonnes.</p>
<p>Growers surveyed by Reuters were generally pessimistic about the board's figures and projections.</p>
<p>&quot;I think 100,000 tonnes will be a more realistic figure,&quot; said an official of a major cocoa plantation in Sabah.</p>
<p>Growers say Tawau has some of the world's best cocoa land but the pod borer disease, adverse rains, drought and scarce labour were killing the industry.</p>
<p>&quot;We have come up with some good bud-grafting and cloning methods to maximise the crop,&quot; said an MCB technician. &quot;But the environmental problems are working faster than we can.&quot;</p>
<p>Growers interviewed by Reuters in the last two years said they saw a dim future for the crop in Malaysia.</p>
<p>Cocoa growers in Sabah had cumulatively lost an estimated 10 billion ringgit ($4.0 billion) in the last 20 years due to crop failure, Hong Ngit Ming, a grower in Tawau, said in May. ($1 = 2.49 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100144">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
