<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10363" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Air Touch joins T$6 bln Taiwan telecom venture.</title>
<headline>Air Touch joins T$6 bln Taiwan telecom venture.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. company Air Touch Communications Inc has signed on as a foreign partner in Walsin Lihwa Corp's T$6 billion (US$218.2 million) foray into Taiwan's telecom market, Walsin said on Friday.</p>
<p>The five-partner venture, Rainbow Star Telecommunications Co Ltd, will be chaired by Walsin managing director Chiao Youjun, Walsin said in a statement.</p>
<p>It said Walsin held a 30 percent stake while President Enterprises and Tainan Spinning shared 30 percent. Yulon Motor and Air Touch each have 20 percent, the most a foreign investor can hold under Taiwan's recently liberalised telecom regulations.</p>
<p>&quot;Responding to the government's calling to promote Taiwan as an Asia-Pacific operations centre, Rainbow Star will provide quality cellular phone services for customers at a reasonable price through beneficial competition,&quot; Walsin said.</p>
<p>The venture is the latest in a string linking Taiwan enterprises and overseas telecom powers since the island opened its telecom market in January.</p>
<p>Major new investors include U.S. giant Sprint Corp, Hong Kong Telecommunications and Singapore Telecommunications.  </p>
<p>The venture's main focus will be mobile telephone services, which is one of several telecom sectors opened up by parliament for private and limited foreign investments.</p>
<p>Previously, telecom services were monopolised by the Directorate General of Telecommunications. Its operations were spun off July 1 as Chunghwa Telecommunications Corp, and the directorate retains only a regulatory and monitoring role.</p>
<p>Three reform laws passed in January give unprecedented though limited access to the market by foreign interests, who had long been barred from telecom operations.</p>
<p>Despite the reforms, Taiwan has come under pressure from the United States to phase out other market barriers.</p>
<p>These include a 20 percent ceiling on foreign ownership of common-carrier services such as basic telephone and data transmission, and a profit cap that obliges telecom firms to reduce rates if operational profits exceed 11.5 percent.</p>
<p>Taiwan negotiators agreed with U.S. trade officials on July 19 to phase out the profit cap over the next year, but remained divided on how to let foreign investors take more equity in Taiwan telecom operations.</p>
<p>($1 = T$27.5)</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
