<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10364" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: APEC to calculate impact of trade liberalisation.</title>
<headline>APEC to calculate impact of trade liberalisation.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum plans to quantify the gains and losses of its regional trade liberalisation plan, a Japanese delegate said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will work on the measures and make a calculation on what the impacts these measures will have on the economies of the APEC region,&quot; Kazutomo Abe, head of an APEC task force studying impact of trade liberalisation, told reporters.</p>
<p>The trade liberalisation programme, which is one of the cornerstones of the 18-member group, aims to bring down tariffs to zero by 2010 for developed countries and 2020 for developing countries.</p>
<p>Abe said the exercise would identify which sectors of each economy would gain or lose by a tariff reduction programme.</p>
<p>Other studies by multilateral agencies have shown that overall, economies tend to benefit from a free-trade regime, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;(The studies) generally indicate that the trade liberalisation measures will benefit all areas in terms of increasing GDP (gross domestic product) and increasing trade,&quot; Abe added.</p>
<p>These economic gains could easily offset any negative impacts, he said.</p>
<p>Some developing countries have expressed fears that freer trade could stifle infant industries.</p>
<p>APEC is comprised of Australia, Brunei, Canada, Chile, China, Hong Kong, Indonesia, Japan, South Korea, Malaysia, Mexico, New Zealand, Papua New Guinea, Philippines, Singapore, Taiwan, Thailand and the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
