<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10376" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore shares open down, Sembawang Maritime up.</title>
<headline>Singapore shares open down, Sembawang Maritime up.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Singapore share market opened flat on Friday with some buying focus on stocks in the news, dealers said.</p>
<p>The 30-share Straits Times Industrials Index dropped 1.03 points to 2,161.70 at 0230 GMT following a Wall Street surge of 43.65 points to 5,733.47.</p>
<p>Yet another takeover offer stirred the market. Sembawang Corp's Thursday announcement of a voluntary takeover of Sembawang Maritime Ltd boosted its share price on Friday.</p>
<p>Sembawang Maritime Ltd (SML) jumped to Singapore $4.00 in early trade before dropping back to S$3.76, up 54 cents or 16.77 percent. Dealers said punters were pushing the SML price up because it was lower than the offer price at S$3.70.</p>
<p>In addition, news on CAM International's diversification into two high-technology vegetable farms attracted attention and its trading volume shot up.</p>
<p>Cam International saw 6.0 million shares crossed at a high S$1.02. Its share was up S$0.05 to S$0.79 on a turnover of 1.41 million shares.</p>
<p>Market volume was 32.89 million shares with gainers leading losers by 114 to 42.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
