<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10377" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan rates on hold, market watches for data leak.</title>
<headline>Japan rates on hold, market watches for data leak.</headline>
<byline>Linda Sieg</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belief that Japan will keep its easy money policy on hold has dulled market interest in a key central bank survey due out next week, but some are keen to see whether the Bank of Japan can prevent leaks of sensitive data.</p>
<p>Most economists expect the central bank's quarterly corporate survey, or &quot;tankan&quot;, to show some improvement in business sentiment when the data is unveiled next Wednesday.</p>
<p>But few anticipate the survey will contain data stunning enough to prompt the central bank to boost interest rates, which it has kept at record low levels for nearly a year.</p>
<p>Most economists surveyed by Reuters forecast that the diffusion index for big manufacturers, an important gauge of corporate sentiment, would rise somewhat from the minus three posted in May, when the last survey was conducted.</p>
<p>Private forecasts ranged from minus four to plus five, with seven out of 15 think-tanks predicting that the index would slip into positive territory for the first time since November 1991. The firms themselves forecast an August index of zero when they were surveyed in May.</p>
<p>The index represents the percentage of firms expecting business to improve minus those who expect it to worsen. The higher the number, the more optimistic the outlook.</p>
<p>&quot;The data is unlikely to show a sharp improvement,&quot; said Jesper Koll, chief economist at JP Morgan in Tokyo. &quot;It will show a modest improvement.&quot;</p>
<p>Major non-manufacturers' are also expected to have grown less gloomy than in May, when their diffusion index was at minus nine. Private forecasts ranged from minus 10 to plus one, but only one out of 13 think-tanks forecast a positive figure.</p>
<p>Companies forecast an August index of minus three in May. Capital spending plans for the fiscal year to March 31, 1997, are expected to be about the same as the six percent rise companies said they planned in May.</p>
<p>Economists said such modest data was unlikely to prompt the Bank of Japan to move soon to tighten short-term market rates or boost the official discount rate at which it lends to commercial banks. Many think there will be no change this year, although some argue the central bank could nudge up short-term market rates before the year's end.</p>
<p>&quot;Interest rate policy is on hold,&quot; Koll said.</p>
<p>Such expectations contrast sharply with rampant market speculation as recently as last month that the central bank was poised to raise rates.</p>
<p>Economists say fears that Japan's economic recovery will falter later this year when public spending peters out and take another hit when the three percent sales tax is raised to five percent from April 1 are reinforcing central bank caution.</p>
<p>While the tankan's content is expected to be something of a damp squib, some analysts are watching for signs that the data has been leaked, as many believe it has been in the past.</p>
<p>The Bank of Japan said late last month that it would release the data in August, the same month the survey was conducted, rather than in early September as has been past practice.</p>
<p>The central bank will also unveil the key figures in the survey at 11 a.m. local time (0200 GMT) rather than 2 p.m. (0500 GMT) as had been the custom. More complete details will be released a day later, also at 11 a.m.</p>
<p>BOJ officials said the change was aimed at making the data available as soon as possible and allowing the market to digest it during trading hours on the same day. The release of other economic indicators has also recently been brought forward.</p>
<p>They flatly denied that the new schedule was related to rumours that &quot;tankan&quot; figures have been leaked in the past.</p>
<p>BOJ officials from Governor Yasuo Matsushita on down have said they did not believe rumours that May tankan data was leaked ahead of its official release at 2 p.m. on June 7. That morning, rumours swirled that the diffusion index for manufacturers would be minus three for May and zero for August -- precisely what the figures turned out to be.</p>
<p>Some analysts remain unconvinced by the official denials of leaks. &quot;The truth is, the data has been leaked the past three times,&quot; said one economist, who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;So they are trying to shorten the time between compilation and the actual release. It will be interesting to see if they can really control the leaking. If not, it could raise a credibility issue,&quot; the economist said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
