<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10374" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks hit by profit-taking in morning.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks hit by profit-taking in morning.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks were weak in Friday morning trade, after a higher start to the session, as this week's rally prompted investors to take profits ahead of a long weekend.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index was down 62.17 points at 11,416.60. Turnover was HK$1.68 billion after the first hour of trade.</p>
<p>Kent Rossiter, institutional sales manager at Nikko Securities, said strong earnings released by Cheung Kong (Holdings) Ltd on Thursday had been discounted by the market and China's interest rate cut had been anticipated. &quot;We are seeing some selling on the good news,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The blue chip index had attempted to move higher in early trade, rising to 11,494.</p>
<p>China announced on Thursday that it was cutting bank deposit and lending rates in response to easing domestic inflation.</p>
<p>Also on Thursday, Cheung Kong (Holdings) posted higher than expected first-half net profit of HK$8.16 billion compared to HK$5.95 billion. Hutchison's interim results were slightly below expectations at HK$7.84 billion versus HK$4.48 billion.</p>
<p>Shares in Cheung Kong fell HK$0.50 to HK$57.00 and Hutchison was down HK$0.90 at HK$48.40.</p>
<p>H-shares were down two points at 839 after rallying on Thursday on hopes of a Chinese rate cut.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone's been anticipating this rate cut in China. H-shares have been rising on the back of that - now after it's happened we're getting profit-taking ahead of the weekend,&quot; said one trader at Salomon Brothers.</p>
<p>&quot;You had the run-up in banking shares, people are probably taking a bit of profit there,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Shares in HSBC Holdings were down HK$1.00 at HK$135.00 and Hang Seng Bank fell HK$0.75 to HK$80.75.</p>
<p>Trading in Shanghai Petrochemical shares was suspended. The company said it would place 500 million H-shares at HK$2.075 each with institutional and professional investors. The stock closed at HK$2.25 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Trading in Recor Holdings shares was also suspended. The stock closed at HK$0.155 on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
