<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10388" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli minister targets illegal foreign workers.</title>
<headline>Israeli minister targets illegal foreign workers.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Heller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Israeli cabinet minister proposed on Friday taking steps to cut growing dependence on foreign workers who have taken jobs which are off-limits to Palestinians and unwanted by Jews.</p>
<p>&quot;We will propose expelling about 1,000 illegal foreign labourers from Israel a month,&quot; Labour and Welfare Minister Eli Ishai said before the cabinet debated the issue at its weekly meeting on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The number of legal workers also should be cut,&quot; he told Israel radio.</p>
<p>But Ishai's proposal was no blueprint for a mass exodus from Israel of workers from countries such as Romania, Thailand, Turkey and China who now do the low-paying manual jobs of Palestinians barred from the Jewish state for security reasons.</p>
<p>It would take authorities more than eight years to expel all of the 100,000 foreigners he said were working in Israel without a permit -- assuming police could round all of them up and no new illegal labourers slipped into the country.</p>
<p>But Ishai said: &quot;There is a problem here. (Hiring foreign workers) pays -- it is good for building contractors....We may have to keep a quota of foreign workers. The question is how many.&quot;</p>
<p>Ishai said 200,000 foreigners work in Israel -- half of them illegally.</p>
<p>Many Israelis initially welcomed the blue-collar foreign influx at the height of the six-year-long Palestinian uprising that began in 1987, during the course of which Arab guerrillas knifed Jews in Israeli cities.</p>
<p>But while the Palestinians had been required by Israeli law to return to their homes in the occupied territories each evening, the foreigners who replaced them remain overnight in squalid housing that has become an eyesore.</p>
<p>Horror stories abound.</p>
<p>Israel's Channel Two television showed on Thursday six Turkish workers locked in a shack on an Israeli farm by their employer, apparently over a financial dispute.</p>
<p>&quot;It is just like a ghetto,&quot; said an incredulous police officer at the scene.</p>
<p>The Palestinian Authority has demanded Israel allow more of its people in to work, saying an Israeli closure had crippled the economy in the self-ruled areas.</p>
<p>Before the Palestinian uprising, as many as 160,000 Arabs from the West Bank and Gaza worked in Israel.</p>
<p>Israel sealed off the territories and stopped Palestinians from entering in February after the first in a series of Moslem suicide bombings that killed 59 people -- including seven Romanian workers. Today some 30,000 Palestinians work in Israel.</p>
<p>Ishai, an ultraorthodox Jew, took a high-profile tour on Thursday of a ramshackle Tel Aviv neighbourhood now home to thousands of foreign workers.</p>
<p>&quot;Every resident of Tel Aviv who comes into contact with foreign workers is likely to face health risks,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Municipal authorities, especially in Tel Aviv, complain they cannot cope with the social, health and crime problems posed by the labourers.</p>
<p>But Nigerians cleaning Israelis' apartments, Thais picking flowers in greenhouses, Chinese construction workers and Filipina nannies heading to church on Sundays have become permanent fixtures in the Jewish state.</p>
<p>In one leafy suburb in central Israel, pairs of Chinese looking for gardening work on their day off approach people in backyards with a plaintive request.</p>
<p>&quot;Avoda?&quot; they ask, using the Hebrew word for &quot;work&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
