<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10383" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: FEATURE - Is central planning still right for Singapore?.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Is central planning still right for Singapore?.</headline>
<byline>Chris Johnson</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Central government planning, one of the keys to Singapore's meteoric economic rise since the 1960's, may be beginning to be a drag on the island's development, economists say.</p>
<p>On August 12, Singapore announced a sharp decline in its economic growth in the second quarter, to seven percent from 10.9 percent a year ago, and said the slowdown could continue for some time.</p>
<p>Officials said the slide was due largely to a slowdown in the core computer and electronics-related industry, which accounts for almost half the country's manufacturing output and provides 60 percent of its non-oil exports.</p>
<p>But economists say Singapore is now too dependent on this once high-growth industry, and many blame the economy's over concentration on that sector on heavy government involvement in industrial planning.</p>
<p>&quot;The high degree of 'government guidance' in industry was successful in the stage of industrial 'catch-up',&quot; said Bernhard Eschweiler, vice-president of economic research at J.P. Morgan.</p>
<p>&quot;But it remains to be seen if government-driven policy will be able to continue to lead Singapore's industrial development with the country well-developed and attempting to be at the forefront of innovation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Singapore's version of central economic planning is quite different from the system adopted by the old communist bloc.</p>
<p>In the 31 years since independence, the avowedly capitalist island-state has built a vast array of state agencies designed to help it match developed Western nations in industry and trade.</p>
<p>State-owned companies, which own and control a huge proportion of local firms including Singapore Airlines and Singapore Telecom, have channelled new investments into proven &quot;winning&quot; industries.</p>
<p>Tax incentives have encouraged overseas investors and many multinational companies to follow a similar path.</p>
<p>These policies have supported a rise in Gross Domestic Product (GDP) of nine percent a year for the last 30 years.</p>
<p>Despite having a population of fewer than three million, Singapore is now the world's 15th richest country and is expected to be the seventh richest by 1999, according to a local research group.</p>
<p>But these policies have also helped discourage diversity.</p>
<p>&quot;So far the government has been wonderfully successful,&quot; said Chia Woon Khien, regional economist at Union Bank of Switzerland.</p>
<p>&quot;But no other countries -- except some oil producers -- are so skewed... The manufacturing sector has become too concentrated in the electronics area and will be subject to the volatility of that industry,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Officials said after the release of last week's figures that Singapore had little alternative to investing in electronics because it had offered, and over time would continue to offer, higher growth than other industries.</p>
<p>They stressed the government wants to see diversification within the electronics industry away from hard-pressed silicon chip-making towards the production of micro-processors.</p>
<p>And they said they want to develop alternative parts of the economy such as financial services and encourage innovation.</p>
<p>But critics say government involvement in the economy may no longer be appropriate for Singapore as a developed economy.</p>
<p>Once a government preference for one type of investment is made known, local companies tend follow the advice, ignoring alternatives. Diversity is an inevitable casualty, they say.</p>
<p>The leader of the opposition Singapore Democratic Party, Chee Soon Juan, argues that strong &quot;government guidance&quot; on industrial policy tends to discourage entrepreneurial activity and the spontaneity needed to invent and develop new products for the future.</p>
<p>&quot;And if we don't diversify, one of these days we could be caught very seriously,&quot; Chee said.</p>
<p>Singapore government officials stress they want to encourage innovation in industry and give out grants to promote it.</p>
<p>But Eschweiler said some industries, particularly emerging ones, only tend to flourish in the absence of regulation.</p>
<p>&quot;Advanced economic development has to be organic. It needs a liberal economic environment,&quot; he said. &quot;That's especially true of financial markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists say the Singapore state appears to be responding to this and is gradually backing away from intervention in policy-making in many areas.</p>
<p>&quot;The role of the government has definitely taken a back seat since the country's recession in the mid-1980's,&quot; said one economist, who declined to be identified. &quot;There is more and more talk of decentralisation and less government involvement.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
