<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10393" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: 401K investors left stock funds in July.</title>
<headline>401K investors left stock funds in July.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Benkoe</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Retirement-plan investors abandoned stock mutual funds during an especially turbulent period in July during the market correction, according to a study of 401k plans.</p>
<p>The data defies the traditional view that individuals who put pension money into mutual funds are passive investors.</p>
<p>&quot;Individuals are more likely to move as the market moves,&quot; said Stacy Schaus of Hewitt Associates, a Lincolnshire, Ill. human resources consultant. &quot;You might even classify those people as traders.&quot;</p>
<p>Hewitt, which conducted the study, found investors pulled about $54.8 million from equity mutual funds between July 11 and July 16. During that time, about $63.2 million flooded into stable-return funds, the study found. The difference between the two sums went into other funds.</p>
<p>The biggest single-day retreat from stock funds, about $25.5 million, occurred on July 16, the day after the Dow Industrials fell 161 points to 5,350., and the Nasdaq Composite fell 43 to 1,060.</p>
<p>The biggest one-day outflow from stable-return funds was $25.2 million on July 17, also marking the biggest one-day gain for stocks funds, about $17.2 million. On July 17, the Dow gained 18 points, and Nasdaq rose 33 points.</p>
<p>&quot;It would indicate that you have a percentage of the population that is doing precisely what they shouldn't be doing,&quot; said Schaus. &quot;They are running away when the market drops and coming back in when it goes up.&quot;</p>
<p>The survey covered 25 plans with total assets of $21 billion, according to Hewitt.</p>
<p>Analysts said they were looking closely at the survey because to date there has been little data to measure the way 401k investors behave.</p>
<p>&quot;It's surprising to me,&quot; said Glen Casey, a defined-contribution consultant at Cerulli Associates in Boston. &quot;It bucks the conventional wisdom that 401k money is less emotional about the market than general retail fund money.&quot;</p>
<p>Kent Novell, vice president of Access Research in Windsor, Conn., believes that 401k investors remain less aggressive in moving around fund money than in the past.</p>
<p>&quot;My guess is that in the old 401k world, you would have had much more movement if the market corrected because you knew you could only move your money once a quarter,&quot; he said. &quot;Today, when you can move it anytime, there's the tendency to wait it out.&quot;</p>
<p>About $675 billion of pension funds were invested in all U.S. mutual funds at the end of 1995, or about 38 percent of $5 trillion in all U.S. retirement funds, according to Access Research.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150214">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
