<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10392" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan tackles 10-year high jobless rate.</title>
<headline>Taiwan tackles 10-year high jobless rate.</headline>
<byline>James Peng</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>With joblessness at a 10-year high of nearly three percent, Taiwan on Friday froze new foreign labour imports and launched job training schemes with an eye toward trimming the rate to 2.3 percent.</p>
<p>Taiwan's statistics directorate announced that unemployment inched up to 2.97 percent in July from 2.6 percent in June, the highest since the jobless rate hit 3.11 in August 1986.</p>
<p>The government, whose earlier economic stimulus measures have failed to halt the rise in unemployment, adopted two new measures in a bid to reverse the trend.</p>
<p>&quot;The cabinet just passed proposals to freeze import of foreign labour and spend T$860 million (US$31.3 million) to introduce a series of job training programmes to counter rising unemployment,&quot; a government spokesman said by telephone.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman at the Council of Labour Affairs said Taiwan would not accept new labour import applications and would freeze the number of foreign workers at 296,114 unless the jobless rate begins to fall.</p>
<p>She noted, however, that the number of foreign workers already in Taiwan totalled 229,492, well below the limit.</p>
<p>In 1991, Taiwan lifted a ban on the hiring of foreign workers to meet what was then a severe domestic labour shortage, importing workers mainly from Indonesia, Malaysia, Thailand and the Philippines.</p>
<p>More recently, a stubborn slowing of Taiwan's &quot;Asian dragon&quot; economy has turned foreign labour into a political issue.</p>
<p>President Lee Teng-hui told the National Assembly in August that Taiwan had prepared countermeasures to reduce joblessness to 2.3 percent -- including limits on foreigners.</p>
<p>&quot;These measures, especially the one on foreign labour, should help us reach the 2.3 percent target announced by President Lee,&quot; a statistics directorate official said.</p>
<p>The directorate attributed July's decade-high unemployment to new inflows of new graduates and summertime job seekers into the labour market and said the rate could move higher.</p>
<p>&quot;The rate should be even higher next month but could begin to decline in September,&quot; the directorate official said.</p>
<p>The official said she expected the jobless rate to gradually fall to between 2.0 percent and 2.5 percent once June-to-August seasonal factors are digested.</p>
<p>Nomura Securities economist Amy Huang disagreed.</p>
<p>&quot;The jobless rate should remain high at around 2.7-2.8 percent in the fourth quarter despite the measures the government is taking to deal with the unemployment problem,&quot; Huang told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;The jobless problem is mainly caused by a slowing economy, and although the economy is seen recovering in the second half, there will be a time lag before it is reflected in the jobless rate,&quot; Huang said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
