<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10397" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Smog-choked East seeks aid from rest of U.S..</title>
<headline>Smog-choked East seeks aid from rest of U.S..</headline>
<byline>Sonali Paul</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Power plants in Alabama might have to clean up their smokestacks and drivers in Illinois might have to pay more for gasoline in a few years, to help New Yorkers breathe more easily.</p>
<p>Eastern states, struggling to get rid of smog without strangling their economies, have drawn more than half the country into a massive project which could eventually force other states to combat smog in the dirtiest eastern cities.</p>
<p>Policymakers from Maine to Texas plan to decide early next year on what steps to take to limit ozone-forming emissions.</p>
<p>The 37-state Ozone Transport Assessment Group (OTAG), assembled over a year ago by the Environmental Protection Agency, could call for emission cuts at power plants, for oil firms to make cleaner fuel or car companies to make cleaner cars to stop dirty air from drifting into eastern cities.</p>
<p>While no decisions have been made yet, coal-burning utilities fear they will be the biggest targets for emissions curbs, although utilities and automobiles produce about the same amounts of smog-forming pollutants.</p>
<p>Models show that utilities could cut nitrogen oxide pollution from their smokestacks for $2,500 or less per ton, using new technology or cleaner fuels such as natural gas, while it would cost more than $15,000 per ton to reduce nitrogen oxide emissions from automobiles.</p>
<p>Increases in fuel manufacturing costs could range from a few cents a gallon to 16.5 cents a gallon, said Marc Meteyer, associate director of the American Petroleum Institute.</p>
<p>Coal industry groups see policymakers, who will have to clear their recommendations with state legislators and governors, as loath to risk alienating drivers and hence voters, by imposing new fuel or tighter car emission controls.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a sense you can get a free political lunch by trading reductions from polluted urban areas with reductions from coal plants from rural areas miles away,&quot; said Eugene Trisko, a West Virginia-based attorney representing coal industry, mining and railroad interests.</p>
<p>But state environmental policymakers involved in OTAG say they aim to be fair about imposing new emissions cuts.</p>
<p>&quot;I think controls on just the utilities aren't going to get us what we need,&quot; said Marlin Gottschalk, a program manager in Georgia's Department of Natural Resources and head of an OTAG group evaluating control options for cars.</p>
<p>Before the states make any recommendations to EPA, they aim to prove scientifically that trimming emissions in one area would actually erase some of the East's ozone.</p>
<p>Researchers are likely to be able to show within the next two months to what extent smog in eastern cities is aggravated by emissions from other regions, said OTAG Chairwoman Mary Gade, director of the Illinois EPA.</p>
<p>So far, the jury is still out on how far and how much pollution is being blown from west to east and south to northeast, and whether the problem is emissions at ground level, spewed from cars and trucks, or emissions higher up, belched by power plants and industrial smokestacks.</p>
<p>&quot;Sensitivity runs showed that if you reduced emissions in one region, you would get benefits in the region itself and also some benefits in the adjacent region,&quot; said the head of OTAG's strategies workgroup, Merrylin Zaw-Mon, who is director of Maryland's air and radiation office.</p>
<p>On the border of Ohio and Pennsylvania, for example, ozone levels were recorded at 100 parts per billion at times when Pittsburgh exceeded the national limit of 120 per billion. The numbers suggest that &quot;just a little bit (of pollution transport) will take you over the standard,&quot; Zaw-Mon said.</p>
<p>But Midwestern and Southern utilities, and oil and coal industry officials, have latched on to preliminary evidence that showed little nitrogen oxide floating all the way from, say, Chicago to New York City, or from Houston to Baltimore.</p>
<p>&quot;At this point, there is nothing to conclude that excessive NOx (nitrogen oxide) reductions on utilities is the answer,&quot; said John Paul, vice president of the Center for Energy and Economic Development, which represents all the major railroads and coal industry.</p>
<p>Natural gas advocates, looking for a bigger share of the utility fuel market, argue there is no need to prove that ozone or ozone contributors travel all the way from Mississippi to Massachusetts.</p>
<p>The combined impact of movements suggest a chain of ozone transport from one area to the next. &quot;It just moves downwind,&quot; said Bruce Craig, director of environmental affairs for the Natural Gas Supply Association.</p>
<p>The one issue everyone has agreed to is that there should be some overall cap on nitrogen oxide emissions with a system for trading emissions allowances, said OTAG Chairwoman Gade.</p>
<p>The cap could call for as much as a 75 percent reduction in expected emissions over the next 10 years, but trading of allowances would help hold down the costs of compliance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
