<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10402" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Toyota to recall 90,000 pickups - report.</title>
<headline>Toyota to recall 90,000 pickups - report.</headline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toyota Motor Corp. plans to recall about 90,000 of its 1995-96 Tacoma pickup trucks because of concerns that a potential structural flaw could affect their suspension and steering, The Dallas Morning News reported Friday.</p>
<p>The newspaper said only two-wheel-drive versions of the truck will be affected by the recall. Notification letters will be sent to owners before Sept. 1.</p>
<p>Although Toyota declined to say how much the cost the potential flaw will cost the company, the labour expense alone for the modifications could run as high as $30 million, the paper said without citing a source.</p>
<p>A company spokeswoman told the newspaper that it had notified the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration of the possible problem in July but the agency decided it was not a serious enough problem to warrant a high-profile recall.</p>
<p>That ruling allowed Toyota to begin a voluntary recall, the paper said in its story from Washington.</p>
<p>The Tacoma pickups were designed and manufactured in California. The Toyota spokesman said the potential flaw in the front strut towers was unlikely to cause problems under normal driving conditions.</p>
<p>The newspaper said that, so far, only 12 Tacoma pickups had been found to have the problem. All but one were used for commercial purposes, and the NHTSA said it had received no complaints about the truck from owners, the report said.</p>
<p>There were no reports of deaths or injuries from the flaw, the paper said. U.S. operations of Toyota, Japan's largest automaker, are headquartered in New York.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
