<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10405" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US shares seen off with bonds after strong durables.</title>
<headline>US shares seen off with bonds after strong durables.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A surprisingly strong July durables goods report sent bonds into a tailspin and will likely pressure U.S. stocks at the open on Friday but analysts still see the Dow pushing for a possible record close later.</p>
<p>&quot;The tilt of the market is still up, but the durable goods number may take some of the energy from an upswing at the opening,&quot; said Alan Ackerman, a market strategist at Fahnestock and Co.</p>
<p>The long bond, flat ahead of the data, tumbled 19/32 to yield 6.89 percent. September S&amp;P 500 index futures slumped 2.40 to 669.45, indicating the Dow may fall some 20 points.</p>
<p>July durable goods orders rose 1.6 percent, against expectations for a 0.3 percent advance. Ex-defence durable goods orders climbed 3.5 percent, compared with expectations for a 0.8 percent rise. June durables were revised up to a 0.2 percent drop from the previously reported 0.6 percent fall.</p>
<p>Tobacco stocks will again be a focus. President Clinton is expected to later announce a new series of restrictions on the sale and advertising of tobacco products in the biggest challenge to cigarette makers in over 30 years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
