<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10411" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bundesbank throws EMU a line--but on its own terms.</title>
<headline>Bundesbank throws EMU a line--but on its own terms.</headline>
<byline>Janet Northcote</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bundesbank, almost unrivalled in its power to influence the course of European monetary union (EMU), seemed finally to put a stamp of approval on a single currency this week with a generous policy easing.</p>
<p>A surprisingly large cut of 0.3 percentage point in its main money market rate to 3.0 percent smoothed currency markets and let other European central banks cut credit costs, defusing several weeks of tension about the likely success of EMU.</p>
<p>But although it floored critics who said the German central bank was bent on undermining a single currency and underlined its growing market sensitivity, analysts cautioned against interpreting the move as a dramatic shift to a pro-Euro policy.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not rush to pin this up as the action of an embryo European central bank,&quot; said Alison Cottrell, senior international economist at PaineWebber in London.</p>
<p>The benefits to EMU stemmed rather from a happy coincidence of domestic needs meshing with external factors. Analysts said the chances of the fiercely-independent Bundesbank shooting itself in the foot to bail out others remained minute.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank has no inflation risk at the moment which means it is allowed to look at other factors...such as the world economic environment,&quot; Cottrell said.</p>
<p>Mathias Haffner, economist at BZW agreed. &quot;There is certainly an international aspect to this and it at least gives a sign that the Bundesbank is not out to block EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;But they would not have cut rates if they had not been satisfied with M3 developments and we will have a rate rise when they think that is right, regardless of EMU,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The bank itself justified the easing, which slashed the repo rate to an historic low, with a slowdown in growth in its main monetary policy indicator, M3 money supply, and low inflation.</p>
<p>The justification came as no surprise to Bundesbank watchers, long accustomed to the bank's untiring efforts to make markets understand that the German central bank must by law set price stability as its absolute priority.</p>
<p>Yet the move, which this time acted to help Europe's EMU aims, stemmed from exactly the same motive as previous interest rate decisions which threatened to scupper the single currency project -- meeting Germany's best interests.</p>
<p>In the summers of 1992 and 1993, the central bank presented a clear case for raising rates and keeping them high, arguing that placing Europe's anchor currency at risk would not benefit anybody in the long term.</p>
<p>Each of those decisions drew international criticism and threw currency markets into fresh turmoil, causing economic agony for countries whose currencies were pegged to the mark.</p>
<p>Although the Bundesbank's pursuit of price stability has by no means slackened, economists say today's Bundesbank has to some extent learned from these experiences and now has a much greater awareness of its power to influence markets.</p>
<p>This was partly reflected in the size of Wednesday's cut -- pitched to catch markets off-guard by exceeding expectations.</p>
<p>In a brief statement about Thursday's decision, Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer made no specific reference to EMU or to European currency or economic worries, saying only that the move was &quot;fitting in the general world context&quot;.</p>
<p>Analysts saw this as an acknowledgment that the central bank was increasingly prepared to look beyond Germany's borders, as long as the domestic situation permitted.</p>
<p>Thomas Mayer, senior economist at Goldman Sachs, who said he believed the repo cut sent a very strong message that the Bundesbank cared about EMU, said: &quot;The really different thing now is that they genuinely do look at other European countries and design policy accordingly.&quot;</p>
<p>But Holger Fahrinkrug at UBS in Frankfurt said he believed that even if the repo cut was motivated by external currency market considerations, the primary motive was still the domestic need to rein in the robust mark.</p>
<p>&quot;The currency issue is of course linked in to EMU but I think they were just concerned from a domestic point of view about the strength of the deutschemark,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
