<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10414" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FOCUS-Finland tracks Buba, convergence talk mounts.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Finland tracks Buba, convergence talk mounts.</headline>
<byline>Sara Henley</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>With speculation mounting that Finland may soon link its currency to Europe's Exchange Rate Mechanism, its central bank on Friday unusually joined a European wave of monetary easing.</p>
<p>The Bank of Finland moved faster than normal to follow a key rate cut by Germany's Bundesbank, saying on Friday it was lowering its tender rate, the key tool of monetary policy, to 3.25 percent from 3.50 percent.</p>
<p>In the past it has tended to wait days or weeks before following a Bundesbank lead, and economists who had widely expected the cut had thought it more likely next week as a demonstration of autonomy by Finland's central bank.</p>
<p>The markka has strengthened by about four percent against the Deutschmark and seven percent against the dollar since early May. Finnish Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen on Wednesday reportedly said a decision on linking the markka to ERM would come in the fairly near future.</p>
<p>Economists saw this as a clear sign Finland would go ahead and link the markka -- although their estimated timing of the decision focused on the end of September to October-November.</p>
<p>The markka has been floating freely since September 1992.</p>
<p>Bank officials insisted the cut would have come irrespective of any easing by the Bundesbank, but some economists believed it showed Finland edging towards convergence with the rest of Europe on the way to Economic and Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>&quot;This was a clear sign that Finland is part of Europe and trends in Europe. It was a very good move,&quot; said OKOBANK Treasury economist Teijo Rantatupa.</p>
<p>Asked if the rate cut was a signal of Finland seriously moving towards closer convergence with core European countries in the run-up to EMU, he said: &quot;This is it.&quot;</p>
<p>The Bank of Finland said the cut was based on more signs that inflation -- currently the lowest level in Europe at 0.5 percent in July -- would remain moderate. Friday's cut brought the key rate down by 275 basis points since October 1995.</p>
<p>Bank of Finland board member and director Matti Vanhala said the cut would have happened whether or not the Bundesbank eased.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the German rate cut) did, of course, not make our decision more difficult ... the operating environment became easier, but our cut would have come in any case,&quot; he told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>Vanhala also denied that the central bank had cut the rate in response to the markka's strengthening, and said he did not think the bank would feel obliged to act to steer the markka's direction.</p>
<p>The bank's stated policy is to intervene only to stem short-term volatility in the markka, not its trend.</p>
<p>Jukka Lepomaki at Merita Bank said speculation about an imminent ERM linkage is being fuelled by employers anxious to pressurise the Bank of Finland into ensuring the markka does not link to ERM at too strong a level.</p>
<p>Finnish industry fears a stronger markka would undermine its competitiveness, in particular against neighbouring Sweden, which is not expected to link the crown to ERM.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
