<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10463" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Moovies plans expansion from box office hits.</title>
<headline>Moovies plans expansion from box office hits.</headline>
<byline>Lorrie Grant</byline>
<dateline>CHARLOTTE, N.C. 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A string of hit movies this summer has the video rental store chain Moovies Inc. confident it can make its name as well known as those of Blockbuster and other, larger competitors.</p>
<p>All video rental stores benefit more from the hits, and sometimes from the flops too, after Hollywood releases the flicks on videotape months later.</p>
<p>Anticipation of a strong year-and-a-half ahead could help Moovies carry out plans to make its logo Bubba the Cow as visible on the retail landscape as the blue-and-yellow neon ticket stub of industry leader Blockbuster, which is owned by Viacom Inc.</p>
<p>Through an aggressive acquistion strategy, Moovies executives have turned the company into the third-largest video retail operator and it is still growing.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a goal of doing 50 stores for all of 1996 and we've already done 16,&quot; Moovies President John Taylor said in a telephone interview from company headquarters in Greenville, S.C.</p>
<p>The expansion would boost the number of Moovies stores to 242, still well below its wealthier competitors. Fort Lauderdale, Fla.-based Blockbuster has nearly 2,800 stores nationwide, while Hollywood Entertainment Corp., based in Beaverton, Ore., has about 400.</p>
<p>Taylor said the new Moovies superstores -- carrying more than 10,000 tapes and about 5,000 titles -- will be in cities and towns where the company already has stores.</p>
<p>&quot;Our goal is to cluster stores. If we have an area where we have five stores already and we think that area can handle 15 of our stores, then we'll continue to open stores in that area until we max out,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Moovies stampeded onto the national scene when it raised $37 million in an August 1995 initial public offering and concurrently completed nine acquisitions -- giving Moovies a chain of 87 stores mainly along the East Coast.</p>
<p>Part of its marketing pitch has been &quot;Kids Rent Free&quot; and reservation programmes. Its logo of the smiling Bubba wearing 3-D shades is used with whimsical category titles, such as &quot;Moo-Dun-It&quot; for mysteries, to bolster its image as a family-oriented retailer. &quot;X&quot; rated movies are not sold.</p>
<p>Moovies stock has swung from a $23.25 high to a $7.50 low as the whole industry struggled last year through box-office &quot;misses&quot; that tend to slow consumer traffic, according to industry analyst Tom Thomson of Wheat First Butcher Singer.</p>
<p>The stock was trading off 12.5 cents at $9.125 Friday.</p>
<p>Thomson said weak film products plagued the whole industry, so earnings gains this year will be closely linked to sales at stores open at least a year, or same-store sales.</p>
<p>&quot;For the second half of this year we expect same-store sales trends to improve because of the very strong results at the box office,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Moovies is expected to earn $5.2 million, or 49 cents a share, on sales of $88 million this year, analysts said. That compares with restated 1995 income of $4.3 million, or 48 cents a share, on revenues of $67.8 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The hot movies of the spring and summer will show up at video stores in the third and fourth quarters of this year and the first quarter of next year,&quot; Thomson said.</p>
<p>Already touted to be the big winners: &quot;Independence Day,&quot; &quot;Courage Under Fire,&quot; and &quot;A Time to Kill.&quot;</p>
<p>A recent Census bureau report showed sales at video rental stores were $6.7 billion in 1994 compared to $6.5 billion at movie theatres -- a drastic turnaround from just three years prior when the video rental business was $5 billion and the movie house business was $6.2 billion.</p>
<p>Moovies had been concentrated on the East Coast until the acquisition in July of Premiere Video extended its reach into the midwestern states of Minnesota, Iowa, Wisconsin, South Dakota and Nebraska.</p>
<p>Taylor said the company's long-term goal was to be a &quot;national player&quot; and that a move to the West Coast would take place within three years, again via acquisition.</p>
<p>&quot;We generally don't like going into a larger area and creating new stores from the ground up,&quot; Taylor said, citing the need to leverage management staff and advertising money.</p>
<p>&quot;What we like to do is make an acquisition first to try to gain some market share and then sprinkle it with some new stores,&quot; he said of the West Coast expansion plan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHARLOTTE, N.C."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
