<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10489" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Digital TV firms lure couch potatoes onto Internet.</title>
<headline>Digital TV firms lure couch potatoes onto Internet.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's pay television giants, facing a wary public as digital TV services are launched, are hoping to lure couch potatoes into their brave new world by splashing the global Internet across ordinary TV screens.</p>
<p>Access to the Internet and commercial on-line services could become an important driver for the fledgling digital pay TV industry, which has been launched in Europe amid much fanfare but with a healthy dose of fear and trepidation.</p>
<p>It could also change the way people experience cyberspace, propelling activities such as multi-user games played across continents via the Internet to the forefront of interactive entertainment in the home, opening a still untapped market.</p>
<p>British satellite pay TV network BSkyB and Germany's Bertelsmann AG, separately announced plans on Friday for Internet access via digital decoders hooked up to TV sets.</p>
<p>The decoders are needed to convert digital signals to make it possible to view programming on TV sets.</p>
<p>&quot;The Internet and on-line services are on the best path to forcefully expand their user base and come out of the computer corner,&quot; Bertelsmann said in an invitation to a news conference to be held on Monday where it will detail its plans.</p>
<p>Digital pay TV has been launched in France and Germany and is about to begin in Britain. For now, it is only accessible via satellite and so is limited to households with satellite dishes.</p>
<p>Cybernauts now use modems to connect their computers to telephone lines to access the global Internet and the World Wide Web, the popular fast-growing portion of the computer network that offers snazzy graphics, animation and sound.</p>
<p>But in the United States, cable television operators and satellite networks are making plans to offer Internet access at greater band-width, or the speed at which data travels. The announcements by BSkyB and Bertelsmann mark the first moves in this direction by European companies.</p>
<p>In London, news of BSkyB's plans boosted that firm's shares. The stock market has been bullish on the company because of its digital TV alliance in Germany with Bavarian media mogul Leo Kirch, who launched the DF1 digital pay TV channel last month.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a logical extension of service considering the equipment and the band-width that they will have,&quot; said Robert Jolliffe, media analyst at ABN AMro Hoare Govett.</p>
<p>Industry analysts expect one of the most popular Internet applications over the TV set could be multi-user games. Even now, cyberkids from around the world crowd the Internet to play global matches of &quot;Risk&quot; and &quot;Dungeons and Dragons&quot;.</p>
<p>But analysts are increasingly sceptical that moving the Internet from the office to the living room will be successful.</p>
<p>Tim Hill, analyst with British technology consultants Inteco, said studies of what Inteco calls the &quot;interactive home&quot; market are not very promising.</p>
<p>&quot;What we have found in years of studying is that an awful lot of people are perfectly happy to be couch potatoes. They don't want to be interactive,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Inteco, which specialises in technology in the home and small office environment, has found that in most European countries well below 10 percent of people without computers would buy one in order to gain access to the Internet.</p>
<p>And Hill added that it was unlikely that people with computers would want to surf the Internet over their TV.</p>
<p>If that doesn't take the wind out of the sails of the digital TV industry, there is another problem.</p>
<p>Consumers will have to dig deep into their pockets to pay for digital decoders to view programming. In Germany, Kirch's &quot;D-Box&quot; decoder is selling for 888 marks ($596.1) and will only work in connection with a satellite dish, an additional cost.</p>
<p>Another wrinkle in Bertelsmann's plans: Deutsche Telekom's cable TV network has to be upgraded before it can offer access to the Internet or on-line services.</p>
<p>&quot;We are testing this in the laboratory. But this possibility doesn't exist now,&quot; a Telekom spokesman said. ($1=1.4895 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
