<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10515" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish press face cuts as headline profits sink.</title>
<headline>Swedish press face cuts as headline profits sink.</headline>
<byline>Belinda Goldsmith</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish newspapers were on Friday bemoaning a slump in profitability after Scandinavia's biggest publisher, Tidnings AB Marieberg, joined a list of papers cutting staff and jazzing up pages in an effort to survive.</p>
<p>Last year profits for Sweden's daily newspapers plummeted to a record low, mainly due to higher newsprint prices, and the woes are continuing in 1996.</p>
<p>The entry to the Stockholm market of a free newspaper, handed out daily to commuters, was adding to the burdens of the established players, stealing readers and advertising revenue.</p>
<p>Marieberg posted sharply lower results for the first six months of 1996, pointing the finger of blame at journalists' strikes, lower advertising revenue and higher newsprint costs.</p>
<p>&quot;The results reflect a weak trend of the economy, in Sweden and internationally, that has affected the newspapers' sales of advertising and the demand for (disposal tableware unit) Duni's products,&quot; chief executive Bengt Braun said in statement.</p>
<p>Marieberg, controlled by Swedish media family, the Bonniers, on Thursday posted a profit after financial items of 75 million crowns ($11.36 million) compared to 350 million crowns a year ago.</p>
<p>Operating income was slashed to 198 million crowns compared with 493 million in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>Its two major daily newspapers, the respected broadsheet Dagens Nyheter and tabloid Expressen, both reported lower results.</p>
<p>However income from its smaller regional papers, Sydsvenskan Dagbladet and Kvallsposten improved.</p>
<p>Marieberg also holds stakes in newspapers and media groups in Latvia, Finland, Poland and Norway.</p>
<p>But Braun said the company has started to restructure the group, which will include cutting 500 staff, equivalent to 20 percent of the workforce.</p>
<p>The group has developed a comprehensive restructuring programme that will be revealed this autumn and carry over until the end of 1997 to have an impact on earnings in 1998.</p>
<p>The plan may involve restructuring costs of about 350 million crowns that will be charged against 1996 income, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The annual costs in the newspaper operations, including the three printing plants, is estimated to decline by about 400 million crowns in part by reducing the number of employees by about 20 percent, or 500,&quot; Braun said.</p>
<p>But Marieberg's newspapers are not the only papers under threat.</p>
<p>Its national broadsheet rival, privately-owned Svenska Dagbladet, has also reshaped its pages in a move to retain readers.</p>
<p>The new threat that has appeared in the market over the past year, free newspaper Metro, has also put the papers on the defence.</p>
<p>Metro, owned by media to pulp conglomerate Kinnevik AB, is handed out to train commuters in Stocholm daily, and has won popularity by ensuring a good mix of news and entertainment information as well as adverts.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to now compete with them because they are so big,&quot; Dagens Nyheter's managing director Joachim Berner told Reuters.</p>
<p>($1=6.603 Swedish Crown)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SCAND">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
