<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10542" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFICAN GOVT TO FUND REVAMPED SABC - NAIDOO.</title>
<headline>S.AFICAN GOVT TO FUND REVAMPED SABC - NAIDOO.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The government will fund the South African Broadcasting Corporation (SABC) once its status as a national public broadcaster is confirmed in legislation, Posts and Telecommunications Minister Jay Naidoo said on Friday.</p>
<p>Naidoo told a news conference in Cape Town that legislation was being prepared to establish the SABC as a public broadcaster with specific obligations and guaranteed revenue sources.</p>
<p>&quot;It has to be a commitment to ongoing funding. The reality is that as the SABC assumes more and more the functions of a national broadcaster, its advertising revenue will fall,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The existing SABC is owned by the state, but has not received public funding for its domestic services for decades. The corporation operates on licence and advertising revenue.</p>
<p>The SABC reported last week that only 40 percent of viewers were paying licence fees, leading to a 600 million rand annual loss. The corporation said it faced a 56 million rand shortfall this year.</p>
<p>The Independent Broadcasting Authority set up after South Africa's 1994 transition from white rule to democracy is currently conducting hearings on the sale of six of the SABC's revenue-generating radio stations.</p>
<p>The sale is expected to net around 600 million rand, but Naidoo reaffirmed on Friday that the proceeds would go to the central government and not to the SABC.</p>
<p>&quot;The SABC can of course apply for some of the funds for specific projects,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Naidoo said a decision on buyers would be announced next month.</p>
<p>&quot;Particularly as we set up other private broadcasters...there is going to be a sharing of the revenue cake related to advertising, so the funding of the national public broadcaster really has to be in the context of its ongoing funding,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The new SABC would be obliged to serve the country's 11 official languages according to a specified formula and to offer distance-learning and other public services.</p>
<p>Naidoo said the government would demand accountability to parliament on the finances of the proposed public broadcaster, but said editorial control would remain exclusively in the hands of a board and the corporation's management.</p>
<p>He said he expected the country's first commercial television licence for terrestrial services to be awarded by July next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
