<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10555" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-MARTINEZ REACHES SEMIS BY BEATING TAUZIAT. [CORRECTED 5:39 GMT]</title>
<headline>TENNIS-MARTINEZ REACHES SEMIS BY BEATING TAUZIAT. [CORRECTED 5:39 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>CARLSBAD, California 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Defending champion and second seed Conchita Martinez of Spain beat Nathalie Tauziat of France 6-3 6-4 Thursday to advance to the semifinals of the $450,000 Toshiba Tennis Classic.</p>
<p>&quot;I played well almost the whole match,&quot; said Martinez, the 1994 Wimbledon champion. &quot;I felt pretty confident out there, so I'm pretty happy with the way I played.&quot;</p>
<p>Fifth seed Gabriela Sabatini of Argentina turned back Sweden's Asa Carlsson 6-1 7-5 while Katarina Studenikova surprised Slovakian compatriot and sixth (Corrects from seventh) seed Karina Habsudova 7-6 (7-4) 6-2, setting up a quarter-final clash with top-seeded Arantxa Sanchez Vicrio of Spain.</p>
<p>Martinez, ranked third in the world, was in control throughout the one hour, 17 minute baseline battle, relying on her heavy topspin ground attack to defeat her 26th-ranked opponent for the seventh time in nine career meetings.</p>
<p>&quot;I was much more aggressive than the other match,&quot; said Martinez, referring to a three-set tussle against Naoko Sawamatsu. &quot;She likes to come to the net, so I was trying to move her around with my forehand and keep it deep. It worked quite well today.&quot;</p>
<p>Sabatini struggled with her serve, committing seven double faults in each set, but still managed to make it into her second quarter-final of the year where she will meet fourth seed Kimiko Date of Japan on Friday.</p>
<p>Sabatini sailed through the opening set despite her errant serve.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not easy and somehow I have to stay calm,&quot; said Sabatini of the rash of double faults. &quot;I get too anxious with my serve and complicate things. It starts getting worse rather than calm. But I'm working on it.&quot;</p>
<p>In the second set, Carlsson began to find the mark with her baseline blasts, building a 5-3 lead. But Sabatini reeled off the next four games to close out the 77-minute straight-sets victory.</p>
<p>&quot;I wasn't happy with the way I played the second set,&quot; said Sabatini, who has fallen to a world 15th ranking following a four-month absence with a pulled stomach muscle. &quot;I really had to fight a lot and wasn't really able to play my game like I was in the first set.</p>
<p>&quot;She was attacking me very well. I was surprised the way she played. She went to the court with a a plan and that's what she did. I really had to fight.</p>
<p>&quot;But I just kept trying. I definitely didn't want to go to a third set. I knew that it was important to win it in two sets. So I just tried to play hard and play each point.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARLSBAD, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
