<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10552" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: MOTOR RACING-BERGER QUICKEST AS VILLENEUVE OUTPACES HILL.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-BERGER QUICKEST AS VILLENEUVE OUTPACES HILL.</headline>
<byline>Timothy Collings</byline>
<dateline>SPA-FRANCORCHAMPS, Belgium 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gerhard Berger, who started from pole position in a Ferrari for last year's Belgian Grand Prix, began this year's event in similar style by clocking the fastest time in Friday's opening practice session in his Benetton Renault.</p>
<p>The veteran Austrian, at 36 the oldest and longest-serving driver in the sport, showed his experience by outstripping all his younger rivals with a best lap of one minute 53.706 seconds on a dry surface at the long Spa-Francorchamps track in the Belgian Ardennes.</p>
<p>His time was faster than that with which he claimed pole position last season and was also the only lap inside the 1:54 barrier, proving that both he and the Renault-powered Benetton team are powerful contenders this weekend.</p>
<p>While Berger excelled in the warm weather, the two Williams drivers who are scrapping for the drivers' title -- leader Damon Hill of Britain and Canadian Jacques Villeneuve, who is 17 points behind  -- contented themselves with set-up and familiarisation work.</p>
<p>Hill, seeking the perfect race settings for Sunday's 44-lap showdown, was seventh fastest in 1:55.281 while Villeneuve, taking his first look at the circuit through the forests, was third in 1:54.443, separated from Berger by Briton David Coulthard's McLaren.</p>
<p>Double world champion Michael Schumacher, hoping for a revival of Ferrari's fortunes with their new seven-speed gearbox, finished eighth just behind Hill after recovering from an accident in the morning when he spun off at the fast downhill Fagnes corner.  </p>
<p>Berger said he was optimistic for the race, which had been expected to be a showdown between Hill and Villeneuve. &quot;We have done everything we wanted to and now we have the same aerodynamic set-up as for Hockenheim, which I believe makes the car more efficient.</p>
<p>&quot;I had a perfect lap to finish with, but this is no reason to relax. We want to stay ahead of the competition.&quot;</p>
<p>Villeneuve was delighted with his first look at the Spa circuit. &quot;It is not an easy track, it's tough to learn, but the car is pretty good. There are a lot of high speed turns that are very demanding, so it is fun.</p>
<p>&quot;I enjoy this type of track, you can really get into it. It is very smooth as if driving on water.&quot;</p>
<p>Hill, who said his relationship with Villeneuve was no more tense than it had been earlier in the season, was also delighted with the track. &quot;It is a tremendous and awe-inspiring circuit, there is no question that you have to put more faith into the machinery and your ability at a place like this than anywhere else.&quot; </p>
<p>Asked about his accident, Schumacher said: &quot;What happened is a real shame because the car was very good in the quick corners, to the extent that I could take Eau Rouge flat.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately, I made a mistake and I lost control of the car. When I hit the tyres, my right leg hit the steering wheel and broke it and that is how I hurt myself. Now I will put myself in the hands of my physiotherapist and tomorrow I plan to be back to normal.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SPA-FRANCORCHAMPS, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
