<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10559" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-WOODS ADVANCES TO QUARTER-FINALS AT U.S. AMATEUR.</title>
<headline>GOLF-WOODS ADVANCES TO QUARTER-FINALS AT U.S. AMATEUR.</headline>
<dateline>CORNELIUS, Oregon 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Twenty-year-old Tiger Woods beat Jerry Courville Jr 3 and 2, then defeated Charles Howell 3 and 1 Thursday to keep his quest alive for a third successive title in the U.S. Amateur Golf Championship.</p>
<p>Woods birdied three consecutive holes on the back nine to overcome a one-hole deficit and close out Courville.</p>
<p>Woods fell behind on the fourth hole when he bogeyed, but came back to even the match with a birdie on the eighth. He took the lead on the 12th when Courville conceded the hole after hitting into the water, and won the 13th and 14th holes with a par and a birdie.</p>
<p>Woods had a par on the 16th, but won the match when 37-year-old Courville, Woods's teammate on the 1995 Walker Cup team, bogeyed.</p>
<p>Woods is trying to become the first player to win three consecutive U.S. Amateur Championships. Prior to titles in 1994 and 1995, he captured three straight U.S. Junior Amateur crowns.</p>
<p>The quarter-finals are scheduled for Friday and the semifinals are Saturday. The semifinal winners will meet in the 36-hole final Sunday.</p>
<p>The winner of the U.S. Amateur receives a direct entry into next year's Masters and U.S. Open, if still an amateur.</p>
<p>Woods became the youngest U.S. Amateur champion in 1994 and edged Buddy Marruci last year in Newport, Rhode Island.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CORNELIUS, Oregon"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
