<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10572" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: TENNIS-AUSTRALIANS ADVANCE AT CANADIAN OPEN.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-AUSTRALIANS ADVANCE AT CANADIAN OPEN.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>It was Australia Day at the $2 million Canadian Open on Thursday as three Aussies reached the quarter-finals with straight-set victories.</p>
<p>Unseeded Patrick Rafter recorded the most noteworthy result as he upset sixth-seeded American MaliVai Washington 6-2 6-1 in just 50 minutes.</p>
<p>Todd Woodbridge, who defeated Canadian Daniel Nestor 7-6 (7-2) 7-6 (7-4), and Mark Philippoussis, a 6-3 6-4 winner over Bohdan Ulihrach of the Czech Republic, also advanced and will meet in Friday's quarter-finals.</p>
<p>Third-seeded Wayne Ferreira of South Africa defeated Tim Henman of Britain 6-4 6-4 after a three-hour evening rain delay and fifth-seeded Thomas Enqvist of Sweden won his third-round match, eliminating Petr Korda of the Czech Republic 6-3 6-4.</p>
<p>Ferreira and Enqvist play in a Friday night quarter-final.</p>
<p>Two Americans, seventh seed Todd Martin and unseeded Alex O'Brien, will meet on Friday after winning matches on Thursday. Martin overcame Cedric Pioline of France 2-6 6-2 6-4 and O'Brien beat Mikael Tillstrom of Sweden 6-3 2-6 6-3.</p>
<p>&quot;If you really look at the match,&quot; said the 12th-ranked Washington after losing to the 70th-ranked Rafter, &quot;I never really got a chance to play because he was serving big and getting in close to the net.</p>
<p>&quot;He was also able to handle my serve pretty easily because my (first) service percentage was only in the 40s. Put those two things together and you get a loss.&quot;</p>
<p>Rafter missed 10 weeks after wrist surgery earlier this year and the time away from tennis has given him a new perspective.</p>
<p>&quot;Before when I was on tour, I always felt I had to be in bed by 9:30 or 10 o'clock and I had to be up at a certain time,&quot; Rafter said. &quot;Now I can go to bed at at midnight or wake up at seven in the morning. I just don't have as many set routines and it's made me a happier person.&quot;</p>
<p>Martin was pleased with his victory over Pioline, his first in five meetings with the 11th-ranked Frenchman. &quot;It's always difficult to win a match when you lose the first set, especially against someone you have never beaten,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I got more aggressive in the second and third sets and the wind picked up and that also affected things because Cedric definitely went off a little bit.&quot;</p>
<p>The 26-year-old O'Brien, who won the ATP Tour stop in New Haven last week, has now won 18 of his last 20 matches, dating back to qualifying rounds in Los Angeles in late July. He ranks 76th after being 285th four weeks ago.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel I'm hitting the ball well even though I'm having more mental letdowns than I did last week,&quot; O'Brien said. &quot;But I'm still competing well.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I got a lot of first serves in,&quot; said Enqvist about his victory over Korda. &quot;I didn't miss that many shots and he was making the mistakes.&quot;</p>
<p>Still marvelling at an exciting 64-stroke rally he won in the last game of his second-round match against Javier Sanchez of Spain on Tuesday, Enqvist joked, &quot;Today against Petr there were about 64 strokes in the whole match. It was mostly short points.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
