<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10580" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-INJURED CHANDA RUBIN OUT OF U.S. OPEN.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-INJURED CHANDA RUBIN OUT OF U.S. OPEN.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Promising 10th-ranked American Chanda Rubin has pulled out of the U.S. Open Tennis Championships with a wrist injury, tournament officials announced.</p>
<p>The 20-year-old Rubin, who was to be seeded 11th, is still suffering from tendinitis of the right wrist that has kept her sidelined in recent months.</p>
<p>Rubin's misfortune turned into a very lucky break for eighth-seeded Olympic champion Lindsay Davenport.</p>
<p>Davenport had drawn one of the toughest first-round assignments of any of the seeded players in 17th-ranked Karina Habsudova of Slovakia.</p>
<p>But as the highest-ranked non-seeded player in the tournament, Habsudova will be moved into Rubin's slot in the draw, while Davenport will now get a qualifier in the first round, according to U.S. Tennis Association officials.</p>
<p>Rubin is the third notable withdrawal from the women's competition after 12th-ranked former Australian Open champion Mary Pierce and 20th-ranked Wimbledon semifinalist Meredith McGrath pulled out earlier this week with injuries.</p>
<p>Men's Australian Open champion Boris Becker will also miss the year's final Grand Slam with a wrist injury.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
