<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10606" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER-VOGTS KEEPS FAITH WITH EURO '96 CHAMPIONS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-VOGTS KEEPS FAITH WITH EURO '96 CHAMPIONS.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trainer Berti Vogts kept faith with his entire European championship winning squad for Germany's first match since their title victory, a friendly in Poland.</p>
<p>Vogts picked no new players for the squad for the September 4 game in Zabrze. Instead on Friday he nominated all 23 Euro '96 veterans including Bremen's Jens Todt, called up before the final by special UEFA dispensation.</p>
<p>He will, however, have to do without the Dortmund trio of libero Matthias Sammer, midfielder Steffen Freund and defender Rene Schneider, who were all formally nominated despite being injured.</p>
<p>&quot;This squad is currently the basis of my planning for the 1998 World Cup,&quot; Vogts said. &quot;We'll have to see which other players produce good league performances to play themselves into the squad.&quot;</p>
<p>Squad:</p>
<p>Goalkeepers - Oliver Kahn, Andreas Koepke, Oliver Reck</p>
<p>Defenders - Markus Babbel, Thomas Helmer, Juergen Kohler, Stefan Reuter, Matthias Sammer, Rene Schneider</p>
<p>Midfielders - Mario Basler, Marco Bode, Dieter Eilts, Steffen Freund, Thomas Haessler, Andreas Moeller, Mehmet Scholl, Thomas Strunz, Jens Todt, Christian Ziege</p>
<p>Forwards - Oliver Bierhoff, Fredi Bobic, Juergen Klinsmann, Stefan Kuntz.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
