<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10618" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: FALLING INFLATION, RATES PUSH ZIMBABWE SHARES UP.</title>
<headline>FALLING INFLATION, RATES PUSH ZIMBABWE SHARES UP.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Falling annual inflation and expectations of lower interest rates pushed Zimbabwean shares to new heights on Friday and brokers said they were looking at &quot;robust&quot; growth on the local bourse in coming weeks.</p>
<p>The key 57-counter industrial index rose 1.7 percent -- or 95.85 points -- to scale a new all time high of 5,675.17. This was a surge of 145.81 points on the week.</p>
<p>The brokers said a strike by the southern African country's civil servants over pay which entered its fourth day on Friday had yet to affect the stock market, warning that prolonged unrest was likely to generate negative sentiment.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was bullish in keeping with expectations in an environment where inflation and interest rates are coming down,&quot; one broker said, adding: &quot;We are looking at robust growth now.&quot;</p>
<p>Zimbabwe's year-on-year inflation slid to 22.0 percent in July from 28 percent in January, leading the Reserve Bank of Zimbabwe (RBZ) to lower its rediscount rate by two percentage points to 27.5 percent.</p>
<p>It had maintained the rate -- the benchmark rate at which it lends to financial institutions -- at 29.5 percent since November 1994 to fight resurgent inflation keeping borrowing rates high.</p>
<p>Leading gains on the stock market on Friday, bankers Barclays jumped 200 cents to 1,850, drawing 50,000 shares out of the market; blue-chip conglomerate Delta rose 50 cents to 2,700, local conglomerate TA Holdings added 13 cents to 120 while Zimpapers put on 10 cents to 610.</p>
<p>Chemical manufacturer Chloride at 65, transport group Clan at 145 and tobacco group TSL at 360 all traded five cents up while a special bargain was struck in hotel chain Zimsun with 1.5 million shares changing hands from an external seller at 340 cents.</p>
<p>Minings closed the week a touch firmer although trade was dull. Gold producer Wankie climbed 300 cents to 14,500 and Wankie Colliery added five cents to 305, pushing the seven-share mining index 22.51 points to 1,274.66 -- a rise of 25.40 points on the week.</p>
<p>-- melia Sithole, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
