<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10616" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICAN PARTIAL GUNS BAN EXPECTED NEXT WEEK.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICAN PARTIAL GUNS BAN EXPECTED NEXT WEEK.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The South African government plans to issue a promised ban on guns at public meetings as part of a package to curb gang-related violence, a spokesman said on Friday.</p>
<p>Maxwell Mulaudzi said legal experts would spend the weekend drafting a proclamation in terms of a law allowing policing minister Sydney Mufamadi to impose the ban in specific parts of the country.</p>
<p>&quot;The minister plans to implement the ban in the Western Cape (province) and he is contemplating KwaZulu-Natal as well. If the text is ready on Monday, the ban will go into force next week,&quot; Mulaudzi told Reuters.</p>
<p>Mufamadi on Thursday announced a series of measures agreed in consultation with police and other ministers and said parliament would be asked to reschedule its programme later this year to adopt legislation necessary to implement the package.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't see that there is any way the legislation can be brought to parliament before October, but we will move heaven and earth to get it through as quickly as possible,&quot; said Douglas Gibson, a Democratic Party member of parliament's scheduling committee.</p>
<p>Mufamadi spearheaded the drafting of a crackdown on violence following clashes in Cape Town between drug-dealing gangsters and the Moslem-based vigilante movement People Against Gangsterism and Drugs (PAGAD).</p>
<p>PAGAD supporters recently burned and shot a drug baron to death and militant anti-crime campaigners armed with handguns, shotguns and automatic rifles have marched repeatedly since then, threatening to kill drug dealers.</p>
<p>Police in riot-control vehicles prevented an armed crowd from approaching the home of an alleged drug-dealer early on Friday.</p>
<p>Mufamadi's plans include:</p>
<p>- minimum sentences for gang-related crime</p>
<p>- a new &quot;super-maximum&quot; category of prison security to prevent breakouts and keep gangsters away from other criminals</p>
<p>- tougher parole measures to ensure that prisoners serve at least two-thirds of sentences for serious or gang-related crimes</p>
<p>- measures to limit contact between gangs in society and in prisons, which are the main recruiting ground for gangs</p>
<p>- a crackdown on police corruption, including measures to encourage &quot;whistle-blowers&quot; to inform on corrupt colleagues</p>
<p>- special units to supervise investigations into gang-related crime and to evaluate unsolved gang-related investigations</p>
<p>- measures to speed up prosecutions and to protect witnesses</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
