<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10612" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: CRICKET-SRI LANKA AND AUSTRALIA SAY RELATIONS HAVE HEALED.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-SRI LANKA AND AUSTRALIA SAY RELATIONS HAVE HEALED.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lanka and Australia agreed on Friday that relations between the two teams had healed since the Sri Lankans' acrimonious tour last year.</p>
<p>The Sri Lankans were first found guilty then cleared of ball tampering and off-spinner Muttiah Muralitharan was called for throwing during a controversial three-test series in Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;Our concern is to get out there and play proper cricket,&quot; Sri Lanka captain Arjuna Ranatunga told a news conference on the eve of a warmup match between the World Cup champions and a World XI team scheduled for Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;What happened is history.&quot;</p>
<p>Australian team manager Cam Battersby said he agreed with Ranatunga.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe relations between the two teams will be excellent,&quot; Batterby said.</p>
<p>The Australians are making their first visit to the Indian Ocean island since boycotting a World Cup fixture in February after a terrorist bomb in Colombo.</p>
<p>Australia have been promised the presence of commandos, sniffer dogs and plainclothes policemen to ensure a limited overs tournament is trouble-free. The tournament, starting on August 26, also includes India and Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>Battersby said he was satisfied with the security arrangements.</p>
<p>Sri Lankan officials said they expected heavy rain which washed out a warmup match on Friday should cease by Saturday.</p>
<p>Australia, led by wicketkeeper Ian Healy, opened their short tour of Sri Lanka with a five-run win over the country's youth team on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
