<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10617" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICAN RAND/BONDS CLOSING REPORT.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICAN RAND/BONDS CLOSING REPORT.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>After striding firmer at a brisk Friday market opening, the rand crept back in the afternoon to end only slightly firmer.</p>
<p>At the finish, the currency was pegged at 4.5400/5450 against the dollar from 4.5520/5570 on Thursday and after touching a day's best level of 4.5210 earlier in the day.</p>
<p>The day kicked off with widespread dollar selling, mainly by offshore players liquidating stale long positions, although some long local players were also believed to have offloaded.</p>
<p>&quot;There was selling out of New York and London overnight which carried through to this morning,&quot; a dealer said. Others said there had been selling out of Singapore and Zurich.</p>
<p>The initial flurry of selling helped the rand firmer before some profit-taking took it briefly back up to just below the 4.54 level shortly before the official opening.</p>
<p>After 0700 GMT, the currency steadily gained ground on further dollar selling before reaching its day's best level by about 0840 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;It's basically been a shake out of stale longs,&quot; one trader said. &quot;If you went long 10 days ago...the cost of carrying those positions means that the rand has to depreciate for them to be profitable.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the fact that the rand had been stable recently meant they had to sell their dollars in order to stop losses.</p>
<p>The afternoon session descended into torpor as the initial wave of dollar selling ebbed.</p>
<p>Dealers said the rand's strength attracted importers -- particularly oil companies looking to cover their petrol imports -- into the market, which took the currency back to the 4.54 level at the close.</p>
<p>They said there were prospects for further gains on Monday with U.K. players out of the market for a bank holiday. A test of the 4.51 level was possible, one said.</p>
<p>Against the crosses, the rand was last at 7.0514/0614 on sterling from 7.0454/0577 on Thursday and at 0.3272/3277 marks from 0.3279/3284 marks previously.</p>
<p>Bond yields -- enthused by the rand's gains -- moved sharply lower in the morning, breaking a key chart level at 15.60 percent before meeting stiff resistance at the 15.50 percent level.</p>
<p>Dealers said initial gains were driven by offshore demand, although locals had also been buying.</p>
<p>One trader, noted, however, that the key R150 continued to hold a 15.50 to 15.70 percent range in place for the last two weeks.</p>
<p>At the finish, the R150 was pegged at 15.555 percent from 15.68 percent on Thursday, while Eskom's 168 was at 15.690 percent from 15.82 percent previously.</p>
<p>Bond Exchange figures showed foreigners were net sellers of 77.09 million rand of South African bonds on Thursday after selling 79.42 million rand on Wednesday. Nominal cumulative volumes were pegged at 4.39 billion rand from 4.48 billion rand.</p>
<p>On the money market, three-month NCDs eased to between 16.65 and 16.85 percent from 16.75 and 16.90 percent, while 90-day BAs were also lower at between 16.10 to 16.20 percent from 16.15 to 16.30 percent.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank said the money market shortage rose to 8.527 billion rand on Thursday from 8.171 billion rand on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Paul Richardson, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
