<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10624" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: PRESS DIGEST - ZIMBABWE - AUGUST 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - ZIMBABWE - AUGUST 23.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Zimbabwe press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE ZIMBABWE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>- State resources in excess of an estimated Z$2 million were used at Zimbabwean President Robert Mugabe's wedding to his former secretary Grace Marufu last weekend despite assurances that the function was a private occasion which would funded from Mugabe's own resources, sources told the Zimbabwe Independent.</p>
<p>- President Robert Mugabe and his bride, Grace, were this week spotted taking a break in Cape Town, South Africa, after their weekend wedding.</p>
<p>- With consumer inflation slowing half a point in July to 22 percent -- its lowest level in a year -- market analysts seem satisfied that, at last, Zimbabwe's inflation cycle has turned, Antony Hawkins, professor of business studies at the University of Zimbabwe reported in an article commissioned by Reuters.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE HERALD</p>
<p>- Public Service, Labour and Social Services Minister Florence Chitauro said on Thursdqy negotiations to resolve a salary dispute with striking civil servants will only start after the workers have gone back to work. Zimbabwe's civil servants defied an earlier ultimatum from Chitauro to go back to work or face dismissal and also ignored calls by their union leaders to stop the strike on Thursday.</p>
<p>- Zimbabwean President Robert Mugabe will attend the annual summit of the 12-nation Southern African Development Community to be held in the Lesotho capital, Maseru, at the weekend, the ministry of foreign affairs said on Thursday.</p>
<p>- Zimbabwe's High Court on Thursday ordered Harare town clerk Edward Kanengoni to step down as returning officer for forthcoming mayoral elections, saying he could be biased against an independent contestant due to his ties with the ruling ZANU-PF party.</p>
<p>-- Emelia Sithole, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 28/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
