<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10625" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - SOUTH AFRICA - AUGUST 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - SOUTH AFRICA - AUGUST 23.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Friday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- Correctional services minister Sipho Mzimela has announced plans to tighten the parole system and to build high-security &quot;super maximum&quot; prisons for dangerous criminals in response to high crime levels.</p>
<p>- First National Bank Holdings Ltd managing director Barry Swart apologised on Thursday night for embarrasing the bank, following his censure by the board for awarding a decorating contract to his daughter.</p>
<p>- Retail group Wooltru Ltd lifted earnings including exceptional items 11 percent to 398.3 million rand for the year to June, restrained by losses in its mainstay Massmart operation and the closure of fledgling retail chain Number 1.</p>
<p>- The ANC's claim that the bombing of Magoo's bar in Durban and Church Street in Pretoria were attacks aimed at military targets raises the possibility that they were sanctioned at high levels within the organisation.</p>
<p>- Southern African ministers decided on Thursday to destroy about 200,000 cattle infected with highly contagious bovine lung disease in Namibia, Botswana and Tanzania.</p>
<p>- Drastic changes to South Africa's higher education system, intended to create places for an additional 700,000 students within nine years and put all institutions on an equal footing, were proposed by the national commission on higher education.</p>
<p>- The South African Broadcasting Corporation warned that its fledgling satellite television service AstraSat could miss the December target set for its pay service launch.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- Chris Stals, the Reserve Bank governor, has contradicted claims made by banking officials and money market dealers this week that commercial banks were &quot;round tripping&quot; at the Reserve Bank.</p>
<p>- Wooltru, the diversified retail company, weathered the downswing in consumer spending and divisional losses to post an 11 percent rise in taxed profit to 399 million in the year to June 30.</p>
<p>- Sappi Ltd , the pulp and paper company, is at the centre of a scandal which could shut down its industrial cellulose plant along the south coast of KwaZulu Natal.</p>
<p>- The Nel commission has rejected the Policy Board for Financial Services and Regulation's recommendation that financial advisors should regulate themselves, fuelling the battle over who should regulate the financial services industry.</p>
<p>- OfficeMart creditors may receive only between 11 cents and 15 cents on the rand if the cession of a loan by its parent company, Mathieson and Ashley Holdings Ltd , to Nedbank is valid, sources close to the company said.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- The police slapping of subpoenas on journalists on at least seven publications and news agencies, to compel them to reveal information, has sparked an outcry among the media fraternity who said it smacked of the harsh 1980s.</p>
<p>- The picture is still far from complete. But the readiness of major political parties to account for their actions in public this week was unprecedented anywhere in the world, Truth and Reconciliation chairman Alex Boraine said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
