<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10637" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: ROMANIA HOPES GOOD 1997 WHEAT CROP, SEES EXPORT.</title>
<headline>ROMANIA HOPES GOOD 1997 WHEAT CROP, SEES EXPORT.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Dascalu</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania, which saw its grain export plans ruined by bad weather this year, will put some 2.3 million hectares under wheat for the 1997 crop amid hopes of re-emerging as a major player on the world grain market.</p>
<p>&quot;Some might say it's too early for projections, but theoretically we can get over seven million tonnes of wheat in 1997,&quot; a senior agriculture ministry official said.</p>
<p>Last year the Balkan country had 2.11 million hectares sown to wheat but an early winter and late snow damaged the crop on almost half that area and Romania harvested a record low of 3.1 million tonnes, some 60 percent down the 1995 level.</p>
<p>&quot;We might count on some 2.0 million tonnes of wheat for export,&quot; said the official, who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>The poor 1996 wheat output, enough to meet only domestic consumption and refresh state reserves, checked Romania's hopes of hard currency earnings from the world grain market.</p>
<p>Last year Romania harvested a bumper wheat crop of 7.8 million tonnes and sold over 1.3 million tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;I doubt we will have another bad winter this year, so I count on an average minimum wheat yield of 3,000 kilograms per hectare,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our records show harsh winters like we've just had might happen once in 15 years or so. However, we must rush now to complete ploughing and sowing as soon as possible. This is the right time to sow next year's wheat crop,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Government sources said the cabinet was expected to approve &quot;within days&quot; subsidised loans worth 1.22 trillion lei for the farming sector, to ensure smooth farm works this autumn.</p>
<p>The government had decided on a 60-per-cent subsidy of the interests on those credits given by merchant banks, they said.</p>
<p>Average lending rate is 57 pecent.</p>
<p>However, reports in the local media over the past weeks said the farming sector was confronted with a series of problems, including an acute shortage of fuel and high prices for seasonal farming works.</p>
<p>Failure of some private and state-run farms to secure credits because of outstanding payments would also add to the problems, the reports said.</p>
<p>Agriculture Ministry data show costs of preparing one hectare for wheat, including purchase of fertlisers and seeds, come to some 530,000 lei.</p>
<p>The ministry has set the purchasing price for wheat at 430,000 lei a tonne. -- Bucharest Newsromm 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
