<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10632" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: ROMANIA APPROVES FRIENDSHIP TREATY WITH HUNGARY.</title>
<headline>ROMANIA APPROVES FRIENDSHIP TREATY WITH HUNGARY.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Romanian government on Friday approved a treaty ending longstanding disputes with neighbouring Hungary and it is ready for signing, Foreign Minister Teodor Melescanu said.</p>
<p>He said the accord, essential for both countries' ambitions to join NATO and the European Union, could be signed in the first half of September.</p>
<p>&quot;The opportunity for finalising the treaty resulted from a compromise by both sides and I really don't see any obstacles which might prevent the Romanian and Hungarian parliaments ratifying it,&quot; Melescanu told a news conference.</p>
<p>Hungarian and Romanian experts met for two days this week in Budapest to put finishing touches to the treaty. Four years in the making, the pact was long delayed by disputes over minority rights for Hungarians in Romania.</p>
<p>The leftist government of the Party of Social Democracy (PDSR) accepted the text at a cabinet meeting on Friday, said Melescanu, and ministers from nationalist coalition partner, the Romanian National Unity Party (PUNR), did not object.</p>
<p>&quot;All ministers agreed the treaty should be signed as early as possible,&quot; said Melescanu, rejecting press reports that the PUNR would try to block the treaty.</p>
<p>PUNR leader Gheorghe Funar has asked for a referendum on the historic deal. In turn PDSR chiefs have threatened to kick his party out of the ruling coalition if it is obstructive.</p>
<p>Hungary said on Wednesday it was set to sign the accord, despite criticism from opposition parties and ethnic Hungarian politicians in Romania.</p>
<p>There are 1.6 million Hungarians in Romania, some seven percent of the population.</p>
<p>Hungary had sought ethnic autonomy for its kinfolk, which Bucharest rejected, mindful of Hungary's long rule over what is now central Romania and fearing a Yugoslav-style secession.</p>
<p>A deal was struck after Bucharest included a Council of Europe-approved clause on minority rights which Budapest then acknowledged did not grant Hungarians collective privileges.</p>
<p>Melescanu said he hoped the treaty would be the starting point in a process of reconciliation between the two countries, which have strengthened commercial and military links since the 1989 fall of communism despite sporadic political bickering. REUTER  231557 GMT aug 96</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
