<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10630" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: PRESS DIGEST - RUSSIA - AUG 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - RUSSIA - AUG 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>IZVESTIA</p>
<p>- President Boris Yeltsin is dissatisfied with the performance of his security adviser Alexander Lebed in charge of tackling the Chechen crisis.</p>
<p>- A state tax accountant in the Southern Russian city of Volgograd tricked the department where she was working out of 24 million roubles ($5,000).</p>
<p>PRAVDA</p>
<p>- For the first time in the last five years a communist has entered the government.</p>
<p>SEVODNYA</p>
<p>- President Boris Yeltsin is either too sure of himself or is concerned by matters other than politics to have let Alexander Lebed play it solo in the Chechen crisis.</p>
<p>- The new government gives the impression of a team which will play a common game but by different rules.</p>
<p>- Russia's inflation takes on negative values as the budget deficit is being turned into debt.</p>
<p>NEZAVISIMAYA GAZETA</p>
<p>- President Yeltsin shortly goes for treatment to a special heart clinic outside Moscow where two high-tech wards have been set up for him, says the paper, quoting a source in the medical centre.</p>
<p>ROSSIISKAYA GAZETA</p>
<p>- It is high time Russian generals stopped sending angry warnings to each other and started to work together.</p>
<p>MOSKOVSKY KOMSOMOLETS</p>
<p>- Russia suffered its worst defeat in two years of the Chechen war when it lost Grozny to the rebels and Alexander Lebed went there in person to sign a document of capitulation.</p>
<p>--Andrei Shukshin, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
