<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10641" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: HUNGARY'S MHB TO TAP FOREIGN MARKETS FOR $50 MLN.</title>
<headline>HUNGARY'S MHB TO TAP FOREIGN MARKETS FOR $50 MLN.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's Magyar Hitel Bank Rt (MHB) said on Friday that it signed an agreement today to take out a $50 million loan from a banking consortium led by Fuji Bank Ltd , Credit Suisse and Union Bank of Switzerland .</p>
<p>&quot;MHB wishes to expand the mid-term loans it gives to its corporate clients and to step up its competitiveness in mid-term financing,&quot; MHB said in a statement.</p>
<p>The five-year loan which bears interest of 0.9 percentage points above LIBOR, is to be repaid in one instalment, it said.</p>
<p>The amount was oversubscribed by $36 million, MHB said, but added that the amount it finally tapped was according to its original business plans.</p>
<p>The lending conditions were finalised before MHB mandated the banks on May 23 to organise the syndicate and they were thus not influenced by expectations of MHB's privatisation.</p>
<p>The Hungarian government decided to offer an 89 percent stake in MHB to strategic investors and intends to complete the sale by the end of the year.</p>
<p>The other members of the consortium are Bank Austria, GiroCredit Bank , Creditanstalt Bankverien, Bayerische Vereinsbank AG , Bankgesellschaft Berlin AG , Bayerische Landesbank Girozentrale , DG Bank, Landesbank Schleswig Holstein Girozentrale, Sumitomo Bank Ltd, Banque Francaise du Commerce Exterieur, Unibank A/S and Banca Monte dei Paschi di Siena SpA.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
