<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10657" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada bonds end weaker on U.S. data, spreads fall.</title>
<headline>Canada bonds end weaker on U.S. data, spreads fall.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian bonds closed weaker on Friday, but outperformed their U.S. counterparts, following the release of stronger-than-expected U.S. durable goods orders for July, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;You've got a little bit of growth there. The market's expecting the (U.S.) economy to roll over and play dead. Well, it's not playing dead,&quot; said Dan Kelly, a fixed-income analyst with CIBC Wood Gundy Securities.</p>
<p>Canada's 8.0 percent bond due 2023 fell C$0.65 to C$102.55 to yield 7.771 percent. The U.S. 30-year benchmark fell 1-12/32 to yield 6.95 percent.  </p>
<p>The spread between the bonds narrowed to 82 basis points from 89 basis points at the close of trading on Thursday.</p>
<p>U.S. and Canadian bonds started the session weaker following the release of stronger-than-expected U.S. July durable goods orders. Orders rose 1.6 percent, compared with forecasts of a 0.3 percent rise.</p>
<p>Spreads between Canadian and U.S. benchmark bonds narrowed in part because fundamentals for bonds remain more positive in Canada, analysts said. Among Canada's postive fundamentals are an inflation rate which is about half the U.S. rate.  </p>
<p>&quot;I do believe spreads will narrow further,&quot; said CIBC's Kelly.</p>
<p>In other prices, the 7.0 percent of 2006 fell C$0.58 to C$97.77 to yield 7.311 percent. The U.S. 10-year benchmark fell 31/32 to yield 6.75 percent.</p>
<p>The spread between the two bonds narrowed to 56 basis points from 63 basis points at Thursday's close.</p>
<p>The three-month cash bill traded at 4.03 percent against the U.S. three-month bill at 5.18 percent.</p>
<p>-- Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
