<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10652" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Commonwealth trip to Nigeria off for now - Canada.</title>
<headline>Commonwealth trip to Nigeria off for now - Canada.</headline>
<byline>Randall Palmer</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Commonwealth ministers concerned about human rights in Nigeria have cancelled a planned trip there because of government restrictions on their mission, the Canadian government said on Friday.</p>
<p>Ministers had planned to visit the Nigerian capital Abuja on Aug. 29-30, but only if they could talk to private groups and individuals in addition to government officials.</p>
<p>&quot;Following the failure of Nigeria to agree to the Commonwealth Ministerial Action Group's conditions for its planned visit to Nigeria at the end of this month, CMAG foreign ministers have decided that the visit should not go forward at this time,&quot; a Foreign Ministry statement said.</p>
<p>Foreign ministers of the British Commonwealth, which suspended Nigeria because of concerns about democracy and alleged human rights abuses, will meet in London on Wednesday to discuss what to do, he told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of members were counting on this (mission) being a great breakthrough. It doesn't look like it's going to be that way,&quot; Foreign Minister Lloyd Axworthy told an earlier news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;So it may be that we'll have to now consider collective action,&quot; he said, noting the impact from action taken by African states against Burundi.</p>
<p>A group of African states imposed sanctions against Burundi in response to the July 25 coup that overthrew the government of elected Hutu President Sylvestre Ntibantunganya and installed Major Pierre Buyoya .</p>
<p>The Nigerian foreign ministry issued a statement on Thursday saying the visit should not be construed as a fact-finding mission.</p>
<p>One of the incidents which sparked the international outcry against Nigeria was the execution last November of author Ken Saro-Wiwa and eight other minority rights activists on charges of murder.</p>
<p>His brother called on Canada in an Ottawa news conference on Thursday to urge fellow Commonwealth nations to impose an oil embargo on the country, Africa's most populous nation.</p>
<p>Axworthy said that in any case Canada was moving ahead with its own measures.</p>
<p>He said, for example, that Christine Stewart, the junior minister who was to have gone to Nigeria, has been working with Canadian oil companies on a voluntary code of conduct regarding Nigeria.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="COMWH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
