<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10663" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian banks poised for higher Q3 profits.</title>
<headline>Canadian banks poised for higher Q3 profits.</headline>
<byline>Darren Schuettler</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's six biggest banks are poised for a further round of buoyant profits when they begin reporting third-quarter earnings on Tuesday.</p>
<p>An improved interest rate picture, higher investment banking and dealing revenues and better loan quality are expected to drive profits in the third quarter ended July 31.</p>
<p>On average, earnings for the so-called Big Six are expected to be 15 percent to 20 percent higher than the third quarter of last year, analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I would expect more sectors of the banks to be more profitable than they were in the corresponding quarter of last year,&quot; Roy Palmer, an analyst with TD Securities, said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Bank of Montreal and Bank of Nova Scotia, Canada's third and fourth largest banks respectively, kick off the earnings parade on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Canada's fifth-biggest bank, Toronto-Dominion Bank, and the smallest, National Bank of Canada, report on Thursday.  </p>
<p>The country's top two banks, Royal Bank of Canada and Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce, are scheduled to deliver their results on Thursday, September 5.</p>
<p>Despite a recent downturn in financial markets, analysts said securities earnings should be stronger than last year. Canada's brokerage industry is dominated by subsidiaries of the countries major banks.</p>
<p>The banks are also expected to benefit from lower loan losses as the industry continues to rebound from disastrous loans in commercial real estate, which collapsed in the late 1980s.  </p>
<p>Despite the correction in stocks earlier this summer, bank stocks have remained strong performers. Lower Canadian interest rates have helped push bank stock prices to all-time highs on the Toronto Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that if the combination of strong profitability couples up with lower interest rates, then it probably will set the backdrop for higher share prices,&quot; said Susan Cohen, an analyst with Deacon Capital Corp.</p>
<p>Analysts said they do not expect any of the banks to raise their dividends during the reporting period.  </p>
<p>But the string of record bank profits are expected to yield dividend hikes at the end of the fiscal year.</p>
<p>The big banks are on track for a third straight year if record annual profits. The group rang up a combined profit of C$5.17 billion in fiscal 1995 ended October 31, up from C$4.25 billion a year earlier.</p>
<p>As for 1997, Palmer said he expects a modest increase in profits.  </p>
<p>&quot;Investment banking is a cyclical business. It may tail off a bit, but there is no sign of a recession yet, so I would think we could get modestly higher earnings next year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bank of Montreal is expected to report a third-quarter profit of C$0.97 per share, up from C$0.93 per share a year ago, according to figures supplied by the International Brokers Estimates Service.</p>
<p>Scotiabank's earnings are seen climbing to C$1 per share in the third quarter, up from C$0.86 a share.  </p>
<p>Toronto-Dominion Bank is expected to post a C$0.72 per share profit, up slightly from C$0.71 per share in the third quarter of 1995.</p>
<p>National Bank's third quarter earnings are forecast to rise to C$0.41 per share from C$0.33 a share a year earlier.</p>
<p>CIBC's third quarter results are pegged at C$1.42 a share compared to last year's C$1.13 per share.</p>
<p>Royal Bank of Canada is seen improving to C$0.96 a share in the third quarter, up from C$0.88 per share a year earlier.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
