<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10678" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RESEARCH ALERT - CRA Managed rated hold.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - CRA Managed rated hold.</headline>
<text>
<p>-- Dain Bosworth said Friday it initiated coverage of CRA Managed Care Inc with a hold rating.</p>
<p>-- Dain said CRA, a specialty managed-care services company focusing on cost containment for workers' compensation, has above-average potential for earnings growth. It also cited a diversifying revenue base and likely margin expansion.</p>
<p>-- It added that CRA shares have been trading recently at 36.1 times its 1996 earnings estimate of $1.17 a share.</p>
<p>-- CRA shares on Friday rose 3/8 at 42-5/8.  </p>
<p>-- &quot;While we believe the premiums to be deserved for (CRA) shares, current levels are significant in the midst of a period of nervous investor sentiment on the broad group of managed-care stocks in general, suggesting some potential for price volatility,&quot; Dain said in a report.</p>
<p>-- Dain said investors should use declines in the stock price for buying opportunities.</p>
<p>-- &quot;Should the company deliver new sales substantially ahead of estimates, bring in a series of major account sales enabled by its new (preferred provider organization) ownership, or achieve an acceleration of growth in its auto-injury managed care business, these events would also lend us to be more aggressive on new positions,&quot; Dain said.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
