<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10674" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Federal oversight, litigation woes descend on Big Tobacco.</title>
<headline>Federal oversight, litigation woes descend on Big Tobacco.</headline>
<byline>Christian Thompson</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>The tobacco industry defended assaults on two fronts Friday, as President Clinton formally approved new federal oversight measures regulating tobacco while an Indiana jury deliberated in the latest tobacco injury suit.</p>
<p>In a Rose Garden ceremony at the White House, Clinton called the regulation of tobacco as a drug an &quot;historic action&quot; aimed at protecting children from exposure to the smoking habit.</p>
<p>The new rules, which give the Food and Drug Administration authority over tobacco, include requiring proof of age to purchase cigarettes, a ban on cigarette sales through vending machines in areas accessible to teenagers, and a ban on tobacco advertising within 1,000 yards of schools.</p>
<p>The rules also mandate anti-smoking education by tobacco companies aimed at the country's youth.</p>
<p>The tobacco industry lashed out at the regulations. Philip Morris Cos. Inc., the world's largest tobacco company, called the moves in Washington a &quot;specious and arbitrary interpretation of federal law&quot; and said only Congress has the authority to give the FDA regulatory authority over tobacco.</p>
<p>&quot;The FDA's rule sets the stage for restrictions that could lead the agency to do even more to deprive adults of their rights by unilaterally forcing the prohibition of cigarettes,&quot; said Steven Parrish, senior vice president of Philip Morris U.S.A.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, an Indiana jury deliberated for a second day in the case brought by Yvonne Rogers against Philip Morris, RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp.'s R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co., and other tobacco companies.</p>
<p>The case, brought on behalf of Rogers' husband Richard, contends the industry was at fault for selling addictive products that cause cancer. Richard Rogers died of cancer in 1987 at the age of 52 after taking up smoking as a child.</p>
<p>If the jury decides against the industry, it would be the second courtroom loss for the tobacco industry in two weeks and would mark the emergence of a monumental shift in tobacco litigation.</p>
<p>On Aug. 9, a Florida jury awarded $750,000 to Grady Carter and his wife in their personal-injury suit against Brown &amp; Williamson Tobacco Corp., the former employer of researcher-turned-whistleblower Jeffrey Wigand.</p>
<p>Although the sum was a drop in the bucket for the $45 billion-a-year industry, it represented only the second time an award was granted by a jury.</p>
<p>Brown &amp; Williamson is a subsidiary of U.K.-based B.A.T Industries Plc.</p>
<p>If that verdict is upheld on appeal, it would be the first time a tobacco company has been found liable for its product, something that has eluded attorneys trying to establish class-action suits against the industry.</p>
<p>With the disclosure of a litany of internal documents from tobacco companies that undermine their historical assertions of innocence, juries are more likely to find cigarette makers culpable for the injuries their products caused, legal experts say.</p>
<p>If the new federal regulations withstand the court battles the tobacco industry has threatened in response, it would be the most sweeping challenge to the industry's freedom since the 1964 Surgeon General's report and federally mandated cigarette warning labels that followed.</p>
<p>Wall Street, which has recently pummeled tobacco stocks, showed little reaction to Friday's developments. Shares of Philip Morris rose $1.25 to $88 in late trading on the New York Stock Exchange, while RJR Nabisco was up 37.5 cents at $25.50, also on the NYSE.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
