<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10702" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. crudes weaken into Sept pipeline nominations.</title>
<headline>U.S. crudes weaken into Sept pipeline nominations.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. crudes weakened broadly on outrights and domestic grades as demand slipped upon the completion of September pipeline nominations.</p>
<p>The reopening of three major Mexican crude export ports also accelerated the market's bearish downtrend, casting more pressure on the near-term market facing higher imports.</p>
<p>The Atlantic arbitrage opened the window to North Sea Gullfaks, Oseberg and even Russian Urals this week, which exerted weight on domestic October grades.</p>
<p>Oct West Texas Intermediate/Cushing was down 30 cents at $21.90-22.00, while the Sep/Oct roll held at 25-30 cents.  </p>
<p>Late Friday afternoon, the remainder of September pipeline requirements were covered but in thin volume and lower prices.</p>
<p>September West Texas Intermediate/Midland fell to minus 20 cents under WTI, down from parity yesterday.</p>
<p>Light Louisiana Sweet/St. James was sold at minus 2 cents to WTI/Cushing, but the parcel was extremely small.</p>
<p>Heavy, sour prices pull backed more dramatically partly with the reopening of Mexican ports, especially Eugene Island.</p>
<p>West Texas Sour/Midland was heard done at minus $1.55 to WTI/Cushing, but Eugene Island dropped to minus $1.60, down from minus $1.25 traded mid-week.</p>
<p>Lacklustre margins and weaker gasoline prices are expected to rein in refinery demand.</p>
<p>Rumours of run cuts in the U.S. Gulf also kept buyers on the sides, although many were doubtful these were because of poor margins.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't believe refiners will cut runs with stocks this low. It's probably turnarounds,&quot; an East Coast trader said, adding that people were trying to keep crude prices afloat.</p>
<p>--Jacqueline Wong, New York Energy Desk, +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
