<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10705" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US late prods fall as NYMEX changes direction.</title>
<headline>US late prods fall as NYMEX changes direction.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot products fell moderately by late Friday as NYMEX futures pulled back from Thursday gains and New York gasoline differentials continued to ease amid stronger imports, players said.</p>
<p>New York Harbor conventional unleaded M2-grade gasoline fell about 0.85 cent a gallon, with bids about 3.00 cents below September futures --about 0.30 cent weaker than Thursday diffs, players said.</p>
<p>And diffs slipped about 0.20 cent on NYH reformulated A2-grade material, traders said, with bids at about 0.40 cent above the print.</p>
<p>Players said at least 13 cargoes from Europe and South America were expected to begin reaching East Coast markets starting Friday, exerting downward pressure on diffs.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the cargoes are already placed with majors, which means they won't be buying as much,&quot; one East Coast trader said, speculating prices could continue softening in the next week.</p>
<p>Heating oil fell about a half cent tracking futures in both centers, players said, with differentials holding steady.</p>
<p>On Thursday, higher NYMEX values had lifted distillates 1.50 cents a gallon and pushed New York Harbor conventional unleaded gasoline 0.60 cent higher despite weaker diffs.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody can figure out how the Merc (NYMEX) is making up its mind,&quot; one frustrated East Coast trader said, noting that NYMEX prices this week have alternated day-to-day between strongly higher and sharply lower values.</p>
<p>-- Ransdell Pierson, New York Energy Desk 212 859-1632</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
