<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10713" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Prudential to reply to allegations Sept. 9.</title>
<headline>U.S. Prudential to reply to allegations Sept. 9.</headline>
<dateline>NEWARK, N.J. 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Attorneys for Prudential Insurance Co of America are scheduled to appear in the U.S. District Court in Newark on September 9 to answer allegations the company destroyed documents that would be damaging to it in its upcoming court battles, court papers showed.</p>
<p>A 1000 EDT (1400 GMT) hearing is tentatively scheduled before Judge Alfred Wolin in federal court to allow Prudential to answer the latest series of charges.</p>
<p>Four former Prudential employees have filed affidavits, swearing that they observed &quot;continuous and wholesale destruction by the management of sales and marketing information.&quot;  </p>
<p>Prudential said any such violation would be a violation of company policy. &quot;We take the issue of destruction of documents very seriously,&quot; a Prudential spokesman said. &quot;It is not condoned by any company policy.&quot;</p>
<p>Prudential said it plans to respond in court to the specific allegations.</p>
<p>The spokesman noted that Prudential last week fired senior vice president David Fastenberg for failing to enforce company directives about preserving documents.  </p>
<p>A company investigation found that files from its Greater Southern Regional Office in Jacksonville, Fla. were discarded in a reorganization and relocation of staff to New Jersey between April and June 1996.</p>
<p>Fastenberg on Thursday filed a lawsuit in state Superior Court in Morristown, N.J., charging defamation and unlawful discharge. Fastenberg denied destroying company documents.</p>
<p>Fastenberg said he was out of town on Prudential business when a secretary allegedly threw out company records at his Jacksonville office.  </p>
<p>A task force of U.S. insurance regulators last month recommended a record $35 million fine against Prudential for improper sales practices.</p>
<p>The task force's action came in response to complaints that Prudential had improperly pressured unsophisticated investors into replacing their life insurance policies to generate commissions.</p>
<p>Prudential has agreed to implement a remediation program. Prudential also launched a new sales process in June and last year hired a top regulator with the National Association of Securities Dealers to head up its compliance functions.</p>
<p>In his affidavit, Thomas Cerchia, one of the former Prudential agents who left the firm after 13 years as an agent in Lake Success, New York, said the company &quot;has engaged in  an elaborate, management-directed attempt to cover up evidence of corrupt sales practices.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEWARK, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
