<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10723" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed July bias no surprise, but next move unclear.</title>
<headline>Fed July bias no surprise, but next move unclear.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Reserve's decision to put in place a mechanism for raising short-term U.S. interest rates in between policy meetings came as no surprise to Wall Street economists, but experts said the central bank's next move on rates remains unclear.</p>
<p>Minutes from the July 2-3 Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting were released by the New York Fed late Friday.</p>
<p>The minutes showed the central bank opted for a so-called &quot;asymmetrical directive&quot; with a bias toward tightening.  </p>
<p>Under normal circumstances, that would mean Fed policymakers had given Fed Chairman Alan Greenspan the power to raise rates unilaterally in between policy-making meetings.</p>
<p>However, the minutes indicated members of the Committee agreed to &quot;consult in some way&quot; before proceeding with any inter-meeting tightening of monetary policy.</p>
<p>&quot;If anybody is surprised that they had a tightening bias, I'm amazed,&quot; said Josh Stiles, senior bond strategist at consulting firm I.D.E.A. Inc.  </p>
<p>&quot;That's no surprise,&quot; echoed Josh Feinman, an economist at BT Securities Corp. &quot;The important thing to remember is that their heads were tilted toward tightening ... No one should mistake where their heads (still) are.&quot;</p>
<p>Feinman suggested the Fed could raise rates if economic growth continues to percolate, but others took a more cautious stance, indicating even more compelling evidence of vibrant growth was necessary.  </p>
<p>&quot;What we saw after the July meeting was (economic) moderation,&quot; said Carol Stone, senior economist at Nomura Securities International Inc. &quot;I think the Fed is probably in good stead to wait again.&quot;</p>
<p>In holding rates steady in July, experts said the Fed was betting the economy would slow from its rapid pace of growth registered in the second quarter. But policymakers clearly recognized the economic risks were to the upside.</p>
<p>In its first estimate of second quarter Gross Domestic Product growth, the Commerce Department said the economy was expanding at a robust 4.2-percent pace.  </p>
<p>And after the FOMC's decision to hold rates steady in July, a strong June payroll employment report called that policy choice into question.</p>
<p>Still, weeks later policymakers were hailed as soothsayers when July data showed a slackening in the labor market and weakness in manufacturing.</p>
<p>More recently, on Friday the government said orders for big-ticket items rose a bigger-than-expected 1.6 percent in July, or more than five times economists' forecasts.</p>
<p>The rise in orders for durable goods, coupled with expectations the jobs market is again exploding in August, prompted some experts to wonder if talk of a Fed rate hike will again start to swirl.</p>
<p>&quot;Where I came down on these durable goods this morning, is yes, they looked strong, but durables are so erratic that you have to wait for confirmation that that sector is strengthening,&quot; noted Stone.</p>
<p>-- Jacqueline Hurlock and Noah Barkin, 212-859-1660</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
