<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10728" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries end down sharply on growth fears.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries end down sharply on growth fears.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries ended sharply lower on Friday after news of strong midsummer orders for durable goods lent weight to investors' worries that the economy was not decelerating promptly enough to keep the Federal Reserve from raising interest rates.</p>
<p>The fear of higher rates or impending inflationary pressures drove the 30-year bond down 1-13/32 to 97-14/32 and its yield up to 6.95 percent, its highest closing level since July 31. The last bit of ground was lost in late trade after the Fed revealed it had adopted a tightening bias in July.  </p>
<p>&quot;The (+1.6 percent) durable goods number crystallized our fears earlier in the week that the economy isn't slowing to a more sustainable pace,&quot; said Chris Rupkey, vice president and economist at Bank of Tokyo/Mitsubishi.</p>
<p>&quot;Back on July 18 when (Fed Chairman Alan) Greenspan said growth would slow to a more sustainable pace, that kicked off a six-point rally,&quot; Rupkey said. &quot;Today the trendline on that rally reversed itself and that sparked a lot of selling.&quot;</p>
<p>The stronger-than-expected July durable goods report &quot;triggered stop-loss and hedge fund selling that led to steep losses,&quot; said analysts at MMS International.  </p>
<p>&quot;The demand side figures (on the economy) have been very strong in the last two weeks,&quot; said Rupkey. &quot;It started with the Redbook (weekly department and chain store sales report) bouncing back in August.&quot;</p>
<p>Weeks of subdued jobless claims have also kept investors worried that a strong labor market would lead to demand for higher -- and potentially inflationary -- wages.</p>
<p>&quot;People definitely are afraid of an August payroll (growth) number above 300,000 (new jobs),&quot; said Rupkey.</p>
<p>A Reuters poll of 21 economists found the average forecast for August non-farm payroll growth to be 238,000 jobs.  </p>
<p>&quot;But the market fears 300,000 to 350,000,&quot; said Rupkey.</p>
<p>&quot;The strong durable goods report set the tone for the day and the market deteriorated,&quot; said Marilyn Schaja, money market economist at Donaldson, Lufkin &amp; Jenrette.</p>
<p>Schaja said all aspects of the orders data were strong. Non-defense and non-aircraft industry related orders rose 3.6 percent following a 2.5 percent rise in June, she observed.</p>
<p>&quot;The data begged the question of whether the Fed has to tighten again,&quot; said Schaja. The Fed last raised interest rates on February 1, 1995.  </p>
<p>When bond prices were already down sharply in late trade, the Fed released the minutes of its July Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting. The minutes confirmed the opinion that the central bank's policymakers had adopted a bias toward tightening at its July 2-3 meeting, voting 11-1 to hold interest rates steady with a tightening bias. They recorded that several FOMC members also said that the tightening bias did not signify a commitment to tighten and they cited &quot;substantial uncertainty&quot; on the inflation outlook.</p>
<p>Prices retreated further after the FOMC minutes were released and ended at their lowest levels of the day.  </p>
<p>On its way down, the market finally overcame stabilizing trades related to the quarterly options expiration, market analysts said.</p>
<p>The 10-year note ended at 101-24/32, down 31/32, to yield 6.75 percent.</p>
<p>At the short end of the maturity range, three- and six-month bill rates rose five and seven basis points, respectively, to 5.05 percent and 5.14 percent.</p>
<p>The 6-1/4 percent two-year note ended at 100-7/32, down 8/32 to yield 6.12 percent.</p>
<p>On a when-issued basis, the $18.75 billion in two-year Treasury notes to be auctioned next week on August 27 also yielded 6.12 percent at the close.</p>
<p>In the intermediate sector, five-year notes ended at 100-13/32, down 20/32, to yield 6.53 percent.</p>
<p>The $12.5 billion in five-year notes to be sold on August 28 were offering a when-issued yield of 6.5075 percent.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1679</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
