<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10727" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dlr finishes lower in U.S., back below 1.48 marks.</title>
<headline>Dlr finishes lower in U.S., back below 1.48 marks.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar finished weaker against most major currencies, pressured by growing dissatisfaction with its failure to sustain a rally even after a large cut in the German repo rate, experts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is very disappointed with the reaction of the dollar yesterday after the Bundesbank move,&quot; said Chris Iggo, an international economist at Barclays Bank Plc. &quot;Most people would have thought that the dollar should have gone higher after the larger-than-expected cut in the repo rate.&quot;</p>
<p>On Thursday, the Bundesbank had lowered its repo rate to 3.0 percent, a historic low.  </p>
<p>Many traders had expected the Bundesbank to only lower the rate by 10 or 15 basis points, but instead, the central bank knocked off 30 basis points.</p>
<p>The dollar closed at 1.4775/85 marks, down from 1.4876/79 at the open.</p>
<p>The dollar fell to 108.10/20 yen from 108.40/50 and to 1.1925/35 Swiss francs from 1.2044/51 at the open.</p>
<p>Losses accelerated after stop loss sell orders were triggered when the dollar fell below 1.20 francs first and then below 1.48 marks, experts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;People are basically selling their long dollar positions against the mark, and against the Swiss, they're initiating short dollar positions,&quot; said David Durrant, a senior currency strategist at I.D.E.A. Inc, a consulting firm. &quot;So, you're getting a double-barreled effect here.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar declines occurred in typically slow summer volume, experts said. Therefore, currency traders were careful not to read too much into the trend.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very thin Friday afternoon market, and it's very vulnerable to exaggerated moves,&quot; said Adam Adelman, a trader at Banque Paribas.  </p>
<p>With the Buba repo rate cut behind it, the foreign exchange market faces the release of Japan's quarterly &quot;Tankan&quot; survey sometime next week along with the revision to second-quarter real U.S. gross domestic product (GDP) on Thursday at 0830 EDT/1230 GMT.</p>
<p>U.S. economists polled by Reuters, on average, expect the GDP revision to come in at 4.2 percent, unchanged from the first estimate.</p>
<p>In other trade, the dollar closed at Canadian $1.3705/10, slightly above C$1.3700/05 at the open. Sterling rose to US$1.5562/69 from US$1.5535/45.  </p>
<p>The Australian dollar closed at $0.7912/17.</p>
<p>-- Donna Sells 212-859-1668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
