<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10739" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: LDC debts lurch lower with U.S. Treasuries.</title>
<headline>LDC debts lurch lower with U.S. Treasuries.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Emerging market debt prices followed declining U.S. Treasuries to trade mostly lower, ending the week on a downbeat.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was quite lethargic,&quot; said a Brady bond trader. Weak Treasuries triggered selling among dealers, but customer business was light, he said.</p>
<p>U.S. Treasuries were battered by report of a strong 1.6 percent rise of durable goods orders in July. The benchmark 30-year T-bond fell more than one point to yield 6.93 percent.  </p>
<p>As in the past, the par bonds bore most of the brunt. The Bradies as a whole still held well, and outperformed the Treasuries on the week.</p>
<p>Bradies have so far outperformed the Treasuries on the week, even accounting the Friday's losses, the trader said.</p>
<p>Mexico managed to buck the trend, with good gains in Discount and Aztec.</p>
<p>Mexico 2008 gained 1-5/8 to 98-7/8, after rising steadily this week on evidences of Mexico's economic recovery.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is less volatile than the pars and discounts,&quot; said Ingrid Iverson, Brady bond strategist at UBS Securities, noting that the Aztec bond was attractive because of its short duration and large collateral.</p>
<p>Mexico Pars eased 1/8 to 67-1/2 while Discount rose 1/2 to 81-5/8.</p>
<p>With the unpopular fiscal package in Congress, Argentina papers continued to underperform.</p>
<p>Argentina Pars fell 3/8 54-1/4 but FRBs were unchanged.  </p>
<p>Ecuador debts were mixed after Petroecuador reached a prelimary agreement with Argentina's largest energy company YPF over the operations of its Maxus subsidiary in Ecuador.</p>
<p>Ecuador Pars fell 1/4 to 37-1/4 but Discounts rose 1/4 to 57-3/4.</p>
<p>Among East European papers, Poland was strong as traders seized the upgrade of Polish Bradies by the U.S. National Association of Insurance Commissioners.</p>
<p>A NAIC official said Poland's sovereign debt was upgraded from three to two (on the scale of five) with one being the highest) in mid-August.  </p>
<p>Poland's long-term foreign currency sovereign debt is rated Baa3 by Moody's and triple B minus by S&amp;P.</p>
<p>With two U.S. major rating agencies already conferring investment grade on Poland's sovereign debt, the Bradies have limited upside before the next upgrade, said a Brady trader. But Iverson of UBS said that even short of being elevated single A, the spreads of Poland's Bradies could narrow by 25 to 50 basis points.</p>
<p>Poland Pars added 1/8 to 54-1/2 and Discounts climbed 1/4 to 95-1/4.</p>
<p>-- Nailene Chou Wiest, 212-859-1674</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
