<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10737" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW-CDW sees direct marketing growth.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-CDW sees direct marketing growth.</headline>
<byline>Susan Nadeau</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>CDW Computer Centers Inc said Friday it saw further growth in direct marketing of personal computers and would keep its focus on business customers.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the direct market channel is still gaining market share over the overall PC industry, and this is a multi, multi billion dollar market,&quot; CDW chief financial officer Harry Harczak said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;We take advantage of growth in the PC market as well as the growth in the channel, because people are still converting to the direct market channel for purchasing,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Mail order is becoming more widely accepted among business customers, as they become more familiar with computers and know what they want to buy, he said. And manufacturers are making equipment easier to set up and service.</p>
<p>&quot;The name-brand manufacturers have began to look to direct marketing as a necessary channel of distribution to grow their business,&quot; Harczak said. CDW began offering Compaq notebook computers in November 1995, for example.</p>
<p>Harczak said the Buffalo Grove, Ill.-based company does not plan to target home users. Businesses currently make up more than 70 percent of CDW's client base.  </p>
<p>&quot;The stock has been a rocket,&quot; said John Larson, an analyst for GS2 Securities. &quot;The last two quarters have surpassed by wide margins Street expectations, and this year they have dramatically increased catalog mailings.&quot;</p>
<p>Shares of CDW rose 3-3/8 at 66 in Nasdaq trading Friday. Within the past year, it has risen from a low of 22-1/2.</p>
<p>Harczak said CDW has improved its marketing and catalog distribution techniques, learning more about its customers while providing further training to its sales staff.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the things we've done is remained focused on what has gotten us to this point, and that is direct marketing of name brands,&quot; Harczak said.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
