<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10736" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natgas futures end with modest short covering gain.</title>
<headline>Natgas futures end with modest short covering gain.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures ended higher across the board Friday in a moderate session, lifted by a steady wave of pre-weekend short covering amid concerns about Tropical Storm Edouard, industry sources said.</p>
<p>September climbed 2.9 cents to close at $1.95 per million British thermal units. October settled 2.4 cents higher at $2.023. Other deferreds ended up by 2.8 to three cents.</p>
<p>&quot;There was some heavy buying on the close that got absorbed, which looked pretty bearish, but there's still some uncertainty over (Tropical Storm) Edouard,&quot; said one East Coast trader, noting cash has been better offered this week.  </p>
<p>At 1100 EDT, Edouard was 1,500 miles east of the Lesser Antilles, moving west at 15 mph with winds of about 70 mph. Despite Friday's modest rebound, most expected forecasts for mild weather through next week to keep the cash on the defensive as bidweek gets underway Monday.</p>
<p>Technically, traders still pegged support in October at Thursday's $1.975 low and resistance in the low-teens.</p>
<p>U.S. Gulf Coast weekend cash prices slipped another five cents Friday to the low-to-mid $1.90s. Midcon pipes were down a similar amount to the mid-$1.70s.</p>
<p>The 12-month strip firmed 3.2 cents to $2.107. NYMEX said 38,464 Henry Hub contracts traded, down from Thursday's revised tally of 60,485.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Henry Hub natgas futures expire Monday, August 26.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Permian natgas closed up two cents at $1.69, while deferreds settled steady to 1.5 cents higher but remained untraded. NYMEX said 42 Permian contracts traded, down from Thursday's total of 64.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Permian natgas futures expire Wednesday August 28.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, September finished down 0.4 cent at $1.766, while deferreds ended steady to 1.5 cents lower. The East/West spread widened by 3.3 cents to 18.4 cents (NYMEX premium). KCBT said 297 lots traded, down from Thursday's 564.</p>
<p>KCBT September natgas futures expire Tuesday, August 27.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
