<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10746" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. foreign crude activity light, Urals deal seen.</title>
<headline>U.S. foreign crude activity light, Urals deal seen.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. foreign crudes remained only moderately busy Friday, well below normal levels, though some talk was generated for mid-to-late September arrivals.</p>
<p>A major U.S. trade house was heard selling a cargo of Russian Urals to its own refining arm, for late September delivery to the U.S. Gulf. Prices were not known.</p>
<p>A Latin America trader was also heard shopping an August 28-30 Urals cargo for late September delivery into Cuba.</p>
<p>A crude broker said the timing of the Urals cargo into the U.S. Gulf was highly unusual.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's not out of the question to have the Urals shipped over, just the timing,&quot; said the broker.</p>
<p>Other talk in the foreign market had Oseberg offered for September 25-30 around 5 cents over October West Texas Intermediate/Cushing.</p>
<p>Brent cargoes were offered at 10-15 cents under October WTI for the same late September delivery.</p>
<p>&quot;The talk is still very expensive for end September. There aren't as many deals because of the high prices, at least compared to last month,&quot; said a trader.  </p>
<p>North Sea cargoes were also being talked up, with a Hydra cargo heard coming over in late September.</p>
<p>In the U.S. aftermarket, traders said a number of partial paper cargoes were dealt at firmer levels.</p>
<p>A major U.S. trade house was the big buyer in the window, takingup 350 lots of October Brent at $20.50, and a smaller 100 lot slice at $20.55. Brent Sep/Oct was sold at 48 cents, traders said.</p>
<p>--Patrick Connole, New York Energy Desk, +1 212 858 1828</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
