<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10758" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oldest Titanic survivor sets sail for site.</title>
<headline>Oldest Titanic survivor sets sail for site.</headline>
<byline>Hagar Scher</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>At age 99, Edith Haisman has seen plenty and lived through a lot. But the oldest living survivor of the Titanic disaster cannot bring herself to look over the side of a ship, even 84 years after the tragedy.</p>
<p>Haisman was packed and ready to set sail on Friday on board a cruise ship to visit the site of the sunken ship and witness efforts to pull a giant slab of its hull from the bottom of the Atlantic Ocean.</p>
<p>The fragile great-great-grandmother, who travels in a wheelchair and is accompanied on her journey by daughter Dorothy Kendle, planned to throw a wreath into the ocean in honor of her father, one of 1,500 people who died in the April 14, 1912, tragedy.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know what she'll feel until we get there,&quot; said Kendle, who acts as her mother's spokeswoman. &quot;But I do know she won't look over the side of the boat. She never does.&quot;</p>
<p>Haisman, just 16 at the time the Titanic struck an iceberg and sank, survived by climbing on board a lifeboat. Her father was never found.</p>
<p>&quot;She's finally laying him to rest,&quot; said Kendle of her mother, who lives in a nursing home in Southampton, England.</p>
<p>The &quot;Titanic Recovery Cruise&quot; has been organized by RMS Titanic Inc., a New York-based company that has the exclusive rights to retrieve artifacts from the sunken ship. One of the excursion's ships was setting sail from New York on Friday, the other was scheduled to depart from Boston on Sunday.</p>
<p>More than 1,700 passengers, including Princess Elletra Marconi, granddaughter of the inventor of the wireless radio that transmitted the first-ever SOS when the 882-foot (268-metre) long Titanic was sinking, are paying $1,500 and upwards to participate.</p>
<p>Heisman and two other survivors, 88-year-old Michel Navratil, a retired professor from France, and Eleanor Shuman, an 86-year-old Illinois resident, are the guests of honor.</p>
<p>The nine-day cruise will feature Titanic-related film screenings and lectures and an exhibit of artifacts since the shipwreck was discovered in 1985, such as dishes, corked bottles of champagne and portholes. Chefs even plan to cook up dishes served on the original trip.</p>
<p>On Aug. 28, passengers will witness the first attempt to raise part of the sunken ship, coordinated by France's oceanographic institute, INFREMER.</p>
<p>RMS Titanic hopes to use the recovered 20-tonne slab of the hull as the centerpiece of an exhibition next spring. The company is also in discussions to establish a fully-fledged Titanic museum.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to create a visible and tangible perception of the ship in an enlightening and dignified manner that respects those who perished,&quot; said RMS spokeswoman Alexandra Foley.</p>
<p>Some experts, however, voice skepticism about the company's motives.</p>
<p>&quot;It is as if a fleet of tractors had plowed the battlefield of Gettysburg,&quot; Robert Ballard, one of the scientists who discovered the wreck, told the newspaper USA Today. &quot;It's scarred the site for many years to come.&quot;</p>
<p>Company representatives point to scientific evidence that the remaining ship debris could be completely absorbed by microorganisms in as little as two decades from now.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to think about a hundred years from now,&quot; said Foley. &quot;This story is part of our global consciousness.&quot;</p>
<p>One of the excursion's most avid supporters is William MacQuitty, producer of the acclaimed Titanic movie, &quot;A Night to Remember.&quot; He too will be a guest aboard the cruise ship.</p>
<p>Belfast-born MacQuitty, 91, has devoted his life to immortalizing the story of the doomed cruise liner.</p>
<p>&quot;When I came to New York in 1958 with my movie, nobody went to see it because there were no stars in it,&quot; he said. &quot;I had to explain the ship was the star.&quot;</p>
<p>Now the danger is overkill. In November, CBS will air a four-hour mini-series entitled &quot;Titanic,&quot; and next summer 20th Century Fox plans to release a $100 million epic on the ship.</p>
<p>The U.S.-based cable Discovery Channel, NBC television network and Britain's Channel Four all plan to release documentaries about the recovery mission.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
