<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10752" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chateau says no decision on merger offers.</title>
<headline>Chateau says no decision on merger offers.</headline>
<byline>Susan Nadeau</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chateau Properties Inc said Friday it is still considering proposals to acquire the company, but the board of directors may not reconvene until after the Labor Day holiday to make the decision.</p>
<p>&quot;It really is going to depend on how long it takes advisors to get their recommendations together,&quot; said Chateau chief financial officer Tamara Fischer.</p>
<p>&quot;We left it open,&quot; Fischer said. &quot;The board will reconvene as soon as our advisors let us know. I'm not certain it will be next week. It may be after Labor Day.&quot;  </p>
<p>Chateau, which develops and operates prefabricated home communities, in July signed a definitive agreement to merge with Colorado-based ROC Communities Inc.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, it received unsolicitied acquisistion offers from both Manufactured Home Communities Inc and Sun Communities Inc.</p>
<p>Fischer said to cancel the ROC agreement, Chateau would have to pay a break-up fee. She said she did not know the exact fee, though it is a &quot;customary&quot; amount and a percentage of the value of the deal.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's not a small number,&quot; Fischer said. &quot;It's a customary fee and it's designed to keep people from walking away.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said the fee, however, would likely not be the deciding factor. Kevin Comer, an analyst for BT Securities Corp, said break-up fees typically range from one-half to one percent, which would work out to about $2 million to $5 million in this case.</p>
<p>Chateau, based in Clinton Township, Mich., in July agreed to merge with ROC to form a new company, with stockholders receiving 1.042 shares per ROC share or one share per Chateau share.  </p>
<p>On Monday MHC, led by investor Samuel Zell, offered $26 in cash or 1.15 MHC shares per Chateau share or operating partnership unit, or a combinantion of stock and cash.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Sun said it was prepared to give 0.892 of a share of Sun's common stock for each Chateau share or unit.</p>
<p>Fischer said the two proposals were a surprise.</p>
<p>&quot;Our legal counsel is evaluating and helping the board understand what their responsibilities are,&quot; she said. &quot;This is extremely complicated and I would hate for anyone to think this is an easy process.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts were split on which offer the board would choose.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the deal with Sun looks a little more attractive even though it's a lower price because of the overlap of properties, potential for cost savings and complementary skill sets,&quot; said analyst William Acheson of Smith Barney. &quot;It would be a bigger overall portfolio.&quot;</p>
<p>But BT's Comer said he sees the MHC and Chateau portfolios meshing better.</p>
<p>&quot;If I were putting my money, I would probably bet with MHC,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010022">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8500031">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
