<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10763" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS / Bay Networks calls.</title>
<headline>U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS / Bay Networks calls.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bay Networks Inc calls attracted broad-based speculative bids amid growing optimism over the firm's share price, traders said.</p>
<p>September calls with strike prices of 25.0, 27.5 and 30.0 were the most active contracts on the Chicago Board Options Exchange (CBOE), with the 27.5 call trading 6,764 contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's mostly speculation,&quot; said Peter Najarian of Mercury Trading, designated primary market maker for Bay Networks options at CBOE. &quot;The stock has been beaten up to a level where...I think people finally decided it was overdone.&quot;  </p>
<p>The stock was up 1-7/8 on the day to 27-1/8. It had tumbled to a low of 20-1/4 on July 24 from a high of 43-3/8 on February 29.</p>
<p>Traders agreed that Bay Network was one of the few stocks that stood out with sizeable gains amid a generally subdued market today.</p>
<p>&quot;What we have seen a little bit of lately is a pick-up in some of the speculative activity,&quot; said Rod Jamieson, vice president of option strategy at EVEREN Securities. &quot;And this one looks like another speculation.&quot;  </p>
<p>He noted that all strikes near the at-the-money level in September, October and December had large total volume, without any inflation by huge institutional orders.</p>
<p>Implied volatilities for September calls have spiked up towards 60 percent from the mid-40s area.</p>
<p>There was vague talk of a big brokerage firm upgrading the stock, but traders were unsure what the optimism was based on.</p>
<p>One trader said it was probably one of bottom-picking plays seen from time to time in battered technology shares like Micron Technology Inc, Iomega Corp.  </p>
<p>Thursday's sharp run-up in Zenith Electronics Corp might have inspired such interest, he said.</p>
<p>Najarian added that there was good interest in selling puts, reflecting the growing bullishness.</p>
<p>He dismissed possibilities of takeover-related buying.</p>
<p>&quot;There's always speculation on companies like Bay Net,&quot; he said. &quot;From a standpoint of takeover, however, as big a company as they are, it's going to take quite a large company to try to take over. So I think those rumors are false.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Shin Kishima/Chicago Derivatives Desk (312) 408-8750</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302019">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
