<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10773" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US CREDIT OUTLOOK - Supply, data and technicals.</title>
<headline>US CREDIT OUTLOOK - Supply, data and technicals.</headline>
<byline>Jose Paulo Vicente</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. credit market players will be focusing on three points next week to give Treasuries a new trend: supply, fresh data and technicals, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will be looking for cues to live through the week until we actually get the key August employment report (on September 6),&quot; said a trader at a primary dealership.</p>
<p>Early in the week, monthly fresh supply will take center stage. The Treasury will offer the market $18.75 billion in two-year notes and $12.5 billion in five-year securities on Tuesday and Wednesday, respectively.  </p>
<p>Demand for the securities is seen uncertain, mainly after some hedge and mutual fund managers decided to dump part of their Treasuries holdings back into the market last week.</p>
<p>Players have grown wary after the sharp sell-off over the last few sessions, which brought the T-bond yield up to a three-week-plus high and resurrected some talk of a possible monetary policy tightening as soon as September.</p>
<p>Analysts said retailers are still seen mostly out of the market, adding that dealers could end up being the ones underwriting the new issues.  </p>
<p>&quot;Retailers are mostly out ... It looks like dealers might have to jump in again and buy some papers at next week's auctions,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the market's technical outlook deteriorated over the last sessions, with the cash T-bond at a 6.93 percent yield and the September futures contract at 109-17/32 in late trade on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The technical outlook for Treasuries is getting bleak primarily because we've now traded back into the old trading range,&quot; said Patrick Dimick, economist at C.S. First Boston.  </p>
<p>Dimick said the market now appears to have rejected the early August uptrade that followed the release of the National Association of Purchasing Management (NAPM) index and the employment report for the month of July.</p>
<p>Both indicators were then viewed as positive for bonds.</p>
<p>Some analysts said, however, rates are well below levels registered at the last two-year auction and some technical charts still see an oversold potential for market.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want to get all super bearish after we just sold off sharply for two days in a row,&quot; said Josh Stiles, senior bond strategist at I.D.E.A. Inc.  </p>
<p>&quot;Technicals are saying there is an oversold condition potential for a little bounce,&quot; Stiles added.</p>
<p>The two-year notes were trading around 6.09 percent in late when-issued trading on Friday. The two-year securities were placed at 6.28 percent at last month's sale.</p>
<p>&quot;And at the time people though the Fed was going to tighten in August,&quot; the I.D.E.A. strategist said.</p>
<p>Stiles added the numbers show many market players still believe in the Federal Reserve's expectations of an economic slowdown in the third quarter.  </p>
<p>On the fresh data front next week, the highlights include July existing home sales, August consumer confidence, weekly jobless claims, July personal income and July factory orders.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Fed refrained from open market operations.</p>
<p>Federal funds are seen opening at 5.25 percent on Monday, in line with the Fed's target for the rate.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
