<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10771" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Outboard Marine getting to know Greenway.</title>
<headline>Outboard Marine getting to know Greenway.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Drawbaugh</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Outboard Marine Corp chief executive Harry Bowman talked Thursday with the principals of Greenway Partners -- Alfred Kingsley and Gary Duberstein -- who have bought an 8.5-percent stake for nearly $30 million in the manufacturer of boats and boat engines.</p>
<p>&quot;It was really just a get-acquainted call,&quot; said Stan Main, spokesman for Outboard Marine, or OMC.</p>
<p>If Waukegan, Ill.-based OMC is anything like some other companies that Greenway has invested in, Bowman may soon get to know Kingsley and Duberstein very well indeed.  </p>
<p>Former associates of Carl Icahn, the two New York financiers specialize in buying shares in companies that are struggling, then pressuring managements for changes.</p>
<p>OMC does not know Greenway's intentions, Main said. He added, &quot;All you can look at is their track record.&quot;</p>
<p>Known as a highly active shareholder, Greenway has sought a three-way break-up of Unisys Corp, the spin-off by Woolworth Corp of its profitable Footlocker division, and helped cause the 1994 sale of U.S. Shoe Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not bashful,&quot; Kingsley said in an interview, confirming that he has had one chat with OMC.  </p>
<p>The topic of discussion on the call was &quot;the company and its operations,&quot; Kingsley said. He added, &quot;We might have more conversations with them.&quot;</p>
<p>Of particular interest, Kingsley said, is OMC's new FICHT fuel injection technology, which the company said can reduce hydrocarbon emissions of two-stroke engines by 70-80 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;It's true that for emissions standards, they have to do something. But I think that they've got an interesting engine here with other applications, in addition to the outboard motor area,&quot; Kingsley said.  </p>
<p>Asked if Greenway was happy with OMC's financial performance, Kingsley said, &quot;The company's probably not satisfied with their performance.&quot;</p>
<p>OMC has made that quite clear in recent quarters and is taking steps to fix the situation, Main said. &quot;There is a plan being developed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Investors have been waiting for improvements at OMC, but are beginning to lose patience, said Lehman Brothers analyst Harriet Baldwin. &quot;It's likely Greenway's effect will be to bring more focus on management,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>OMC makes Evinrude and Johnson outboard motors, as well as Chris-Craft and Four Winns boats. The company posted a loss in its third-quarter ended June 30 of $0.18 per share, compared to a profit of $1.39 per share last year. Quarterly revenues were $291 million, down from $329.6 million a year before.</p>
<p>Shares in the company were up 1-5/8 to 17-3/8 Friday after the Greenway stake was announced in a filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. A year ago, OMC shares traded in the low 20s.</p>
<p>Main said OMC is pursuing other markets for the FICHT system. &quot;We are talking with people who make personal watercraft engines or motorcycle engines,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In addition, he said OMC is taking cost-cutting steps. &quot;We are looking very hard at our corporate overhead costs and expect some dramatic cost savings there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>For example, OMC may consolidate administrative functions for its boat companies from six locations to one in Nashville, Tenn., Main said.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk  312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
