<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10778" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Toyota to recall 90,000 Tacoma pickups.</title>
<headline>Toyota to recall 90,000 Tacoma pickups.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toyota Motor Corp said Friday it was recalling about 90,000 two-wheel-drive Tacoma compact pickup trucks to repair a suspension flaw that could cause a loss of steering control.</p>
<p>The recall involves all of two-wheel-drive Tacomas built since production of the trucks began in January 1995. The recall does not involve four-wheel-drive models.</p>
<p>The trucks are built in Fremont, Calif., by New United Motor Manufacturing Inc, Toyota's joint venture with General Motors Corp.  </p>
<p>Jeremy Barnes, a Toyota spokesman in Torrance, Calif., said the recalled trucks have a defective front suspension support tower that can crack under simultaneous vertical and horizontal loadings, such as when the truck hits a pothole during hard braking.</p>
<p>Over time, the cracks could worsen and cause a loss of steering control, or force the front wheels to collapse under the vehicle. Toyota has reports of 12 trucks with cracked towers, but the problem has produced no accidents or injuries.  </p>
<p>Toyota has repurchased eight of the 12 trucks and repaired the other four, Barnes said, adding that owners had noticed that their trucks' front wheels were pitched at an odd angle.</p>
<p>Barnes said Toyota has sent a letter to owners instructing them to bring their trucks to dealerships, which will install a reinforcement plate on the suspension tower free of chrage. The extensive repair takes about six hours per truck, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to remove the suspension, weld the reinforcement, reinstall the suspension and realign the vehicle,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Barnes added Toyota has not sold Tacomas at U.S. dealerships since mid-July in order to make the same repair to all trucks now in dealer inventory. All 1997 Tacomas are being assembled with the suspension reinforcements.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
