<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10776" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Most IMM currency futures finish higher.</title>
<headline>Most IMM currency futures finish higher.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most IMM currency futures finished higher, led by strength in September Swiss francs and marks.</p>
<p>Early weakness in September yen futures was tied to a stronger than expected U.S. July durable goods report, but yen managed to climb into positive territory as the dollar slipped.</p>
<p>July durable goods orders rose 1.6 percent, outstripping the forecast for an 0.3-percent gain and June's revised 0.2-percent drop. Excluding defense orders, that figure was up 3.5 percent.  </p>
<p>Strength in September marks and Swiss francs was tied to ideas the recent wave of interest rate cuts could be the last for the time being. The Bundesbank cut its repurchase rate by 30 basis points to an historical low at 3.00 percent early on Thursday, with many other countries following suit. Finland and Denmark cut rates early on Friday.</p>
<p>Futures volume picked up Friday compared with levels earlier this week. One U.S. bank bought 1,500 September yen contracts on the close, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;September yen really drafted up with the rest of the currencies,&quot; an IMM currency futures trader said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think we're seeing some profit-taking before all this stuff out next week and because London's out Monday,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>London and Hong Kong market holidays on Monday could keep markets thin early next week, he said, and the Japanese economic line-up next week is rather full.</p>
<p>&quot;Things did pick up in here and this is going to turn some dollar bulls around, at least in the yen if we get strong reports from the Japanese on their economy,&quot; the trader said. &quot;People might think they'll be ready to hike rates in Japan,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Traders said marks and Swiss franc gained as the dollar followed the weak Treasury bond tone after the strong durable goods report.</p>
<p>Sept yen ended up $0.000014 to $0.009282, marks gained $0.0061 to $0.6773, Swiss francs gained $0.0097 to $0.8395, Sterling rose $0.0066 to $1.5566, Can dollar gained $0.0007 to $0.7306, Aussie dollar fell $0.0013 at $0.7893, Mexican peso fell $0.000400 at $0.131675. --Derivatives Desk 312-408-8750 E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
