<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10789" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USWC light crudes fall, talk thin ahead of weekend.</title>
<headline>USWC light crudes fall, talk thin ahead of weekend.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast light crudes fell on weaker West Texas Intermediate values, with few prospects of a deal ahead of the weekend.</p>
<p>October WTI was burdened by weaker product futures and fell about twenty cents from Thursday. The September/October roll widened from 20 to 40 cents in afternoon trade.</p>
<p>That left October WTI at $22.00/22.10 a barrel.</p>
<p>Buyers had ample crude for September and began to focus on purchasing October cargoes, though a major refiner was said to seek offers.  </p>
<p>Early Thursday, the dominant ANS producer sold to a Hawaiian refiner at $2.05 a barrel under October WTI, 10 cents lower than the previous sale.</p>
<p>Atlantic Richfield Co denied market rumors from late Thursday and early today that its Ferndale, Washington, refinery had an outage.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't had any operational problems,&quot; a spokesman said.</p>
<p>Prices for Line 63 slipped with WTI, but spot deals off WTI remained dormant.</p>
<p>Arco on Wednesday limited crude oil shipments on Line 63 to 46.81 percent of nominations for September.</p>
<p>Kern River and Wilmington grades were unchanged late.</p>
<p>-- David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles bureau +1 213 380 2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
