<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10787" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY precious metals end mostly higher, volumes low.</title>
<headline>NY precious metals end mostly higher, volumes low.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York precious metals futures ended mostly firmer Friday, on low volumes, with trading expected to remain slow next week due to holidays in London and Hong Kong on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw some light position squaring today ahead of the holidays Monday, but silver still looks like might have more upside, and if December gold can hold above $390 then could see more upside too,&quot; FIMAT USA Inc trader Frank Aburto said.</p>
<p>COMEX December gold ended up $0.70 an ounce at $392.2 an ounce, after trading up to a high for the week at $393.7.</p>
<p>Total estimated gold futures volume was 13,000 lots.  </p>
<p>In New York bullion trade, spot gold was quoted $388.00/388.50, from a London afternoon fix of $387.50, and a New York close Thursday at $387.20/387.70.</p>
<p>COMEX September silver ended down 2.3 cents at $5.197 an ounce, after drifting back from the week's high, seen Thursday, at $5.245, which was the highest level since June 4.</p>
<p>Total estimated volume in silver futures was 19,000 lots.</p>
<p>Open interest in the September silver contract has been falling sharply and stood at 34,878 lots on August 22, representing 174.39 million ounces, reflecting shortcovering of positions ahead of the start of the delivery period.  </p>
<p>Registered silver stocks stood at around 107.9 million ounces, with another 46.5 million ounces stored in New York bank vaults but not registered, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;While September open interest is falling sharply, it still exceeds these stocks, applying some upward pressure on prices,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>NYMEX October platinum ended up $0.60 at $403.50 an ounce, with NYMEX September palladium up $0.90 at $125.90.</p>
<p>&quot;Platinum group metals remain weak due to low summer fabricator demand,&quot; FIMAT's Aburto said.</p>
<p>--Clive McKeef, New York Commodities Desk, +212-859-1641.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
