<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10790" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: COMEX copper ends higher ahead of LME holiday.</title>
<headline>COMEX copper ends higher ahead of LME holiday.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX copper settled slightly higher in largely routine trading with volume heavier than in previous sessions this week due to rolling over of positions from September to December, traders said.</p>
<p>Prices were boosted by shortcovering on LME ahead of a long weekend. LME is closed Monday due to a national holiday.</p>
<p>There will be no regular LME stock report on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A rise of 5,675 tonnes in LME stocks Friday to 271,675 tonnes was in line with trade expectations.</p>
<p>December COMEX settled 0.35 cent up at 90.00 cents a lb, traded 90.65 to 89.30 cents. September went out 1.05 cents higher at 91.70 cents. Volume was estimated at 12,000 lots with 2,669 switches.</p>
<p>COMEX stocks Friday rose 606 short tons to 21,250 tons.</p>
<p>Although global copper production has risen, the market has yet to move into surplus, John Gross of the Copper Journal said.</p>
<p>&quot;To the extent domestic demand remains steady, Asia is growing and Europe is recovering, we believe the global market will consume more metal, thereby preventing a rapid build up of stocks,&quot; Gross said.</p>
<p>U.S. durable goods orders in July rose more than expected.</p>
<p>-- Huw Jones, New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
