<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10809" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: UAL to use cash, financing to pay for jets.</title>
<headline>UAL to use cash, financing to pay for jets.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>UAL Corp, parent of United Airlines, said Friday it will purchase 51 new jets valued at $4.4 billion with a combination of cash from operations and financing arranged at the time of delivery.</p>
<p>On August 22, United announced it ordered 27 new wide body aircraft from Boeing Co and 24 narrow-body A319 aircraft from Airbus Industrie.</p>
<p>Based on the manufacturers' list prices, the value of the Boeing order would be $3.5 billion and the Airbus order would be $900 million. But company spokesman Joseph Hopkins reiterated that United paid less than list price.  </p>
<p>He declined to give the exact amount paid for the planes.</p>
<p>On August 15, United said it was ordering $2.5 billion in planes from Boeing and was looking to buy about $600 million worth of narrow body planes from Boeing or Airbus. United did not specify the number of planes to be purchased at that time.</p>
<p>Hopkins said United expects to take delivery of all its new planes by the year 2002.</p>
<p>The delivery schedule calls for four A319 planes from Airbus to be delivered in 1997, 15 in 1998 and the others in subsequent years.  </p>
<p>Of the 19 new 747s ordered from Boeing, two 747-400 planes will be delivered in 1996, six in 1997 and four in 1998, with the rest to be delivered later.</p>
<p>The schedule for the new order of two 777 planes from Boeing, combined with 34 previously ordered, include eight being delivered in 1996, 14 in 1997 and four in 1998.</p>
<p>Six new 757 jets from Boeing, combined with previous orders, will be delivered starting with four this year, two in 1997 and three in 1998.</p>
<p>United has said it is buying the new planes to replace older models in an effort to upgrade its fleet without expanding capacity beyond demand.</p>
<p>Hopkins said United's plans for 1996 call for eight 737-200s, six DC10-10s made by McDonnell Douglas Corp and three 747-100s to be retired.</p>
<p>In 1997, United plans to retire eight 737-200s, four DC10-10s, four DC-30s and six 747-100s. In 1998, it will retire 29 737-200s, six DC10-10s, four 747-100s and six 747-200s.</p>
<p>Hopkins said United normally seeks a buyer for its retired planes.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
