<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10802" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT - Tobacco oversold but bottom not seen yet.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Tobacco oversold but bottom not seen yet.</headline>
<byline>Betty Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philip Morris Cos Inc and other tobacco shares have been hammered by mounting litigation and increasing U.S. oversight, but their oversold condition does not provide a buying opportunity yet, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no valuation arguments to buy the stocks at these prices. It might be a trader argument, but the fundamentals scare me away,&quot; said Paul Rabbitt, an Oppenheimer quantitative analyst. The group has a &quot;weak/neutral valuation. It's very cheap on dividend but very expensive on cash flow.&quot;  </p>
<p>Philip Morris was up 7/8 to 86-3/4 Friday afternoon, but still a far cry from the 106 level it was trading at two weeks ago, when a Florida jury ruled against the industry in a lawsuit and triggered a sell-off. Wall Street is now awaiting the verdict in a key tobacco litigation case in Indiana.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, President Clinton Friday endorsed a Food and Drug Administration plan and approved rules to curb teen-age smoking by restricting the sale and advertising of tobacco.</p>
<p>With the negative fundamental overhang, technicians did not yet see a bottom for the group. &quot;There is zero reason to buy Morris technically,&quot; said Ralph Bloch of Raymond James.  </p>
<p>&quot;There's no sign of a bottom yet. Morris has broken down badly and is trying to find support but it's very, very early. We need a lengthy period of rebuilding,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Likewise, Ed Nicoski, a Piper Jaffray technical analyst, said, &quot;Tobacco is not technically appealing. There are too many other places to invest. Tobacco has too many problems in terms of lawsuits.&quot;</p>
<p>Nonetheless, some traders noted Morris was attracting some bargain hunters because of its $1 a share quarterly dividend and hopes for a dividend increase next week.  </p>
<p>&quot;Morris might raise its dividend next week. It's a 4.6 percent yield now, and the yield could be 5.5 percent. There's some bargain-hunting, but it might be early,&quot; said Marty Kearney, a trader at PTI Securities.</p>
<p>Among other tobacco stocks, RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp, parent of R.J. Reynolds Tobacco, rose 1/4 to 25-1/2, Loews Corp added 1/2 to 75-5/8 and smokeless tobacco maker UST Inc was unchanged at 30-3/4.</p>
<p>-- Wall Street desk, 212-859-1731</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
