<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10803" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: C-Cube rises on link to Zenith - analyst.</title>
<headline>C-Cube rises on link to Zenith - analyst.</headline>
<text>
<p>SAN FRANCISCO, Aug 23 (Reuter) Shares of C-Cube Microsystems Inc rose 4-3/8 to 34-3/4 on the possibility that the maker of semiconductor-based encoders could get some of Zenith Electronics Corp's $1 billion contract for supplying ditigal TV set-top boxes to the Americast consortium, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The activity in the stock today and yesterday is related to the announcement by Zenith, tied back to DiviCom which C-Cube will close (acquire) on next week,&quot; said Alex Brown &amp; Sons analyst Greg Mischou. &quot;My understanding is DiviCom has a design win from Zenith,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>C-Cube has had an agreement to acquire DiviCom, a Milpitas, Calif.-based maker of technology used in set-top boxes, in a deal scheduled to close Aug. 28.</p>
<p>The possibility of C-Cube ending up supplying Zenith was reported in the San Francisco Chronicle on Friday.</p>
<p>C-Cube officials did not immediately return phone calls.</p>
<p>Mischou said that while such a supply contract would surely be positive, &quot;There are a lot of factors that have to come together before this can be put in the numbers,&quot; or estimates of how a Zenith contract would affect C-Cube's revenues or earnings.    &quot;First it is a 1997 event,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analyst Elias Moosa of Robertson, Stephens &amp; Co said the possibility that C-Cube will wind up getting Zenith's business &quot;at this time is still speculation.&quot;</p>
<p>But he added that the Americast-Zenith deal suggests that &quot;C-Cube could be a prime beneficiary of a wider opportunity,&quot; from Americast and from other companies in the current move to deploy digital cable TV systems and set top box technology. &quot;Americast serves 68 million customers, they are not going to stop at 3 million,&quot; Moosa said. The deal between Zenith and Americast calls for Zenith to supply at least 3 million set top boxes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
