<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10813" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natgas futures hold late short covering gains.</title>
<headline>Natgas futures hold late short covering gains.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures were still holding gains in moderate, late-session trade, boosted by more pre-weekend short covering amid concerns about Tropical Storm Edouard, industry sources said.</p>
<p>At 1405 EDT, September climbed 3.9 cents to $1.96 per million British thermal units after hitting $1.90 on ACCESS. October was 5.1 cents higher at $2.05. Others also were up.</p>
<p>&quot;We're still seeing short covering ahead of the weekend because of Edouard,&quot; said one Houston-based trader.</p>
<p>At 1100 EDT, Edouard was 1,500 miles east of the Lesser Antilles, moving west at 15 mph with winds of about 70 mph.  </p>
<p>But most expected the gains to be short-lived, noting that mild weather next week in the Midwest and Northeast was likely to set a bearish tone during bidweek.</p>
<p>With September set to expire Monday, technical traders remained focused on October, still pegging support at Thursday's low of $1.975 and resistance in the low-teens.</p>
<p>U.S. Gulf Coast weekend cash prices slipped another five cents Friday to the low-to-mid $1.90s. Midcon pipes were down a similar amount to the mid-$1.70s.</p>
<p>NYMEX said 19,448 Henry Hub contracts traded at 1330 EDT. NYMEX September Permian natgas firmed 2.5 cents to $1.695, while deferreds were untraded at 1410 EDT. NYMEX said 39 Permian contracts traded at 1330 EDT.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Permian natgas futures expire Wednesday August 28.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, September was still unchanged at $1.77, while deferreds were steady to up 1.5 cents. The East/West spread widened by 3.9 cents to 19 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>KCBT September natgas futures expire Tuesday, August 27.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
