<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10811" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: EIS shrs off on contract dispute -- traders.</title>
<headline>EIS shrs off on contract dispute -- traders.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in EIS International Inc fell sharply in afternoon Nasdaq trade on Friday as investors became aware of the potential departure of a top customer at an EIS unit, Wall Street traders said.</p>
<p>Two hours before the market close, EIS was off three points at 15-7/8 on volume of more than two million shares -- ten times the stock's average daily volume.</p>
<p>Earlier in the afternoon the shares fell as low as 14-5/8 after starting the day with a 1/8 rise to 19.</p>
<p>The stock's 12-month low is 13-7/8.  </p>
<p>The traders said EIS, a maker of call center management systems, conducted an early-afternoon conference call to detail a contract issue, which was included in the company's latest 10-Q filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
<p>One trader said an unhappy customer was arguing that the service did not live up to company claims and was filing a claim to break the contract and possibly recover payment made to the EIS unit so far.</p>
<p>No one was immediately available at Stamford, Conn.-based EIS to explain the dispute or detail the conference call.  </p>
<p>The trader said the contract in question was placed with EIS's Cybernetics unit, a workforce management software company acquired earlier this year.</p>
<p>He said that according to the 10-Q filing, the company has recognized $3.8 million in income through June 30 related to the contract.</p>
<p>In the 10-Q, he said, EIS said an escrow account had been established to cover costs associated with any termination of the contract, though the company said it expected the issue to be resolved.  </p>
<p>In the second quarter the company reported income of $0.27 per share, or $3.1 million, versus $0.21 per share, or $2.2 million, in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>Second quarter revenues grew to $30.6 million from $20.8 million in the 1995 second quarter.</p>
<p>The company went public in July 1992 with a 1.725 million-share offering at $5 per share.</p>
<p>-- Brendan Intindola, Wall Street Desk 212-859-1734</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
