<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10814" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American Brands' Advanced Gravis offer still open.</title>
<headline>American Brands' Advanced Gravis offer still open.</headline>
<dateline>OLD GREENWICH, Conn. 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>American Brands Inc said Friday that its unit's tender offer for Advanced Gravis Computer Technology Ltd remained open despite resistance by some Advanced Gravis shareholders.  </p>
<p>American Brands said it was not aware of more than a small minority opposed to the offer by its operating unit, ACCO World Corp. The offer for all of Advanced Gravis' shares, at C$0.45 a share, will stay open until 0001 EDT/0401 GMT on September 10.</p>
<p>American Brands said its offer represented a 20 percent premium over the average price for Advanced Gravis' shares.</p>
<p>The stock was trading at C$0.41 on the Toronto stock exchange on Friday afternoon. The company also trades as bulletin board stock in the United States.</p>
<p>The offer was unanimously approved by Advanced Gravis' board of directors, the company said.</p>
<p>American Brands said it knew of no litigation filed against the tender offer or any proceedings or investigations under way before the securities commssions of the United States and Canada.</p>
<p>Norm Levenson, a spokesman for a group of Advanced Gravis dissident shareholders, said on Friday that the group was seeking an order from the U.S. and Canadian regulators to halt the deal.</p>
<p>Advanced Gravis manufactures controls used in popular video games.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OLD GREENWICH, Conn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
