<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10820" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed to review changes to rules under Regulation Y.</title>
<headline>Fed to review changes to rules under Regulation Y.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Reserve Board on Friday said it will review a sweeping proposal that would speed the process for mergers of banks in good standing and make it easier for them to engage in nonbanking activities.</p>
<p>The proposal would revise a host of rules under the Fed's &quot;Regulation Y&quot; to bring them more up to date, Fed officials said. The regulation details the types of activities in which bank holding companies and their subsidiaries can engage.</p>
<p>In a meeting to consider the changes, Fed Chairman Alan Greenspan said the board is trying to review a &quot;whole list of rules&quot; that might have been pertinent to the goal of maintaining the safety and soundness of the banking system 20 years ago but are no longer appropriate.</p>
<p>Fed Governor Susan Phillips said the changes are aimed at reflecting changes in the market.</p>
<p>Among other things, the proposal would establish a streamlined 15-day notice procedure for certain banks wishing to acquire other banks.</p>
<p>To qualify for the expedited procedure, banks must be well capitalized and well managed and have satisfactory or better records in complying with the Community Reinvestment Act.  </p>
<p>Adequately capitalized and well managed banks would also be eligible for a streamlined 15-day notice procedure for establishing or acquiring nonbanking entities.</p>
<p>The proposal would expand holding companies' abilities to offer packages of nontraditional services, such as offering discounts to credit card users if they are also mortage customers or offering tax planning services to brokerage customers.</p>
<p>It would also broaden the holding companies' ability to engage in activities such as derivatives trading and investment, investment advisory and management consulting activities.</p>
<p>The Fed will seek input about the proposal during a 60-day comment period. After that, the staff will review the proposals for incorporation into a final proposal that can be put forth for a vote by the Fed board.</p>
<p>Fed staff members said that if everything goes according to plan, the proposal could be approved by the end of this year or the beginning of next year.</p>
<p>Paul Smith, senior counsel for the American Bankers' Association, praised the proposal.  </p>
<p>&quot;It makes holding companies more competitive and that should increase competition in the marketplace for these services in general,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they are trying to say that the board should not be a hurdle to holding companies' attempts to compete with non-banking competitors,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Smith pointed out, however, that the Fed is limited in its ability to lift the statutory barriers to competition that the banking industry is seeking.</p>
<p>For that, the industry wants Congress to enact changes to the Glass Steagall Act that separates commercial and investment banking activities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
