<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10851" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Caribbean nations seek trade beyond palm trees.</title>
<headline>Caribbean nations seek trade beyond palm trees.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Zengerle</byline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>White sand beaches and swaying palm trees bring billions of dollars each year to the economies of the Caribbean, but the region's island nations want to be known for more than tourism.</p>
<p>With total populations barely matching the size of many smaller U.S. and European cities, the small democracies have struggled to maintain a position in the rapidly consolidating world trade market.</p>
<p>To compete, they have formed regional alliances, led by the 14-member Caribbean Community and Common Market (Caricom), which links the English-speaking Caribbean into a free-trade region. But even Caricom represents a total population of only 6 million people, about one-sixth the size of neighboring Colombia alone.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Caricom nations) are all very small, and even together they are very small,&quot; Edwin Carrington, Caricom secretary-general, told a conference on Caribbean business here this week.</p>
<p>Caricom's highest-profile fight has been its battle to preserve its share of the European market for bananas.</p>
<p>In a dispute that has come before the World Trade Organization, Central American nations, supported by the United States and U.S. companies that own banana plantations there, are trying to overturn Caribbean banana exporters' special access to the European Union.</p>
<p>Caribbean leaders have reacted angrily to what they called an assault on the region's way of life by greedy conglomerates, noting the huge importance of bananas to Dominica, Saint Lucia and other former European colonies in the eastern Caribbean that are almost totally dependent on exports of the fruit for their foreign exchange earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;Bananas are under a serious threat. That threat, if successful, will undermine the economic stability of the community,&quot; said Carrington, who noted that instability in the Caribbean would be a threat to the hemisphere as a whole.</p>
<p>Outside of agriculture, Caribbean nations face the loss of foreign investment to Mexico, which has special access to the U.S. market as a member of the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA).</p>
<p>Caribbean tourism is thriving, with visitors bringing some $14 billion to the region's economies last year. But the islands are wary of relying too much on tourism alone, and economists seconded the concern.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very cyclical industry. Things are changing all the time. In any situation, you don't want to rely on one area that will kind of go up, go down,&quot; said Dan Sarel, a professor of marketing at the University of Miami.</p>
<p>Tourism depends on good weather, and a cold winter like this year's boosts tourist visits. But the hurricanes that battered many islands last year knocked out hotels and other facilities for months.</p>
<p>Tourism also is increasingly competitive, with Pacific Rim nations, Hawaii and Mexico among destinations competing for travel dollars, and many passengers now choose to visit the islands on cruise ships, generating less revenue than those who stay overnight.</p>
<p>Another concern is recent studies showing that about 70 cents of each tourist dollar spent in the Caribbean leaves the region again to pay for imported products and services, said Charles Maynard, adviser to the Caribbean American Business Network, which sponsored the conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Not enough of what the visitors spends remains in the destination,&quot; he said. Maynard said Caribbean businesses were trying to sell products like pepper sauces, fruits and telephone cards to tourist centers.</p>
<p>&quot;If we can develop these linkages (between local companies and international tourism) and if the hotels can purchase more from the farmers, and from the agro-producers, then we will be able to get more out of tourism,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>One advantage for small nations like Saint Kitts-Nevis, which has 40,618 people, or Saint Lucia, with 139,908, is that a relatively small contract can have a big impact on the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;It may just take one or two people in a partnership to transform life in these islands,&quot; Maynard said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CARIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
