<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10855" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. refiners to face pricey butane this winter.</title>
<headline>U.S. refiners to face pricey butane this winter.</headline>
<byline>Laney Salisbury</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. refiners and end-users of normal butane are likely to battle price spikes and scarce inventories in the upcoming gasoline blending season, analysts warned on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very tight market for normal butane right now,&quot; said Dan Lippe, an LPG analyst with Petral Consulting Co in Houston.</p>
<p>According to the latest industry inventory data, the major energy producing region of the U.S. Gulf Coast showed a scant 1.8 million barrel stock build for June, about 66 percent below the historical average.  </p>
<p>&quot;At this point I would have to say that we would not see total U.S. stocks higher than 17.5 million for August,&quot; added Lippe. The level is about 33 percent below the historical average of 23.2 million for this peak inventory month.</p>
<p>Market watchers said normal butane began to come under pressure in March, when higher prices on propane and ethane made it an attractive feedstock for cracking ethylene.</p>
<p>In recent months, isomerization units have also been preying on normal butane to process isobutane, which is then used to make the gasoline additive MTBE.  </p>
<p>&quot;There has been a strong ethylene feedstock demand since early March and most MTBE plants are on stream,&quot; said Lippe.</p>
<p>Imports have also not alleviated the shortage underpinned partly by strong petrochemical demand.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though we have been getting more imports than typical, inventories are still low,&quot; Ron Gist, an analyst with Purvin and Gertz said.</p>
<p>With the September start of the gasoline blending season, when federal regulations call for higher vapor pressure, refiner demand for butane is expected to increase from 50,000 barrels per day in July to 250,000 bpd by November.  </p>
<p>&quot;November, December, January and February is the peak blending season and it's entirely possible we will run out of (some grades) of normal butane,&quot; said Lippe.</p>
<p>Prices, already about six cents above levels last year, may increase another 10 cents by January if the blending demand holds amid continuing low inventories, said Lippe.</p>
<p>Another factor still unclear in the market, is Mexico's demand for butane following lost production at its largest gas processing plant in a crippling July explosion.  </p>
<p>So far, Mexico has been focusing on propane and &quot;it appears they are tying to make up their loss of butane with propane,&quot; said Lippe.</p>
<p>On August 14, Mexico signed a contract with Saudi Arabia to buy about 240,000-250,000 tonnes of propane between September and March, but traders and analysts expect Mexico to demand more in later months.</p>
<p>-- New York Energy Desk +212-859-1631</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
