<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10866" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New York City plans $1.6 bln note sale in Sept.</title>
<headline>New York City plans $1.6 bln note sale in Sept.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York City said on Friday that it plans to issue in mid-to late-September approximately $1.6 billion of revenue anticipation notes that will have two different maturities and be sold competitively.</p>
<p>Further, in November the city is planning to sell about $75 million of taxable bonds through competitive auction, and as much as $750 million of new and refunding general obligation bonds through its underwriting syndicate.  </p>
<p>The first part of the revenue anticipation note deal is expected to total about $550 million and come due in March, while the second part likely would be about $1.05 billion and mature around the end of June.</p>
<p>Using two different maturities allows the city to retire the short-term notes as soon as it gets the revenues, reducing its borrowing costs, John White, the city's bureau chief of debt management, told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, you want to pay them off as soon as possible. Certain revenues are coming in at the end of March and other revenues are not coming in until the end of the fiscal year.&quot;  </p>
<p>New York City's fiscal year ends on June 30.</p>
<p>White, who added that the city's need for cash tends to vary throughout the year, said the notes will be repaid with various revenues, including the city's sales taxes and state aid for health, welfare and education.</p>
<p>The final details of the offering are expected to be set after the U.S. Labor Day holiday on September 2.</p>
<p>In November, New York City anticipates selling about $500 million of bonds for new money. If market conditions are favorable and the city determines it would save money by refinancing existing issues, it might add a refunding of as much as $250 million to the sale.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is no market for a refunding, then we won't do it,&quot; said White. &quot;(But) we typically slap a little refunding on a new money (offering).&quot;</p>
<p>While the city's syndicate would handle the bond sales, the approximately $75 million of taxable issues that would be sold at the same time would be issued through a competitive auction.</p>
<p>-- Joan Gralla 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
