<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10879" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LCE coffee ends down as weakness continues into PM.</title>
<headline>LCE coffee ends down as weakness continues into PM.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Robusta coffee futures closed around intraday lows at the end of Friday's session as earlier weakness predominated after selling in New York, traders said.</p>
<p>Activity on the London market was described as lacklustre by market players, anxious to square positions before the extended weekend. The LCE is closed on Monday due to a public holiday.</p>
<p>Origin sales brought the November contract back down from its earlier $1,719 high, countering the effects of fund buying.</p>
<p>At the close November stood $28 lower on the day at $1,667 and all other traded positions were lower. Switch activity was concentrated in Sept/Nov and overall volume totalled 4,636 lots.</p>
<p>Nearby tightness in New York, where the September contract received no delivery notices on Thursday against a background of insufficient certified stocks, is seen stirring the market higher in the coming days.</p>
<p>Technical analysts said November's rally above $1,700 was likely to extend with help from underlying support, but a heavy band of supply could keep the momentum slow.</p>
<p>&quot;Critical resistance over $1,700 has now seen a more serious challenge and there is an increasing possibility it will be cleared,&quot; said Elli Gifford in the latest weekly futures summary from Investment Research in Cambridge.</p>
<p>&quot;However, the market is somewhat overbought and thus a very firm close through this resistance is required if the uptrend is to accelerate enough to make $1,800 as a target realistic.&quot;</p>
<p>The November contract was expected to trade sideways in the medium term, but move higher on a short-term basis.</p>
<p>Resistance was pegged in a band between $1,700 and $1,800, with nearby support at $1,590.</p>
<p>-- Jeremy Smith, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8064</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
