<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10888" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products firm, gasoline under pressure.</title>
<headline>Med oil products firm, gasoline under pressure.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mediterranean oil products were broadly firm on Friday. Gasoline was steady, but sentiment was under some pressure on Friday as West African demand had dried up and most refiners in the region had physical length.</p>
<p>Demand in the eastern Mediterranean was thin, while Ukraine had yet to appear as a Black Sea buyer.</p>
<p>Naphtha continued to climb on tight supply. Prices gained $2.00 per tonne to $196 cif Med as very little Egyptian or Algerian was available.  </p>
<p>Demand was good, both from petrochemical companies faced with strong LPG prices and from refiners who were buying high N+A for reforming to compensate for reducing crude throughput.</p>
<p>Gas oil was generally firm although Russian appeared to be under some pressure with five cargoes due before end-August.</p>
<p>Traders said 20,000 tonnes of a 32,000-tonne Russian cargo had been sold at quotes cif high +$2.00, basis La Nouvelle. Premiums were put at roughly quotes cif high +50 cents/+$1.50, basis Genoa.</p>
<p>A Turkish tender was awarded for two cargoes and one optional, all to be delivered in the third decade of September.  </p>
<p>Tempotrade was reported to have picked up one cargo and also the optional cargo at around mean fob +$8.50.</p>
<p>An Italian refiner was offering a low sulphur cargo at formula +$2.75 with bids at formula +50 cents/+1.0.</p>
<p>High sulphur cracked fuel oil remained tight with bunker spec material particuarly difficult to buy. Traders said prices were around $96-97 fob Med.</p>
<p>Low sulphur cargoes were also a touch firmer although the main Med buyer was not showing any interest. Some traders were said to be looking to buy product to blend with high sulphur to meet some interest from a Med refiner for two percent sulphur.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
