<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10881" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reuters historical calendar - August 30.</title>
<headline>Reuters historical calendar - August 30.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the major events to have occurred on August 30 in history.</p>
<p>30 B.C. - Cleopatra, Queen of Egypt, died. She is said to have committed suicide by allowing an asp to bite her breast.</p>
<p>1125 - Lothair II, Duke of Saxony, was elected king of the Germans.</p>
<p>1483 - Louis XI of France died and was succeeded by Charles VIII.</p>
<p>1757 - Russia defeated the Prussians at Gross Jagersdorf In the Seven Years War.</p>
<p>1797 - Mary Shelley, English novelist, born. Author of &quot;Frankenstein&quot;, she was the wife of the poet Percy Bysshe Shelley.</p>
<p>1862 - The second battle of Bull Run took place in the U.S. Civil War. Confederate forces under General Stonewall Jackson defeated the Federal army.</p>
<p>1881 - Clement Ader patented the first stereophonic sound system in Germany.</p>
<p>1896 - Raymond Massey, Canadian-born character actor, born. His early career was marked by his portrayal of Abraham Lincoln in both stage and screen versions of &quot;Abe Lincoln in Illinois&quot;.</p>
<p>1914 - One of history's great military disasters took place at the Battle of Tannenberg. The Russian Second Army under Samsonov was enveloped and crushed by the Germans, who lost 30,000 men. Samsonov committed suicide.</p>
<p>1916 - Turkey declared war on Romania.</p>
<p>1918 - Lenin, new leader of Soviet Russia, survived an assassination attempt by a social revolutionary.</p>
<p>1924 - Diplomats in London signed the Dawes plan, an agreement calling for payment of reparations by Germany to her former enemies in World War One.</p>
<p>1928 - Jawaharlal Nehru founded the Independence of India League to work towards freedom from British rule.</p>
<p>1932 - Hermann Goering was elected president of the German Reichstag.</p>
<p>1940 - Sir J.J. Thomson, English physicist who discovered the electron in 1897, died aged 83 and was buried near Isaac Newton in the nave of Westminster Abbey.</p>
<p>1957 - Senator Strom Thurmond of South Carolina set a new filibuster record in the U.S. Congress when he spoke for over 24 hours against a civil rights bill.</p>
<p>1963 - A &quot;hot line&quot; link between the Kremlin and the White House went into operation, designed to reduce the risk of accidental war and reduce sudden East-West tension.</p>
<p>1973 - Kenya banned the hunting of elephants and the trade in ivory.</p>
<p>1981 - President Mohammad Ali Rajaei and Prime Minister Mohammad Javad Bahonar of Iran were killed in a bomb blast.</p>
<p>1982 - PLO leader Yasser Arafat abandoned his headquarters in Beirut following Israeli invasion of Lebanon.</p>
<p>1983 - Lt-Col Guion Bluford became the first Afro-American in space, one of a crew of five on the space shuttle Challenger.</p>
<p>1990 - The Bulgarian parliament approved Andrei Lukanov as prime minister.</p>
<p>1991 - Azerbaijan declared independence from the Soviet Union.</p>
<p>1993 - Businessman Robert Malval was sworn in as Haiti's new prime minister.</p>
<p>1994 - Bosnian Serbs overwhelmingly rejected an international peace plan in a weekend poll with the final result showing more than 90 percent of those who voted said &quot;No&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
