<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10890" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE gas oil higher on futures, premiums firm.</title>
<headline>NWE gas oil higher on futures, premiums firm.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>NWE gas oil was firm on Friday as benchmark futures added to Thursday's gains and premiums remained strong, traders said.</p>
<p>The IPE September contract ended the day 25 cents higher at $191.25 after having gained $3 on Thursday, and was expected by some dealers to hit $200 in the near future.</p>
<p>Details of the IOC diesel tender award for October had not emerged on Friday but traders' estimates of what they would take had fallen to under 400,000 tonnes from 800,000 tonnes earlier in the week  </p>
<p>A German heating oil cargo traded at Sept IPE +$3.75 per tonne, cif Hamburg. Premiums on DIN were Sept IPE +$3/+$4.</p>
<p>Traders said interest in FOD cargoes out of France remained limited. On the Russian cargo front, premiums were steady at Sept IPE +$1.0/+$2.0 per tonne.</p>
<p>There was buying interest for low sulphur out of France. Premiums were put at Sept IPE +$10.50/+$11.50, cif NWE A German refiner was bidding Sept IPE +$8.0 for summer quality 0.05.</p>
<p>The barge market was subdued. High benchmark screen prices had scared buyers off, traders said. Premiums were put at Sept IPE +25 cents/+$1.0 per tonne, fob ARA.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
