<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10894" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dated Brent slumps as six cargoes turn wet.</title>
<headline>Dated Brent slumps as six cargoes turn wet.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dated Brent values fell sharply at the close of business on Friday as six cargoes turned wet and one traded as low as September -17 cents after an earlier deal at Sept -5 cents, traders said.</p>
<p>They said North Sea crudes were under pressure on good supply and the closure of the arbitrage window to the U.S., which had earlier soaked up more than five million barrels of sweet crude.</p>
<p>An oil major who kept two of Friday's six dates sold them on to a trader at September -10 cents for cargoes loading September 7-9.  </p>
<p>Another cargo also moved to a trader at September -17 cents for a September 8-10 loading.</p>
<p>Of the six cargoes turning wet on Friday, one was five o'clocked and was likely to be deferred to Sept 11-13. Earlier on Friday, a cargo loading Sept 3-5 moved at Sept -5 cents.</p>
<p>The only other North Sea grade to trade on Friday was a Forties loading Sept 14-16 which was done at September +28 cents, unchanged from Thursday.</p>
<p>Brent CFDs were flat with next week's dates talked at Oct Brent +38/+40 cents and the week after at +25/+31 cents. Brent Sept/Oct was done at +46, +48, +49 and +50 cents.  </p>
<p>Oct/Nov traded at +46 cents and was assessed at +43/45 by the end of the day. Nov/Dec was valued at +42/+45 cents.</p>
<p>The West African market was assessed firm to mid-September.</p>
<p>An Escravos trade on Thursday added to a flurry of deals earlier in the week. The price of the Escravos, loading around Sep 20, could not be confirmed.</p>
<p>&quot;It's moving well right through to the third decade,&quot; said a trader for a major.</p>
<p>Steady demand was seen into the Mediterranean, the U.S. Gulf Coast and the U.S. east coast.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
