<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10893" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE high sulphur fuel firm, but market very thin.</title>
<headline>NWE high sulphur fuel firm, but market very thin.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>High sulphur cracked fuel oil remained firm in NWE although only barges were seen to have traded.</p>
<p>Barges traded at $100, $101, $102 fob ARA before the market faltered as buying interest evaported.</p>
<p>&quot;I've been trying to shift 1,000 tonnes this afternoon at $102, but nothing. I don't even see bids at $100,&quot; said one seller.</p>
<p>High sulphur cracked cargoes were firm around $96-98 fob NWE on the back of tight supplies and a trader bidding to cover EdP spec material.  </p>
<p>The narrowly balanced market has gained support from the enquiry although some dealers believe the bidder already holds sufficient supplies. &quot;I think the rise has plateaued. It's tight, but where is the fundamental demand to drive it higher,&quot; said one trader. Although there was no prompt material seen there are several M-100 cracked cargoes and E-4s and M-40s. The low sulphur cracked sector saw steady prices around $104-105 fob NWE with support from crude and interest for three prompt cargoes into Lebanon. Some traders were heard looking to blend low sulphur with high sulphur to get two percent material to sell into a Med buyer. -- London Newsroom, +44 171 542 8980</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
