<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10895" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Hoechst unit says to conduct Cardizem trial.</title>
<headline>Hoechst unit says to conduct Cardizem trial.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hoechst Marion Roussel said on Friday it was preparing to conduct a trial of Cardizem CM, a drug used to treat high blood pressure which the Lancet medical journal reported may increase the risk of cancer.</p>
<p>Earlier on Friday the Lancet published research by Dr Marco Pahor of the University of Tennessee in Memphis which found that people who had been using these so-called calcium channel blockers were 70 percent more likely to develop cancer.</p>
<p>In a commentary the Lancet said randomised trials should be organised immediately but that &quot;industry is likely to baulk at this suggestion on grounds of cost&quot;.  </p>
<p>However, Hoechst Marion Roussel, a unit of Hoechst AG, said it was already preparing to conduct a large-scale, four-year controlled trial of Cardizem to evaluate the long-term effects on patients being treated for high blood pressure before the Lancet report.</p>
<p>&quot;More than 8,000 people with high blood pressure will be enrolled in the trial and followed for four years. Among study end points, new-incident cancer will be recorded as part of the study design,&quot; the pharmaceutical company said in a statement.</p>
<p>The statement said patients should not be alarmed by the Lancet report and the company said it stood behing its products.  </p>
<p>&quot;In fact, the National Institutes of Health cautions that the dangers of uncontrolled high blood pressure may outweigh any possible cancer risk seen by this study,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>It said the authors of the report had concluded the evidence of their study was insufficient to recommend withdrawal of treatment, adding that clinical trials since the introduction of Cardizem in 1982 had produced no clinical evidence to suggest a causal relationship between the drug and cancer.</p>
<p>Other sellers of such calcium channel blockers are Pfizer Inc, Bayer AG and Astra Merck Inc, a joint-venture between Merck and Co and AB Astra .</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
