<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10908" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GDR Report-India premiums fail to keep up momentum.</title>
<headline>GDR Report-India premiums fail to keep up momentum.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The rally in Indian global depositary receipts faltered on Friday as the market failed to keep pace with underlying stocks ahead of a three-day weekend in London.</p>
<p>It has very quiet, not much movement in the GDRs, said a broker.</p>
<p>Premiums in the GDR market have expanded from under five percent in the past week to 10.87 percent now, although the gains have faded as the local market has caught up.</p>
<p>The Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) 30 share index added 42.60 points to 3,431.40.</p>
<p>&quot;Unit Trust of India has been in the Indian market and I do not believe in this rally,&quot; said the broker. &quot;It appears to be the government acting to prop up prices before the sale of state companies,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Indian government is proposing to sell $600 million to $1.0 billion of overseas telephone monopoly VSNL via a GDR offering and State Bank of India plans an issue of up to $400 million in GDRs.</p>
<p>Auto firm Mahindra &amp; Mahindra reported vehicle sales rose 23 percent from April 1-August 22 from a year ago, but the figures had little impact on Mahindra GDRs, which closed up 25 cents at $10.75/$11.75.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Indian Hotels added eight cents to $25.50/$26.50 and East India Hotels fell 10 cents to $21.00/$22.00.</p>
<p>Premiums for Korean GDRs expanded to 21.96 percent from yesterdays 19.85 percent after the Korea Composite Index added 1.79 points to 781.42.</p>
<p>In Taiwan, premiums shot up to 9.58 percent from 7.79 after the central bank made a surprise cut in reserve requirements.</p>
<p>The Taiwan Weighted Index gain 39.40 points to 6,200.22.</p>
<p>-- David Chance, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5887</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
