<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10903" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK picks Prism for two rail franchises.</title>
<headline>UK picks Prism for two rail franchises.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The UK's Office of Passenger Rail Franchising (Opraf) said it had chosen Prism Rail Plc as preferred bidder for both the South Wales &amp; West and Cardiff railway franchises.</p>
<p>Prism already has one of the 25 British train operating companies currently being privatised -- the LTS Rail suburban London franchise which it was awarded on May 9.  </p>
<p>Prism was formed specifically to pursue the opportunities afforded by Britain's rail privatisation process.</p>
<p>If it successfully completes negotiation of franchise contracts for the two Welsh lines it will become the first private sector company to have three separate franchise lines.</p>
<p>Opraf said it expected a formal award announcement would be made soon giving further details of the deal.</p>
<p>These would normally include the lengths of the franchise periods, the levels of subsidy agreed over their lives and any undertakings on investment in services or rolling stock.</p>
<p>The two Welsh lines are set to become the 10th and 11th lines to be franchised from the 25 passenger train firms.</p>
<p>-- Andrew Huddart, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8716</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
