<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10909" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: World Insurance Network says pilot due by year end.</title>
<headline>World Insurance Network says pilot due by year end.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>World Insurance Network (WIN) said it expects to have a pilot of its international communications system for brokers up and running by the end of this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We would expect to have completed our testing and to have a pilot by the end of this year. The actual roll-out will depend on logistics and planning,&quot; WIN Director David Evans told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>The surprise departure of WIN chief executive Michael Heath this week to return to the U.S. for personal reasons would not delay the project's development, Evans added.</p>
<p>WIN is owned by six of the world's largest insurance brokers -- Alexander &amp; Alexander, Aon Group, Johnson &amp; Higgins, Marsh &amp; McLennan, Sedgwick and Willis Corroon.</p>
<p>It is expected to result in a major efficiency breakthrough for the international insurance broking industry and will lead to significant cost savings.</p>
<p>&quot;Bearing in mind that brokers in particular are heavily dependent on message and document exchange, we think that this is the right step in enabling us to have inter enterprise communications within the industry,' Evans said.</p>
<p>The main project developers are British Telecommunications and MCI.</p>
<p>Evans described investment as &quot;substantial&quot;, but declined to give a figure for the project, which was launched last November with a staff of three and currently employs 40 people.</p>
<p>Staff numbers are not expected to rise above this level, as WIN will buy in expertise as needed.</p>
<p>Evans, who also works for Alexander &amp; Alexander, and Sedgwick's Richard Wales will act as full time chief executives until a replacement for Heath is found, Evans said.</p>
<p>The new chief executive will probably have a background in financial services beyond insurance broking, he added.</p>
<p>WIN currently plans a two stage development programme, the first involving document exchange and electronic mail, while the second will deal with much more advanced electronic commerce, Evans said.</p>
<p>&quot;For the second level of products we need to do more work with the insurance carriers. We've had a lot of discussion with a number of very large international insurers, many of whom are anxious to participate in WIN once we've released the terms of trade, which we've not done yet, but it's impending,&quot; Evans said.</p>
<p>This stage will use existing industry standards and will have significant implications for back office operations.</p>
<p>-- John Sanders, Reuters Insurance News 44 171 542 2769</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
