<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10918" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Soccer-Arab team breaks new ground in Israel.</title>
<headline>Soccer-Arab team breaks new ground in Israel.</headline>
<byline>Ori Lewis</byline>
<dateline>TAIBE, Israel 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>For the first time in Israeli history, an Arab team will take the field when the National League soccer season starts on Saturday.</p>
<p>Hapoel Taibe fields four Jewish players and two foreign imports -- a Pole and a Romanian. The rest of the side is made up mainly of Moslem Arabs.</p>
<p>The club, founded in 1961, has a loyal following in Taibe, an Arab town of 28,000 in the heart of Israel.</p>
<p>But away from their home ground, they face unfriendly crowds who taunt the players with racist abuse.</p>
<p>&quot;The very first thing we thought about after we knew we would be promoted was the game against Betar Jerusalem,&quot; said Taibe supporter Karem Haj Yihye.</p>
<p>Two weeks ago Taibe, coached by Pole Wojtek Lazarek, met Betar, a club closely associated with the right-wing Likud party, for the first time in a Cup match in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Chants from the crowd of &quot;Death to the Arabs&quot;, and bottle-throwing during the game marred the match which ended in a goalless draw.</p>
<p>One Taibe supporter required hospital treatment for cuts and bruises after a stone struck his head as he was driving from the stadium.</p>
<p>&quot;We're used to hearing the taunts of &quot;Death to the Arabs',&quot; said Sameh Haj Yihye, a Taibe resident who studies at Jerusalem's Hebrew University. &quot;But we know that these are only words, nobody has died from hearing them and it only makes us support our team more vehemently.&quot;</p>
<p>The dusty town of Taibe lacks the amenities of Jewish communities and many Israeli Arabs have long complained of state discrimination.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no parks or empty areas of land around here, so when we want to play a friendly game of soccer we all load up in the car and travel to Tel Aviv,&quot; 60 km (36 miles) away, Sameh Haj Yihye said.</p>
<p>The town's ramshackle 2,500-seat ground is accessible only by two dirt tracks.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan to build a 10,000-seat stadium, but it may well be situated elsewhere,&quot; said club chairman Abdul Rahman Haj Yihye. &quot;We will discuss this with the mayor and hopefully a new or refurbished ground will be completed by the start of the new year.&quot;</p>
<p>In the meantime, Taibe will play all their heavily policed home matches at the Jewish coastal town of Netanya.</p>
<p>&quot;We are Israelis, there is no question about that,&quot; said Karem Haj Yihye, a hotel waiter.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't have any connection with the Palestinians, they live over there,&quot; he said, pointing to the West Bank seven km (four miles) to the east.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't feel our club represents Palestinian Arabs,&quot; said club chairman Abdul Rahman. &quot;We are trying to do all we can to run a professional outfit, we are pleased at any support we get, but do not go out looking to represent the whole Arab world.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIBE, Israel"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
