<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10916" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Golf: Norman sacks his coach after disappointing season.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Golf: Norman sacks his coach after disappointing season.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>World number one golfer Greg Norman has sacked his coach Butch Harmon after a disappointing season.</p>
<p>&quot;Butch and I are finished,&quot; Norman told reporters on Thursday before the start of the World Series of Golf in Akron, Ohio.</p>
<p>Norman, a two-time British Open champion, parted ways with his long-time mentor after drawing a blank in this year's four majors, winning two tournaments worldwide.</p>
<p>The blonde Australian opened with a level par round of 70 in Akron, leaving him four shots adrift of the leaders, Americans Billy Mayfair and Paul Goydos and Japan's Hidemichi Tanaki.</p>
<p>On Wednesday Norman described this year as his worst on the professional circuit since 1991, when he failed to win a tournament.</p>
<p>&quot;My application this year has been strange,&quot; Norman said. &quot;Maybe I haven't been as keyed up as I should have been.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Sometimes you don't have it in your head to play. Maybe this was one of those years where I was there, but I wasn't 100 percent there, and you have to be 100 percent to perform,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
