<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10912" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dlr bumps along lows in featureless late Europe.</title>
<headline>Dlr bumps along lows in featureless late Europe.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar remained in tight ranges by late European trade, bumping along the session lows and unruffled by a jump in U.S. July durable goods orders.</p>
<p>The orders rose 1.6 percent against an average forecast of a 0.3 percent rise and a revised figure of a 0.2 percent fall in June.</p>
<p>Ex-transportation the figure was up 2.1 percent and ex-defence orders it rose 3.5 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said the data was a good indication that the U.S. economy was improving but cautioned over the volatility of the data and its influence on Federal Reserve monetary policy.  </p>
<p>Dealers here bemoaned the dollar's inability to break higher after Thursday's hefty Bundesbank repo cut.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar had a perfect opportunity to go up after the repo cut but it couldn't break through the congestion from the last few weeks,&quot; said Alan Collins, head of technical analysis at Merita Bank. This resistance is around 1.4950-60 marks.</p>
<p>While the repo cut had an impact on the mark in the short-term, it got support from the perception that this could be the last in the German easing cycle and from expectations of fiscal and structural economic problems during the forthcoming 1997 European budget negotiations.  </p>
<p>But some uncertainty remains over whether the Bundesbank could cut again and this period of post-repo cut calm may bring some of Europe's high-yielders back into fashion.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people still see the chance for further cuts, or at least a period of German rate stablility, and over the next few days we'll start to see high-yielders being picked up again,&quot; said a dealer at a British merchant bank.</p>
<p>By 1518 GMT, the dollar was trading at 1.4865/67 marks against a session high of 1.4930 and from late Thursday's level of 1.4958/63 marks. Dollar/yen stood at 108.48/58 against 108.41/51 on Thursday.  </p>
<p>Japan's quarterly Tankan survey is due next Wednesday but analysts said that only an extremely strong report would change the outlook for steady Japanese interest rates.</p>
<p>Against the yen, the mark was firming to its session highs in late Europe, trading at 72.95/97 from its morning levels around 72.60 yen and from late Thursday's 72.47/50 yen.</p>
<p>The mark was steady but off the day's highs on the crosses in late trade, and dealers attributed much of the day's activity to the crosses rather than the dollar.</p>
<p>Mark/lira stood at 1018.45/85 from 1017.25/75 Thursday. Mark/French franc was at 3.4132/36 against 3.4077/80.  </p>
<p>The Swiss franc was stronger against the mark and dollar by late trade after the Swiss National Bank reiterated that it is still &quot;generous&quot; with money market rates after resisting the European trend to lower key interest rates.</p>
<p>Dollar/Swiss franc stood at 1.2022/27 from 1.2095/05 and mark/Swiss was trading at 80.82/85 centimes against 80.85/88 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Denmark, Finland and Portugal cut key money rates today, citing moderate inflation and the trend in Europe to ease rates.</p>
<p>-- Andrew Reierson, London Newsroom +44 171 542 6745</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
