<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10934" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: CWB sees malt barley price up on China, S. America.</title>
<headline>CWB sees malt barley price up on China, S. America.</headline>
<dateline>WINNIPEG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chinese and Latin American demand for western Canadian malting barley should raise prices in crop year 1996/97 (Aug/July), CWB market analyst Larry Sawatzky said.</p>
<p>&quot;We raised our PRO (Pool Return Outlook) because of continued strong demand from Asia and South America, China in particular. China is our largest two-row malting barley export market,&quot; Sawatzky said.</p>
<p>Select Two-Row Canada Western Designated Barley PROs for August were revised up C$0.09 a bushel to the C$230-250 a tonne range from last month's C$226-246 a tonne range.</p>
<p>Reduced European exports of two-row barley and lower Australian sales in the last crop year allowed the CWB to make market share gains in Colombia and Brazil.</p>
<p>Chinese and Latin American maltsters buy two-row barley because it has a higher extraction rate than six-row, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the Chinese may be eating a little less of our bread, they're drinking a little more of our beer,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Select Six-Row Canada Western Designated Barley PROs, however, were left unchanged Thursday at C$191-211 a tonne.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. is our major market for six row. We're want to see what happens with the quality of their crop,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Gilbert Le Gras 204 947 3548</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINNIPEG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
