<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10937" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Adventure fanatics prepare for race of a lifetime.</title>
<headline>Adventure fanatics prepare for race of a lifetime.</headline>
<byline>Cynthia Osterman</byline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER, British Columbia 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>About 360 adventurers from nine countries will trek glaciers, climb mountains, whitewater raft, horseback ride, canoe and mountain bike on a gruelling 300-mile (480 km) endurance race starting on Saturday in Canada's rugged wilderness.</p>
<p>Those taking part include a 73-year-old great-grandmother, U.S. Air Force fighter pilots, bankers, students, housewives and a former fashion model.</p>
<p>The event, called the Eco-Challenge, is part of a growing sport known as adventure racing in which competitors push themselves to their limits for days over a perilous wilderness course, finding their way by compass and barely stopping to sleep.</p>
<p>Organisers expect about two-thirds of the participants to drop out or be disqualified before the finish. The hardy ones are expected to complete the course in about six days with first-place finishers receiving $10,000 in prize money.</p>
<p>The Eco-Challenge has been staged twice before -- in Utah and Maine last year -- and is modelled on similar races overseas, notably the Raid Gauloises which began in France.</p>
<p>This year the Eco-Challenge is being held in the Coast Mountains north of Vancouver on Canada's west coast, an area filled with treacherous peaks, ice fields and frigid waters. The exact location of the course is kept secret until hours before the race begins.</p>
<p>While the endurance test may sound like hell on earth to many, it is the adventure of a lifetime for 54-year-old California finance executive Jim Newman who has trained nearly a year for the race.</p>
<p>&quot;You do this for the love of it ... It becomes a high point in your life,&quot; said Newman.</p>
<p>Former British fashion model Sarah Odell has competed in seven such races from Patagonia to Borneo and finds the sport addictive. &quot;You get moments where you are miserable ... but it's incredible. I love the competitive atmosphere.&quot;</p>
<p>In the Eco-Challenge, competitors race in teams of five which must include both men and women. Team members must remain within 100 yards (meters) of each another at all times and finish together.</p>
<p>With racers carrying about 40 pounds (18 kg) of gear on their backs, broken bones, sunstroke, dehydration and exhaustion are common.</p>
<p>Organisers monitor competitors at checkpoints every 10 miles (16 km) and from helicopters. Racers also carry radios for use in emergency.</p>
<p>While participants must be in top condition, the competition is billed as a tougher psychological test than a physical one.  &quot;The challenge of crisis management and interpersonal relationships defeats teams far sooner than the physicality of it,&quot; said Eco-Challenge founder and former British paratrooper Mark Burnett.</p>
<p>In spite of the sport's increasing popularity, it is not without critics. Some environmentalists worry competitors may damage fragile wilderness while other opponents deride it as overly commercial because of heavy corporate sponsorship.</p>
<p>The Eco-Challenge bills itself as environmentally friendly and its rules forbid teams from leaving behind any food, supplies or waste. That means participants must even pack out their own excrement.</p>
<p>Teams have to pay an entry fee of $10,000. Other costs, including travel and equipment expenses, can add an extra $40,000 to the total, prompting many participants to canvass corporate sponsors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER, British Columbia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
