<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10932" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Durum prices hinge on harvest quality - CWB analyst.</title>
<headline>Durum prices hinge on harvest quality - CWB analyst.</headline>
<dateline>WINNIPEG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>World durum prices will hinge on conditions leading up to North America's harvest that affect the crop's protein content, a Canadian Wheat Board market analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;The concern with the North American durum crop is it's still susceptible to an early frost,&quot; CWB analyst Larry Sawatzky said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Environment Canada's 10-day frost outlook Friday called for slight frost risks on the northeast Prairie grainbelt Sunday and Monday, then in central Alberta's foothills Tuesday and next weekend.  </p>
<p>Harvest should be general between August 30 and September 6.</p>
<p>&quot;There haven't been any major changes in the world durum market in the past month. Crop prospects still look quite good in the major exporting regions, Canada, the U.S. and Europe,&quot; Sawatzky added.</p>
<p>The CWB left its world price projection for No1 Canada Western Amber Durum unchanged Thursday at the C$210-C$240 a tonne range in crop year 1996/97 (Aug/July).  </p>
<p>The forecast is still well below June's estimate of the CWB's final price for 1995/96 which sets Manitoba farmgate prices at C$7.03 a bushel compared to the August estimate for the current crop year of C$5.17 a bushel, he said.</p>
<p>North Africa's durum wheat crop was estimated to be twice the size of last year's drought-cut crop, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The rain in France (which may reduce protein content) might have an impact but not a big enough impact for us to change the PRO (Pool Return Outlook) right now,&quot; Sawatzky said.</p>
<p>&quot;If there are quality problems, then protein premiums for durum could go way up,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Gilbert Le Gras 204 947 3548</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINNIPEG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
