<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10948" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Rwandan group says expulsions could be imminent.</title>
<headline>Rwandan group says expulsions could be imminent.</headline>
<byline>Buchizya Mseteka</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Repatriation of 1.1 million Rwandan Hutu refugees announced by Zaire and Rwanda could start within a few days, an exiled Rwandan Hutu lobby group said on Friday.</p>
<p>Innocent Butare, executive secretary of the Rally for the Return of Refugees and Democracy in Rwanda (RDR) which says it has the support of Rwanda's exiled Hutus, appealed to the international community to deter the two countries from going ahead with what it termed a &quot;forced and inhuman action&quot;.</p>
<p>The RDR has the support of Rwanda's 40,000-strong former Hutu army which moved into Zaire in 1994 with the refugees after the Tutsi-dominated Rwanda Patriotic Front (RPF) took power.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a lot of fear, fear for our people. They (Rwanda and Zaire) have done it before and they will do it again. Our information is forced repatriations will start within the next few days,&quot; Butare told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the expulsions would be against international laws and had to be prevented by the international community.</p>
<p>&quot;Like before, our people will be sent back against their will and they will be treated without any dignity or concerns for their safety,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We appeal to the international community to do everyting in its power to deter the two countries from going ahead with the expulsions,&quot; Butare added.</p>
<p>The U.N. refugee agency said on Friday it was not consulted by Rwanda and Zaire over the planned repatriation of the refugees, many of whom refuse to return because of fears they will be punished for their involvement in the 1994 genocide.</p>
<p>Roman Urasa, head of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) in Rwanda, said in a statement that UNHCR was taking Thursday's announcement by Zairean Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo and Rwandan Prime Minister Pierre Celestin Rwigema seriously.</p>
<p>He expressed hope that repatriation would be voluntary.</p>
<p>&quot;We were not consulted about this and although there have been a lot of statements from Zaire, one has to take into account the fact that this has been done at prime ministerial level,&quot; Urasa said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are therefore treating it with more seriousness. What is important is the interpretation of the word 'immediately'.&quot;</p>
<p>Kengo told a joint news conference with Rwigema in Rwanda's capital Kigali on Thursday the repatriation operation would begin with the closure of all Rwandan refugee camps in Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;The two heads of government have decided to make operational the organised, massive and unconditional repatriation of all Rwandan refugees,&quot; Kengo said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is going to be carried out rapidly. The repatriation will be enormous and immediate. We are at a stage where Zaire is going to proceed with the closure of the camps,&quot; Kengo added.</p>
<p>Kengo was visiting Rwanda as it received thousands of Rwandan Hutu refugees leaving its southern neighbour Burundi.</p>
<p>Butare said the returning Rwandan refugees were subjected to harassment, beatings and many had been sent to prison.</p>
<p>&quot;Our people are being treated worse than cows. The security situation in Rwanda is deteriorating by the day and in such an environment, people cannot expect justice,&quot; Butare said.</p>
<p>Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko has intervened in the past two years to stop Kengo from ordering, in violation of international law, the deportation of the 1.1 million Rwandans.</p>
<p>Last August, Zairean troops forcibly expelled some 15,000 Rwandan and Burundian Hutus. The expulsions were stopped only after Mobutu stepped in following an international outcry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
