<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10947" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: More than 800 Rwandan refugees return from Burundi.</title>
<headline>More than 800 Rwandan refugees return from Burundi.</headline>
<byline>Christian Jennings</byline>
<dateline>BUTARE, Rwanda 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than 800 Rwandan Hutu refugees returned to Rwanda on Friday, ending two years in exile and leaving only 11,000 in the last Rwandan refugee camp in Burundi.</p>
<p>Paul Stromberg, spokesman for the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR), said 825 Rwandan refugees returned to Rwanda from Rukuramigabo camp as well as 600 who left on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;That leaves fewer than 11,000 in Rukuramigabo. The bulk of the returnees went towards Butare but 50 went to (Rwanda's capital) Kigali,&quot; said Stromberg, speaking by telephone from Burundi.</p>
<p>Rukuramigabo is the sole remaining Rwandan refugee camp in Burundi since an operation to return 50,000 refugees to neighbouring Rwanda from Magara camp was completed on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We just have to empty Rukuramigabo and then the Rwandan refugee problem in Burundi will be over,&quot; said an aid official.</p>
<p>&quot;I did not move out of Burundi before because I really thought the army in Rwanda would lock me up and torture me for being a Hutu,&quot; said Dative Ngendahuriyo, sitting aboard a UNHCR bus waiting for it to start on the trip to her home commune.</p>
<p>&quot;There came a moment when so many people went back I just followed. That's how I decided things for the past two years,&quot; she added, sitting alongside a plastic bucket, a blanket, plastic sheeting, a sack of maize and a hoe donated by agencies.</p>
<p>&quot;I just seem to have been waiting in line for two years,&quot; said Athanase Murenhije at Musange transit camp near Butare. &quot;That's all you do in a refugee camp, just wait and hear lies.&quot;</p>
<p>Up to 6,000 returnees -- some with goats, chickens and ducks -- left Musange transit camp on Friday for their home districts to make space for a new influx from northern Burundi.</p>
<p>The return of some 66,000 Rwandan refugees from Burundi since July is the biggest mass movement in the region since two million Rwandan Hutus flooded out of Rwanda to Tanzania, Burundi and Zaire in 1994 during three months of genocide and civil war.</p>
<p>Many of the refugees refused to go home, saying they feared attacks in reprisal for the genocide. They changed their minds after the Tutsi-dominated Burundi army seized power on July 25.</p>
<p>There were a total of 88,000 Rwandan refugees in four camps in Burundi in June and some 135,000 at the start of the year.</p>
<p>Stephano Severe, head of the UNHCR office in Butare, said: &quot;The operation has gone well and I would like to think if this happens in Zaire we could move in the same way,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rwanda and Zaire said on Thursday they planned to repatriate 1.1 million Rwandan refugees in eastern Zaire in an operation that would begin immediately with closure of all refugee camps.</p>
<p>UNHCR was not consulted about the decision and a refugee lobby group said on Friday it feared forced expulsions of Hutu refugees from eastern Zaire could start within a few days.</p>
<p>Officials said 223 Hutu refugees who refused to leave Magara for Rwanda on Thursday spent the night in the otherwise empty camp in north Burundi and were interviewed by UNHCR on Friday.</p>
<p>The U.N. Human Rights office in Rwanda said on Thursday 271 Rwandan refugees who returned from Burundi in July and August were arrested by Rwandan authorities and 62 were released.</p>
<p>Rwandan authorities screen returning refugees and arrest any suspected of involvement in the 1994 genocide of up to a million Tutsis and Hutu moderates by Hutu troops, militiamen and mobs.</p>
<p>The London-based human rights group Amnesty International accuses the Burundian army of forcing the Rwandan refugees back by using torture and extrajudicial executions to terrorise them.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUTARE, Rwanda"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
