<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10942" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada Prairie harvest seen general in 7-14 days.</title>
<headline>Canada Prairie harvest seen general in 7-14 days.</headline>
<dateline>WINNIPEG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swathing of western Prairie crops began with the harvest expected to become general across the region in seven to 14 days,  Pioneer Grain Co Ltd said in its crop report for the week ended August 21.</p>
<p>British Columbia's Dawson Creek region reported some swathing of canola and barley in the past week with most fields seven to 10 days behind. Frost in late August was a serious concern.</p>
<p>Alberta farmers began swathing their crops with some harvesting in the south while parts of the north needed another week for the crop to finish ripening.  </p>
<p>Northwest Saskatchewan reported more than 90 percent of cereals and canola completed filling with some swathing of early barley and canola fields. Average to slightly above quality and yields were forecast barring an early frost.</p>
<p>North central Saskatchewan reported most crops at 10 to 15 days from harvest.</p>
<p>In the north, most cereals and canola were 85 percent filled and about three percent of cereals and five percent of canola was swathed.</p>
<p>In the south, most crops finished filling with five to 10 percent of canola swathed.  </p>
<p>Yields were forecast to be average to above average with harvest becoming general in two weeks.</p>
<p>Northeast Saskatchewan reported 85 percent of cereals filled, with oats at 75 percent. Eighty-five percent of canola and 80 percent of flax finished filling. Crops were rated good to excellent with yields forecast at average to above average and harvest becoming general in two weeks.</p>
<p>Southwest Saskatchewan swathed 15 percent of wheat and durum, 40 percent of barley and oats. Despite initial fears of reduced yields on low moisture, preliminary yield estimates were reported at above average for most of the region.</p>
<p>Southeast Saskatchewan swathed 10 to 20 percent of its crops with a small amount of harvesting done.</p>
<p>Eastern Saskatchewan and western Manitoba reported slower ripening on cool weather. Swathing was expected in one week.</p>
<p>Manitoba should begin swathing cereals and canola in the south next week. All regions reportd crops in good conditions with average yields expected. The extent of fusarium damage won't be known until harvest time, the report said.</p>
<p>-- Gilbert Le Gras 204 947 3548</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINNIPEG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
