<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10945" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Rwanda says it seeks orderly return of refugees.</title>
<headline>Rwanda says it seeks orderly return of refugees.</headline>
<byline>Buchizya Mseteka</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rwanda on Friday poured scorn on charges it wanted the expulsion of 1.1 million Rwandan Hutu refugees from Zaire, saying it sought an orderly, decent and well-organised return.</p>
<p>Emmanuel Ndahiro, senior aide to Rwandan strongman and Vice-President Major-General Paul Kagame, told Reuters by telephone from Kigali that despite agreement with Zaire no time frame was set for the operation.</p>
<p>He dismissed as &quot;pure propaganda&quot; charges by a Rwandan Hutu lobby group that Zaire and Rwanda planned to start a &quot;forced and inhuman&quot; repatriation of the refugees within the next few days.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody (in Rwanda) is advocating an abrupt return of the refugees. The return should be orderly, decent and well-organised because not even powerful America can afford to take in one million people at once,&quot; Ndahiro said.</p>
<p>In Kinshasa, a delegate of the United Nations refugee agency said an agreement between the Zairean and Rwandan prime ministers did not set a time limit for the refugees' return.</p>
<p>Hubert Edongo Menye, UNHCR regional delegate for Central Africa, said he would meet Interior Minister Gerard Kamanda wa Kamanda on Saturday to discuss Thursday's agreement to send the refugees home.</p>
<p>&quot;This repatriation is a large scale operation, both costly and dangerous, which must take account of the dignity and safety of the refugees,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said a joint communique issued after the prime ministers' Kigali meeting had talked about the &quot;progressive closure&quot; of refugee camps in eastern Zaire, an operation which he said would need the support of the international community.</p>
<p>Menye said the communique had set no time limit, but added: &quot;If the conditions are met, the refugees can be repatriated.&quot;</p>
<p>The exiled Rally for the Return of Refugees and Democracy in Rwanda (RDR) appealed on Friday to the international community to help stop Zaire forcibly expelling its Rwandan Hutu refugees.</p>
<p>The RDR, which has the support of Rwanda's 40,000-strong former Hutu army which moved into Zaire in 1994 with the refugees after Kagame's Tutsi-dominated Rwanda Patriotic Front took power, said it feared for the safety of Hutus in Rwanda.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a lot of fear, fear for our people. They (Rwanda and Zaire) have done it before and they will do it again. Our information is forced repatriations will start within the next few days,&quot; said RDR Executive Secretary Innocent Butare.</p>
<p>But Ndahiro said careful planning was essential to avoid logistical problems and a humanitarian crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;For a million people plus, you need to plan carefully, you need to ensure they are handled decently. If you do things abruptly then you risk running into the same chaos that characterised their exit in 1994,&quot; Ndahiro said.</p>
<p>The 1.1 million refugees in eastern Zaire are part of two million Randans who fled at the end of three months of civil war after the 1994 genocide of up to a million people by Hutus.</p>
<p>Zairean Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo told a news conference with his Rwandan counterpart on Thursday the operation would begin with the closure of all Rwandan refugee camps in Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;The two heads of government have decided to make operational the organised, massive and unconditional repatriation of all Rwandan refugees,&quot; Kengo said in Kigali.</p>
<p>&quot;This is going to be carried out rapidly. The repatriation will be enormous and immediate. We are at a stage where Zaire is going to proceed with the closure of the camps,&quot; Kengo added.</p>
<p>Asked whether he believed that Zaire, which threatened in the past to expel all the Rwandan Hutus, would keep its deal with Rwanda, Ndahiro said: &quot;Your guess is as good as mine.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We have had several meetings with Zaire in the past...but we hope this time they will keep their word,&quot; Ndahiro said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
