<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10961" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UGANDA: Weak coffee price lowers Uganda export income.</title>
<headline>Weak coffee price lowers Uganda export income.</headline>
<byline>Edmond Kizito</byline>
<dateline>KAMPALA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Uganda's export earnings fell by nearly 4.0 percent in the financial year to June 30 because of weak world prices for its key coffee exports, the Finance Ministry said on Friday.</p>
<p>Export revenue fell to $555.3 million in 1995/96 from $577.5 million the year before, the ministry said in a report.</p>
<p>&quot;The major factor behind the decline in overall exports was the sharp drop in the world prices of coffee, after more than doubling between the period 1993/94 and 1994/95,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;The big increase in the volume of coffee exports of about 32.5 percent in 1995/96 over the previous year was not enough to compensate fully for the fall in prices,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Uganda's coffee exports in 1995/96 rose to 3.84 million 60-kg (132 lb) bags from 2.89 million in the previous year due to better weather and the maturing of a new prolific coffee type planted three years ago, according to official records.</p>
<p>But low world prices meant coffee exports fetched only $392.61 million in 1995/96, compared with $442.16 million in 1994/95, the records showed.</p>
<p>Despite this, coffee contributed a high 70.0 percent of Uganda's total export revenues, even though this was down from 76.6 percent the year before, the ministry said.</p>
<p>Uganda has been trying to boost other exports like cotton, tea, tobacco and flowers to make its reviving economy less dependent on world coffee prices.</p>
<p>In 1995/96, rising export earners included fish, second only to coffee, and bringing in $29.88 million, up from $16.99 million in 1994/95, the report said.</p>
<p>Other key exports were cotton, $12.16 million; hides and skins, $9.65 million; tobacco, $9.24 million; tea, $8.75 million, cereals $7.71 million and beans $6.73 million.</p>
<p>The government is trying to promote exports of vanilla, flowers, oil seeds, cocoa, animal skins, silkworm and tropical fruits as an alternative to the &quot;traditional&quot; export crops.</p>
<p>But production of these remains low, and economists say it will be a long time before they make a serious contribution.</p>
<p>Coffee is expected to dominate this year's exports too. Industry analysts say coffee exports for the current crop year (October-September), will rise to 3.8 million bags from 2.76 million in the last year, and could climb to 4.2 million bags in 1996/97, they say.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UGANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KAMPALA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UGANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
