<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10965" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FORECAST - Iscor steeled for grim results.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Iscor steeled for grim results.</headline>
<byline>Charles Phahlane</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African steel giant Iscor Ltd will post weak results on Tuesday, dented by poor domestic demand and low international steel prices, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Their results will be downright poor, to put it bluntly. The problem is the steel price. They have taken a major knock from it,&quot; one analyst, who declined to be identified, said.</p>
<p>Other industry observers agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;Steel consumption is lower. Last year we had big construction going on but this year it is quiet. There is no relief from the RDP (Reconstruction and Development Programme). Steel prices are also at their lowest in real terms in years,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>A Reuters poll of analysts forecast earnings per share at a 29.7 cent consensus, with a range between 26.0 and 32.0 cents, down from 38.00 cents last year. The dividend was put at 15.0 versus 16.5, with the range between 14.5 and 16.5 cents.</p>
<p>The devaluation of the rand, which has lost over a fifth of its value against the dollar since mid-February, could have helped improve exports but Iscor lost out by forward sales of dollars, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;They have only started to unwind some of their forex positions now...They were well covered in their financial year to June. So they won't get much of a boost from the rand right now,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>Iscor issued a profit warning in May that the downswing in the commodity cycle would dampen results in the second half and the fall in export dollar prices had been steeper than expected since the announcement of its interim results.</p>
<p>But it said a weak rand was expected to discourage imports and encourage domestic sales.</p>
<p>Analysts said domestic steel sales depended largely on the state of the economy as further weakness in the rand would adversely affect domestic sales.</p>
<p>&quot;With the pressure to increase (interest) rates I see a potential for domestic sales to weaken,&quot; another analyst said, adding that domestic sales would be down by about 10 percent in the June year-end.</p>
<p>Iscor's mine operation was seen posting good results but it only accounted for a fraction of Iscor's profits, analysts said.</p>
<p>Analysts said asset sales by Iscor in the second half would also help.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
