<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10967" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Mauritius shares shed Wednesday's gains.</title>
<headline>Mauritius shares shed Wednesday's gains.</headline>
<byline>Mike Chung</byline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The share index at the Stock Exchange of Mauritius (Semdex) lost 2.56 points to 321.63 on Friday in a market that lacked clear direction, brokers and floor dealers said.</p>
<p>The index lost Wednesday's gains and was back on Monday's levels. The Mauritius bourse trades on Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays.</p>
<p>Turnover was provisionally posted at 4.50 million rupees on 144,997 shares versus 8.05 million rupees on 260,094 shares on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The Semdex went up on Wednesday on the rising shares of State Bank of Mauritius and Air Mauritius. But it went down again under the weight of the same stocks which fell today (Friday),&quot; a share analyst said.</p>
<p>State Bank of Mauritius lost 10 cents to 8.40 rupees on 33,795 shares and Air Mauritius slumped 3.50 rupees to 51.50 rupees on 2,480 shares.</p>
<p>The up and down &quot;yoyo&quot; trend of these leading shares over the week reflected the absence of a general clear market direction and the low liquidity of stocks as investors remain on the sidelines, one dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the present market conditions, a relatively small volume can push prices in any one direction,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The uncertainty prevailing around an imminent cabinet reshuffle announced by the prime minister when former Finance Minister Rundheersing Bheenick resigned two weeks ago is seen as the major cause behind such subdued market mood.</p>
<p>Most of Friday's volume was again concentrated in deals on leading shares while the rest of the market attracted less volume in the absence of general investor interest.</p>
<p>Mauritius Commercial Bank, which accounted for around half of the volume, was unchanged at 73 rupees on 29,362 shares.</p>
<p>Building materials manufacturer United Basalt Products gained 40 cents to 25.50 rupees on 75 shares.</p>
<p>Investment-based United Docks remained at 40.50 rupees on 9,010 shares and National Investment Trust was stable at 12.50 rupees on 10,000 shares.</p>
<p>Conglomerates Rogers was unchanged at 94.50 rupees on 1,300 shares and Ireland Blyth lost 10 cents to 13.40 rupees on 2,288 shares.</p>
<p>Oil company Shell Mauritius surged 70 cents to 16.20 rupees on 1,040 shares while hotel concern Sun Resorts dropped 50 cents to 35.50 rupees on 25,322 shares.</p>
<p>-- Port Louis ++230 212-6870</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
