<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10964" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UGANDA: Ugandan rebels abduct 300 civilians, army says.</title>
<headline>Ugandan rebels abduct 300 civilians, army says.</headline>
<dateline>KAMPALA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ugandan rebels abducted 300 civilians, including school pupils, from northern Uganda before crossing into southern Sudan, army officers said on Friday.</p>
<p>They said about 150 rebels of the Lord's Resistance Army (LRA) led by its leader Joseph Kony crossed near Palabek, a border town in the northern district of Kitgum on Monday night.</p>
<p>&quot;Some 39 of the captives were students abducted from the Sir Samuel Baker Secondary school. The rebels crossed at full speed ahead of our troops who tried to catch up with them,&quot; an officer told Reuters.</p>
<p>Speaking by telephone from Gulu, 345 (215 miles) north of Kampala and the main army base fighting the insurgency, the officer said the rebels narrowly escaped an army ambush as they moved north.</p>
<p>&quot;We nearly got them, but they detected us and forked to the east before escaping between our lines into Sudan,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The LRA rebels, who say they want to rule Uganda in line with the Bible's 10 Commandments, returned to their bases in Sudan after entering Uganda on July 8, according to the army.</p>
<p>The army says the rebels killed 108 Sudanese refugees at a camp near Kitgum and moved to Gulu district, where they killed more than 500 people in raids on villages, army and police posts and by landmines.</p>
<p>The rebellion has disrupted the north, which has nearly four million people. Schools, hospitals, and government offices have closed in most areas outside Gulu, northern politicians say.</p>
<p>Up to 180,000 civilians are holed up in the town after fleeing villages to escape LRA attacks, reporters in Gulu said.</p>
<p>President Yoweri Museveni, himself a former guerrilla, has ruled out talks with the rebels and vowed to defeat them.</p>
<p>Sudan's government denies backing the LRA and giving it bases and accuses Uganda of supporting Sudanese rebel forces.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UGANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KAMPALA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UGANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
