<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10977" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>LIBERIA: Liberia's new leader arrives with warlord Johnson.</title>
<headline>Liberia's new leader arrives with warlord Johnson.</headline>
<byline>Jackson Kanneh</byline>
<dateline>MONROVIA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Liberia's new woman head of state has returned to Monrovia with the faction leader at the centre of fighting earlier this year, promising the latest peace accord will bring peace and reconciliation.</p>
<p>Hundreds of supporters, including several women's organisations, cheered Ruth Perry and Roosevelt Johnson as they disembarked from a Nigerian airforce plane on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I bring with me love, unity, reconciliation and peace for Liberia,&quot; Perry told the crowd, who booed the outgoing chairman of the ruling Council of State, Wilton Sankawulo.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't do it alone, but with the support and assurances of my colleagues and us all, I am sure the war is now over,&quot; Perry added.</p>
<p>West African heads of state and Liberian faction leaders meeting in the Nigeria appointed Perry on Saturday as part of a new peace accord which sets a timetable for disarmament by the end of January and elections on or around May 30 next year.</p>
<p>The latest agreement threatens faction leaders with sanctions, including seizure of assets and war crimes tribunals, if they are seen to be obstructing the peace process.</p>
<p>Faction leaders have accused each other of breaking a ceasefire which was supposed to come into force on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Perry told reporters she would travel to Grand Cape Mount, her home county in western Liberia, to halt clashes reported there between Johnson's supporters and fighters loyal to council member Alhaji Kromah.</p>
<p>&quot;Both Alhaji Kromah and General Johnson have asked me to go to Cape Mount personally to make peace and I am going to go to Cape Mount as the first place to make a move,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Perry, 57, was a Liberian senator during the 1980s under the government of slain president Samuel Doe.</p>
<p>Over a dozen peace deals have failed to end the war launched by Charles Taylor and his National Patriotic Front of Liberia (NPFL) in late 1989. Taylor and Kromah are both vice-chairmen on the Council of State.</p>
<p>Their attempt to arrest Johnson for murder in April triggered some of the bloodiest fighting of the war in the streets of Monrovia, pitting Johnson's ULIMO-J faction and its ethnic Krahn allies against Taylor and Kromah.</p>
<p>Health officials estimate that some 1,200 people were killed in seven weeks of fighting in the city centre.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONROVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LIBERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
