<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10973" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Shares edge higher at Nairobi bourse.</title>
<headline>Shares edge higher at Nairobi bourse.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Nairobi Stock Exchange (NSE) 20-share index marginally corrected as stock prices appeared to recover across the board, brokers and floor dealers said.</p>
<p>The index rose 4.40 points to stand at 3069.29. Turnover was posted at 13.014 million shillings on 524,285 shares from 28.060 million shillings on 1,063,168 shares on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Share prices for most counters edged slightly higher as there was good demand for stocks across the board,&quot; a bourse official said.</p>
<p>There was demand for the national carrier Kenya Airways which led to its slight recovery but traded volumes were still thin as there was not enough supply. Most speculators were still holding back their Kenya Airways shares after a few bad weeks, a floor dealer said.</p>
<p>Kenya Airways traded 44,818 shares at 10.10 from 10, Nation Printers &amp; Publishers rose 2.0 to 103 and CMC Holdings fell to 60 from 61.</p>
<p>Among the plantations, Brooke Bond rose to 175 from 173, Rea Vipingo traded 32,088 shares at 11.40, 11.20 and 11.30 from 11.25 and Sasini Tea &amp; Coffee rose 2.0 shillings to 53.</p>
<p>Financial stocks were the most actively dealt. There was good trading for most of the counters but the best performance was in the National Bank of Kenya.</p>
<p>National Bank continued to dominate market trading with a total of 303,812 shares dealt at 18.50, down to 16.50, and bounced back to 17.15 from 18 shillings previously.</p>
<p>Housing Finance Company of Kenya rose to 26 from 25, Kenya Commercial Bank of Kenya gained to 56 from 55 and Standard Chartered Bank rose to 47 from 46.25.</p>
<p>Oil concern Total Kenya rose a shilling to 76.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
