<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10972" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Foreigners want lower p/e to buy S.African shares.</title>
<headline>Foreigners want lower p/e to buy S.African shares.</headline>
<byline>Melanie Cheary</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deterred by rand volatility and political anxieties, foreign investors are holding out for cheaper ratings before plunging back into the South African share market, analysts and fund managers said on Friday.</p>
<p>Even commodity and industrial shares -- whose export earnings stand to win most from the rand's fall -- look too expensive against a backdrop of fading faith in the government's ability to deliver its promised economic miracle, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our market is in a de-rating phase from an international point of view,&quot; said Denzil Newman, portfolio manager at Syfrets Asset Management in Cape Town.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreigners believe our p/e (price earnings) ratios should be lower, even for commodity shares. But our p/e ratios are now lower than they have been since 1993 -- some are so low that you can't expect much more of a de-rating.&quot;</p>
<p>The Johannesburg Stock Exchange industrial index is currently sitting with a p/e ratio of about 15, from 18.5 at the start of the year. But analysts say many foreigners want to see it down a couple more points before they return.</p>
<p>Despite buying 9.5 billion rands worth of equity stocks since March 1995, when the financial rand was scrapped, foreigners are seen straddling the fence until South Africa proves itself economically and the rand stabilises.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to look at the overall sentiment. At the moment what is undermining our market has been the unstable rand, and nobody is sure where it is going,&quot; said David Shapiro, chief dealer for Frankel Pollak.</p>
<p>&quot;People are starting to lose confidence in the ANC's (African National Congress) ability to really turn the economy around. We're starting to question the competence of the people in charge.&quot;</p>
<p>Spooked by media coverage of escalating violent crime, already wary foreign investors have received little encouragement from recent company results, analysts added.</p>
<p>&quot;Most results have been quite disappointing... although if the rand stays weak, we're going to see some strong bounces in earnings for commodity companies,&quot; Newman said.</p>
<p>Highveld Steel and Vanadium Corp Ltd dropped interim earnings to 39.3 million rand from 98.4 million previously and warned its second half would disappoint further.</p>
<p>Its holding company Anglo American Industrial Corporation Ltd suffered, too. Half-year attributable income slid to 427 million rand from 471 million previously.</p>
<p>Another heavyweight to post poor results was Impala Platinum Holdings whose gamble on currency hedging, plus a furnace failure, knocked its year attributable income to 176 million rand from 281 million in the previous year.</p>
<p>In addition to dismal performances already reported, a number of companies have issued profit warnings ahead of their results announcements.</p>
<p>Shares in pulp and paper producer Sappi Ltd fell last week when it warned that second half earnings would get no benefit from improved markets and would be below the first half.</p>
<p>In May Iscor Ltd  ISCO.J also warned that profits would decline in the second half of the year.</p>
<p>However, some analysts keep faith that the market will turn around by the end of the year or mid-1997.</p>
<p>&quot;We're a little wounded at the moment. We're not strong enough yet to turn around, but could do so in the fourth quarter,&quot; Shapiro said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
