<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10976" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African Telkom equity partner deal seen by March.</title>
<headline>S.African Telkom equity partner deal seen by March.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The South African government hopes to decide by March on an international consortium to take over a minority share of the state utility Telkom, Minister of Posts and Telecommunications Jay Naidoo said on Friday.</p>
<p>Naidoo said the long-awaited deal, which is expected to spearhead a government's privatisation drive, could begin to take shape after a progress report to the cabinet in September.</p>
<p>&quot;The timetable really is that we hope to get into active negotiations towards the end of this year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The ministry would report to the cabinet next month on the progress made in talks with the Telkom board, trade unions and eight potential foreign equity partners.</p>
<p>&quot;Our view is that a partner for Telkom wouldn't be a single operator. We're approaching the matter in terms of encouraging a consortium approach that brings in different forms of expertise.&quot;</p>
<p>Naidoo said he expected a formal shortlist to be finalised by cabinet towards the end of this year.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect cabinet to make a final decision on this by March next year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He identified the potential partners as France Telecom, Germany's Deutsche Telkom, British Telecom, Stet Spa in Italy, a Dutch and Swedish consortium of KPN and Telia, Bell Atlantic Corp and South Western Bell Corp.</p>
<p>Naidoo said the equity stake on offer was still subject to negotiation, but added that while it would be &quot;significant&quot;, the government would retain a majority stake.</p>
<p>Responding to questions, he said a 30 percent shareholding was within the range of discussion.</p>
<p>Officials have previously talked of the sale of 25-30 percent.</p>
<p>Naidoo said the period of exclusivity that would be granted to Telkom's telephony branch before direct competition would be allowed would also be open to negotiation with potential buyers.</p>
<p>He reaffirmed that he would not include the exclusivity guarantee in legislation, but would make it part of the licence conditions and said the guaranteed monpoly would be &quot;in the ballpark of&quot; the period of five to seven years proposed in a policy white paper earlier this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The exclusivity period is intended to ensure that universal service is delivered and to allow us to rebalance tariffs... so that Telkom is prepared for international competition,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The South African government has undertaken to double the number of private telephones over the next five years from four million serving mainly white areas at present to eight million, with a much greater penetration in traditionally black areas.</p>
<p>South Africa's international telephone rates are higher than most of its trading partners, which has led to a proliferation of &quot;call-back&quot; schemes allowing big clients to take make calls at cheaper foreign rates.</p>
<p>Naidoo said it would be for the cabinet to decide what should be done with the proceeds of the proposed partial privatisation, adding that official government policy was to apply privatisation revenue to reducing the state debt, improving infrastructure and promoting black economic empowerment.</p>
<p>He said Telkom would have to motivate proposals to use all or part of the proceeds from the equity deal for telecommunications projects.</p>
<p>The Telkom deal and the imminent sale of six state-owned radio stations are the first projects of a government commitment to the privatisation of viable state-owned utilities.</p>
<p>Others in line for full or partial privatisation include South African Airways, the airports company, sections of the rail and road transport network, state-owned leisure facilities and the electricity generator Eskom.</p>
<p>Economic analysts have cited visible progress on privatisation and the further relaxation of exchange controls as key factors in building foreign investor confidence in South Africa's post-apartheid economy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
