<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10978" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FORECAST - Gencor yr shr, div set to climb.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Gencor yr shr, div set to climb.</headline>
<byline>Melanie Cheary</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Climbing on income from transactions and unlisted aluminium units, Gencor Ltd is likely to stretch year earnings despite a profit slump at its Impala Platinum Holdings Ltd, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>Due to announce results for the year ended June 30 on Monday, Gencor is seen raising its earnings per share partly on the back of one billion rand received for its Malbak stake and the highest ever attributable income made by Samancor.</p>
<p>Robust income from gold operations, which swelled due to the rand's collapse in mid-February, bringing in a higher metal price, was also seen pushing overall group income up.</p>
<p>Analysts polled by Reuters forecast earnings per share of between 92 and 94.5 cents with consensus at 93.12. They ranged dividend between 25 and 27 cents with consensus at 25.75 cents.</p>
<p>Last year Gencor earned 73.8 cents per share and declared a dividend of 20 cents per share.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite very unattractive results for Impala, Gencor should still post very positive earnings thanks to big transactions,&quot; said an analyst who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Another analyst said he had revised down his earnings forecast to 93 cents from 102 cents, weighed by Implats' announcement they had locked in at 3.92 rand to the dollar. The rand was last bid at 4.5290.</p>
<p>&quot;The rand gold price is at its highest ever and earnings from gold in the last couple of quarters have been great,&quot; another analyst said.</p>
<p>In the three months to end-June, Gengold made distributable profit after capital spending of 56.69 million rand compared to 44.2 million in the preceding quarter.</p>
<p>Although the Malbak deal was announced after the group's year end, analysts said the sale could boost earnings.</p>
<p>Gencor's unlisted aluminium subsidiaries Billiton and Alusaf were seen fuelling profits and offsetting any group losses suffered on account of Implats' unfortunate currency hedges.</p>
<p>In contrast to Implats, Billiton won the benefits of forward sales already in place, bringing in higher earnings despite a softer aluminium price, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Billiton had a lot of hedges in place (at the time Gencor acquired it) because of the original financing. These higher prices may have helped,&quot; said an analyst.</p>
<p>Better export prices won by a weaker rand would also support earnings in the year under review and extend into the current financial year, analysts said.</p>
<p>Alusaf's new Hillside smelter had exceeded expectations by coming on-stream earlier than forecast and producing greater volumes, all of which further supported the year's income.</p>
<p>&quot;This is all very positive for earnings,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>Looking to the current financial year, analysts said the Columbus Stainless joint venture held the key to Gencor's earnings growth, while Implats forward sales still in place for the current first half would cap any profit surge.</p>
<p>Implats year earnings plunged to 282 cents per share from 451 cents, with dividend slipping to 100 cents from 175 cents.</p>
<p>On the other hand, Samancor's attributable income reached an all-time high, rising 82 percent to 676 million rand from 372 million rand.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
