<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10979" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria oil firms warn new rules may raise costs.</title>
<headline>Nigeria oil firms warn new rules may raise costs.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria's joint venture oil operators on Friday warned that new government orders on cash contributions could result in another layer of bureaucracy and increased oil production costs.</p>
<p>&quot;The most worrying thing is the question of handling the money, and the possibility of more government interference, which has to be interpreted as more bureaucratic tangles,&quot; one joint venture oil company official said.</p>
<p>Late on Thursday oil minister Dan Etete told oil executives that Nigeria was not getting a fair deal from the oil joint ventures and set out a new way for government contributions for production and exploration be paid, among other measures.</p>
<p>&quot;We already have extensive vetting, with strict contract approvals and again for cash-calls, there is no need for any more. It would inevitably increase costs, and probably the delay in cash-call payments. It would hurt the joint ventures, in which Nigeria has the largest share,&quot; the company official said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still trying to work out what it really means. It may be a matter of rhetoric, or it may be that the minister has definite plans worked out,&quot; another company official said.</p>
<p>Delays in cash-call payments have frequently provoked the ire of the oil companies in the past, and this year government has cut by 30 percent its initial budget provision of $2 billion for oil operations, a decision challenged by the companies.</p>
<p>Ongoing negotiations between the two sides are trying to hammer out new Memorandum of Understanding (MOU) rules for joint venture operations.</p>
<p>Analysts say budget cuts make it unlikely that Nigeria will reach its turn of the century output capacity target of 2.5 million barrels a day. The government is under severe pressure from a $32 billion foreign debt to keep spending under control.</p>
<p>State-run Nigerian National Petroleum Corp (NNPC) is the majority partner in joint ventures with subsidiaries of Royal Dutch/Shell Group, Mobil Corp, Chevron Corp, Agip SpA and Elf Aquitaine.</p>
<p>Nigeria pumps around two million barrels of crude a day.</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
