<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10981" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>COTE D'IVOIRE: Ivory Coast sacks managers of state oil firm.</title>
<headline>Ivory Coast sacks managers of state oil firm.</headline>
<dateline>ABIDJAN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The government of Ivory Coast has sacked the board of state oil producer PETROCI after an audit of its finances revealed irregularities, a statement published on Friday said.</p>
<p>&quot;Taking account of serious difficulties found in the administrative and financial management, the cabinet has decided to replace the current managers and appoint interim managers until the restructuring announced below can be carried out,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The statement, published after a cabinet meeting on Thursday, said PETROCI would be reorganised into a holding company and subsidiaries responsible for exploration and production, gas, and industries and services.</p>
<p>It named a new director-general and two deputies, and an eight-member board of directors including the cabinet secretaries of the economy, trade and mines and oil resources ministries.</p>
<p>PETROCI's main activities include oil exploration and the sale of butane gas.</p>
<p>It has a 20 percent stake in the consortium developing the offshore Lion and Panther oil and gas fields, and owns 45.73 percent of refiner Societe Ivoirienne de Raffinage (SIR), and 20 percent of bitumen firm Societe Multinationale de Bitumes (SMB).</p>
<p>In March and April, the cabinet ordered a series of audits of state firms, particularly in the oil and gas sector.</p>
<p>The cabinet is still waiting for the results of audits of SIR, SMB, mining company SODEMI and petroleum storage firm GESTOCI, the statement said.</p>
<p>The independent daily Le Jour carried a series of articles this month accusing its managers of nepotism and financial malpractice. Director-general Moussa Fanny told the paper President Henri Konan Bedie was satisfied with his work.</p>
<p>An editorial in Le Jour welcomed the move as part of recent government efforts to crack down on corruption and insecurity.</p>
<p>&quot;Threats against corrupt ministers, security raids, sackings of inadequate company directors...These are a number of acts which suggest the new Ivory Coast is on its way,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABIDJAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COTE D'IVOIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
