<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10989" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: UNHCR says not consulted over Rwanda refugee move.</title>
<headline>UNHCR says not consulted over Rwanda refugee move.</headline>
<byline>Christian Jennings</byline>
<dateline>KIGALI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.N. refugee agency said on Friday it had not been consulted by Rwanda and Zaire over the planned repatriation of 1.1 million Rwandan Hutu refugees who fled to Zaire in three months of war and genocide in 1994.</p>
<p>Roman Urasa, head of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) in Rwanda, said in a statement that UNHCR was taking Thursday's announcement by Zairean Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo and his Rwandan counterpart Pierre Celestin Rwigema seriously.</p>
<p>He expressed hope that repatriation would be voluntary.</p>
<p>&quot;We were not consulted about this and although there has been a lot of statements from Zaire, one has to take into account the fact that this has been done at prime ministerial level,&quot; Urasa said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are therefore treating it with more seriousness. What is important is the interpretation of the word immediately,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Kengo told a joint news conference with Rwigema that the repatriation operation would begin with closing all Rwandan refugee camps in Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;The two heads of government have decided to make operational the organised, massive and unconditional repatriation of all Rwandan refugees,&quot; said a statement read by Kengo.</p>
<p>&quot;This is going to be carried out rapidly. The repatriation will be enormous and immediate. We are at a stage where Zaire is going to proceed with the closure of the camps,&quot; Kengo added.</p>
<p>Urasa said he hoped the two countries would involve his agency in any planned operation and stressed that it should be voluntary.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope UNHCR will be involved and if this is the case, we would welcome it and hope it will be voluntary,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kengo's statement came as Rwanda received thousands of Rwandan refugees who were leaving its southern neighbour Burundi.</p>
<p>The U.N. refugee agency said it ended on Thursday the repatriation from Burundi of more than 45,000 Rwandan Hutu refugees from the biggest camp in northern Burundi.</p>
<p>Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko has intervened in the past two years to stop Kengo from ordering, in violation of international law, the deportation from Zaire of the 1.1 million Rwandan Hutus.</p>
<p>Kengo's visit was the first by a senior Zairean official since the Tutsi-dominated Rwandan Patriotic Front rebels took power in 1994 and drove into exile in Zaire the Hutu government and Hutu soldiers held reponsible for the genocide.</p>
<p>Last August, Zairean troops forcibly expelled some 15,000 Rwandan and Burundian Hutus. The expulsions were only stopped after Mobutu stepped in following an international outcry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIGALI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
