<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="10980" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FORECAST - No cheer from July S.Africa money supply.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - No cheer from July S.Africa money supply.</headline>
<byline>Ben Hirschler</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African markets can expect little cheer from July money supply figures out next week, with M3 growth set to rise again and private sector credit expansion remaining high, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>The week's other key figure will be second quarter GDP, due on Tuesday, which is expected to show the economy bowling along at a fair rate on the back of a buoyant farming sector.</p>
<p>But it is the money supply data that will take centre stage as Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals grapples with pressures for an interest rate hike to shore up a recently shakey rand.</p>
<p>Year-on-year preliminary M3 growth is likely to show a rise of 16.2 percent in July from 15.65 percent in June, according to a consensus forecast of 11 economists polled by Reuters.</p>
<p>The annual rate of increase will be exaggerated by a low year-ago base, but the main driving force remains ballooning private sector credit growth, analysts said.</p>
<p>Despite South Africa's punitive interest rates, the consensus forecast is for private credit growth of 18.4 percent in July, little changed from 18.6 percent in June.</p>
<p>High credit demand reflects both consumers snapping up cars and other goods ahead of expected price rises due to the slide in the rand, and corporate switching to local loans from foreign borrowings which have become too expensive.</p>
<p>&quot;It's still very much a case of pre-emptive buying by consumers and substitution of foreign financing with local loans,&quot; said Johan Roussouw, economist at stockbroker Huysamer Stals.</p>
<p>Peter Calitz, of life assurer Sanlam in Cape Town, predicted private credit growth would only start to slow appreciably from the fourth quarter. By the second quarter of 1997 it could be down to around the 12 percent level which Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals has indicated he would like to see.</p>
<p>South African quarter-on-quarter gross domestic product (GDP) on a seasonally adjusted and annualised basis is expected to show growth of 4.2 percent in April-June, up from 3.3 percent in the first quarter.</p>
<p>However, some analysts cautioned that the figures could be distorted by a possible upward adjustment in the first quarter data, effectively shifting some anticipated second quarter growth back into the earlier period.</p>
<p>Agriculture, enjoying its best season in years after excellent summer rains, will continue to drive growth as harvesting of this year's record maize crop kicks.</p>
<p>Maize production has leaped to 9.66 million tonnes from 4.41 million last year, and farmers are also enjoying high prices.</p>
<p>Other sectors have also shown surprising strength, according to economists.</p>
<p>&quot;Manufacturing looks strong, retail sales have been quite nice and the numbers that have been reported from things like electricity generation have been positive,&quot; said Kevin Lings, economist at Nedcor bank.</p>
<p>The weeks' other main figure will be the July trade balance, originally scheduled for release this week but now due from Monday.</p>
<p>Economists said they expected a return to a trade surplus in July after a small 27.6 million rand deficit in June, with the consensus forecast pointing to a surplus of 600 million rand.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
