<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11015" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovakia - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovakia - Aug 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - Steel producer VSZ has discussed possible ways of cooperation with the Chinese firm Yunnan Tin Corporation and with Pohang Ironand Steel Co of South Korea.</p>
<p>- The overall volume of loans from commercial banks increased by some 18.99 billion crowns, or six percent, in the first half of the year to total around 307.1 billion as of June 30.</p>
<p>- Some 98 agricultural firms worth around 12.3 billion crowns, have so far been privatised in the second privatisation wave. The total number of agricultural companies slated for the second wave was 250, with property estimated to be worth some 66.5 billion crowns.</p>
<p>- Revenues from the sale of water totalled 1.1 billion crowns in the first half of this year, some 4.2 percent less than in the same period last year.</p>
<p>- The overall area sown with oil plants (rapeseed and sunflower) in Slovakia totals about 130,000 hectares. The country's consumption would require the area to increase at least to 160,000 hectares.</p>
<p>PRACA - The paper quotes Russian oil sources as saying the manager-employee joint-stock company Slovintegra, which holds 39 percent in oil refiner Slovnaft, has already paid off the remaining 900 million crowns of the total sum of one billion, for the stake bought from the National Property Fund.</p>
<p>SME - The paper writes VSZ now controls about 45 percent in Dopravna Banka.</p>
<p>PRAVDA - Slovak opposition parties are preparing joint proposals for personnel reconstruction at the supervisory bodies controlling the Slovak Inteligence Service (SIS) and the National Property Fund (NPF) -- the state privatisation agency.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
