<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11011" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Poland - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Poland - Aug 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- According to an agreement by the Three-party Commission for Socio-Economic Affairs comprised of the government, trade unions and employers, Poland's public sector workers in February 1997 will get a one-time payment of 16.3 zlotys to make up for inflation this year.</p>
<p>- Germany's Pfeifer &amp; Langen sugar giant opened a new company in Poland on Thursday with a founding capital of one million zlotys.</p>
<p>- Poland's Agricultural Market Agency (ARR), the food market regulator, and other economic institutions say pork prices will rise in the next few months.</p>
<p>- In June next year NATO will decide on Poland's joining the pact, Defence Minister Stanislaw Dobrzanski said.</p>
<p>- F-16 Falcon, F-18 Hornet and Mirage 2000 fighter aircraft will be presented at the Bydgoszcz International AeroInterLot'96 Fair on Friday, as Poland wants to modernise its airforce.</p>
<p>- The governing coalition led by former communists put down the opposition Union for Freedom's (UW) mass-media rights bill, which was endorsed by other opposition parties and sought to update older legislation passed in 1984. The UW bill &quot;was not worth consideration,&quot; coalition deputies said.</p>
<p>- According to Walter Catlow, president of US-based Ameritech International, the firm wants to keep its engagement in the Centertel analogue cellular telephone company but it is extremely worried by recent activities of the main shareholder, Telekomunikacja Polska SA, which could lead to Centertel's disintegration.</p>
<p>NOWA EUROPA</p>
<p>- Two construction sector firms, Melnox and Atlantis, will start operating in the SSE Europark Mielec special economic zone, the Industrial Development Agency's (IDA) Mielec branch director Mariusz Bledowski said.</p>
<p>- The IDA plans to form an investment fund which will group Polish shoemaking and leather producing firms and eventually list its stock on the Warsaw bourse, IDA president Arkadiusz Krezel said.</p>
<p>- Negotiations on the sale of up to 75 percent of the Polski Handel Spozywczy (PHS) food retail and wholesale chain will soon be concluded, privatisation ministry spokesman Jerzy Godula said.</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>- The opposition centrist UW fully supports the demands voiced by the association of owners of homes built on Poland's former German lands. The association's members demand full land property rights and fear possible claims by the previous German owners following Poland's entry to the European Union.</p>
<p>- Poznan-based Wielkopolski Bank Kredytowy (WBK) will receive a 10-year loan of 8.6 million zlotys to buy a branch of Bydgoski Bank Budownictwa construction bank.</p>
<p>- According to Powszechny Bank Gospodarczy (PBG) President Andrzej Szukalski, PBG and the other banks to join the Pekao SA banking group should preserve their identity. But Szukalski's statement has not prevented ever more PBG staffers from leaving the bank.</p>
<p>ZYCIE WARSZAWY</p>
<p>- The government wants to liberalise regulations on lotteries and gambling in expectation of increased tax revenues thought to go up by 320 million zlotys after liberalisation.</p>
<p>- The Daewoo FSO car plant wants to introduce a new passenger car model to be produced alongside the Polonez model to increase the plant's employment, Daewoo FSO spokeswoman Krystyna Danilczyk said.</p>
<p>PARKIET</p>
<p>- On September 16 the Warsaw bourse will start continuous trade in shares of Bank Slaski, Bank Rozwoju Exportu (BRE), and the Stalexport, Budimex and Universal foreign trade companies.</p>
<p>- Poland's industrial output in July exceeded by 10 percent the results in the same period last year, according to Central Statistical Office data.</p>
<p>- Lodz-based PBG bank's net profit in the first half this year reached 71.8 million zlotys, representing 60.6 percent of its forecasted annual profit.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
