<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11014" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - Aug 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>DELO</p>
<p>- Electricity distributor Elektro Slovenija said it appealed to all its customers to save electricity because supply could be effected due to damage at one part of its power plant Sostanj.</p>
<p>- The Slovenian state Payment Agency has appealed after a court decision that it had to give up a part of its premises to the newly-established state Auditing Agency.</p>
<p>- Slovenia's centrist Democratic Party, currently holding four out of 90 parliamentary seats, said it expected to gain seven percent of seats in the general elections scheduled to take place by December this year.</p>
<p>- The left-wing United List of Social Democrats said the government should reduce unemployment and increase minumum wage.</p>
<p>DNEVNIK</p>
<p>- Slovenian President Milan Kucan is expected to begin a second round of talks with parliamentary parties before fixing the date for a general election. According to Slovenian legislation, elections should take place between October 27 and December 8.</p>
<p>REPUBLIKA</p>
<p>- Parliament is expected to end its debate on a new proposal for the law on bankruptcies in September.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
