<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11017" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Aug 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - &quot;Anheuser-Busch's demands are unrealistic and we are not in a situation where we would have to privatise this firm,&quot; Agriculture Minister Josef Lux said.</p>
<p>- Shoe production is now at half of 1989 levels.  For the first time since 1989, imports of shoes are exceeding exports.</p>
<p>MLADA FRONTA DNES - The American Federal Bureau of Investigations (FBI) is sending an agent to Prague by the end of this year to help Czech police in the fight against organized crime and international terrorism.</p>
<p>- Six to eight health insurance companies are considering a merger in order increase chances of survival.</p>
<p>LIDOVE NOVINY - Expenditure cuts in this year's state budget may be considerably higher than the 9.3 billion crowns predicted by the Ministry of Finance.  One reason is that customs offices lost more than two billion crowns due to the bankruptcy of Kreditny Banka Plzen and this was not accounted for in the ministry's estimate.</p>
<p>PRAVO - The sale of 500,000 hectares of state land is expected to begin next year and to last for 10 years. Currently parliament is working on a version of a law to control the sales, which should be passed by the end of this year.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
