<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11013" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Aug 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>24 CHASA</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's cabinet approved the sale of up to 75 percent of the debt-ridden Plama oil refinery, initially slated for liquidation, Privatisation Agency's executive director Vesselin Blagoev said.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria has failed to meet some of the targets, set in its reform programme agreed with the International Monetary Fund last month, central bank governor Lyubomir Filipov said after talks with the IMF mission head Anne McGuirk in Sofia.</p>
<p>-- Two former directors of the Arsenal military plant had been arrested in the southern town of Stara Zagora, the newspaper said without specifuying what charges were brought against them.</p>
<p>PARI</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>-- The government reduced the stakes for voucher sell-offs in 60 state firms slated for privatisation, Privatisation Agency's executive director Vesselin Blagoev said.</p>
<p>-- The European Union said it would transfer 40 million European currency units to the Bulgarian National Bank (BNB) on August 29 under a balance of payments agreement signed in 1994, the BNB said.</p>
<p>STANDART</p>
<p>-- One Romanian woman was killed and 15 people were injured in a crash near the northern town of Rousse when a Romanian bus collided head on with a Bulgarian one.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>-- Electricity prices are expected to rise by 14-17 percent in September, energy minister Roumen Ovcharov said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's budget deficit rose by 1.2 billion levs to 69.727 billion levs in the first half of August, which is 86.4 percent of the year's target set in the revised budget, the finance ministry said.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-876032</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
