<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11022" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary bank unit AEB to finance Gazprom projects.</title>
<headline>Hungary bank unit AEB to finance Gazprom projects.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>AEB bank will finance projects undertaken by Russia's Gazprom group, which will boost AEB's capital to make it one of the largest Hungarian banks, AEB Chairman Megdet Rahimkulov told a news conference on Friday.</p>
<p>Gazprombank, the financing arm of Russia's gas giant Gazprom, recently bought 100 percent of Altalanos Ertekforgalmi Bank (AEB) from the Hungarian state and western investors' Central European Development Corporation.</p>
<p>AEB is the first bank Gazprom purchased abroad.  </p>
<p>Gazprombank will boost AEB's registered capital to 4.5 billion forints from one billion by mid-September, Rahimkulov said. The capital will be further raised by 0.5 billion this year, partly or wholly by the Russian National Savings Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue the capital raises in 1997 and 1998, to make AEB one of the strongest Hungarian banks,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Gazprombank plans to develop AEB's retail banking activities and the Hungarian bank will also finance part of Russia's gas imports to Hungary and the neighbouring countries and Gazprom's investments in the region, he said.</p>
<p>The bank will be involved in a $500 million project, to begin next year, in which Panrusgaz, the joint venture of Gazprom and the Hungarian oil and gas company MOL will build a 600 km pipeline, which can supply Slovakia, Hungary, Slovenia and Italy with Russian gas.</p>
<p>As AEB is not strong enough yet to finance such large projects alone, it has begun negotiations with Hungary's OTP bank and Magyar Kulkereskedelmi Bank to make up a consortium, Rahimkulov said.</p>
<p>-- Sandor Peto, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
