<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11023" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish banking group agreement possible next week.</title>
<headline>Polish banking group agreement possible next week.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's finance ministry on August 28 is likely to decide the final shape of an agreement to form a group of four state-owned banks, the deputy president of Bank Pekao SA, the group's planned leader, said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;A meeting is planned for August 28 of the presidents of the banks of the group with deputy finance minister Ryszard Pazura. I hope that at that meeting we'll submit a text largely agreed on,&quot; Andrzej Dorosz told reporters.</p>
<p>He said that the four banks -- Pekao,  Powszechny Bank Gospodarczy SA (PBG),  Bank Depozytowo-Kredytowy SA (BDK) and  Pomorski Bank Kredytowy SA w Szeczinie (PBKS) still remained divided over some details of the plan.</p>
<p>Dorosz said the finance ministry, which represents the state treasury as the banks' owner, would have to make the final decision if the banks failed to agree next week.</p>
<p>&quot;The final decision always rests with the owner,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>All four banks have agreed to take part in the government's consolidation plan aimed to form a banking group led by the Warsaw-based Pekao SA, which would later be privatised, but remained divided over how the group would operate. -- Jacek Ramotowski +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
