<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11021" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: UN reports rising tensions before Bosnia election.</title>
<headline>UN reports rising tensions before Bosnia election.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.N. officials expressed concern on Friday over a pattern of political violence in northwestern Bosnia before post-war elections but said Moslem police had pledged to halt abuses in the area.</p>
<p>Political opponents of the ruling Moslem nationalist SDA party have been subjected to threats and violence in Cazin repeatedly in the run-up to nationwide polling on September 14.</p>
<p>International Police Task Force (IPTF) officials have accused local police of standing by and allowing the incidents to occur and of failing to investigate them properly afterward.</p>
<p>Alex Ivanko, spokesman for the international police, said two more politically motivated explosions were reported in the Cazin area in recent days.</p>
<p>But Ivanko told reporters the IPTF had won a commitment from the government police commander in the Bihac canton &quot;to ensure that there are no such incidents in the future&quot;.</p>
<p>He said the Bosnian police official had promised to mount more night patrols and to dismiss the chief of police in Cazin as well as the head of criminal investigations there.</p>
<p>Opposition leader Haris Silajdzic, a former Bosnian prime minister, was attacked with a metal pipe at a rally in Cazin earlier this summer.</p>
<p>International election monitors said members of the SDA were responsible for the attack.</p>
<p>Kris Janowski, spokesman for the office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) in Sarajevo, said his agency was disturbed by the climate of political violence in Bihac.</p>
<p>&quot;The UNHCR is very concerned about the rising political violence and intimidation in Bihac, which is often directed against returning refugees,&quot; Janowski said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sadly, Bihac today stands out as the scene of the most violence in the (Bosnian Moslem-Croat) federation.&quot;</p>
<p>The UNHCR also slammed Serb authorities over a number of human rights abuses against non-Serbs, blocking free movement for civilians less than a month before the September vote.</p>
<p>Janowski reported a &quot;continuing contempt for the rights of minorities&quot; in Bosnia's Serb republic, listing a series of incidents which violate the letter and the spirit of the Dayton peace agreement.</p>
<p>He said the Serb violations include:</p>
<p>-- trying to turn the administrative boundary line between the Moslem-Croat federation and the Serb republic into an international border.</p>
<p>-- requiring Moslems and Croats from Serb-held Teslic who want to visit the federation to secure a re-entry permit from local police.</p>
<p>-- requiring those persons visiting the Serb republic from the federation to inform police and remain only five days.</p>
<p>-- making citizens of third countries with Moslem or Croatian names to pay a visa fee of 45 German marks ($30) even though they had already entered Bosnia.</p>
<p>-- preventing 11 Moslem families evicted from their homes in the Banja Luka area two months ago from returning and threatening others in that area with eviction.</p>
<p>-- blocking dozens of &quot;assessment visits&quot; in which Moslems and Croats tried, with UNHCR assistance, to return to their former homes in the Serb republic to determine whether it would be possible to move back permanently</p>
<p>Serb nationalist leaders oppose reunification in Bosnia and want a separate, sovereign territory linked to Serbia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
