<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11029" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania private oil operators plan national co.</title>
<headline>Romania private oil operators plan national co.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Private firms in Romania's oil and gas sector plan to create a national company next month as a counter to the recently formed state-run National Oil Company, an executive said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;This is intended as a vehement response to attempts to set up a monopoly with the National Oil Company from which private capital was totally excluded,&quot; Teodor Vostinaru, president of General Trading and Investments Co SA, told Reuters.</p>
<p>General Trading and Investments, a Romanian private oil products operator, is one of the initiators of the new company, to be called Petrogas SA.</p>
<p>The National Oil Company recently created by the government groups 12 state-owned refineries, four transport and 41 oil distribution companies as well as a research institute and an oil exploration firm.</p>
<p>Its declared aim was to consolidate Romania's sprawling state-run oil industry and ensure funds to import the crude oil Romania's energy-hungry industries badly need.</p>
<p>But oil sector analysts dubbed it an East bloc bureaucratic conglomerate and expressed fears it would be a step back in oil sector reforms.</p>
<p>Vostinaru said Petrogas's role was to bring private companies together, allowing them &quot;to reach opportune decisions on the future development of the oil and gas sector.&quot;</p>
<p>He said private companies operating in Romania accounted for more than 30 percent of gas processing activities and made some 40 percent of the country's gas imports. There are also 25 private companies in oil businesses in Romania.</p>
<p>Petrogas will be officially founded on September 9.</p>
<p>It plans to have a 250 billion lei share capital, of which some 52 percent will be Romanian private capital, a maximum of 27 percent Romanian state capital and around 21 percent foreign capital. The nominal worth of a share will be 100,000 lei.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had signals that the planned capital can be fully subscribed by founding members. So far, more than 20 companies said they were willing to participate and the list remains open to all operators in the sector,&quot; Vostinaru said.</p>
<p>&quot;And we have had equally good signals from foreign companies,&quot; he added. ($=3,157 lei) -- Luli Popescu, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
