<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11025" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Poland's ashing cavalry may ride again.</title>
<headline>Poland's ashing cavalry may ride again.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's famous cavalry is set to ride again, if a group of enthusiasts who met in Warsaw on Friday has its way.</p>
<p>They formed an association which aims to train and equip a cavalry squadron and then offer it to the Defence Ministry for use on ceremonial occasions, PAP news agency said.</p>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Roman Jagielinski was elected president. The association also includes other parliamentary deputies from his co-ruling Peasant party, army officers and cavalry veterans as well as amateur riders.</p>
<p>Poland's dashing Ulans last won renown by holding out for a month against an invasion by mechanised Nazi German forces and then by Soviet troops in 1939.</p>
<p>Poland's communist rulers abandoned the long cavalry tradition in favour of tanks after World War Two. The army is now struggling to modernise, on a low budget, and has no horse-borne troops for ceremonial purposes.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope that many people will rally round the squadron, especially former cavalrymen and Ulans -- people who have long cherished this dream but did not have the means to carry it out,&quot; group secretary Lieutenant-Colonel Zbigniew Radon said.</p>
<p>Radon said it planned to employ former cavalry officers to train serving soldiers at Warsaw's military LEGIA riding club, which he runs, and equip them with horses and 1936-style uniforms with money raised from donations and subscriptions.</p>
<p>Army and Defence Ministry spokesmen were not immediately available for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
