<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11030" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria-Russia bank to raise capital to 5 bln lvs.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria-Russia bank to raise capital to 5 bln lvs.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The private Bulgarian-Russian Investment Bank (BRIB) plans to raise its capital four-fold to five billion levs by the end of 1998 to meet new central bank minimum capital requirements, the bank's chief executive director said.</p>
<p>&quot;The bank's board will propose at the shareholders' meeting on October 5 to raise the capital to five billion levs from 1.25 billion levs through a new share issue,&quot; Svetoslav Bozhilov told Reuters.</p>
<p>Bozhilov said &quot;We hope to raise our capital to 2.5-2.7 billion levs by the end of March next year because there is an interest from potential subscribers for some 1.5 billion levs worth of shares from the new issue.&quot;</p>
<p>The central bank raised minimum capital requirements for commercial banks on August 15 to 1.4 billion levs and 2.2 billion levs for a domestic and a full banking licence, respectively. That compared with previous requirements of 800 million levs and 1.2 billion levs, respectively.</p>
<p>The new requirements are to be met by licensed banks by March 31, 1997. BRIB got a full banking licence in January 1995.</p>
<p>Par value of the new shares will remain unchanged at 10,000 levs, Bozhilov said. The stocks will be offered to current shareholders and, after negotiations, to other investors.</p>
<p>The bank's rise in capital will also help it avoid subsequent rises in the short term, which could be called for if the lev falls further, Bozhilov said.</p>
<p>He said the bank plans to have the capital of five billion levs fully paid-in by the end of 1998. -- Roumiana Tikholova, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
