<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11031" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatians uncertain about deal with Belgrade.</title>
<headline>Croatians uncertain about deal with Belgrade.</headline>
<byline>Zoran Radosavljevic</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatians showed mixed emotions on Friday over an accord to normalise ties with Serbia-led Yugoslavia, their former enemy, with some expressing fears the deal was hastily arranged and could turn out for the worse.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything that leads to peace is necessary. But still I am suspicious. I don't trust Serbs after all that's happened,&quot; said Domagoj Pejic, 33.</p>
<p>Foreign ministers from Croatia and Yugoslavia earlier signed the mutual recognition accord in Belgrade, ending five years of crisis that followed Croatia's bid for independence.</p>
<p>&quot;It's high time this happened. Normalisation is necessary and there can't be any progress without it,&quot; said Franjo Saban, 26, a Zagreb student.</p>
<p>But hatred and mistrust still run deep on both sides after years of hostile propaganda and a bloody conflict that displaced hundreds of thousands of civilians.</p>
<p>Political analysts said important legal issues regarding refugees and amnesty had yet to be resolved and the accord would probably do little to improve the lives of ordinary Croats and Serbs in the near future.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not really enthusiastic. Too much blood has been shed for Croatia to allow today's signing. I would personally build a Chinese wall between us but Western forces are dictating otherwise,&quot; said taxi driver Ivan Tomljenovic.</p>
<p>Croatia declared independence from federal Yugoslavia in 1991. But minority Serbs, fearing for their rights, proclaimed their own state of Krajina, armed and backed by the Yugoslav army.</p>
<p>Most Croats were expelled from the Krajina region and hundreds of civilians were killed in a seven-month war that ended with a truce in January 1992.</p>
<p>The Croatian army recaptured Serb-held territory a year ago, prompting an exodus of 200,000 Serbs to Bosnia and Yugoslavia, now comprising only Serbia and Montenegro.</p>
<p>&quot;The normalisation comprises a handshake over Croatian graves and the destruction of Croatian culture,&quot; wrote columnist Srecko Jurdana in the Nacional weekly.</p>
<p>Some Croats, saying Belgrade was responsible for starting the war, said the deal was reached too quickly and did not force Yugoslavia to acknowledge its role in the conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;This process is fraught with unnecessary haste. We don't think the agreement should set no conditions (for Yugoslavia),&quot; Zlatko Tomcic, leader of the peasant party, told Vjesnik daily.</p>
<p>But, after so much suffering and violence, other Croatians said it was time to put the war behind them and move on.</p>
<p>&quot;Things eventually have to be solved. I therefore support the normalisation. People have to be able to go back to their homes, both Croats and Serbs,&quot; said Andjelka Rogosica, 32.</p>
<p>If Croatians were less than enthusiastic about the accord, many Serbs in rump Yugoslavia expressed disgust.</p>
<p>Opposition leaders accuse Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic of betraying the Serb minority in Croatia whose cause he once championed.</p>
<p>&quot;What kind of a stupid president makes a deal with the Croatian fascists?&quot; said a Belgrade taxi driver. &quot;What did all those people die for?&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
