<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11038" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian air traffic controllers threaten strike.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian air traffic controllers threaten strike.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgarian air traffic controllers have threatened to go on strike at the beginning of September to demand more pay, the chief of the Bulgarian association of air traffic controllers (Bulatka) said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will launch our strike in the beginning of September as now we are collecting signatures from those who will go on strike and then we will give (our employer) a week-long warning,&quot; Stefan Raichev told Reuters.</p>
<p>The controllers are demanding the monthly wage be increased to $1,000 from some $230 per month, while traffic has increased 10 percent since last year, Raichev said.</p>
<p>The director general of the air traffic service Valentin Valkov said if now controllers launch a strike it would be illegal.</p>
<p>&quot;A strike at this stage would be illegal as it breaks legal procedures,&quot; Valkov told a news conference on Friday.</p>
<p>He said air traffic was congested during the summer with charter flights carrying foreign tourists to the Bulgarian Black Sea resorts.</p>
<p>&quot;I can not afford curbing the charter flights of our national carrier -- Balkan Airlines,&quot; Valkov said.</p>
<p>He said he would collect the signatures of would-be strikers among the 1,380 traffic controllers and technicians in an attempt to prepare a schedule for their replacement.</p>
<p>A construction of a new modern air traffic centre in Sofia is planned to start on March 1 next year, Valkov said, adding that it is expected to cost some $15-$20 million.</p>
<p>In 1994 the European Investment Bank agreed to extend a 30 million ECU ($25 million) loan for improving the efficiency and capacity of Bulgaria's air traffic control system, Valkov said.</p>
<p>The new centre will be built with funds of the Bulgarian side, while its equipment, which will be supplied by foreign firms, will be funded through the bank's loan, he added.</p>
<p>-- Liliana Semerdjieva, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
