<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11043" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine to issue T-bills on August 27.</title>
<headline>Ukraine to issue T-bills on August 27.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukraine's central bank will auction three-month, six-month, nine-month and 12-month discount treasury bills on August 27, the head of the bank's capital markets and exchange department, Vitaly Migashko, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The central bank is not setting the issue volume in advance. It last auctioned three-month treasury bills on August 22 and six- and nine-month bills on August 20.</p>
<p>At the three-month T-bill auction, the bank sold 1.153 trillion karbovanets worth of paper, with an average annualised yield of 57.30 percent. The average price was 8.750 million karbovanets.</p>
<p>On August 20, a sale of 79.37 billion karbovanets worth of paper averaged a yield of 59.90 percent. The average price was 7.700 million karbovanets.</p>
<p>The 770 million karbovanets worth of nine-month paper sold at an average yield of 59.90 percent.</p>
<p>On August 6, the 6.206 trillion karbovanets worth of 12-month discount T-bills sold with an average yield of 55.19 percent. The average price was 6.450 million karbovanets.</p>
<p>--Irene Marushko, Kiev Newsroom +380 33 229 2264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
