<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11048" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian stocks mixed, new market vigour expected.</title>
<headline>Croatian stocks mixed, new market vigour expected.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks were mixed, with marginal losses among some of the blue chips, but traders expected the Zagreb Stock Exchange to regain its pre-summer vigour.</p>
<p>&quot;Next week prices of market heavyweights could easily go up,&quot; one trader said, referring to drugs firm Pliva and Zagrebacka Banka.</p>
<p>Another trader said the market activity was almost totally dependent on Pliva's and Zagrebacka's trading in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Their Zagreb prices always reflect developments in London. And then the two encourage trading in other issues,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>* Of eight active issues, one rose, one was flat and six fell.</p>
<p>* The only gainer Pliva added 100 kuna to close at 11,200 with 96 shares changing hands. Its GDRs were quoted lower on London Stock Exchange at $45.5 from Thursday's $46.</p>
<p>* Hotelier Laguna traded flat at 800 kuna with 87 shares sold.</p>
<p>* Most active Zagrebacka banka lost eight kuna to close at 682 kuna, with 7,660 shares sold. Its GDRs, trading at SEAQ International, were flat at $14.125.</p>
<p>* Hotelier Jadranturist inched down two kuna, closing at 158 on volume of 308 shares.</p>
<p>* Confectioner Kras lost five kuna, closing at 260 with 263 units sold.</p>
<p>* Food processor Podravka edged down five kuna to close at 225 kuna, selling 379 shares.</p>
<p>* Hotelier Suncani Hvar lost 5.6 kuna to close at 38.10, selling 646 shares and trading for the first time in more than a month.</p>
<p>* Privredna Banka closed at 140 kuna on volume of 515 shares. It last traded at 185.20 kuna in late January.</p>
<p>* Daily volume rose to 9,954 shares, turnover almost halved at 6.5 million kuna. Total weekly turnover three times higher at 43.8 million kuna.</p>
<p>* Central bank's exchange rate: 5.2556 kuna = $1. -- Laura Lui, Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
