<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11041" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: Hansabank, Forexbank active on Estonian bourse.</title>
<headline>Hansabank, Forexbank active on Estonian bourse.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ativity on the Estonian stock exchange leapt on Friday, boosted by healthy trade in leading bank Hansabank and in Forexbank, dealers said.</p>
<p>Overall activity was 7.4 million kroons versus 3.44 million kroons. The Tallinn stock exchange rose 0.15 percent to 95.84.</p>
<p>Hansabank was the most active stock on trade of 3.8 million kroons and it closed at 92.40 kroons, a slight rise from Thursday's 92.20 kroons.</p>
<p>Forexbank traded 2.14 million kroons of stock and ended at 77 kroons, unchanged. Even normally quiet Tallinna Bank was in demand as it turned over 1.26 million kroons.</p>
<p>Its price was slightly lower at 39.35 kroons, versus 39.40.</p>
<p>Savings Bank, in the news as shareholders approved a merger with the Bank of Industry and a 10 million kroon share issue, was barely traded.</p>
<p>it registered business of just 68,110 kroons at a price of 34.70 kroons, down from yesterday's 34.95.</p>
<p>On the free market, Tallinn Pharmaceuticals dominated with trade of 924,157 kroons and a price of 41.80 kroons, a surge from yesterday's 37.40 kroons.</p>
<p>Total free market business was 1.4 million kroons.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
