<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11044" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian domestic debt rises 68.6 pct this year.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian domestic debt rises 68.6 pct this year.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's government debt rose by 68.6 percent to 582.5 billion levs in the first seven months of this year from 345.4 billion levs at the end of 1995, finance ministry figures showed.</p>
<p>In the January-July period, net revenue from treasury paper sales amounted to 169.4 billion levs, while the Finance Ministry paid  financial institutions 87.4 billion levs for maturing discount bonds and 46.5 billion levs in interest and coupon payments.</p>
<p>Treasury paper worth 237.3 billion levs was in circulation by end-July, ministry figures showed.</p>
<p>Companies and individuals bought 11.7 billion levs and $10.1 million worth of lev- and dollar-denominated bonds issued by the government to transform the bad loans of state enterprises to local banks.</p>
<p>Under Bulgarian law these bonds can be used as a means of payment in privatisation deals.</p>
<p>The par value of bad loan bonds issued was 213.2 billion levs by July 31.</p>
<p>Reducing the enormous domestic debt burden is a major element of Bulgaria's reform programme, agreed with multilateral lenders.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
