<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11051" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary rate cut tracks inflation fall - analysts.</title>
<headline>Hungary rate cut tracks inflation fall - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Sandor Peto</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Bank of Hungary's (NBH) one percent base rate cut is in line with the decline of inflation and might have also been instigated by the government decision to delay energy price hikes, analysts said on Friday .</p>
<p>The NBH reduced its base rate to 24.50 percent earlier on Friday from 25.50.</p>
<p>&quot;It was noticeable that in the past two months the central bank intensified the reduction of rates,&quot; GKI Research Institute's Judit Barta said.</p>
<p>&quot;My interpretation is that the central bank believes that inflation is declining,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>&quot;It is likely to be in accordance with the decline of interest rates which took speed in the past two or three weeks,&quot; Postabank Securities' Attila Torok said.</p>
<p>Monthly inflation was 0.4 percent in July, down from 0.9 percent in June, while year-on-year inflation slowed to 23 percent from 23.6 percent.</p>
<p>The annual yield on twelve-month Treasury bills dropped to 23.69 percent at an auction earlier on Friday, compared with 25.00 percent one month ago.</p>
<p>Analysts said the central bank's base rate has usually closely followed the money market since Hungary introduced a pre-announced forint devaluation system last March.</p>
<p>However, the base rate cut, which was larger than some analysts expected, could have also been encouraged by changed inflation expectations following the government's decision on Thursday to delay energy price hikes from October until January, analysts added.</p>
<p>&quot;If the government puts off the energy price rises, this will also slow down inflation,&quot; Citibank's Csaba Varga said.</p>
<p>The rate of the energy price hike has not been decided yet, but the government said it was below 40 percent.</p>
<p>The delay in the energy price hikes mean that year-on-year inflation will drop by some 1.5 to two percent by December and will be around the 20 percent government target, analyst said.</p>
<p>The government decision will reduce expected annual inflation by only a few tenths of a percentage point from some 24 percent, compared with 28.2 percent in 1995, but it will substantially reduce the households' heating costs, they added.</p>
<p>Torok said the central bank is also likely to cut its repo rates in the near future, and the base rate cut makes probable that the repo rate cut will be larger than previously expected.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps they will cut the repo by half percentage point now instead of 0.25 percentage point,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
