<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11067" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria sells two hotels in Black Sea resorts.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria sells two hotels in Black Sea resorts.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's Privatisation Agency said on Friday it had sold two hotels in the Black Sea resorts of Zlatni Pyasatsi and Slanchev Bryag for a total of 155.966 million levs.</p>
<p>Under the deals the Bulgarian buyers will have to invest some 175 million levs in the hotels.</p>
<p>The Privatisation Agency has sold another 14 hotels and restaurants in the two purpose-built holiday complexes since August 15 for some 376 million levs, Privatisation Agency's official data show.</p>
<p>Though state-owned, Bulgarian resorts are not subsidised by the state and have to rely solely on revenues to upgrade their facilities.</p>
<p>Germans and Russians top the list of foreign visitors to Bulgaria's seaside holiday complexes, followed by Britons and Scandinavians.</p>
<p>The agency also said it had sold Madara Intertour tourist company based in the northern town of Shoumen for 406 million levs to a Bulgarian buyer. The new owner will have to invest some 80 million levs under the contract.</p>
<p>The firm includes three hotels and four restaurants and had a turnover of 40 billion levs in 1995, the Privatisation Agency said in a statement.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 981 8569</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
