<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11065" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish bourse seen needing higher trade for growth.</title>
<headline>Polish bourse seen needing higher trade for growth.</headline>
<byline>Steven Silber</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares are expected to rise on Monday but analysts said higher turnovers were needed to confirm that the current seven-session rise would flower into longer term growth.</p>
<p>The main market's WIG index rose this week to 13,888.2 points, up 9.3 percent from last Friday's close. It has risen 11.6 percent over the past seven sessions, closing in on this year's 27-month, July 5 high at 14,282.2 points.</p>
<p>&quot;We could soon pierce our latest high but if it doesn't happen in higher turnover we could soon have falls,&quot; said Ryszard Wojnowski, an analyst Bank Gdanski brokerage.</p>
<p>Turnovers did rise this week, nearly doubling to around 110 million zlotys each session from early August's doldrums, but analysts were divided on whether higher trade reflected foreign institutional buying.</p>
<p>&quot;The higher turnovers perhaps represent smaller investors trying to get in before foreign investors,&quot; said Remigiusz Tarka, an analyst at IB Austria Securities.</p>
<p>Others said foreign investors were already in, shown by the impressive growth of some of the bourse's fundamentally strong largest-cap stocks.</p>
<p>Kety, BFK, Stomil Olsztyn, BRE and BPH all rose nearly 17 percent this week, with Kety possibly helped by the news on Thursday it would invest 50 million zlotys this year.</p>
<p>Analysts said a good sign was companies' slightly better July earnings reports released by last Monday and the month's 4.8 percent growth in industrial production.</p>
<p>They said the bourse did not yet seem threatened by the upcoming reorganisation of cabinet ministries, which has deeply divided the ruling coalition of ex-communists and a peasant party over power-sharing.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody believes the coalition will suddenly break apart,&quot; said Gdanski's Wojnowski.</p>
<p>On Thursday the bourse announced it would add five stocks to the continuous trade system from September 16 -- Bank Slaski, Stalexport, Budimex Universal and BRE, popular large-cap stocks.</p>
<p>The addition would make 10 stocks in the system, with the bourse planning to have all 20 stocks in the WIG 20 blue chip index quoted live by year-end.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
