<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11066" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo GDP grows 2.5 pct in Jan-June - report.</title>
<headline>Yugo GDP grows 2.5 pct in Jan-June - report.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslavia's gross domestic product (GDP) rose 2.5 percent during the first half of the year, but the figure was well below expectations, the federal Centre for Development and Economic Policy said on Friday.</p>
<p>The centre's report said that in the first six months of the year industry output was up 2.1 percent, agriculture 1-2 percent, transport 18 percent, catering and tourism 1.8 percent against the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>In the same period the construction industry continued falling, by 16.2 percent compared to the first six months in 1995, the report said.</p>
<p>The centre said that the figures indicated the government's goal of 12.5 percent growth this year might not be attainable.</p>
<p>The Yugoslav government has said its 1996 economic policy should secure a rise in industrial output of 10.5 percent and an expansion of agricultural production by three percent.</p>
<p>It also says that the suspension of U.N. sanctions last November would give Yugoslavia scope to boost exports by 50 percent. But it grew only 0.7 percent in January-June period.</p>
<p>In 1995 Yugoslavia's GDP stood at $15 billion or up six percent against the previous year. The 1995 figure represented a mere 55.4 percent of GDP in 1990. -- Gordana Kukic, Belgrade Newsroom +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
