<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11063" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian net reserves rise to 21 trln rbls.</title>
<headline>Russian net reserves rise to 21 trln rbls.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's net foreign currency reserves rose to 21 trillion roubles on July 1 from 20 trillion on June 1, the central bank said on Friday.</p>
<p>Reserves were calculated at a rate of 4,640 roubles to the dollar, it said in its weekly bulletin.</p>
<p>The central bank issued the following data (trillions of roubles):</p>
<p>				   July 1	 June 1	Jan 1</p>
<p> Monetary base		  129.4	  118.8	103.8</p>
<p>comprising</p>
<p>    Net currency reserves    21	     20	   35.7</p>
<p>    Net domestic assets     108.4	   98.8	 68.1.</p>
<p>Under Russia's $10 billion three-year loan from the International Monetary Fund, the Fund sets performance targets for the budget deficit, net domestic assets -- defined as the monetary base less net currency reserves -- and net reserves.</p>
<p>The Fund withheld payment of the July tranche of the loan because of concern about poor tax revenue collection, but earlier this week agreed to disburse it.</p>
<p>Targets under the IMF programme have not been officially published.</p>
<p>But London investment bank Deutsche Morgan Grenfell said in a research note in March that under the programme net domestic assets were due to rise to 103.2 trillion roubles at the end of June from 98.8 trillion roubles at the end of May.</p>
<p>Net reserves were due to fall to $4.5 billion -- 20.88 trillion roubles at the exchange rate used by the central bank -- from $4.7 billion.</p>
<p>Russian officials had asked the Fund to modify the targets, and economists close to talks between Russia and the Fund said some targets had been changed.</p>
<p>--Jonathan Lynn, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
