<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11068" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish 3-day rev repo cut seen not affecting rates.</title>
<headline>Polish 3-day rev repo cut seen not affecting rates.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Bank of Poland's (NBP) reverse repo rate cut earlier today was a result of the money market's overliquidity and should not affect deposit rates or T-bill yields next week, analysts said.</p>
<p>The NBP cut its three-day reverse repo maximum rate to 17.70 percent from 19.12 percent at the last drainage, a 14-day operation on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The cut was not caused by the NBP's will to lower drainage rates, but was rather the result of the market's huge cash surplus,&quot; said Marek Wieczorkiewicz, chief dealer at PKO BP.</p>
<p>&quot;Drainage rates may still rebound,&quot; Wieczorkiewicz added.</p>
<p>Analysts said Friday's move to mop up liquidity would not likely be used as a benchmark because it was much shorter than the NBP's main reverse repo 14-day period.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's reverse repo should not be considered a full fledged drainage, it is more like a spot/next deposit,&quot; said one foreign bank dealer in Warsaw.</p>
<p>On the money market overnight rates closed at 6.0/8.0 percent, down from 12.0/13.0 percent at the opening and Thursday's 15.0/17.0. Tomorrow/next rates were at 12.5/17.0 percent against 9.0/12.0 in early trade and 12.0/16.8 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Analysts said longer-term deposit rates on the money market still used the 19.12 percent 14-day reverse repo rate as a benchmark and did not move after today's cut in the reverse repo rate.</p>
<p>-- Wojciech Moskwa +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
