<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11073" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romanian leu nudges down to 3,155/65 to dlr.</title>
<headline>Romanian leu nudges down to 3,155/65 to dlr.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Romanian leu drifted lower on Friday to 3,155/65 to the dollar after having stuck at 3,150/60 over the past week in slack interbank trading.</p>
<p>Traders said the leu's small slide would not impress hard currency owners who are looking for a dollar much more fattened for sale before they will join the market.</p>
<p>&quot;I have fewer and fewer sellers. The ratio between dollar sellers and buyers is one to four,&quot; said a frustrated trader with one of the four market-making dealer banks.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm struggling to convince exporters to deal on other currencies as prices are better. But they are still reluctant, selling only when they have to settle outstanding payments,&quot; said a trader with a broker bank.</p>
<p>The German mark or French franc, quoted up to 2,181/48 lei and 642/74 lei, give at cross weaker leu-dollar prices of around 3,400.</p>
<p>Operators said they expect renewed pressure on the battered leu currency in September when activity will intensify after the summer torpor.</p>
<p>&quot;The signs are very clear on the retail market where leu- dollar prices have started a pre-autumn downswing,&quot; said another trader with a broker bank.</p>
<p>At licensed money changing bureaux the leu has weakened to some 3,500 to the dollar after loitering near 3,450 over the past days.</p>
<p>Money market dealers said short-term rates closed the week marking time at 47-48 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Even with the end-month factor one-week rates are unlikely to touch 49 percent,&quot; said one trader, adding that most banks have already fulfilled their minimum reserve targets. -- Mirela Eremia, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
