<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11078" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: No corporate stocks trade in Bulgaria this week.</title>
<headline>No corporate stocks trade in Bulgaria this week.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>No corporate issues traded for a third week in a row on the Bulgarian stock market where no shares were bid or offered due to low interest, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;There were no shares on offer and neither brokers nor investors bid for shares because of low yields and high risk compared to other investments,&quot; said a broker from the Sofia Stock Exchange (SSE).</p>
<p>Investors eyed treasury paper or foreign currency investments instead, the broker said.</p>
<p>Short-term government paper now yields between 108 and 188 percent while the lev kept falling on the domestic forex market, trading near 199.50 on Friday, down from 194.20/30 a week ago.</p>
<p>Only the SSE operated this week after the Bulgarian Stock Exchange (BSE) went into a summer recess on August 5.</p>
<p>The BSE will resume trading on September 2.</p>
<p>Only three repo deals in treasury paper were struck on the SSE where weekly repo turnover rose to 3.264 million levs from 2.0 million levs last week.</p>
<p>The 13-share Reuter All Bulgaria Stock Exchange Index (RABSI) closed at 41.31 points, unchanged from last Friday.</p>
<p>					 RABSI</p>
<p>   Aug 23	WEEK'S CHANGE     1996 HIGH	   1996 LOW</p>
<p>   41.31	  0.00 pts   55.48 (15.02.96)  41.05 (12.07.96)</p>
<p>		    0.00 pct</p>
<p>				   * ALL-TIME HIGH   * ALL-TIME LOW</p>
<p>				   112.2 (27.04.94)  41.05 (12.07.96)</p>
<p>* RABSI calculated on daily basis since February 1, 1994</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 981 8569</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
