<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11079" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Excess cash seen pushing Polish T-bill yields down.</title>
<headline>Excess cash seen pushing Polish T-bill yields down.</headline>
<byline>Wojciech Moskwa</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish T-bill yields were seen falling near secondary market levels at next Monday's 600 million zloty primary aucton due to large demand caused by cash surpluses on the money market, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand may be three times bigger than the treasury's relatively small offer, and yields will inevitably fall,&quot; said Wojciech Kowalczyk, dealer at Bank Handlowy SA.</p>
<p>The Treasury will offer on Monday 300 million zlotys of 52-week bills and 100 million each of the 8-, 13- and 26-week papers.</p>
<p>Analysts estimated the average yield of the benchmark 52-week T-bill would ease to about 19.6 percent on Monday from 19.73 at the last primary auction.</p>
<p>In secondary trade, the benchmark was near 19.50 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Large demand will pull down yields at the tender, but they are still likely to be slightly higher than Friday's secondary market yields,&quot; said Slawomir Komonski, treasurer of Societe Generale.</p>
<p>Analysts saw the average yield on the shortest 8-week paper to falling to about 19 percent from 19.06 percent and the yield on 26-week paper to about 19.40 percent from 19.68 percent.</p>
<p>They said the average yield of the 13-week bill should fall to about 19.05 percent from 19.51 percent on August 5, when the paper was last sold at a primary auction.</p>
<p>Analysts said money market cash surpluses, caused by a scale-down in the number of reverse repo drainages by the central bank, will create the large demand at Monday's auction.</p>
<p>One-day interbank deposit rates tumbled to 12 percent on Friday from nearly 18 percent earlier this week as the central bank's longer-term outright sales failed to soak up the market's excess cash.</p>
<p>&quot;There is too much money on the market, and banks need alternatives to overnight deposits at 12 percent,&quot; said Wojciech Labryga, dealer at Bank Slaski SA.</p>
<p>Analysts expected the money market to stay over-liquid for much of next week, the last of the August reserve period, with some net three billion zlotys seen flowing into the market by Wednesday, August 28.</p>
<p>&quot;Through the over-liquidity, banks build up surpluses on their required reserve accounts so they should not have any trouble balancing reserve positions next week,&quot; said one foreign bank dealer based in Poland.</p>
<p>Analysts saw Friday's three-day drainage rate cut to 17.70 percent, against 19.12 percent for the 14-day operation on August 20, as highlighting the extent of the over-liquidity.</p>
<p>They said banks could look to the Treasury's 391 million zloty one-year index-linked bond auction on Tuesday as an alternative to 52-week T-bills, but they expected that auction to be undersubscibed.</p>
<p>They said the average price should inch up from the last auction on July 30 when it was 96.65 percent. The bond's coupon is the base inflation rate with no premium.</p>
<p>On the forex market, the zloty should breeze through the week between 1.5 and two percent from the trading band centre in slow summer trade.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no clear cut trends on the market other than adjustments to dollar/mark swings, and the zloty is likely to remain in its present band next week,&quot; said Bogdan Stepkowski, forex dealer at ING bank.</p>
<p>The zloty closed the week at 1.75 percent from the trading band centre against last week's close at 1.60 percent. On Friday, the zloty closed at 2.7405/25 per dollar versus Thursday's 2.7420/60 and at 1.8423/28 to the mark from 1.8430/85.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
