<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11076" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine celebrates year five of independence.</title>
<headline>Ukraine celebrates year five of independence.</headline>
<byline>Rostislav Khotin</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukraine celebrates five years of independence from Kremlin rule on Saturday, describing civil and inter-ethnic peace as its main post-Soviet achievement.</p>
<p>Ukraine's declaration of independence in 1991, backed nine-to-one by a referendum in December of that year, effectively dealt a death blow to the Soviet empire and ended more than three centuries of rule from Moscow.</p>
<p>Ukraine, with a Russian community of 11 million people -- the world's largest outside Russia -- has avoided conflicts like those in Russia's Chechnya, neighbouring Moldova, and the former Soviet republics of Georgia, Azerbaijan and Tajikistan.</p>
<p>&quot;Ukraine's biggest achievements for five years are the preservation of civil peace and inter-ethnic harmony,&quot; President Leonid Kuchma said in televised statement this week.</p>
<p>&quot;Unlike many other post-Soviet countries we were able to deal with conflict situations in a peaceful and civilised way.&quot;</p>
<p>But independence was initially accompanied by hyperinflation and economic collapse, although there are signs of a turnaround.</p>
<p>Inflation -- a hyperinflationary 10,300 percent a year in 1993 -- was a respectable 0.1 percent a month in June and July and the economy has just begun to grow.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt that economic growth has already started,&quot; said Adelbert Knobl, head of the International Monetary Fund's mission in Ukraine. &quot;The national bank and the government have every reason to be proud of their efforts.&quot;</p>
<p>Central bank officials said on Thursday that a much-postponed hryvna currency would &quot;definitely&quot; be introduced before the end of this year.</p>
<p>It will replace the interim karbovanets currency, which was introduced at par to the Russian rouble in 1992 but now trades at almost 33 karbovanets per rouble.</p>
<p>Ukraine has repeatedly promised to introduce the hryvna but had to postpone the plans because of economic problems.</p>
<p>Proud of its record in promptly joining both the Council of Europe and NATO's Partnership for Peace, Ukraine has displayed a certain naivety in foreign policy, offending China this week by allowing a Taiwanese minister to appear on a very public, if unofficial visit.</p>
<p>China cancelled a visit by a top-level delegation in protest. Kiev's Foreign Minister Hennady Udovenko said Beijing was overreacting.</p>
<p>But Ukraine, seeing itself as a bridge between Russia and the rapidly westernising countries of eastern Europe, is looking west as well as east.</p>
<p>Kuchma has said Kiev wants membership of the European Union, associate membership of the Western European Union defence grouping and to move closer to NATO.</p>
<p>One message from the West came this week, when U.S. President Bill Clinton congratulated Ukraine on the anniversary, promising to support market reforms and praising Ukraine as a &quot;stabilising factor&quot; in a united Europe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
