<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11084" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenia electric imports up after plant problem.</title>
<headline>Slovenia electric imports up after plant problem.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenian electricity producer and distributor Elektro Slovenija on Friday called on consumers to save electricity and said it hoped a power deficit caused by a plant outage would be shortlived.</p>
<p>Elektro's problems began on Monday when part of the Sostanj power plant broke down.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the largest supply crisis since independence (in 1991),&quot; the firm's operations director Milan Jevsenak told Reuters. &quot;I expect the damage to Sostanj will be repaired on Sunday. But if there are any other serious break-downs in the meantime, Slovenia could find itself in the dark.&quot;</p>
<p>Jevsenak said to ensure that there was no repeat of the current problems, Slovenia needed to construct more power plants and open import lines to Hungary and the former Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>The nation, which consumes an average 26 million kiloWatts daily, has had to double its imports to about six million kiloWatts a day, mainly from Austria and Switzerland.</p>
<p>Jevsenak noted domestic production traditionally declined in the summer due to regular maintenance. He said problems could continue until September 20, when all the main overhauls would be finished.</p>
<p>Slovenia has not suffered an electricity shortage since 1991.</p>
<p>-- Marja Novak, Ljubljana newsroom +386 61 125 8439</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
