<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11081" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenian shares firm slightly, seen blocked.</title>
<headline>Slovenian shares firm slightly, seen blocked.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenian shares firmed 0.07 percent on Friday but traders said the marekt showed little sign of breaking out its current trading range before the end of the month.</p>
<p>&quot;In the past five years we have never had such a standstill on the market. Many investors are not buying because they are afraid of losing more money than they already have this year,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>* The seven-share SBI index firmed 0.66 points to 981.26.</p>
<p>* Nine shares rose and three fell, while 11 were untraded.</p>
<p>* Turnover fell to 52.3 million tolars from 86.8 million.</p>
<p>* Food company Droga was most actively traded, firming 0.01 percent to 15,425 tolars on volume of 1,532 shares for total turnover of 23.6 million tolars.</p>
<p>* Pharmaceutical company Salus was the top gainer, rising 8.61 percent to 8,689 on volume of 290 shares for total turnover of 2.5 million tolars.</p>
<p>* Bank Probanka was the leading decliner, falling 3.04 percent to 15,010 on volume of 10 shares for total turnover of 0.2 million tolars.</p>
<p>* Drug maker Lek, who this week signed its first deal with a rump Yugoslav company since the break-up of Yugoslavia in 1991, was not traded as several brokers said they were unaware of the deal. -- Marja Novak, Ljubljana newsroom, 386-61-125-8439</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
