<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11082" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: MOL sees '96 results down on price rise delay.</title>
<headline>MOL sees '96 results down on price rise delay.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Hungarian government's Thursday decision to delay energy price rises to January 1, 1997 from October 1 will adversely affect oil and gas company MOL 's 1996 results, the company said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the delay) will have a negative impact on MOL Rt's results,&quot; deputy managing director Tibor Gulyas told Reuters. &quot;Our entire gas business will continue to make losses,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The government postponed the energy price rise saying it could not accept the results of a Trade and Industry Ministry study on which it would have based the price rise, and will appoint a government official to review the study.</p>
<p>MOL, which buys most of its gas from Russia, suffered a 14.5 billion forint loss in the gas business in 1995 and said earlier this year it expected to lose 2.5 billion forints in 1996.</p>
<p>First half results are not yet available as MOL has applied for an extension of the August 15 deadline for submitting them to the Budapest bourse because it is making an overall audit for the first half of 1996 in preparation for further privatisation steps later this year.</p>
<p>Gulyas only said losses as a direct result of the price rise delay would be &quot;in the order of billions (of forints).&quot;</p>
<p>However &quot;Hungary's gas supply, for which MOL is responsible, is not in danger,&quot; Gulyas said.</p>
<p>The government decree currently in force regarding energy prices guarantees energy suppliers and utilities an eight percent profit margin as of January 1, 1997.</p>
<p>On the Budapest Stock Exchange on Friday MOL shares slid to a daily low of 1,540 forints but later rebounded to end at 1,595 forints, down 165.</p>
<p>-- Denes Albert, Budapest newsroom +36 1 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
