<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11095" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: Estonian president faces re-election challenge.</title>
<headline>Estonian president faces re-election challenge.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former Estonian communist and leader of Estonia's drive for independence from the Soviet Union said on Friday he would challenge President Lennart Meri in a presidential election on Monday.</p>
<p>Arch-rival Arnold Ruutel and Meri contested the last presidential election in 1992, one year after the small country quit the Soviet Union. Meri, 67, is now seeking a second term.</p>
<p>Ruutel, 68, is currently deputy speaker of parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;Arnold Ruutel has agreed to run for the office of president,&quot; a spokesman for Ruutel's Country Peoples Party told Reuters after a party conference.</p>
<p>In Estonia, parliament chooses the president and the two men face a first round of voting on Monday, with a second and possibly third round the following day.</p>
<p>The winner needs the backing of 68 of the 101 members of parliament and will serve a five-year term.</p>
<p>The charismatic Meri is favourite to win in the first round with the public support of almost 60 MPs.</p>
<p>Ruutel so far only has the confirmed support of 22 members of parliament, including 20 from his own party.</p>
<p>But victory for Meri is not guaranteed as some politicians believe he has abused his position by taking too much power.</p>
<p>The main criticism against him is that he signed an agreement on the withdrawal of Russian troops in 1994 without consulting parliament.</p>
<p>Critics say the deal left too many former Soviet military personnel in Estonia.</p>
<p>Many Estonians regard the hundreds of thousands of Russian-speakers left in their country after independence as colonists and especially dislike former Soviet military staff.</p>
<p>Meri is very popular amongst ordinary Estonians and many regard him as a good spokesman for their country.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
