<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11091" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian lending rate inches up to 9.1 pct.</title>
<headline>Croatian lending rate inches up to 9.1 pct.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Croatian lending rate inched up 10 basis points to 9.1 percent in thin trade on Friday due to scarce demand by the usual borrowers on Zagreb's Money Market.</p>
<p>Total settlements fell to 26.2 million kuna, against supply of 177 million, and dealers said fresh loans accounted for only 3.5 million.</p>
<p>State investment bank HBOR rolled over 14 million kuna at a new, lower rate of 10 percent.</p>
<p>Call money rose to 10.0 percent from 9.7 percent, while insurers kept five-10 day kuna placements flat at 8.0 percent. The 31-366 day rate fell to 8.0 percent from 11.4 percent.</p>
<p>Because no banks asked for kuna funds to square positions, there was no overnight trade. That left 693.9 million kuna on the supply side.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Croatia said it stayed out of the foreign exchange market on Friday. Its kuna midrates for Saturday and Monday were flat at 5.2632 against the dollar and 3.5459 versus the German mark. -- Zoran Radosavljevic, Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
