<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11097" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Sidanco tender neutral for Chernogorneft - MC.</title>
<headline>Sidanco tender neutral for Chernogorneft - MC.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Russian government's planned investment tender for 34 percent of oil company Sidanko is positive for the parent but neutral for its main operating unit AO Chernogorneft, MC Securities said in a note.</p>
<p>The Federal Property Fund has said the stake will be on offer next month for 110 billion roubles but that the winner must invest at least 325.1 billion roubles in Sidanko.</p>
<p>The winner must also own and hand over to Sidanko 13 percent of Chernogorneft.</p>
<p>MC says the total value of the deal is at least $112.1 million and that this values Sidanko, whose reserves have been put at 12.8 billion barrels, at $329.7 million.</p>
<p>MC says the tender conditions mean the Uneximbank commercial bank, which won a tender for 51 percent of Sidanko under the government's shares-for-loans scheme and already owns 13-18 percent of Chernogorneft, looks well placed to win.</p>
<p>It says this may lead to additional investment in Sidanko but that, as a majority owner, it might well have made that investment anyway.</p>
<p>The position for Chernogorneft, which is 15.3 percent foreign-owned, is less clear, MC says. Chernogorneft is one of Russia's most liquid shares.</p>
<p>The company would benefit from being a subsidiary of a well-run Sidanko, the note said.</p>
<p>But, if Uneximbank were to hand over its Chernogorneft shares to Sidanko, the parent might be tempted to offer less favourable terms to Chernogorneft in any future share swap between Sidanko and its operating unit.</p>
<p>On the other hand, MC said, Sidanko's need for investment would probably stop it treating large numbers of foreign investors unfairly.</p>
<p>Chernogorneft shares closed on the Russian Trading System at $8.75 on Thursday but had not traded by 1100 GMT on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Nigel Stephenson, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
