<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11104" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Matav says expects to fulfil 1996 business targets.</title>
<headline>Matav says expects to fulfil 1996 business targets.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian telecommunication company Matav Rt said that based on first half year results it expected to fulfil its 1996 profit and sales targets.</p>
<p>&quot;In the first six months of the year we achieved the proportional part of the sales revenue and profit forecast (for the whole year),&quot; Matav said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Net sales revenues may exceed (the targeted) 190 billion forints by the end of the year and the over 12 billion forints profit is also a realistic target,&quot; it said. In 1995 Matav posted a net profit of 293 million forints on sales of 135.5 billion.</p>
<p>Matav which is 67 percent owned by MagyarCom, a 50-50 consortium of Germany's Deutsche Telekom and U.S.'s Ameritech, is exempted from taxation.</p>
<p>Matav declined to give figures for the first half of the year, but said its board approved the January-June consolidated figures which were calculated according to International Accounting Standards.</p>
<p>&quot;This (report) shows that the Matav group developed dynamically in the first six months of the year and the successful completion of the privatisation gave a boost to work,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Matav's privatisation ended last December when the German-American consortium acquired an additional 37 percent share package to boost its share in Matav to 67 percent.</p>
<p>Matav said the group's investments will surpass 240 billion forints during the three years between 1994 and 1996. The group's development plans for 1996 call for the connection of almost 300,000 new lines.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
