<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11118" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania oil workers cancel indefinite strike.</title>
<headline>Romania oil workers cancel indefinite strike.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romanian workers in the petrochemical industry have cancelled plans for an indefinite strike after wrestling concessions from their employers, a trade union leader said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We decided to give up the strike. Our main demands have been met,&quot; trade union leader Constantin Sirbu said from the oilfield of Ploiesti, north of Bucharest.</p>
<p>Last month the unions threatened to launch an all-out stoppage from Friday to protest against the authorities' failure to reform the sector and to ensure sufficient crude oil supplies to refineries.</p>
<p>&quot;Refineries work now at around 50 percent capacity, compared with 20 percent last month. Things have improved and we were also promised job security,&quot; Sirbu said.</p>
<p>A union demand for an increase of 50,000 lei in the average monthly wage of 440,000 lei had also been met, he said.</p>
<p>An acute shortage of hard currency as well as unforseen imports of crude and fuel oil made to cope with Romania's unusually large energy demand last winter forced the country to halve its crude oil imports over January-July.</p>
<p>The government responded by creating a special hard currency fund for crude imports that forces some 100 state-run companies to exchange part of their hard currency earnings at the central bank's disadvantageous exchange rate.</p>
<p>Last week, the country's main oil trader Petrolexportimport said it had paid its outstanding bills and that it would import some 5.0 million tonnes of crude by the end of 1996.</p>
<p>A new National Oil Company holding group that has brought the country's sprawling oil industry under the one umbrella, expected to better channel funds in the oil sector and help finance crude imports, also became operational this month.</p>
<p>&quot;According to our estimates, refineries will work at some 75 percent capacity which means processing around 18 million tonnes of crude a year,&quot; Sirbu said.</p>
<p>Romania has a bloated refining capacity of some 35 million tonnes a year (equivalent to around 700,000 barrels per day), inherited from the communist era. A government programme aims to trim capacity to some 20 million tonnes (about 400,000 bpd) over the next five years.</p>
<p>-- Bucharest Newsroom +40 1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
