<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11124" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the reports carried by Estonia's newspapers on Friday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- Both the Estonian and Latvian parliaments ratified a bilateral sea border agreement.</p>
<p>- Mare Korkjas won a gold medal in swimming and Anneli Ojastu a silver medal in long-jump at the Atlanta Para-Olympics.</p>
<p>- President Lennart Meri faced renewed allegations of KGB links during the Soviet era. Five members of parliament issued a statement asking Meri to answer questions about contradictory data in his biography, his deportation to Siberia, trips abroad, jobs in the 1950s and reports to VEKSA, which worked with the KGB.</p>
<p>POSTIMEES</p>
<p>- The heads of nine parliamentary parties were asked to rate Meri's chances of re-election in the first round between zero and 10. The results showed an average rating of 4.2 out of 10.</p>
<p>- Meri was registered officialy on August 22 as a presidential candidate.</p>
<p>SONUMILEHT</p>
<p>- Meri was issued his Estonian passport yesterday.</p>
<p>EESTI PAEVALEHT</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Siim Kallas and head of the Reform Party says there is no chance he will stand for president.</p>
<p>ARIPAEV</p>
<p>- Tallin Pharmaceutical Producers is negotiating over opening a branch in Russia.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
