<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11128" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- At present investment funds cannot operate in market because there is no market. They could work on exchange but stocks there are unattractive, newspaper quotes Ioana Vlas, president of national union of investment funds.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Tarom plans to sell its Airbus planes and to purchase eight Boeing 737s.</p>
<p>- Finance Minister senior official said on Thursday government was planning to freeze prices of number of products including foodstuffs and petrol, as well as of energy and rents till 1997.</p>
<p>- Newly created National Oil Company with its current structure and tasks seems to express government tendency to monopolise oil sector.</p>
<p>- State Ownership Fund (FPS) managed to privatise 2,311 state companies so far, Emil Dima, president of FPS's administration board says in interview.</p>
<p>TINERETUL LIBER</p>
<p>- Number of licensed securities companies in Romania has reached 89.</p>
<p>AZI</p>
<p>- Banc Post plans to raise its capital by 2.2 billion lei this year, when it forecasts gross profit of 31 billion lei.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>-  Banca Romana petru Dezvoltare is first Romanian bank to go private in next few months. Bank vice-president Ioan Niculescu says in interview bank has consolidated its position owing to performing credits for investment in private sector.</p>
<p>- Romania expects post-privatisation fund to become operational in early October, Iacob Zelenco, president of National Privatisation Agency said.</p>
<p>CRONICA ROMANA</p>
<p>- Court of Accounts says in statement control of National Bank showed irregularities in using profit.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Teodor Melescanu, president of national committee to support President Ion Iliescu's candidacy for a new presidential term in November 3 polls, breaks diplomatic status which says &quot;diplomats cannot be party or political organisation members and cannot implicate themselves in parties' or political organisations' activities&quot;.</p>
<p>- &quot;I have nuanced some ideas&quot; says Romanian journalist on interview with Emil Constantinescu, presidential candidate of main opposition Democratic Convention (CDR) bloc in the U.S. last month. The interview caused a scandal as Constantinescu allegedly said he would bring exiled King Michael back to the country after being elected president in the November 3 polls.</p>
<p>- Statement from ex-king Michael says he keeps his impartialty over whole political life in Romania and stresses that Romania's main responsibility now is to hold free and democratic elections to insure a stable government afterwards.</p>
<p>- Disinformation seems to be policy to be used by ruling Party of Social Democracy (PDSR) in electoral campaign, said Mircea Ionescu Quintus, head of National Liberal Party (PNL), second largest in the opposition CDR bloc.</p>
<p>- Newspaper publishes a four-page report on August 23, 1944, when Romania switched sides from Nazi germany to join the Allied forces in World War Two.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Former reformist Prime Minister Petre Roman, candidate for presidency of Social Democratic Union (USD) said he would not collaborate with parties willing to change the constitution.</p>
<p>- Agriculture Minister Valeriu Tabara is campaign manager of Gheorghe Funar, presidential candidate of National Unity Party (PUNR) and Justice Minsiter Iosif Gavril Chiuzbaian is spokesman of PUNR's campaign staff for parliamentary elections.</p>
<p>- Three of the four casinos on the Black Sea coast were shut down for grave financial irregularities.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- Diversion with &quot;pro-monarchist statement of CDR leader Emil Constantinescu&quot; came to an end after the author of the interview with Constantinescu admitted he had changed some ideeas, says the newspaper warning the population to learn from the case on how a diversion can be organised.</p>
<p>CRONICA ROMANA</p>
<p>- An apartment in a concrete block in Bucharest, 5.5 hectares of farming land, a 10-year old Fiat and a new Cielo car, 200 square metres in a mountain resort are Prime Minister Nicolae Vacaroiou's assets, which he declared to &quot;avoid any possible denigration&quot;.</p>
<p>- Treaty with Hungary is a starting point which can help to advance in a longer and more complex process regarding the historic reconciliation between the two countries, says Defence Minister Gheorghe Tinca in interview.</p>
<p>- Upper house of Senate to resume sessions after summer holidays on September 2.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- People with full blowen AIDS are discriminated, while Romania's legal system grants protection, says the newspaper. ($=3,157 lei) -- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
