<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11125" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Granic arrives to sign Croatia-Yugoslavia treaty.</title>
<headline>Granic arrives to sign Croatia-Yugoslavia treaty.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslavia and Croatia were poised on Friday to sign a landmark normalisation treaty ending five years of tensions and paving way for stabilisation in the Balkans.</p>
<p>Croatian Foreign Minister Mate Granic landed at Belgrade airport aboard a Croatian government jet on Friday morning for talks with his Yugoslav counterparts and a signing ceremony expected around noon (1000 GMT).</p>
<p>On Thursday the Yugoslav government endorsed the text of the agreement on normalising relations between the two countries, the Yugoslav news agency Tanjug said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government assessed the agreement as a crucial step to resolving the Yugoslav crisis, ensuring the restoration of peace in former Yugoslavia,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Last-minute talks this week on the legal fine print finally cleared the way for a treaty based on mutual recognition within internationally recognised borders and the establishment of diplomatic relations, diplomats said.</p>
<p>The pact ends five years of hostility after Croatia's secession from federal Yugoslavia. Western powers regard diplomatic normalisation between Croatia and Serbia, twin pillars of the old multinational federal Yugoslavia, as a crucial step towards a lasting peace in the Balkans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
