<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11132" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Belgrade press on Friday. Reuters has not verified them and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>NASA BORBA</p>
<p>- Yugoslavia and Croatia to recognise each other on Friday.</p>
<p>- Federal Republic of Yugoslavia accepted all IMF terms, says Mihajlo Nikolic, advisor to ex-Natbank governor Dragoslav Avramovic.</p>
<p>- Kragujevac weapons factory employees enter fourth day of strike.</p>
<p>- July inflation of 6.6% calls for lower taxes and greater exports or external borrowing.</p>
<p>- Bosnian Serb Army general staff criticises IFOR for simultaneously disarming Bosnian Serbs and arming the other side, instead of acting as a peace force.</p>
<p>- Hague Tribunal for War Crimes in the former Yugoslavia opens office in Belgrade Friday.</p>
<p>- Bosnian Serb president and vice-president will be elected by majority vote, says Bosnian Serb member of Temporary Election Committee Slobodan Kovac.</p>
<p>- School-year will not begin on September 2 if the Government does not pay the teachers overdue salaries, says Independent Teachers' Trade Union.</p>
<p>- Serbia and Montenegro, which are in a defacto confederate relation, should have separate armies, as they already have their own police forces, says Col. Ljubodrag Stojanovic, recently dismissed head of the Yugoslav Army Chief-Of-Staff Information Department.</p>
<p>POLITIKA</p>
<p>- Yugoslavia holds no more Croatians in jail, Croatia to account for 2,278 Serbs by September 30, says government committee for humanitarian issues. Yugoslav and Croatian committees to meet in Belgrade on September 13.</p>
<p>- Elections in Eastern Slavonia, Baranja and western Srem are not feasible before mid-1997, says the region's president Goran Hadzic.</p>
<p>VECERNJE NOVOSTI</p>
<p>- Belgrade bus company &quot;Lasta&quot; and Zagreb's &quot;Pan-turist&quot; to launch daily traffic from Belgrade to Zagreb and Belgrade to Osijek on September 15 at the latest, says Lasta inter-city manager Zoran Leontijevic.</p>
<p>- Illegal cigarette trafficking costs the state at least 1.5 billion dinars. - Belgrade newsroom, 381 11 +224305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
