<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11134" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in the Latvian newspapers on Friday. Prepared for Reuters by the Co-operation Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- Parliament ratified the treaty on the maritime border between Latvia and Estonia.</p>
<p>- Parliament approved a declaration on the occcupation of Latvia, which calls on the international community to recognise the fact of Latvia's occupation by the Soviet Union in 1940. Ten deputies, representing the Socialist Party and the People's Harmony Party, voted against the bill.</p>
<p>- Parliament approved a draft bill which will formally legalise abortions. The bill is strongly opposed by the Christian Democrat faction and the Catholic Church.</p>
<p>DIENA</p>
<p>- The Latvian Farmer's Union and the Union of Christian Democrats give partial support to the plan of Prime Minister Andris Shkele to abolish district governments. The two parties believe that the heads of the districts should be chosen by local residents.</p>
<p>- After receiving an anonymous letter of threats to those investigating the activities of the OMON, a Moscow-backed paramilitary unit which fought against restoring Latvia's independence in 1990-1991, the interior ministry decided to start criminal proceedings.</p>
<p>- The mayor of the city of Ventspils, Aivars Lembergs, who holds posts in several business companies, refuses to abide by the anti-corruption law, which says he should give them up.</p>
<p>NEATKARIGA RITA AVIZE</p>
<p>- 40 workers from the Riga mirror works went on strike to protest against delays in payment of salaries.</p>
<p>BIZNESS &amp; BALTIYA</p>
<p>- Economy Minister Guntar Krasts met with officials from the Russian embassy in Latvia to discuss co-operation between the two countries.</p>
<p>- President of the Latvian Gas company, Adrian Davis, said in an interview that the appointment of Piotr Rodionov to the post of energy minister in Russia will help the privatisation of Latvian Gas.</p>
<p>DIENAS BIZNESS</p>
<p>- Foreign companies will be offered up to 35 percent of shares from the Latvenergo new share issue.</p>
<p>- The brewery Varpa starts producing Czech-brand Brauner beer.</p>
<p>- The Bank of Latvia starts hard currency clearing.</p>
<p>- Losses of the Latvian Shipping company reached $51.4 million.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
