<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11133" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Croatian newspapers on Friday.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Mate Granic travels to Belgrade to sign the agreement on normalisation of relations with Yugoslavia, and Croatia can be satisfied with what has been achieved in last-minute talks.</p>
<p>- Croatian kuna, Bosnian dinar and German mark gain equal status as currencies in Bosnia's Moslem-Croat Federation.</p>
<p>- National oil company INA starts exploitation of the vital Djeletovci oilfield in the last Serb-held enclave of Eastern Slavonia.</p>
<p>- War damage is estimated at 150 billion kuna, and Croatia has so far invested 3 billion in reconstruction which will take at least 10 more years, says Jure Radic, Minister of Development and Reconstruction.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- Salaries of the employed in the drugs firm Pliva, trading on the London Stock Exchange, will rise by nine percent by the end of the month.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- Plane crash near Dubrovnik which killed U.S. Commerce Secretary Ron Brown in April was caused by bad flight planning and organisation, and a mistake made by the pilot, concludes joint American-Croatian investigation. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
