<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11146" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Dolly leaves trail of destruction in Mexico, 2 dead.</title>
<headline>Dolly leaves trail of destruction in Mexico, 2 dead.</headline>
<byline>Chris Aspin</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hurricane Dolly crashed into Mexico's Veracruz state on Friday, killing at least two people and leaving a trail of destruction in its wake, authorities and news reports said.</p>
<p>Dolly, the fourth big weather system of the Atlantic season, ploughed into the northern tip of the largely agricultural Veracruz, ripping down telephone wires and electric poles, smashing windows and uprooting trees.</p>
<p>One woman died when she was hit by a high tension cable that crashed to the ground as Dolly came ashore around 11 a.m. EDT (1500 GMT), close to the port of Tampico in the Gulf of Mexico, media reports said.</p>
<p>National television network Televisa said heavy rains brought on by Dolly in the northern state of Nuevo Leon, killed a man when he was swept away by strong currents in the Topo Chico River in the industrial city of Monterrey.</p>
<p>Hurricane Dolly weakened rapidly as it moved over land in Mexico on Friday and was downgraded to a tropical storm with maximum winds of 55 mph (88 kph), but threatened flash floods and mudslides in mountainous areas, the National Hurricane Center said.</p>
<p>Tropical Storm Edouard, moving through the Atlantic Ocean, strengthened but remained far from land and was a threat only to shipping interests.</p>
<p>At 2 p.m. EDT (1800 GMT), the center of Tropical Storm Dolly was located at latitude 21.9 north, longitude 99.0 west, about 75 miles (121 km) west-southwest of Tampico, Mexico, and was moving west-northwest at 13 mph (21 kph).</p>
<p>A hurricane warning for coastal areas of Mexico was discontinued.</p>
<p>Forecasters said they expected Dolly to continue weakening as it moved into the mountains, but residents were warned to be alert for torrential rains and life-threatening flash floods. The storm could dump six to 12 inches (15-30 cm) of rain on parts of Mexico, they said.</p>
<p>Radio network Radio Red reported 2,300 people were evacuated from the low lying regions around Tampico and that rivers were rapidly rising in the region from the torrential rains dumped over a wide area of southern and eastern Mexico.</p>
<p>Ruben Diaz Garza, director of the local newspaper El Sol de Tampico, told Reuters that Dolly had made around 1,500 people homeless and that the entire port of some 500,000 was without electricity and drinking water.</p>
<p>Dolly raced across the Caribbean this week to slam into Mexico's Quintana Roo state on Tuesday. It burst into the Gulf of Mexico on Wednesday after crossing the Yucatan Peninsula on Wednesday, home to hundreds of Maya ruins.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
