<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11149" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Gruma, ADM link forges N. American grains powerhouse.</title>
<headline>Gruma, ADM link forges N. American grains powerhouse.</headline>
<byline>Chris Aspin</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. agribusiness conglomerate Archer Daniels Midland and Mexico-based corn flour giant Gruma announced plans to link up Thursday, forging a continent-wide grains-to-food powerhouse.</p>
<p>Gruma, the world's largest producer of corn flour and maker of corn pancake tortillas, and Decatur-Ill.-based ADM hope to seal their North American venture by Sept 30.</p>
<p>Key elememts of the partnership are that ADM will obtain a 22 percent stake in Gruma for $258 million. The venture also has the companies combining U.S. corn flour operations and Mexican wheat flour operations into joint ventures.</p>
<p>The partnership is subject to Gruma shareholder approval and a green light from Mexico's Antitrust Commission and other North American regulatory bodies.</p>
<p>Gruma and ADM reckon the joint ventures will represent 25 percent of the $660 million U.S. corn flour market and a significant portion of the $1.5 billion Mexican wheat flour market.</p>
<p>In an interview, Gruma Chief Executive officer Eduardo Livas said the companies hoped to beef up Mexican wheat milling, taking capacity from current levels of 250,000 metric tons per year to one million tons in five to seven years.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to focus first on utilizing the capacity and then expanding operations,&quot; Livas said, adding that the companies sought to reach a market share of around 25 percent to 30 percent.</p>
<p>Livas said combining the companies' U.S. corn flour milling operations would take the total capacity up to 515,000 tons per year. Gruma already has capacity of 350,000 tons in the United States.</p>
<p>Livas said they plan to divest one Texas corn flour mill and introduce Gruma technology and beef up capacity in two others in California and Kentucky. &quot;We plan to refurbish and bring them over to our technology so we can increase capacity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said Gruma planned to use almost all the $258 million payment from ADM to pay down short-debt. The company currently holds bank debts totalling $580 million.</p>
<p>Felix Boni, director of research at HSBC James Capel in Mexico City, said the wheat side of the venture looked like a probable long-term move for Gruma and ADM to enter the Mexican bread market.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, strategic advantage for Gruma is that it gains access to ADM technology and also access to their distribution and transportation network,&quot; Boni said, adding that on the financial side, Gruma will reduce its debt levels and should improve operating costs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
