<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11144" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile tells Hashimoto it expects more investments.</title>
<headline>Chile tells Hashimoto it expects more investments.</headline>
<byline>Roger Atwood</byline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chileans want Japan to invest more heavily in their country and can offer easy access to the vast Brazilian market as an inducement, President Eduardo Frei told Japan's Premier Ryutaro Hashimoto on Friday.</p>
<p>Frei and Hashimoto met on the second day of the Japanese leader's official visit to Chile, part of a Latin American tour aimed at raising Japan's profile in a region it once wrote off as a land of turmoil and disasters.</p>
<p>Officials of both countries said Japan was now looking to Latin America as the only place where economic growth rates could match those of southern Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;Latin America is really changing, and therefore we hope the prime minister's visit will act as a catalyst to arouse Japanese investors' interest,&quot; said Hiroshi Hashimoto, the premier's spokesman.</p>
<p>Nowhere was the change more evident than in prosperous Chile, he told reporters.</p>
<p>He said Frei made it clear to Hashimoto that Chile expected Japan -- Chile's second largest trading partner -- to start putting real money into the South American country where it is now only a minor investor.</p>
<p>&quot;During the meeting, President Frei said he expects there to be a real increase in direct Japanese investments in Chile,&quot; said Japanese president's spokesman.</p>
<p>Frei mentioned Chile's recent free trade agreement with the Mercosur bloc, which includes Brazil, as one of Chile's benefits, he said. The agreement will phase out tariffs between Chile and Mercosur, which also includes Argentina, Uruguay and Paraguay, over 15 years.</p>
<p>He signalled that Hashimoto liked the idea.</p>
<p>&quot;Japanese businessmen may see more advantages to investing in Chile, and from Chile exporting to Brazil, than investing directly in Brazil,&quot; said the spokesman.</p>
<p>The Japanese have about $500 million invested in Chile -- making them a distant seventh among investors by country.</p>
<p>Hashimoto's visit to Chile was dominated by hard-headed economics, with none of the multi-million dollar loans and aid packages his entourge signed in Mexico. His only donation in Chile was $480,000 for a cultural institute.</p>
<p>The premier was due to fly to Brazil early on Saturday and will later visit Peru and Costa Rica.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
