<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11140" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories reported by Hungary's press, based on information by Nepszabadsag's Hungary Around the Clock service. For further details on how to subscribe to Hungary Around the Clock, please contact Monica Kovacs at (361) 351 2440 or fax your request to (361) 351 7141.</p>
<p>ALL PAPERS</p>
<p>- The price of energy and the cost of higher education will remain constant at least until the end of the year, the government announced Thursday.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- The opposition Christian Democratic People's Party began collecting signatures Thursday in a bid to force Parliament to hold a special session to debate the Hungarian-Romanian basic treaty.</p>
<p>- The Alliance of Free Democrats is calling for a minimum HUF 10 billion more for the purpose of raising the family allowance next year.</p>
<p>- The foreign-owned Danubius Hotels Rt appears set to buy the hotel chain Hungaria Szalloda for HUF 8.1 billion, now that the State Privatisation and Holding Co announced Thursday that it approved the bid for the 14-member chain.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- The Budapest Stock Exchange on Thursday suspended trading of Danubius shares on grounds that preliminary news reports indicating that Danubidus' bid for the Hungarian Szalloda hotel chain had met with success were impossible to substantiate and could thus have unduly influenced investors.</p>
<p>- July saw a HUF 2.6 billion increase in household hard currency savings, indicating a slight reversal of the trend seen over the first seven months of the year.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- Monsignor Piero Marini, a representative of Pope John Paul II said Thursday that no disease can mar the September visit by the Pope to Hungary as he is in a good state of health.</p>
<p>NAPSZABADSAG</p>
<p>- Bela Marko, president of the Democratic Federation of Hungarians in Romania said that the Hungarian cabinet had indicated a desire to discuss the draft of the basic treaty with Romania with his group next week.</p>
<p>MAGYAR HIRLAP</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- The president of the Trade Union of Higher Education Employees announced Thursday that there will be no further dismissals in the higher education sector this year.</p>
<p>- Citizens of the former Soviet Union have &quot;rediscovered&quot; Hungary, observes this paper, noting that last year's one million legal visitors has restored the number seen five years ago.</p>
<p>- The Scandinavian airline SAS will increase the weekly number of its Budapest routes from eight to ten as of September 3.</p>
<p>- The Economic Competition Agency imposed a HUF 3 million</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>fine Thursday on the cosmetics retail chain Azur over two advertisements it says misled consumers.</p>
<p>- A Finnish consortium comprising two companies, Ivo and Tomen, has been awarded majority ownership of Budapest Eromu (Power Plant), the State Privatisation and Holding Co. announced.</p>
<p>NAPI GAZDASAG</p>
<p>- ABN-AMRO Bank Magyarorszag Rt, subsidiary of Holland's ABN-AMRO Bank NV, saw a $400 million gross profit in the first half and boosted its balance sheet footing by nearly HUF 6 billion, to HUF 35.5 billion.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- Administrative State Secretary Elemer Kiss said the cabinet wants to sell Magyar Hitel Bank to a strategic investor who will purchase 90 per cent of the shares and guarantee to raise its primary capital.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom (36-1) 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
