<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11143" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia army chief cites rebel threat.</title>
<headline>Colombia army chief cites rebel threat.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA, Colombia 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leftist guerrillas operating across Colombia are simply &quot;gangsters,&quot; but they pose the single biggest threat to the country's democratic stability, Army chief Gen. Harold Bedoya said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've referred to them successively as subversives, guerrillas and insurgents, but in reality they're nothing but gangsters,&quot; Bedoya said in a speech late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Let us not be fooled. In Colombia a group of mafiosos disguised as a political insurgency wants to pull off the robbery of the century -- the illegal appropriation of an entire government through violent blackmail and illict enrichment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>His remarks came on the same day that leftist guerrillas killed four Colombian marines patrolling a river in the drug-infested southeastern province of Guaviare, authorities said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Military spokesmen said Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) rebels early on Wednesday attacked a high-speed patrol boat with automatic weapons and dynamite. Three marines were wounded in addition to the four killed.</p>
<p>Guaviare, a FARC stronghold, is one of Colombia's leading cocaine production centres. The FARC, the country's largest and oldest rebel group, specialises in protecting rural drug farms and laboratories.</p>
<p>In his speech, Bedoya also made an appeal for foreign military aid to fight the so-called &quot;narco-guerrillas&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Colombia's narco-guerrillas are now the worst threat to our democracy and its institutions,&quot; he said. &quot;We want our friends to recognise that, to understand it and to collaborate in the vast fight we're engaged in.&quot;</p>
<p>Many countries, including the United States, maintain curbs on aid to Colombia's military because of its poor human rights record.</p>
<p>The Colombian army chief made his remarks at a ceremony in the capital marking the launch of a book written by one of his staffers entitled &quot;The FARC Cartel&quot; that details what Bedoya describes as the FARC's now-dominant role in the drug trade.</p>
<p>Western diplomats say there is no solid intelligence to prove the FARC has become a dominant player in global drug markets like the billionaire leaders of the Cali cartel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA, Colombia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
