<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11157" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine stocks extend losing streak at close.</title>
<headline>Argentine stocks extend losing streak at close.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine stocks surrendered early gains to close lower again Thursday in slow volume, dogged by fiscal worries and a slump in bellwether YPF, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market faces a great deal of uncertainty over the economy and it doesn't look like the outlook is improving,&quot; said Jose Napoli of brokers Ignoto y Napoli.</p>
<p>The weighted MerVal index shed 1.1 percent to 491.71, extending losses so far this week to 6.5 percent.</p>
<p>YPF's share price fall followed Ecuador's decision Wednesday to cancel a contract with its subsidiary Maxus.  </p>
<p>The oil giant, which fell with the rest of the market Wednesday but typically outperformed the index, slid 2.3 percent in the session to $21.1, matching its ADRs.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not clear exactly how the Ecuador situation will evolve or affect YPF, but the news finally rubbed off on the stock today,&quot; said Npoli.</p>
<p>Traders said the market remained chiefly concerned about the fiscal question -- how soon Congress will pass a package of tax hikes, whose delay raises the ghost of political infighting, and to what extent those same measures may thwart a budding economic recovery.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
