<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11156" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks end soft, rally pauses to consolidate.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks end soft, rally pauses to consolidate.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican stocks closed lower in a volatile session on Thursday as profit-taking took hold following the record-setting performances from earlier in the week, dealers said.</p>
<p>The IPC index of leading stocks lost 23.04 points or 0.68 percent to 3,389.33.</p>
<p>&quot;After the big increases that we've had it was normal that there would be some profit-taking,&quot; one trader said. &quot;It's important to note that the market respected resistance. The market has to consolidate its advance. It's not logical that it will continue to grow so fast.&quot;  </p>
<p>The IPC index opened strong, surging to a high of 3,428.40 points early in the session that was just four points off the record intraday high. But it then plummeted rapidly until hitting support levels just below 3,380 points.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is rewarding long-term investors, but for those who entered at 3,000, it's a good chance to take profits,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;The adjustment is also good because it gives new investors a chance to get in when prices are cheap.&quot;</p>
<p>Volume was brisk at 149.53 million shares on 4,874 trades. Of 111 stocks traded, losers outpaced gainers, 57 to 35.  </p>
<p>Topping the list of percentage losers  .PL.MX was Cydsasa A, down 5.03 percent or 88 centavos to 16.60 pesos, followed by Sidek L, off 4.76 percent or nine centavos to 1.80 pesos, and Autlan A, down 3.66 percent or 32 centavos to 8.42 pesos.</p>
<p>On the list of gainers  .PG.MX, Ponder A climbed 5.71 percent or 20 centavos to 3.70 pesos and Elektra L shares were up 5.26 percent or 80 centavos to 16 pesos.</p>
<p>Telmex L shares, the largest issue on the bolsa, continued their winning streak by gaining 0.78 percent or 10 centavos to 12.84 pesos. Telmex ADRs closed unchanged at 34-1/8.</p>
<p>-- Dan Trotta, Mexico City newsroom, (525) 728-9507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
