<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11152" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: COFFEE-Brazil watches progress of export tax bill.</title>
<headline>COFFEE-Brazil watches progress of export tax bill.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Bulloch</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The progress of a bill to remove a 13 percent export, or so-called ICMS tax, from goods including coffee is being watched with interest by traders, some of whom are still sceptical over the true merits of any change.</p>
<p>&quot;I personally am totally against removing the tax. The end-buyer is going to want to see a 13 percent drop in prices, producers will want a 13 percent rise in prices and exporters are going to be caught in the middle,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>Others were wary that in the case of coffee, another tax, such as a contribution or value added tax, could be introduced to make up for lost revenue.</p>
<p>Last week Planning Minister Antonio Kandir reached an agreement with finance secretaries representing Brazil's 27 state governments to eliminate the tax.</p>
<p>The Lower House of Brazil's Congress had been due to vote on a motion making the bill a priority on Wednesday afternoon but the session was suspended as negotiations continued over the terms of compensation.  </p>
<p>The bill would offer state governments 3.6 billion reais ($3.56 billion) in compensation during the first year of the new system, of which 25 percent would be paid in cash.</p>
<p>The remainder would be paid in securitised government debt paper which would be used to reduce debts of state-level debts to the federal government, the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>The reasoning behind the bill is that it will go a long way to reducing the high costs of doing business in Brazil, known as the &quot;custo Brasil&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically the federal government is hoping to stimulate even more revenue from exports,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>Coffee exports in the first seven months of this year represented 2.67 percent of total export revenue, bringing in around $730 million, down 40.17 percent from last year.</p>
<p>However in the month of July, its participation grew to 3.48 percent, the fourth largest earner, with revenue up 15.31 percent from last year at $155.27 million.</p>
<p>July marked the rebirth of Brazilian exports as shipments once again surpassed the one million bag mark and August figures are showing an upward trend.  </p>
<p>As of August 20, exports based on bills of lading totalled 528,153 bags, according to the latest bulletin from the Rio de Janeiro Center of Commerce. Certificates of origin however reached 862,748 bags.</p>
<p>Domestic producers however are now showing a more marked reluctance to sell, with higher international prices and funds coming through from the government to hold back coffee.</p>
<p>In the domestic market, Santos brokers Escritorio Carvalhaes on August 22 quoted fine-to-extrafine Mogiana/Minas green beans at 122/123 reais per 60 kg, well up from the 108/110 reais quoted on August 15.  </p>
<p>On the export market, prices were more stable, with Santos brokers Wolthers &amp; Associates quoted speciality 17/18s coffees unchanged at 14 over New York for Sept/Oct shipment.</p>
<p>Fine 17/18s were three under, also steady, but Swedish qualities had firmed to 10 under from last week's 11 under.</p>
<p>-- Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 5074151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42390">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
