<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11158" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Caracas stocks dip on profit-taking in busy trade.</title>
<headline>Caracas stocks dip on profit-taking in busy trade.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Caracas stocks shed some of this week's earlier gains, dipping amid a burst of profit-taking that, brokers say, is only a blip in an otherwise upwards trend.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a very dynamic session, with both local and foreign investors paying a lot of attention... but the profit-taking was only among very selected stocks,&quot; said Financorp broker Hector Perez.</p>
<p>The market's 19-share index slipped 0.76 percent to close at 4,575.33 as eleven million shares traded worth 1.7 billion bolivars ($3.6 million).  </p>
<p>Food producer Mavesa, which has led the market's rise over recent sessions, lost 2.40 bolivars to close at 115.55. Similarly, steel producer Sivensa dropped 10.00 bolivars to end at 300.00.</p>
<p>&quot;It was only profit-taking,&quot; said Profimerca trader Miguel Gonzalez who sees sustained rises lying ahead for the bolsa, albeit interspersed with days of profit-taking.</p>
<p>Among traded issues 21 fell, 14 rose and eight closed flat. Bellwether stock Electricidad de Caracas gained 2.00 bolivars to end at 388.00.</p>
<p>-- Ana Isabel Martinez, Caracas newsroom</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
