<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11167" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUATEMALA: Guatemala state utility to sell two power plants.</title>
<headline>Guatemala state utility to sell two power plants.</headline>
<dateline>GUATEMALA CITY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The state-owned Guatemalan Electric Co (EEGSA) plans to sell two power plants through an international bidding process, as Congress prepares to approve a bill to end the government's monopoly on electric production and distribution, the Energy and Mines Ministry said Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will open bidding for the Laguna plant and the Stewart and Stevenson turbine in order to capitalize the Guatemalan Electric Co,&quot; Henry Hernandez, a spokesman for the ministry, told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Under the proposed General Electricity Law, which Congress is expected to pass next week, the new owners of the plants could sell electricity directly to consumers on the open market.</p>
<p>The EEGSA, which sells power to residents of the Guatemala City area, owes $115 million to the National Electrification Institute (INDE), also owned by the government. The INDE produces electricity that it sells to the EEGSA and directly to consumers outside the capital.  </p>
<p>According to Hernandez, the ministry will form a commission, including members of religious and human rights group, to monitor the bidding process.</p>
<p>Hernandez said bidding would open soon after the commission was formed in late September. The ministry hopes to sell the thermoelectric plants by February, he said.</p>
<p>Hernandez said the Stewart and Stevenson plant, in the southern department of Escuintla, has a current capacity of 28 megawatts. The Laguna plant, in Amatitlan about 20 miles (32 km) south of Guatemala City, has a capacity of 80 megawatts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUATEMALA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUATEMALA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
