<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11165" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile shares end down, seen steady next week.</title>
<headline>Chile shares end down, seen steady next week.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chilean blue chips closed softer Friday as news of stronger-than-expected June economic growth diminished hopes of an early cut in interest rates, said traders.</p>
<p>The market is expected to remain steady next week with light volume depriving the bolsa of momentum, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Next week will be a period of consolidation,&quot; said Pedro Santa Maria, finance manager of brokerage Socimer. &quot;I don't see any substantial changes unless some market-moving news emerges.&quot;</p>
<p>The 40-share IPSA index ended down 0.72 percent at 97.65 points. The IGPA index declined 0.45 percent to 5,365.56 points.  </p>
<p>Volume rose to 22.6 billion pesos with turnover boosted by an offering of nine billion pesos of Soquimich A series shares, said traders.</p>
<p>Dealers noted heavy speculative trading in power utilities Endesa and Enersis.</p>
<p>Traders reported a flurry of sell orders after the central bank said the economy expanded 6.3 percent in June compared with analysts' forecasts of a five percent increase.</p>
<p>Analysts said the report may just have been a one-off blip, with other indicators, including retail sales figures, pointing to a slowdown in economic growth.  </p>
<p>The central bank previously said it would not reduce interest rates until the economy has cooled and inflationary pressures eased.</p>
<p>Losers included winery Concha y Toro, down 2.45 percent at 159 pesos, forestry firm Masisa, down 2.44 percent at 200 pesos, and telecoms company CTC, which fell 1.51 percent to 2,290 pesos.</p>
<p>Gainers included power distributor Chilquinta, up 1.38 percent at 2,180 pesos, Banco O'Higgins, up 0.33 percent at 1,530 pesos, and fertilizer company Soquimich , which rose 0.23 percent at 2,135 pesos.</p>
<p>-- Margaret Orgill, Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595 x212</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
