<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11160" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico same-day Cetes rate closes higher at 24 pct.</title>
<headline>Mexico same-day Cetes rate closes higher at 24 pct.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's same-day Cetes rate closed higher on Thursday, reversing a downward trend when one investor brought paper into the secondary money market  MXAAB at the end of the day in order to square positions, dealers said.</p>
<p>The same-day Cetes rate rose 50 basis points to 24 percent, a rate dealers said was not representative of the market. Earlier Thursday, the rate bottomed out at 23 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;Rates were way down because of speculation,&quot; one dealer said. &quot;People didn't want to buy paper at those levels, and then someone came in with a lot of paper and in order to square positions.&quot;</p>
<p>Rates for bank notes and acceptances dropped 90 basis points to close at 24.50.</p>
<p>Rates on longer-term Cetes also fell sharply in the secondary market with 28-day Cetes down 57 basis points to 24 percent, 91-day rates down 125 basis points to 26.50 percent and six-month rates down 160 basis points to 29 percent.  </p>
<p>Dealers said expectations for another round of rate drops in next week's primary Cetes auction and a heavy liquidity injection of 14.196 billion pesos by Banco de Mexico on Thursday helped bring rates down.</p>
<p>The shortfall for Friday is estimated at four billion pesos.</p>
<p>-- Karina Balderas, Mexico City newsroom, (525) 728-9562</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
