<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11173" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Two dead as southern Colombia rocked by protests.</title>
<headline>Two dead as southern Colombia rocked by protests.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA, Colombia 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least two people were killed on Friday when demonstrators protesting against the Colombian government's drug crop eradication programme clashed with security forces for a second day, authorities said.</p>
<p>The clashes occurred in Caqueta, one of three southern provinces where thousands of peasant growers of coca leaf, the raw material for cocaine, have protested since mid-July against government efforts to wipe out the staple crop.</p>
<p>William Sanchez, mayor of Belen de los Andaquies, southwest of Florencia, the provincial capital of Caqueta, said first reports indicated that four demonstrators had been killed there in early morning clashes with security forces.</p>
<p>But later reports quoted authorities as saying only two dead had been confirmed.</p>
<p>Sanchez, who spoke by telephone with the Noticiero Nacional television programme, said the victims were protesters gunned down by troops. At least 17 people were injured in the clashes, the domestic news agency Colprensa said.</p>
<p>Florencia itself was a virtual war zone, meanwhile, after rioting erupted when soldiers firing teargas canisters sought to break up a protest march through the centre of the city.</p>
<p>Contact with the city was virtually impossible after protesters firebombed the local offices of the state telephone company. But news reports said rock-throwing protesters, some of them armed with Molotov cocktails, had gone on a rampage across the city, attacking government offices and banks and ransacking the home of Florencia Mayor Hector Orozco.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Horacio Serpa, who has said that the anti-government protests were being orchestrated by leftist guerrillas, told the Caracol radio network that the government was &quot;very concerned&quot; by the violent turn they had taken.</p>
<p>He fell short of announcing any specific measures the government might take to halt the protests, but said &quot;anarchy leads only to misfortune.&quot;</p>
<p>One demonstrator was shot dead and eight others seriously injured on Thursday when they tried to fight their way past riot police manning barricades across a bridge on the outskirts of Florencia.</p>
<p>In all, at least nine protesters have been killed in Caqueta and two neighbouring provinces since last month.</p>
<p>The government, under heavy pressure from Washington to destroy vast tracts of coca and opium poppy this year, has vowed to continue spraying them from the air with herbicide in a bid to stem the flow of illicit drugs onto U.S. streets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA, Colombia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
