<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11177" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Nicaragua says will fight Leucadia debt suit.</title>
<headline>Nicaragua says will fight Leucadia debt suit.</headline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Nicaraguan government said on Friday it was &quot;surprised,&quot; but will fight a suit filed against it by a U.S.-based company over $26.3 million in unpaid debt plus interest.</p>
<p>Leucadia National Corp, a New York-based banking and insurance company, filed the suit in a U.S. court on Thursday alleging Nicaragua had failed to pay back $26.3 million in debt Leucadia bought on the secondary market in 1986 and 1987.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't know why (Leucadia) is doing this. They know that Nicaragua has no more funds; that we could never, under any conditions, pay 100 percent of the debt,&quot; Nicaragua's Vice Minister of External Cooperation, Sergio Mario Blandon, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Blandon said he will meet with lawyers to decide Nicaragua's legal strategy and is confident Leucadia's actions will not lead other creditors to demand payment.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an isolated case. We're confident it won't unleash a series of other such suits,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Leucadia bought the debt from the defunct New York securities firm Drexel Burnham Lambert and the former U.S. subsidiary of Britain's National Westminster Bank, which loaned the money to Nicaragua in 1980.</p>
<p>In December, cash-strapped Nicaragua with international help agreed to buy back $1.1 billion of its commercial debt, paying creditors eight cents on the dollar, for a total of $88 million. But Leucadia refused to agree to the deal.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe they now realize they were left out of a good deal, and by making a fuss they think they can re-open the negotiations,&quot; Blandon said.  </p>
<p>Nicaragua's Central Bank President Evenor Taboada said he thought Leucadia's suit was off base.</p>
<p>&quot;We made it explicitly clear to buyers that Nicaragua couldn't pay back the full amount of the debt, but only 8 cents on the dollar,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nicaragua, generally considered the poorest country in Latin America after Haiti and one of the most indebted, is trying to reduce the size of its debt through debt forgiveness by creditor governments and buying back its commercial debt.</p>
<p>It has been included in an initiative by the G-7 countries to ease the debt burden on the world's poorest countries.</p>
<p>Leucadia is also suing the African nation of Zaire for non-payment of a smaller loan.</p>
<p>-- David Koop, Managua bureau, (505) 266-3300</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
