<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11170" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine bonds find little new direction.</title>
<headline>Argentine bonds find little new direction.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine bonds ended slightly weaker on Friday, although traders said the market remained essentially trendless.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is going nowhere for the time being,&quot; said the head trader at a large Argentine bank.</p>
<p>The 5.5 percent dollar-denominated Bocon Previsional 2 due 2001 fell $0.05 to 114.50, while Argentina's FRB due 2005 fell 1/8 to 76-5/8.</p>
<p>&quot;At some stage there will have to be a new trend, but for now we are just making intra-day trades and not taking out any new positions,&quot; said the head trader.  </p>
<p>The same issues kept the market range-bound this session as during the rest of the week. Uncertainty around whether or not the government's recently announced economic measures really will be passed by Congress is the main concern.</p>
<p>If anything, the market is more negative than positive because of increasing signs of discontent with the government's economic policies.</p>
<p>For instance a Gallup poll in a local newspaper on Friday found 72 percent of respondents disapprove of the government's economic policies.  </p>
<p>That is food for thought for President Carlos Menem, who is trying to convince recalcitrant members of his Peronist party in Congress to pass tax increases that may give the consumers even less disposable income.</p>
<p>But Economy Minister Roque Fernandez said on Friday he was confident ruling Peronist Party legislators would help pass his controversial austerity package in early October.</p>
<p>There could be some support for bonds next week if President Carlos Menem puts more pressure on his party to pass the measures quickly on his return on Monday from a trip to Asia. In the money market, one day call money rates fell to 8.95 percent from 9.75 percent.</p>
<p>-- Axel Bugge, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 54 1 3180668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
