<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11172" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexican stocks close down, but off lows.</title>
<headline>Mexican stocks close down, but off lows.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican stocks petered out on Friday after a week of record highs gave way to a session of profit-taking, although prices made up some ground toward the close of trade after falling through support levels.</p>
<p>The IPC index of leading stocks fell 24.96 points or 0.74 percent to 3,364.37.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was very weak. Most of the people paid to see what was going on and got out early,&quot; one floor trader said.</p>
<p>Traders said the fact that stocks bottomed out at the 3,332 resistance level and rebounded was a good sign that stocks are consolidating in preparation to rise again.  </p>
<p>But volume was very low at 62.57 million shares in 2,708 transactions. Losers outpaced gainers 51 to 31.</p>
<p>Benchmark Telmex ADRs fell 3/8 to 33-3/4 while in Mexico Telmex L shares, the largest issue on the bolsa, fell 14 centavos or 1.09 percent to 12.70 pesos. Telmex A shares fell 1.25 percent or 16 centavos to 12.62 pesos.</p>
<p>Retailers took the biggest hit with Grupo Salinas y Rocha L shares topping the lists of losers .PL.MX by falling five percent or two centavos to 38 centavos. Gigante B followed, off 4.44 percent or 12 centavos to 2.58 pesos and Grupo Palacio de Hierro fell 3.85 percent or 20 centavos to 5 pesos.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
