<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11185" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine stocks rebound but undertone seen weak.</title>
<headline>Argentine stocks rebound but undertone seen weak.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine stocks rebounded earlier than expected to end higher Friday for the first time this week, but traders said the gains could be shortlived.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a technical reaction,&quot; said Jorge Bonanno of brokers Interfin. &quot;It took us a bit by surprise but it doesn't look too serious -- just look at the dismal volume.&quot;</p>
<p>The blue-chip MerVal index  .MERV jumped 1.8 percent to 500.37, paring losses in the week to 4.7 percent.</p>
<p>Traders had earlier forecast weakness in oil giant YPF would drag down the rest of the bolsa, which dived 6.5 percent between Tuesday and Thursday (Monday was a market holiday).  </p>
<p>YPF, the bolsa's bellwether and least volatile stock, fell 5.0 percent between Wednesday and Friday, stung by Ecuador's decision Tuesday night to scrap a deal with its subsidiary Maxus and by news Thursday the Argentine government would sell part of its stake in the company to boost revenues.</p>
<p>YPF said Friday it had clinched a new tentative deal with Petroecuador to resume Maxus operations.</p>
<p>In the session floor volume slowed to a paltry 13.7 million pesos from 16.4 million Thursday, while over-the-counter deals were also very slack at 37 million pesos against 45 million Thursday.  </p>
<p>Analysts blame the market's losing streak, which pushed the MerVal to its lowest close so far this year Thursday, on worries over a package of tax measures drawn up nearly two weeks ago by Economy Minister Roque Fernandez.</p>
<p>The package may not come up for a final vote in Congress until early October and stocks were expected to remain weak while legislators keep them guessing.</p>
<p>Ironically investors were also worried about the effect the measures themselves may have on the economic recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;Short-covering may push prices a bit higher but there will be caution while economic fears remain,&quot; said Bonanno.  </p>
<p>In the session the broad market tacked on 0.9 percent, with winners beating losers 30 to 13 and 12 issues closing flat.</p>
<p>Best main-tier performers were construction stock Polledo, which surged 8.8 percent, petrochemical concerns Ipako and Indupa, up 4.7 percent and 3.9 percent each, and oil companies Sol Petroleo and Astra, up 4.4 percent and 3.6 percent.</p>
<p>Among losers YPF shed 0.5 percent, pulp and paper maker Celulosa lost 3.8 percent and sugar refiner Ledesma shed 1.8 percent.</p>
<p>-- Carmen Pignotti, Buenos Aires Newsroom 541 318-0657</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
