<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11180" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian stocks end lower, weighed down by cement.</title>
<headline>Colombian stocks end lower, weighed down by cement.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian stocks ended slightly lower as investor concerns about local cement makers losing market share to Mexico's Cemex weighed down equities for the second consecutive day.</p>
<p>The losses were limited, however, with Medellin's IBOMED general price index ending down just 0.15 percent at 13,129.52 and Bogota's IBB inching down a miniscule 0.06 percent to close at 847.21.</p>
<p>More than 1.5 billion pesos of shares traded hands in Bogota, while volume in Medellin totalled 1.2 billion.  </p>
<p>As in Thursday's trading, the day's biggest losers were cement companies. Brokers said selling was prompted by investor fears that Cemex, the world's third-largest cement company, positioned itself to become a dominant player in the Colombian market with the purchase of Industrias e Inversiones Samper earlier this week.</p>
<p>Cemex had already purchased Cementos Diamante earlier this year and its total $700 million investment in Colombia is expected to result in fierce market competition.</p>
<p>Diamante was among the stocks most hurt by Friday's liquidation of cement stocks.  </p>
<p>The company, which Cemex purchased in May, fell 4.76 percent in Medellin to close at 3,800 pesos per share. It closed down 2.56 percent in Bogota, also ending at 3,800.</p>
<p>Cementos Argos, another leading cement company, fell 1.90 percent in Bogota, ending the session at 5,160 pesos per share.</p>
<p>Other losers included insurance giant Suramericana de Seguros, which ended down 2.77 percent at 3,800 pesos a share and Banco de Colombia, which slipped 2.29 percent in Medellin to end at 425 pesos a share.</p>
<p>-- Javier Mozzo, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
