<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11182" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>TRINIDAD AND TOBAGO: Tight security in Trinidad after coup scare.</title>
<headline>Tight security in Trinidad after coup scare.</headline>
<dateline>PORT OF SPAIN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police have beefed up security in Trinidad and Tobago to quell fears of an uprising fuelled by tensions between the government of the twin-island Caribbean nation and its Moslem minority.</p>
<p>Brig. Carl Alfonso, who heads the Trinidad and Tobago defence force, assured the public his troops and other security forces were loyal to the government.</p>
<p>&quot;The army is committed to the public safety and is prepared to work hand-in-hand with the police,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Rumours of an uprising similar to a violent coup attempt launched six years ago by the radical Black Moslem group, Jamaat Al-Moslemeen, came to a head last Friday after a radio report of an anti-government plot linked to the Jamaat. Workers were sent home from work early.</p>
<p>Government officials have dismissed the radio report as &quot;malicious speculation&quot;. But police have beefed up security at government buildings, set up roadblocks at key intersections and mounted more frequent patrols.</p>
<p>National Security Minister Joe Theodore said the government was investigating information it received last Saturday that some 300 army-type combat uniforms had been brought into the country and distributed.</p>
<p>He asked the public to report to the police anyone in possession of such uniforms.</p>
<p>Jamaat members on July 27, 1990, failed in a bid to topple the government of then-Prime Minister Ray Robinson in a coup attempt that killed 34 people.</p>
<p>More recently the group has been at odds with the government of Prime Minister Basdeo Panday over the state's attempt to evict Jamaat from a stretch of land on the western fringe of Port of Spain.</p>
<p>Jamaat wants the government to compensate it for the destruction of its headquarters, and won a compensation award of more than $1 million in 1994. But the money has never been distributed because it has been tied up in court, officials said.</p>
<p>Minister of Legal Affairs Kamla Persad-Bissesar said the government could not act until there was a final resolution in the courts.</p>
<p>Jamaat attorney Subhas Panday, who also is the prime minister's younger brother and a former member of parliament, said the Moslem organisation wanted the money and intended to take action to get it. But he said it would not be violent.</p>
<p>&quot;The Jamaat will do nothing to disturb the peace and quiet or in any way endanger the security and stability of the society,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Of Trinidad's 1.2 million population, 33 percent are Roman Catholic, 25 percent are Hindu and six percent are Moslem. About 40 percent of the population is of African descent, and about 40 is Indian, with the remainder of mixed, European and Chinese descent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TRTO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT OF SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TRINIDAD AND TOBAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
