<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11208" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Former envoy says U.S. demands too much of Colombia.</title>
<headline>Former envoy says U.S. demands too much of Colombia.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. demands that Colombia enact reforms to create a &quot;perfect and impeccable&quot; judicial system by next year are impossible to meet, a former Colombian envoy to Washington said on Friday.</p>
<p>Carlos Lleras de la Fuente, who resigned as ambassador to Washington in April, said he had obtained memorandums outlining &quot;12 or 14&quot; key demands the Clinton administration has made of Colombia.</p>
<p>Colombia was likely to be hit with punitive economic sanctions unless the reforms are carried out, Lleras said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's impossible to think that in five months our poor, weak and limping judicial system can be turned into something perfect and impeccable, possibly even better than the one in the United States,&quot; Lleras said. &quot;But that seems to be the gist of these documents from our neighbours up north.&quot;</p>
<p>Lleras, in an interview with RCN news radio, said Washington was putting the government of President Ernesto Samper &quot;up against the wall&quot; by asking for too much in too little time.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks as if they (the United States) want to create a problem when it comes to Colombia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>One of the reforms the United States is pressing for is an end to Colombia's constitutional ban on extradition in effect since 1991.</p>
<p>Drug kingpins waged a bloody campaign of bombings and assassinations in the late 1980s and early 1990s to pressure Congress into enacting the ban on extradition.</p>
<p>Constitutional amendments in Colombia must be passed by two consecutive sessions of Congress, making it impossible for the ban on extradition to be lifted this year.</p>
<p>Justice Minister Carlos Medellin said another troublesome demand Washington was making would allow U.S. agents to board ships in Colombia's territorial waters to search for drugs.</p>
<p>Such permission could not be granted without an amendment to the constitution, he said.</p>
<p>Lleras resigned in April, one month after the United States decertified Colombia as a partner in U.S. counternarcotics efforts. He cited allegations that Samper used drug money to finance his 1994 election campaign.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
