<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11216" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: COCOA--Coimbra scaling down cocoa operation.</title>
<headline>COCOA--Coimbra scaling down cocoa operation.</headline>
<byline>Brian Homewood</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's Comercio e Industrias Brasileiras Coimbra are scaling down their cocoa operation in Bahia but are not abandoning the market, a company source said.</p>
<p>The announcement came as producers predicted the coming main crop would be unlikely to reach 1.0 million 60-kilo bags because of a severe drought in the growing region.</p>
<p>Coimbra, part of the Louis Dreyfus group, have stopped buying cocoa beans direct from farmers and will now only buy on the inter-dealer market, the source said.  </p>
<p>The decision was seen by traders as the lastest sign of the decline in the beleagured Bahia cocoa trade.</p>
<p>Only a handful of shippers remain in the trading center of Salvador and most of them are rumoured to be considering abandoing the business altogehter, traders said. If this happens, the major grinders will become the only buyers for Bahia cocoa beans.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be that in six months I am the only one left,&quot; said one bean seller. &quot;When I buy cocoa off farmers I would like to say 'see you next year' but I'm not sure that I will be around.&quot;  </p>
<p>The drought, one of the worst in living memory, is the latest blow to the Bahia growing region, which in the last decade has been struck by falling productivity caused by low prices plus the spread of witch's broom disease.</p>
<p>Although rain fell last week, farmers said dry weather returned again this week and that the main crop, which some felt earlier this year could reach 2.0 million bags, is now expected to be half that total or less.</p>
<p>&quot;Although there have been reports of rain on the North-East coast, most of it fell in the sea,&quot; said producer Ronaldo Monteiro.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't know if we will get one million bags. There is no possibility of a recovery at this stage,&quot; Monteiro said. The main crop runs from October to April, while the current midcrop, expected to reach 1.5 million bags, is already said to be drying up.</p>
<p>&quot;We're buying very little, there is very little left from the midcrop,&quot; said a trader. &quot;There is only one million bags expected from the main crop -- I used to trade that myself in the good old years.&quot;</p>
<p>The estimated total of 2.5 million is still expected to be enough to satisfy the local grinders, who already have stocks.</p>
<p>With very little being exported, supply is expected to be greater demand, despite a total which is tiny by Bahia's traditional standards, and this will meaning lower prices for farmers. Spot prices are currently between 15 Real and 15.50 Real per 15 kilo arroba.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, they are paying us less than the international price which should be around 17 Real,&quot; said Monteiro.</p>
<p>The only consolation for farmers is a government bill to eliminate from commodities the 13 percent sales tax that farmers pay to the state governments.</p>
<p>The bill, put forward by planning minister Antonio Kandir, is due to be voted on in Congress after August 27 and the government hopes that if there are no hitches, it will come into effect in January.</p>
<p>Estimates are that without the tax, the current price paid to farmers would be around 17 Real per arroba.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
