<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11220" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Hurricane Dolly bashes into Mexican Gulf coast.</title>
<headline>Hurricane Dolly bashes into Mexican Gulf coast.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hurricane Dolly bashed into Mexico's eastern state of Veracruz Friday, dumping torrential rains, the National Meterological Service said in an update.</p>
<p>The eye of huge weather front made landfall around 1000 local/1500 GMT about 40 km south-south east of the port of Tampico, packing sustained winds of 120 km/h (75 mph) and gusts up to 150 km/h (94 mph), it added.</p>
<p>There were no immediate reports of deaths or damage in the zone, which is at the northern tip of the agricultural state of Veracruz, close to the border with Tamaulipas state.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is expected that Dolly will continue edging west-northwesterly, gradually losing force as it moves over land,&quot; the service predicted.</p>
<p>Heavy rains were registered across eastern and southern Mexico and shipping alerts remained in place from Puerto Progreso in Yucatan state to Matamoros, the most northerly point of Tamaulipas.</p>
<p>Ports distant from where Dolly touched land had started to re-open. At the height of storm in the Gulf of Mexico 37 ports were closed. Two of Mexico's main crude export ports -- Dos Bocas and Cayo Arcas -- have already re-started operations and a third -- Pajaritos is about to re-open, port sources said.</p>
<p>Veracruz is one of Mexico's most prosperous agricultural states. In the low-lying zone where Dolly came ashore, the main activities are livestock farming, sugar cane growing, and citrus production.</p>
<p>--Chris Aspin, Mexico City newsroom (525) 7289530.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
