<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11226" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: SOYBEANS -- Brazil mulls proposed end to export tax.</title>
<headline>SOYBEANS -- Brazil mulls proposed end to export tax.</headline>
<byline>Diana Kinch</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Brazilian government's proposed elimination of the state-level ICMS tax as part of a tax reform is likely to meet with an unfavorable reaction from other soybean producers abroad, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Lifting the tax would impact on the international market,&quot; a Sao Paulo-based trader said. &quot;Elimination would make Brazil internationally more competitive but the reaction from abroad may not be positive.&quot;  </p>
<p>Another trader said elimination of ICMS, a kind of value-added tax levied on exports of products including soybeans, soymeal and soyoil, might even be construed as a kind of subsidy by competitors abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;This is because the federal government would initially pay state governments compensation to cover shortfalls they may suffer from non-receipt of the tax,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This could cause problems for exports to the European Union and may not go down too well with the U.S. either,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Talks between major producing states Parana and Rio Grande do Sul and the federal government on compensation payment levels have already run into disagreement.</p>
<p>Trade sources estimate the benefits exporters of soyproducts could gain from the proposed tax exemption should be equivalent to those arising from a 5 to 10 percent devaluation of the real.</p>
<p>Brazilian producing sources meanwhile declared themselves unequivocally in favor of elimination of the tax, currently charged at a rate of 13 percent on the fob export price of soybeans, 11.1 percent on soymeal and 8.8 percent on soyoil.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're totally in favor,&quot; said a spokesman for Rio Grande do Sul cooperatives federation Fecotrigo. &quot;For a long time Brazil has been an exporter of taxes and an importer of subsidies.</p>
<p>&quot;Brazilian producers have suffered a 20 percent drop in income since the launch of the real in July 1994,&quot; the Fecotrigo spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we should start to be able to compete on more or less equal terms with producers abroad,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Despite export difficulties cited by Fecotrigo and Brazil's Vegetable Oils Association Abiove, government statistics show soymeal exports in January-July made up about six percent of Brazil's total export revenue for the period.</p>
<p>An Abiove spokesman said that lifting the ICMS tax cannot be considered to be a subsidy as comparable taxes do not exist in other areas such as Europe or the US.</p>
<p>&quot;Elimination of the tax could however be an incentive for producers to plant more and invest more in technology, which has recently been difficult due to rising costs. Doing away with ICMS will help reduce the &quot;custo Brasil&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Most of these cases have dragged on for months due to expectations by state governments of an early definition of federal government policy on ICMS as part of its tax reform.</p>
<p>Soyproduct producers in Rio Grande do Sul state however won a court order earlier this year allowing them a reduction in ICMS tax charged on soymeal and soyoil to 5.5 percent.</p>
<p>According to Abiove, producers and exporters in Maranhao state have also achieved a reduction in ICMS to seven percent on soybean sales.</p>
<p>-- Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 5074151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
