<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11227" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian Q2 GDP up 2.2 pct, down sharply from '95.</title>
<headline>Colombian Q2 GDP up 2.2 pct, down sharply from '95.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombia's gross domestic product grew by 2.2 percent in the second quarter, down from a bubbling 4.7 percent growth rate in the second quarter of 1995, the National Planning Department said.</p>
<p>It said the economy grew 3.9 percent in the first quarter, meaning that growth during the first half of the year averaged 3.0 percent.  </p>
<p>Finance Minister Jose Antonio Ocampo has said the government is maintaining its 4.0 percent growth target for this year. But independent analysts, including the respected economic think-tank Fedesarrollo, say real growth is expected to be closer to the 3.0 percent seen in the first half.</p>
<p>The 2.2 percent growth figure for the second quarter is the lowest this decade.</p>
<p>Loan rates of more than 40 percent have been cited as one of the leading reasons for a sharp slowdown in the industrial sector this year.  </p>
<p>The recent appreciation of Colombia's peso currency against the dollar has also prompted growing concerns about a weakening of the country's export sector.</p>
<p>Political uncertainty stemming from the prolonged drug corruption scandal dogging President Ernesto Samper has been cited as another cause for Colombia's economic slowdown.</p>
<p>Despite the relatively poor second quarter growth figure, the Planning Department said oil output was seen growing 9.8 percent in 1996 and coal output was seen growing 20 percent.</p>
<p>The agricultural sector excluding coffee grew by an anemic 0.8 percent in the first half.  </p>
<p>The Planning Department said the agricultural sector, excluding coffee, was expected to rebound to 6.0 percent growth in the second half, thanks to bumper sesame, soy, tobacco and cotton crops.</p>
<p>It said the calendar year's coffee crop was projected to be 8.0 percent lower than in 1995.</p>
<p>-- Tom Brown, Bogota Newsroom 571 610 7944</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
