<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11238" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Spoilt soybeans disrupt Paranagua capesize loading.</title>
<headline>Spoilt soybeans disrupt Paranagua capesize loading.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>An investigation into the causes of damage to a soybean cargo is delaying loading of capesize vessels at Brazil's Paranagua port, an official said.</p>
<p>&quot;A Paranagua civil court decreed August 16 there shall be no more loading or unloading of the capesize Lika until the causes of the damage have been established,&quot; said port authority technical director Luis Ivan de Vasconcelos.</p>
<p>&quot;The investigation is being carried out by an independent body and should be finished Saturday. But we already have 63 vessels waiting to berth at the port, including 20 to load soybeans and pellets, two of which are capesize,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Lika started loading on August 8 and its prolonged stay in the port's capesize berth is disrupting the entry of other vessels, the port director said. Paranagua has only one berth, No. 14, which can handle capesize vessels.</p>
<p>The blighted soybeans were discovered August 12. The vessel, with a Greek flag, is being operated by Brazilian operator Marcon for UK company Worthington, and was due to carry a total cargo of 71,900 tonnes of soybeans to Rotterdam. Some 8,500 tonnes of soybeans had already been loaded onto the ship before the problem was discovered, and some 6,000 tonnes of these may be damaged, Vasconcelos said.  </p>
<p>All the damaged soybeans are in the ship's No. 1 and No. 9 holds and the rest are unaffected, he said.</p>
<p>The damaged soybeans are in a state known as &quot;burnt&quot;, Vasconcelos said. This means they have been exposed to excessive humidity and have started to ferment and turn dark, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;They may have been in the silo for too long without ventilation or they may not have dried sufficiently. The quality is not good enough to ship,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Vasconcelos said the soybeans loaded onto Lika were a mixture of Paraguayan and Brazilian origin. There are seven silos at the port used for Paraguayan soybeans, two horizontal and five vertical silos, he said.</p>
<p>-- Diana Kinch, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 5074151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
