<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11241" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil's Banerj to be audited -- paper.</title>
<headline>Brazil's Banerj to be audited -- paper.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rio de Janeiro's state Accounting Office has ordered an in depth audit of state bank Banco do Estado do Rio de Janeiro (Banerj) to see if its private administrator committed any irregularities, a newspaper said.</p>
<p>Banerj has been managed by private investment bank Bozano, Simonsen since January 2 in preparation for privatization.</p>
<p>The Accounting Office (TCE) accuses Bozano, Simonsen of witholding information on Banerj's financial performance, which forms the basis for its remuneration for administering the state bank, O Globo newspaper said.  </p>
<p>The TCE says Bozano, Simonsen has already received 43 million reais ($43 million) in remuneration from Rio de Janeiro state for the period January to May without presenting accounts to verify that that amount had indeed been earned, O Globo said.</p>
<p>The president of Bozano, Simonsen, Paulo Ferraz, was fined 17,000 reais ($17,000) by the TCE for witholding the financial data.</p>
<p>The TCE said if Banerj's accounts showed the sum to be unjustified, Bozano, Simonsen would have to pay back the difference, O Globo said.  </p>
<p>Under the original contract, Bozano was to receive 5 percent of Banerj's sale price in preference shares, but the contract has been changed to allow for payment of the 5 percent in cash.</p>
<p>The TCE says Bozano, Simonsen has already received 43 million reais ($43 million) in remuneration from Rio de Janeiro state for the period January to May without presenting the accounts to verify the correctness of the sum, O Globo said.  </p>
<p>The president of Bozano, Simonsen, Paulo Ferraz, was fined 17,000 reais ($17,000) by the TCE for witholding the financial data.</p>
<p>The TCE said if Banerj's accounts showed the sum to be unjustified, Bozano, Simonsen would have to pay back the difference, O Globo said</p>
<p>The TCE also objects to an amendment which would allow Bozano to receive 5 percent of the sale of Banerj assets, and to a change in the way Bozano calculates its remuneration, O Globo said.</p>
<p>Banerj is due to be privatized in December this year.</p>
<p>-- Simona de Logu, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 507 4151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
