<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11248" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil cenbank silent on Bamerindus credit lines.</title>
<headline>Brazil cenbank silent on Bamerindus credit lines.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's Central Bank Friday declined to comment on a newspaper report which said it was on the verge of agreeing to special credit lines for the country's troubled fourth largest private bank, Bamerindus.</p>
<p>A Central Bank spokesman added, however, that Bamerindus' first half results, showing a small 20.4 million real profit, revealed there was still &quot;a need for liquidity&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still searching for a solution,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The Gazeta Mercantil daily, in an unsourced story, reported that the likely solution for Bamerindus was extensive rediscount lines with 90 day terms, renewable for another 90 days, and paying 4.0 percent a year above the Basic Interest Rate (TBC).</p>
<p>It added that the solution would allow the bank's main shareholder, Sen. Jose Eduardo Andrade Vieira, a powerful ally of President Fernando Henrique Cardoso, to remain in charge.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone knows the decision will be political, given the importance of Andrade Vieira, one of the key backers of the campaign that elected Fernando Henrique Cardoso,&quot; Gazeta said.</p>
<p>-- Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom 55-61-2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
