<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11240" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile trade surplus slumps to $255 mln Jan-July.</title>
<headline>Chile trade surplus slumps to $255 mln Jan-July.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chile's $142 million trade deficit in July brought its trade balance in the first seven months of the year to $254.7 million, down from $1.47 billion in the first seven months of last year, the Central Bank said.</p>
<p>The July deficit and the widely expected drop in the accumulated surplus were due largely to lower prices on major exports, the Central Bank said in a report.</p>
<p>&quot;The July result is fundamentally the result of the fall in exports, an effect mainly of lower international prices for our products, combined with a moderate but significant rise in imports,&quot; said the report.  </p>
<p>The slump in export income highlighted Chile's continuing dependence on natural resources, mainly in mining and forestry, for the bulk of its foreign trade income, despite over a decade of solid economic growth.</p>
<p>Exports of copper, by far Chile's number one export, rose slightly last month to $580 million from $556 million in July 1995, Central Bank figures showed.</p>
<p>But the next three largest exports -- paper pulp, fresh fruit and fishmeal -- all plumetted.  </p>
<p>Paper pulp, or cellulose, tumbled to $50.8 million last month from $161.4 million in the same month last year. Fresh fruit exports, currently in a seasonal lull, slipped to $22 million from $31 million in July last year.</p>
<p>Fishmeal exports fell to $45 million from $78 million in July last year, the bank reported.</p>
<p>Imports for the first seven months of the year came to $9.24 billion, up sharply from $7.99 billion in the same period of 1995, while total exports rose narrowly to $9.48 billion from $9.46 billion in the first seven months of last year.  </p>
<p>July figures showed imports higher in most categories. Consumer good imports rose to $279 million from $239 million in July last year, while capital goods imports rose to $431.4 million from $246 million in July last year.</p>
<p>-- Roger Atwood, Santiago newsroom +56-2-699-5595 x211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
