<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11257" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the highlights of the main Sao Paulo and Rio de Janeiro newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>GAZETA MERCANTIL</p>
<p>-- CENTRAL BANK PREPARES SPECIAL LOAN FOR BAMERINDUS</p>
<p>Brazil's Central Bank is considering giving private bank Bamerindus a long-term discount line to solve its liquidity problems.</p>
<p>-- PETROBRAS POSTS 655 PCT PROFIT RISE</p>
<p>Brazilian state-owned oil giant Petrobras has posted first half profits of 303 million reais ($303 million), up 655 percent from the first six months last year.</p>
<p>-- PUBLIC SECTOR DEFICIT GROWS IN JUNE</p>
<p>Brazil's Central Bank said the public sector deficit reached 12.8 billion reais ($12.8 billion) in June, the equivalent of 3.57 percent of gross domestic product (GDP), up from 2.33 percent of GDP last year.</p>
<p>O GLOBO</p>
<p>-- RIO MAYOR CANDIDATE CONDE UP AT 39 PCT IN POLLS</p>
<p>Rio de Janeiro mayoral candidate Luiz Paulo Conde has risen in the polls to 39 percent of the vote, and for the first time the survey shows he would win in the first round of voting.</p>
<p>-- RIO MAYOR LOWERS REAL ESTATE TAX IN VIOLENT AREAS</p>
<p>Rio de Janeiro Mayor Cesar Maia has lowered the IPTU real estate tax in areas where the value of real estate has fallen due to the proximity of violent neighborhoods and shantytowns.</p>
<p>-- PUBLIC SECTOR WORKERS TO GET PAY RISE IN 1997</p>
<p>The federal government is to grant a pay rise to public sector workers in the 1997 budget, estimated to bring personnel costs to 44 billion reais ($44 billion).</p>
<p>FOLHA DE SAO PAULO</p>
<p>-- MILITARY REJECTS CHARGES AGAINST PARA MILITARY POLICE</p>
<p>A military court in Brazil's northern state of Para has rejected homicide charges brought against 155 military police officers said to have been involved in the April massacre of 19 landless peasants in Para's Eldorado do Carajas.</p>
<p>-- BOMB FOUND AT SAO PAULO BOOK EXHIBITION</p>
<p>A small homemade bomb was found in a bathroom at the 14th Bienal do Livro book exhibition in Sao Paulo. It was removed and made safe by military police.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified the stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- Simona de Logu, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 507 4151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
