<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11258" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru Congress approves possible Fujimori 3rd term.</title>
<headline>Peru Congress approves possible Fujimori 3rd term.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>LIMA, Peru 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Peruvian Congress approved in the early hours of Friday morning a key constitutional interpretation that paves the way for a third reelection bid from President Alberto Fujimori in 2000.</p>
<p>Legislators voted 70-3 in favour of the proposal after an often fiery debate which lasted more than nine hours.</p>
<p>&quot;This measure means that if President Alberto Fujimori wants to run again for the presidency, he could,&quot; said Ricardo Marcenaro, a legislator with Fujimori's New Majority-Change 90 movement.</p>
<p>Under Peruvian law, a president who has been elected for two consecutive terms in office is not allowed to run in the following election.</p>
<p>But the single-chamber Congress, controlled by the government with 70 of a total 120 seats, voted in favour of an interpretation that means Fujimori's first term in office will not be taken into account should he stand for reelection.</p>
<p>Fujimori was elected president in 1990 and again in 1995. But after he dissolved the then opposition-dominated parliament in 1992, a new constitution was written the following year by a reformulated, pro-Fujimori Congress.</p>
<p>Congress upheld on Friday that only elections under the new constitution had validity when an incumbent president wished to put himself forward as a candidate for the next term.</p>
<p>Fujimori, who enjoys a more than 60 percent popularity rating, is widely expected to seek a third term. Although he has not formally announced his intention, he has been quoted as being in favour of another bid for the presidency.</p>
<p>Opposition leaders condemned Congress' measure as an abuse of Peru's constitution by a weak legislature subservient to an authoritarian leader.</p>
<p>Most anti-government legislators walked out of the chamber in protest prior to the vote at 1 a.m. local time (0600 GMT) after a debate that often degenerated into personal insults.</p>
<p>&quot;I reject the reelection in the name of justice, liberty and the dignity of Peruvians,&quot; said Fernando Olivera Vega, of the opposition Independent Moralizing Party. &quot;This represents an abuse of the constitution.&quot;</p>
<p>Prominent local political analyst Francisco Sagasti said the vote &quot;shows there is little interest (from the government) in respecting the letter or the spirit of the constitution.&quot;</p>
<p>Local and foreign financial markets, however, were expected to react favourably to the enhanced prospect of a third term for Fujimori.</p>
<p>&quot;His reelection does not worry the market, because there is confidence in his administration. When he was reelected in 1995, the market responded favourably with continuous rises,&quot; said Pablo Navarro, a stockbroker with the local investment house Fortuna.</p>
<p>In six years of power, Fujimori has virtually defeated Peru's communist guerrillas, radically reformed the economy along free-market lines and reintegrated the nation into international financial markets.</p>
<p>But he is often criticised at home for failing to overcome the high levels of poverty and unemployment that still afflict this South American nation of 24 million people.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA, Peru"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
