<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11259" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Nicaragua, Honduras downplay border spat.</title>
<headline>Nicaragua, Honduras downplay border spat.</headline>
<dateline>MANAGUA, Nicaragua 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Representatives of Nicaragua and Honduras on Thursday hastily sought to calm tensions over a border dispute which flared up this week when the Honduran army chief said he was ready to go to war.</p>
<p>Honduran Vice President Guadelupe Gerezano and Nicaraguan Foreign Minister Ernesto Leal both minimised the conflict and said such incidents should be resolved diplomatically.</p>
<p>&quot;So far in 1996 there has not been one single incident of a boat being captured on the Caribbean Sea near Honduras, and no incidents are being registered,&quot; Leal said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know who wants to start a conflict, but there's nothing there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The countries have an ongoing border dispute over a stretch of the Atlantic Ocean rich in fish. Honduras claims the maritime border is the 15th parallel and Nicaragua the 17th parallel.</p>
<p>The dispute was ignited this week when Honduras' armed forces chief Gen. Raul Hung said, &quot;I have my budget, I have my reserves of fuel in case that, God forbid, we enter a confrontation. I have what is needed to respond.&quot;</p>
<p>His comments came after Nicaragua launched three new coast guard boats off its Atlantic coast and Honduran fishermen said they were chased by Nicaraguan patrol boats while in Honduran waters.</p>
<p>Honduran Vice President Gerezano dismissed the remarks, saying, &quot;I think his statements were distorted since no minister can make those kind of statements, because the person who runs the country's foreign policy is the president.&quot;</p>
<p>Gerezano was speaking at a meeting of Ibo-American women ministers in Managua.</p>
<p>Nicaraguan navy vessels and Honduran fishing boats engage in periodic clashes leading to regular diplomatic incidents and mutual accusations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA, Nicaragua"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
