<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11250" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Hurricane Dolly poised to pounce on Mexican coast.</title>
<headline>Hurricane Dolly poised to pounce on Mexican coast.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hurricane Dolly, the fourth big weather front of this Atlantic season, is poised to make landfall on the border of Mexico's Veracruz and Tamaulipas states, weather authorities said Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Dolly will continue picking up steam gradually...and it is expected to make landfall at 1300 local (1800 GMT) close to the town of Panuco, Veracruz, and 11 km (7 miles) west of Tampico, Tamaulipas, with sustained winds of 130 km/h (81 mph) and gusts up to 160 km/h (100 mph) as a category one hurricane on the Saffir-Simpson scale,&quot; the service said.  </p>
<p>Dolly, currently moving west-northwest at 17 km/h (11 mph), has coastal communities in the two states on maximum alert, Civil Protection Agency officials said.</p>
<p>Shipping alerts are still in force between Puerto Progreso in Yucatan state and Matamoros in Tamaulipas, across the border from Brownsville, Texas, the weather service said.</p>
<p>A total of 37 ports were closed Thursday as Dolly whipped up heavy seas throughout the Gulf of Mexico. Heavy rains were reported across the east and south of the country, with flooding in the northern city of Monterrey.</p>
<p>Among the ports closed were Mexico's three Gulf crude export ports -- Pajaritos, Dos Bocas and Cayo Arcas -- captains for the ports confirmed Thursday.</p>
<p>Dolly raced through the Caribbean earlier this week and slammed into the Yucatan Peninsula, causing light damage and leaving less than 100 people homeless. It crossed over into the Gulf of Mexico Wednesday and since has edged slowly toward Veracruz and Tamaulipas.</p>
<p>--Chris Aspin, Mexico City newsroom (525) 7289530.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
