<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11253" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Bamerindus' fate hinges on Brazil Cenbank credits.</title>
<headline>Bamerindus' fate hinges on Brazil Cenbank credits.</headline>
<byline>Fatima Cristina</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The fate of bank Bamerindus hinges on a special credit line now being negotiated with the Central Bank, analysts said.</p>
<p>But its approval, they added, would underscore the political clout of the owner of Brazil's fourth-largest private bank and reveal a double-standard in how the government treats troubled private banks.  </p>
<p>The fact that Bamerindus is owned by Senator Jose Eduardo Andrade Vieira, a former Agriculture Minister and powerful ally of President Fernando Henrique Cardoso, weighs in favor of it receiving financial help not offered to other banks that need restructuring.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the solution will end up being political instead of technical,&quot; a banking sector analyst at a local consulting firm said.  </p>
<p>Bank board president Mauricio Schulman said Tuesday that Bamerindus is hoping to land Central Bank credits as well as spinoff assets to help it overcome liquidity problems and restore public trust.</p>
<p>Schulman told reporters during a press conference to announce Bamerindus's 20.4 million-real net profit for 1996's first half that the bank has about 2.0 billion reais in government debt paper that could be sold or used to back the loan.</p>
<p>The Central Bank, perhaps sensitive to being accused of acting politically, refused to confirm or deny it is negotiating with Bamerindus.  </p>
<p>The banking analyst, who asked not to be named, said the Central Bank helped failed banks Nacional and Economico, which were among Brazil's top 10 banks, by brokering their sale to healthy banks and granting special PROER credit lines.</p>
<p>PROER funds are specifically earmarked to finance bank mergers and buyouts involving a change of ownership.</p>
<p>In Bamerindus's case, majority shareholder Andrade Vieira has refused to surrender control.  </p>
<p>Among the assets that Bamerindus could sell are its mortgage portfolio, which the bank planned to sell to state-run bank Caixa Economica Federal (CEF), and its indebted pulp and paper subsidiary Inpacel.</p>
<p>But analysts are doubtful Bamerindus can raise enough money on its own and the sale of its assets will take more time than the bank can afford.</p>
<p>&quot;The sale of assets involves negotiations that are too complicated,&quot; said Carlos Daniel Coradi of consulting firm EFC Consultores Financeiros.  </p>
<p>Even if Bamerindus gets the Central Bank loan, analysts doubt whether the bank will be able to regain investor confidence.</p>
<p>&quot;The bank will have to work really hard to rebuild its credibility,&quot; said Erivelto Rodrigues, director at banking consultant Austin Asis.</p>
<p>Bamerindus' first half results confirmed persistent rumors about liquidity problems and heightened speculation about the possible transfer of control of the institution, the last large private bank that needs restructuring.</p>
<p>EFC's Coradi said Bamerindus' balance sheet shows the bank needs some 1.9 billion reais to return to December 1994's liquidity levels, when the bank showed a 0.93 percent current ratio.</p>
<p>Like most Brazilian banks, Bamerindus suffered from the effects of the Real stabilization plan, which slashed inflation and virtually eliminated banks' high profits earned on wide arbitrage spreads.</p>
<p>Analysts also said the bank will be forced to keep cutting costs. Bamerindus, which had reported a 10 million real loss in the first quarter, returned to the black in the January-to-June period mostly due to deep staffing cuts.</p>
<p>On Friday, Brazil's Central Bank Friday denied a newspaper report which said it was likely to agree to special credit lines for Bamerindus.</p>
<p>A spokesman said Central Bank President Gustavo Loyola had authorized him to issue a formal denial that there were any plans to grant special liquidity assistance to Bamerindus.</p>
<p>The Gazeta Mercantil daily, in an unsourced story, reported that the likely solution for Bamerindus was extensive rediscount lines with 90 day terms, renewable for another 90 days, and paying 4.0 percent a year above the Basic Interest Rate (TBC).  </p>
<p>-- Sao Paulo newsroom, 55-11-2324411 (c) Reuters Limited 1996</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
