<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11263" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Hashimoto arrives in Chile to boost Japan trade.</title>
<headline>Hashimoto arrives in Chile to boost Japan trade.</headline>
<byline>Roger Atwood</byline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto arrived in Chile on Thursday on the second leg of a Latin American tour to drum up more trade with a region traditionally dominated by the United States.</p>
<p>Hashimoto, arriving from Mexico, will meet President Eduardo Frei for talks aimed at giving a high-level political push to the two countries' growing trade ties.</p>
<p>The Japanese prime minister was also due to sign financing agreements for a local pollution control programme, a key issue in Chile where winter smog chokes the capital Santiago.</p>
<p>Officials said the visit was part of a new Japanese drive to expand its trade and investment ties in Latin America, an area it long shied away from because of fears of political turmoil and the economic dominance of the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a certain revaluing of Latin America by the Japanese, and we want them to know that we offer the best conditions to be their bridge into this continent,&quot; said a top Chilean official.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a tremendously important visit for us,&quot; he said. &quot;We have a growing economic relationship, to which we are now adding an important political component.&quot;</p>
<p>Plans to boost trade and investment will feature high on Frei's agenda in talks with Hashimoto on Friday, the official said.</p>
<p>He said Chile hoped to present itself to Hashimoto as Japan's best hope for a gateway to Latin America due to Chile's record of stable economic growth and its long Pacific coast studded with modern ports.</p>
<p>Although Japan is Chile's second largest trading partner, it is a distant seventh in the ranking of foreign investors by country with about $500 million invested. The United States is number one in both categories.</p>
<p>The two nations have a couple of points of friction. Chile has supported a worldwide ban on whaling, opposed by Japan, and has also strongly protested shipments of nuclear waste through Chilean waters on their way to Japan from Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;Both are areas of disagreement but we have a civilised dialogue on them. I wouldn't call them real conflicts,&quot; said the official. Hashimoto was due to leave early on Saturday for Brazil.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
