<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11267" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine peso rebounds, death rumour quashed.</title>
<headline>Philippine peso rebounds, death rumour quashed.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>--------------------------- *** ----------------------------</p>
<p>* Trades choppy as some banks try to manipulate</p>
<p>------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The Philippine peso bounced back in choppy trading on Friday to close at 26.213 pesos from 26.225 after false rumours about the assassination of the country's defence chief sent the market into a panic late Thursday.</p>
<p>The day's average was at 26.205 versus 26.209.</p>
<p>Turnover was at a record $383.6 million from $180 million.  </p>
<p>The Central Bank had to intervene, buying as well as selling, to quell the market manipulation by some banks to make the peso volatile, traders said.</p>
<p>Some banks &quot;saw the chance for volatility,&quot; a foreign bank trader said. They pulled down the peso to a low of 26.24 pesos from 26.192 high after the market sold over $100 million to the Central Bank in early trades at 26.202 pesos, traders said.</p>
<p>The banks thought the market may have become short on dollars after the Central Bank bought $100 million in bond proceeds and from those who went into a buying frenzy late Thursday from those rumours, they said.  </p>
<p>The Central Bank had to put a floor on the peso's slide by selling dollars at 26.24 pesos, traders said.</p>
<p>Eventually, the peso advanced in late trading as overseas funds came in for interest rate arbitrage, they said. The Central Bank may have bought dollars again at 26.215 pesos to limit the peso's rise, dealers said.</p>
<p>Traders said these same banks may again try to inject more volatility in the market. The stable peso for the past eight months hardly yielded enough foreign exchange profits for these banks, they said.</p>
<p>But they believe the Central Bank has enough ammunition to fight manipulations with its gross international reserves at a record $11.5 billion.</p>
<p>- LILIAN KARUNUNGAN (632) 841 8937</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
