<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11274" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MACAU: Macau monetary aggregates up sharply in first half.</title>
<headline>Macau monetary aggregates up sharply in first half.</headline>
<dateline>MACAU 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Macau's Monetary and Foreign Exchange Authority on Friday said the territory's major monetary aggregates grew significantly in the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>Narrow money supply M1 grew by 4.1 percent between January to June 1996 to 19.2 billion patacas (US$2.4 billion) compared with the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>Broad money supply M2 grew by 12.7 percent versus the same period in 1995, hitting 72.7 billion patacas.</p>
<p>The banking sector's net foreign assets rose 17.6 percent to 40.5 billion patacas in June versus the same month in 1995.</p>
<p>The local pataca currency in circulation grew 11.8 percent to 1.324 billion patacas in June versus June in 1995, although the Hong Kong dollar is more widely circulated in Macau.</p>
<p>Of M2 in June, 56.7 percent was held in Hong Kong dollars, 28.6 percent in patacas and 14.7 percent in other currencies.</p>
<p>Domestic credit grew 3.9 percent to 39.9 billion patacas in June versus the same month in 1995 but the banking sector's consolidated balance assets totalled 120.9 billion patacas in June, down 1.29 percent.</p>
<p>(US$1 = 8 patacas)</p>
<p>--Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 28436441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MACAO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MACAU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MACAU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
