<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11285" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Sembawang disappoints with 42 pct H1 profit fall.</title>
<headline>Sembawang disappoints with 42 pct H1 profit fall.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Diversified marine conglomerate Sembawang Corp on Friday announced a 42.2 percent fall in first-half net profit to Singapore $17.12 million from S$29.62 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Group revenue rose 21.9 percent to S$728.18 million in the six months to June 30, 1996, from S$597.19 million in the same period in 1995. But the group's operating profit fell 18.3 percent to S$51.66 million, from S$63.22 million.</p>
<p>Sembawang said in a statement it had faced difficult market conditions in the shiprepair business, and this had affected the performance of its marine and heavy industries group.</p>
<p>The company's transportation and logistics sectors also suffered from a lack of salvage operations, it said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the result was well below market expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;Our analyst's last forecast, which was recently revised downwards, was a net profit of S$20.8 million, or a fall of 32 percent from last year,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;This really is disappointing.&quot;</p>
<p>Sembawang posted an extraordinary gain of S$51.49 million, which it said was due to &quot;gains realised from disposal of quoted investments held for long-term purposes&quot;.</p>
<p>The group statement gave no immediate hope for a dramatic improvement in its situation.</p>
<p>&quot;Difficult operating conditions are expected to prevail in the second half of 1996, but barring unforeseen circumstances, the directors expect a satisfactory performance,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
