<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11297" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodia's Hun Sen alleges assassination plot.</title>
<headline>Cambodia's Hun Sen alleges assassination plot.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodian Second Prime Minister Hun Sen said on Friday that exiles in Canada were out to assassinate him and he doubled the $1 million price on his head to anyone who finds out who is behind the plot.</p>
<p>Speaking in a radio broadcast from the central province of Pursat, Hun Sen said &quot;a meeting (of Cambodians) in Canada&quot; wanted to kill him for $1 million in cash, adding that he wanted authorities in North America and Interpol to investigate.</p>
<p>He said he had received a note about the alleged plot from sources in Long Beach, California.</p>
<p>Hun Sen was addressing guests at a ceremony including U.S. Ambassador to Cambodia Kenneth Quinn.</p>
<p>&quot;Hun Sen's head for $1 million is a little bit cheap,&quot; he said in the broadcast. &quot;...I would like to declare that if it only takes $1 million to take my life, I will offer $2 million to someone who finds evidence to show who is orchestrating the attempt.&quot;</p>
<p>The premier, a former member of the Khmer Rouge guerrilla group which ruled the country from 1975-79, has alleged numerous attempts on his life, most notably by King Norodom Sihanouk's half brother Prince Sirivudh who denied the charges but was forced into exile at the end of last year.</p>
<p>The Khmer Rouge, now waging a low-level insurgency against the coalition government, on Friday reiterated its claims that breakaway leader Ieng Sary was seriously ill.</p>
<p>Ieng Sary was sentenced to death in absentia in 1979 for his role in the deaths of more than one million people under Khmer Rouge rule.</p>
<p>He broke from hardliners in the Maoist group earlier this month and has since been talking peace with the government.</p>
<p>&quot;Ieng Sary is seriously ill and he cannot walk as he is paralysed in half of his body and has to travel in a wheelchair,&quot; clandestine Khmer Rouge radio, monitored here on Friday, said.</p>
<p>It said Ieng Sary, who commands the loyalty of at least two major Khmer Rouge military officers on the northwest border with Thailand, had had operations on his eyes and heart.</p>
<p>&quot;His wounds are not better but the traitors catch him to lead them,&quot; said the radio.</p>
<p>The Khmer Rouge have called for his capture and execution.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
