<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11290" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Chiang Kai-shek's grandson blasts Taiwan rulers.</title>
<headline>Chiang Kai-shek's grandson blasts Taiwan rulers.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The grandson of Taiwan's Nationalist leader Chiang Kai-shek, who lost a civil war and fled to the island in 1949, bluntly told the island's ruling party on Friday where it was going wrong.</p>
<p>&quot;It may not be so bad if a political party is either playing money politics or engaging in a power struggle,&quot; said Chiang Hsiao-yung, a Nationalist member.</p>
<p>&quot;But if a party has the problems of both, it is bound to decline,&quot; Chiang was quoted by the state-funded Central News Agency as saying during a two-day Nationalist party congress.</p>
<p>Nationalist delegates were scheduled to discuss during the congress reforms aimed at boosting the party's appeal.</p>
<p>Chiang Hsiao-yung criticised an earlier party decision that said the time was inappropriate to consider the removal from Taiwan to China of the embalmed bodies of Chiang Kai-shek and his son, the late president Chiang Ching-kuo.</p>
<p>&quot;I will not accept the meeting's conclusion, neither will our family members. This matter cannot be decided by only a few people in the party,&quot; Chiang Hsiao-yung said.</p>
<p>Chiang Hsiao-yung, who suffers from cancer of the esophagus, said he did not discuss the issue with Chinese authorities during his July visit to Beijing to seek medical advice.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people say moving the bodies to the mainland will give the enemy a chance to whip the bodies...but I'd rather let the enemy whip the bodies than to let our own people whip the bodies,&quot; Chiang Hsiao-yung said.</p>
<p>The Chiang family fears the two presidents, who presided over an uncompromising autocracy on the island until Chiang Ching-kuo began democratic reforms just before his death in 1988, may not be given sufficient respect in Taiwan as the influence of the opposition grows.</p>
<p>Many portraits and statues of the Chiangs have been removed as Taiwan has developed into a more pluralistic society.</p>
<p>Ousted in a civil war, Chiang Kai-shek and his Nationalist government were forced to flee to Taiwan by Mao Zedong's Communist army in 1949. He died in 1975 without realising a goal of reclaiming power on the Chinese mainland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
