<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11292" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Korean banks go borrowing.</title>
<headline>ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Korean banks go borrowing.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Korean borrowers were in the Asian debt news again on Friday, with a new issue, a few closings and chatter on deals to come.</p>
<p>Kyungki Bank launched a US$40 million floating rate note issue via Sumitomo Finance (Asia) and Union Bank of Switzerland.</p>
<p>The three-year notes were launched at par and re-offered at 99.82. They pay a margin of 40 basis points over the six-month London Interbank Offered Rate.</p>
<p>With fees, the all-in return to top tier managers is 49 basis points.</p>
<p>That's in line with Kyungki's previous deal, which was launched last year.</p>
<p>Kyungki is a South Korean specialized bank that was established in 1969 for the purpose of developing the economy of the Kyungki regional district.</p>
<p>The bank has a debt rating of Baa1 from Moody's Investors Service and a Bank Financial Strength Rating of D.</p>
<p>It is one of a number of such banks that have tapped the Asian debt market this year.</p>
<p>Syndicate managers said issues of these institutions have not benefitted as much as those of the top tier banks from renewed interest in Korean credits that followed July's news that the country was moving closer to attaining OECD membership.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, most Korean bank issues continue to attract good demand, with European banks increasingly showing interest.</p>
<p>Korea Merchant Bank's recent floating rate certificate of deposit issue was increased to US$90 million from US$70 million in syndication, bookrunners CS First Boston Hong Kong and KDB Asia announced today.</p>
<p>The deal attracted 17 banks, many of which are European.</p>
<p>Another Korean company, Samsung Hong Kong, doubled its three-year loan issue to US$100 million in syndication, arranger DKB Asia said.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, bankers report that KEXIM is looking to launch a Eurobond.</p>
<p>Bankers speculate that SBC Warburg and Nomura, which arranged KEXIM's five-year bond set in June, will lead the latest borrowing but this was not confirmed.</p>
<p>The bond should be a few hundred million U.S. dollars in size, bankers said.</p>
<p>Asian Banking Corp has a smaller issue in mind, a US$60 million floating rate certificate of deposit. The five-year (three-year put) deal is expected to pay 67 basis points over LIBOR all-in.</p>
<p>Bankers said KEB International London is likely to arrange the transaction.</p>
<p>--Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2847 4039</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
