<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11307" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: N.Koreans join southern students on hunger strike.</title>
<headline>N.Koreans join southern students on hunger strike.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Korean students on Friday expressed support for two South Korean students on a hunger strike in the North by beginning a fast, state media reported.</p>
<p>The official Korean Central News Agency (KCNA), monitored in Tokyo, said members of North Korea's youth federation and university students started a fast to express solidarity with the two students on hunger strike on the North Korean side of the border town of Panmunjon.</p>
<p>South Koreans Ryu Se Hong and To Jong Hwa began the hunger strike on Wednesday night to press for the release of fellow students detained by South Korean authorities during a pro-unification student riot earlier in the week.</p>
<p>About 3,200 students were arrested this week in Seoul after riot police stormed a teaching block at Yonsei University.</p>
<p>KCNA identified the fasting North Koreans as Ho Chang Jo, chairman of the North's headquarters of the National Alliance of Youth and Students of the Country's Reunification, members of the group and representatives of universities in North Korea.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
