<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11300" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian Metals - S'pore copper premiums dip on China.</title>
<headline>Asian Metals - S'pore copper premiums dip on China.</headline>
<byline>Ang Bee Lin</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore copper premiums eased this week as anticipated strong demand from China for early September delivery failed to emerge, traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>Premiums over London Metal Exchange (LME) cash metal dipped to around $80 a tonne, the lower end of last week's $80-$85 range, they said.</p>
<p>The market had expected China to take delivery of significant tonnages of copper for early September when three-month metal prices fell below the $2,000 a tonne level.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices have fallen below the $2,000 mark, but we have not seen any real buying by the Chinese,&quot; said a U.S trader.</p>
<p>However, Shanghai copper futures ended down across the board on Friday on panic selling sparked by rumours of new arrivals of spot copper in the port.</p>
<p>Traders said premiums were largely unaffected by a report that up to 100,000 tonnes of copper held in Shanghai bonded warehouses probably belongs to the country's strategic state reserves. While the news stirred little excitment among traders in Singpapore, they said the news did clear some market doubts. </p>
<p>&quot;At least we know they are not going to put the 100,000 tonnes back in the market, potentially threatening a further price fall,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Traders said the market was also carefully watching three month LME copper contracts coming due in September.</p>
<p>They said traders who were holding contracts in June when the market crashed on the Sumitomo trading saga will see their contracts expire next month.</p>
<p>These traders are expected to either roll-over their contracts or to take physical delivery, said a U.S trader.</p>
<p>&quot;It'll be interesting to see what happens,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Traders also said market sentiment was sluggish ahead of a bank holiday in London on Monday.</p>
<p>Aluminium was also in the doldrums amid poor demand.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is at its lowest that I have seen and the Chinese are not really buying,&quot; the U.S trader said.</p>
<p>In the zinc market, premiums recovered marginally, drawing support from a firm U.S market while Japanese traders are still negotiating with Western producers on term prices.</p>
<p>    Lead				+45		  +45</p>
<p>    Nickel			    +230-240	   +230-240</p>
<p>Zinc demand in Indonesia and Philippines is holding up well but demand from Thailand is less than normal as the country's economy has slipped into a slight recession, the traders said. Singapore indications as a premium to LME cash in US$/tonne:</p>
<p>					 Aug 22		Aug 12</p>
<p>    Aluminium (Western)	   +50		  +50</p>
<p>    Aluminium (Indian)	    +45		  +45</p>
<p>    Aluminium (Russian)	   +35		  +40</p>
<p>    Aluminium (Indonesian)	+40		  +40</p>
<p>    Copper			    +80		  +80-85</p>
<p>    Zinc (Chinese)		  +75		  +60</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
