<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11303" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China talks airport loans with Japan, France.</title>
<headline>China talks airport loans with Japan, France.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>China has started discussing with the governments of Japan and France loans to finance Shanghai's new international airport, the head of the airport construction department said on Friday.</p>
<p>The first phase of the airport will cost 12 billion yuan and construction is due to begin in September, Wu Xiangmin told reporters.</p>
<p>About a third of this cost will be foreign government loans, mostly to buy foreign equipment and materials which China cannot produce, he said.</p>
<p>The main provider will probably be the Japanese government whose loans are not tied to purchases of Japanese goods, unlike those of other governments that are tied to purchases of goods from their own countries, he said.</p>
<p>The rest of the funding will come as loans from China's State Development Bank and the department's own three billion yuan in capital, he said.</p>
<p>The first phase, with one runway, is due to start operation at the end of 1999 and be completed in 2005, with an annual capacity of 20 million passengers and 750,000 tonnes of cargo, he said.</p>
<p>The final planned airport envisages four runways and an annual handling capacity of 70 million passengers and five million tonnes of cargo, he said.</p>
<p>But his department has no timetable or cost estimates for this final plan, which will depend on the growth of Shanghai's aviation sector.</p>
<p>In the 1986-90 period, Shanghai's passenger growth at its existing Hongqiao airport grew an annual 23 percent, reaching 11 million in 1995 and an estimated 13 million in 1996, he said.</p>
<p>Initial estimates show Shanghai's passenger volume in 2000 at 20 million, while Hongqiao's capacity is only 9.6 million, so there is an urgent need for a new airport, he said.</p>
<p>Currently, Shanghai ranks top among Chinese airports for cargo and third, after Beijing and Guangzhou, for freight, he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
