<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11314" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta shares close at day-high as tensions ease.</title>
<headline>Jakarta shares close at day-high as tensions ease.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta share prices closed at their day-high on Friday on the back of active buying both by local and foreign operators following an easing in political tension, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Jakarta composite index closed 4.93 points, or 0.91 percent, up at 549.21 points. Advancers led decliners by 56 to 46, with 46 counters unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;More foreigners re-entered the market by buying medium and big-size stocks selectively. They gained confidence following the lowering of political tension,&quot; said Budiyanto Wijaya, a broker with DBS Securities Indonesia.  </p>
<p>The market was cheered by news on Thursday that the country's opposition figurehead, Megawati Sukarnoputri, was in talks with the government to end a row over her ouster as chief of the Indonesian Democratic Party.</p>
<p>Brokers also said better-than-expected interim results of some companies, coupled with rumours of possible acquisitions and joint ventures, boosted the market.</p>
<p>Conglomerate Bimantara Citra, controlled by President Suharto's son Bambang Trihatmodjo, topped the active list with 21.7 million shares traded, rising 250 rupiah to 2,425 rupiah.  </p>
<p>Brokers said the rise was due to increased confidence about the political situation and market talk of possible upcoming deregulation in broadcasting ownership. Bimantara controls the Rajawali Citra Televisi Indonesia television channel.</p>
<p>Brokers said Bimantara was also boosted by talk that its car-manufacturing subsidiary had received a large number of orders for two vehicles launched last month.</p>
<p>Heavyweight Semen Gresik rose 275 rupiah to 6,425 rupiah on a volume of 2.6 million shares following talk that Morgan Stanley Capital Index (MSCI) would increase its weighting of the stock.  </p>
<p>Cigarette-maker Gudang Garam rebounded to 8,125 rupiah in late trade after falling to 7,825 rupiah at midsession.</p>
<p>Brokers said it had fallen on talk that MSCI planned to reduce the weighting of the stock.</p>
<p>&quot;But later on, it was said the effective date for the new weighting is not immediate,&quot; said one local broker. Confirmation was not immediately available.</p>
<p>--- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364 (c) Reuters Limited 1996</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
