<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11318" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks end 1.47 pct up on speculative buys.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks end 1.47 pct up on speculative buys.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks ended 1.47 percent higher in moderate trade on Friday as investors returned to the market and bought blue-chip shares for speculative reasons after recent falls in prices, brokers said.</p>
<p>The SET index ended 16.02 points higher at 1,106.73 on 4.3 billion baht trade. Gainers trounced decliners 230 to 82 while 117 issues unchanged. The SET-50 index was 1.43 points higher to 84.66.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors bought blue-chip shares as they thought prices have come down quite a lot already,&quot; said Chetta Meemangkang of Prime Finance and Securities.  </p>
<p>Friday's buying was also partly due to the current high money supply in the system, Chetta said.</p>
<p>Brokers said Japanese funds were investing in the finance sector in the morning and foreigners in general were not selling much, compared with heavy selling last month.</p>
<p>Large capitalised banks along with communication and energy issues were in focus.</p>
<p>United Communication topped the active list, rising six baht to 262. Wattana Karnpaet Plc, debuting on Friday in the health care sector, fell 6.50 baht from its initial public offering price of 35. -- Suthep Chawla (662) 252-9950</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
