<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11313" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: ING eyes Thailand expansion plan.</title>
<headline>ING eyes Thailand expansion plan.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch financial services group Internationale Nederlanden Groep NV (ING) said on Friday it had placed high priority on expanding its corporate and investment banking presence in Thailand.</p>
<p>Jan Cherim, who heads the group's Thai banking operation, said ING is waiting for the Thai authorities' approval to upgrade its representative office and offshore banking units into a full branch.</p>
<p>Phillip Shirriff, chief executive of ING's financial services in Asia, said last year ING has joined Dhana Siam Finance and Securities Plc in applying for a life insurance business licence in Thailand.</p>
<p>He said the ING-Dhana Siam joint venture is one of about 30 local and foreign applicants seeking a share of a high potential life insurance business in Thailand where only seven percent of its people take out life insurance policies.</p>
<p>Shirriff said he did not know when Thailand would proceed with its earlier plan to grant 12 new life and 12 non-life insurance licences.  </p>
<p>Cherim, general manager of ING Bank in Thailand, said recent measures by the Thai central bank to curb inflows of short-term foreign funds has undermined efforts to make Bangkok a regional financial centre.</p>
<p>He said the central bank's move to raise the size and lengthen the minimum maturity of loans that offshore banking units can offer to clients have prompted their clients to turn to Singapore.</p>
<p>ING reported on Thursday that pretax profit of its Asian operations fell to 120 million guilders in the first half of 1996 from 135 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Shirriff said the 11.1 percent profit decline was partly due to what he called a frustrating part of a growing insurance business which takes five to six years to achieve a profitable return on its assets.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662)-2529950/3</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
