<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11323" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan Q4 aluminium premiums seen around $62/tonne.</title>
<headline>Japan Q4 aluminium premiums seen around $62/tonne.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Premiums for fourth-quarter aluminium shipments to Japan were being set around $62 per tonne over London Metal Exchange cash prices during talks this week between producers and Japanese trade houses, market sources said on Friday, although no deals could be confirmed.</p>
<p>They added that many deals were still under discussion and may not be concluded until next week.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no reason to hurry,&quot; said one trader, who added that some talks may drag into September.</p>
<p>Traders gave no indications, however, of any acrimony between the two sides. &quot;Talks at our company are going smoothly,&quot; said one source at a large trade house.</p>
<p>Most traders said they doubted the premium negotiations would be affected by next week's talks in Tokyo between Venezuelan government officials and a Japanese consortium, which are locked in a dispute over the Venalum aluminium refinery. The Japanese own a 20 percent share of the facility.</p>
<p>Venalum recently decided to resume, on a one-time basis, ingot shipments to Japan that had been suspended since February due to the dispute. The resumption was intended, one industry source said, as an olive branch to the Japanese.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't think this will be resolved quickly,&quot; said a trader at a major Japanese trade house.</p>
<p>Traders also dismissed suggestions that a recent rise in output at Japan's big rolling and extrusion mills would strengthen the producers' negotiating positions.</p>
<p>While output at Japan's seven biggest mills rose 2.5 percent year-on-year in July, industry sources said this was due mainly to a seasonal boost in beverage can sheet output, while Japan's overall domestic aluminium demand this year was expected to rise only slightly from 1995.</p>
<p>-- Edmund Klamann, Tokyo Commodities Desk (81-3 3432 6179)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
