<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11321" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL shares end mixed, focus again on second liners.</title>
<headline>KL shares end mixed, focus again on second liners.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share prices closed mixed with market focus again on second liner stocks as blue chips extended their consolidation after sharp gains earlier in the week, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was another uneventful day as funds stayed on the sidelines,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;Interest was very selective and price movements were slow throughout.&quot;</p>
<p>The benchmark Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange Composite Index ended at 1,119.48, down 1.28 points. The Second Board index closed up 6.43 points at 511.43.  </p>
<p>Market volume was 176 million shares, with gainers beating losers 320 to 215.</p>
<p>Leading the fall in blue chips was Telekom Malaysia which dropped 30 cents to 21.80 ringgit.</p>
<p>Technology Resources fell five cents to 7.70 ringgit after reporting half-year earnings that were below market expectations. Maybank, however, rose 20 cents to 24.00 ringgit on the back of higher than expected full-year profits announced earlier this week.</p>
<p>Spot month August Composite Index futures closed up 2.0 points at 1,113.5. -- Syed Azman (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
