<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11330" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: FOCUS - China not seen rushing to buy palm oil.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - China not seen rushing to buy palm oil.</headline>
<byline>Syed Azman</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian palm oil surged on Friday after news that China has approved imports of 1.3 million tonnes of palm oil between now and March 1997, but traders and refiners were doubtful if that would translate into real deals.</p>
<p>They said the current high palm oil prices would deter Chinese importers, who have been buying the cheaper soybean oil and had no immediate need to switch to palm oil.</p>
<p>&quot;Just because they have been allowed to import palm oil does not mean they have to buy,&quot; said a trader who has done deals with China.</p>
<p>&quot;China will not pay at these prices,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Talk of the China imports has been circulating in the market for the past few weeks before it was confirmed by Malaysian Primary Industries Minister Lim Keng Yaik on Thursday.</p>
<p>Lim also said that he believed 80 percent of the Chinese imports would come from Malaysia, the world's largest exporter, and the remainder from Indonesia.</p>
<p>Lim had requested that China consider increasing the quota for import of palm oil when he visited Beijing in June.</p>
<p>The confirmation sparked off heavy speculative buying in the local palm oil market. The benchmark third position November crude palm oil futures rose 36 ringgit ($14.4) to 1,196 ringgit ($480) a tonne in Friday afternoon trade.</p>
<p>Traders said players bought on speculation that exports could be further boosted in the next few months.</p>
<p>Malaysian palm oil exports in July were 646,017 tonnes, the second highest monthly figure ever recorded, helped by strong demand from India. The healthy exports are expected to be sustainable until October.</p>
<p>Exports to China, however, have slackened this year.</p>
<p>China was estimated to have bought 481,108 tonnes of Malaysian palm oil during the first half of 1996, against 721,422 tonnes in the corresponding period last year, according to the Palm Oil Registration and Licensing Authority (PORLA).</p>
<p>Refiners said the lower imports were due to ample supply of soft oils due to a bumper harvest and low domestic prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Some industries could be looking to buy palm oil but I don't think it will in large quantities,&quot; said an industry official. &quot;The higher the prices, the lesser are the chances that China will buy.&quot;</p>
<p>Most of the Malaysian palm oil is used by China's instant noodle producers.</p>
<p>Palm oil is also subjected to an 18 percent import duty in China, compared with 13 percent imposed on soybean oil.</p>
<p>($1 = 2.4920 ringgit)</p>
<p>- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
