<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11337" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Moroccan stock market keeps upward trend.</title>
<headline>Moroccan stock market keeps upward trend.</headline>
<dateline>CASABLANCA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Casablanca bourse ended the week higher to maintain its upper trend after the price of the largest capitalised stocks rose, stockbrokers said.</p>
<p>The all-share index rose 0.56 percent to close at 399.88 compared with last week.</p>
<p>Upline Securities Index which tracks the ten most liquid stocks rose 0.9 percent to close at 51,104 points.</p>
<p>ONA Group, Morocco's largest private conglomerate and market blue chip, jumped 3.32 percent to close at 405 dirhams compared with last Friday, a Casablanca Finance Intermediation (CFI) stockbroker said.</p>
<p>&quot;The appreciation of ONA shares continued over the week to close at 405 dirhams...The market reacted to the positive expectation of the group's 1996 results and to the recent purchase of four mines including IMITER sliver mine,&quot; Younes Benjelloun, analyst at CFI said.</p>
<p>Moroccan government agreed to sell four mines, including a silver and copper mine to ONA Group at a minimum price of 648.8 million dirhams, the Minister of Privatisation Abderrahman Saaidi said.</p>
<p>It launched an international tender in March to sell four mines --silver, copper, fluorite, cobalt-- in one lot. The biggest mine is Societe Metallurgique d'Imiter (SMI), in which the state offered its majority 69 percent holding or 668,380 shares. It valued the stake at a minimum 448.9 million dirhams.</p>
<p>With its 6.9 billion dirhams market capitalisation, ONA conglomerate, is the second largest capitalised company and counts for more than 10 percent of the total bourse capitalisation, he said.</p>
<p>ONA remains very much in demand by investors, stockbrokers said.</p>
<p>Wafabank, one of the largest listed banks, rose 1.2 percent to close at 420 dirhams.</p>
<p>Banque Marocaine du Commerce Exterieur, one of the most liquid stocks, gained three points to close 390 dirhams.</p>
<p>Traded volume during four days rose to 82 million dirhams, from 71 million the previous week.</p>
<p>The stock market was closed on Tuesday due to a national public holiday.</p>
<p>($1= 8.6 dirhams)</p>
<p>-- Rabat newsroom (212-7) 726518</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CASABLANCA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
