<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11366" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: N.Dakota spring wheat about one-third harvested.</title>
<headline>N.Dakota spring wheat about one-third harvested.</headline>
<dateline>BISMARCK, N.D. 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Dakota's spring wheat crop was about one-third harvested and early yields were running above average expectations, a spokesman for the state's wheat commission told Reuters on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're probably around that 30 to 33 percent mark being harvested,&quot; said Jim Peterson, marketing specialist for the North Dakota Wheat Commission.</p>
<p>Peterson said yields in southeast North Dakota, South Dakota and central and southern Minnesota had been &quot;certainly above expectations.&quot; He said he had heard reports of many fields yielding more than 50 bushels per acre.  </p>
<p>But Peterson warned that yields of 50 bushels would likely be the exception, not the norm, when tabulating North Dakota's final average spring wheat yield.</p>
<p>&quot;The key thing is that the best wheat has now been harvested,&quot; Peterson said.</p>
<p>Peterson said the average yield to date was probably 15 bushels per acre higher than the average for fields in western North Dakota, where wheat was planted late and has since been stressed by heat and dryness.</p>
<p>Still, Peterson said test weights had so far been &quot;exceptional,&quot; running 62 to 64 pounds per bushel on average.  </p>
<p>Earlier this month, the U.S. Department of Agriculture pegged North Dakota's 1996 spring wheat yield at 30.0 bushels per acre, which would be a three bushel increase over the state's actual 1995 yield of 27.0 bushels.</p>
<p>Managers at scattered North Dakota elevators confirmed that the harvest had yet to progress further to the north, and said the average yield in the northern part of the state would probably be lower than in the south.</p>
<p>Keith Ihry, manager of the Farmers Elevator Co in Walhalla, in northeast North Dakota, said that only about 10 percent of the wheat in his region had been harvested.  </p>
<p>&quot;The wheat we've taken in so far has been of pretty good quality, with yields in the 30 to 40 bushels per acre range,&quot; Ihry said.</p>
<p>Ihry said he had not seen much of a problem with scab, a fungal disease that can cause yield and quality losses on all small grain crops, but he said &quot;it could get worse in some of the later-planted stuff&quot;.</p>
<p>Dennis Novacek, manager of the Fessenden Co-op Association, a grain elevator in central North Dakota, said wheat harvest was around 15 percent complete in his area.</p>
<p>&quot;The early stuff looks pretty good but we're just starting to get into some of the scabbier stuff,&quot; Novacek said.</p>
<p>He said yields were running between 20 to 40 bushels per acre, but that there were &quot;more 40-bushel fields than 20.&quot;</p>
<p>--Greg Frost, 816 561-8671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BISMARCK, N.D."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
