<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11369" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME cattle and pork futures seen up after reports.</title>
<headline>CME cattle and pork futures seen up after reports.</headline>
<byline>Jerry Bieszk</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Live cattle, live hog and especially pork belly futures at the Chicago Mercantile Exchange are expected to trade higher Monday following the realease Friday afternoon of the monthly USDA Cattle-on-Feed and Cold Storage reports, livestock analysts said.</p>
<p>Live cattle futures are expected to trade steady to 0.500 cent higher in nearbys Monday as the cattle report showed on-feed supplies low and cattle placements lighter than estimated. Pork belly futures are seen up the 2.000 cent limit on much less than expected storage stocks.  </p>
<p>USDA reported August 1 on-feed cattle supplies at feedlots with capacity of 1,000 head or more in the seven major feedlot states at 86 percent of last year, close to the average estimate of 86.1 percent. However, placements of cattle onto feedlots during July ran at 106 percent of last year, under the average guess of 110.5 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said many cattle remained on grass longer due to high feed prices during July. This kept total feedlot supplies down, and feeders are expected to keep their cattle on grass until the new corn crop is harvested in the fall.  </p>
<p>&quot;They will keep them on grass as long as possible,&quot; said Jim Sauter, feeder cattle futures trader for Saul Stone, citing the relatively high feed costs.</p>
<p>Pork belly futures are expected to show the largest price movement following the reports. The Cold Storage report put frozen belly stocks at 28.533 million lbs, far below the low end of early estimates of 35.1 to 38.7 million lbs. USDA said frozen belly stocks in July were the lowest since July 1976.  </p>
<p>&quot;Evidently the entire amount of bellies that were in private coolers, not reporting to the Mercantile Exchange, was used up during the month of July,&quot; said Chuck Levitt, senior livstock analyst for Alaron Trading Corp.</p>
<p>Analysts expect August pork bellies to trade up the daily limit their two remaining trading days.</p>
<p>A low belly supply is very significant now, compared to other low stock periods, because hog numbers are down and pork production is seen down about six percent in the fourth quarter. Pork production had increased after those other low stock years because hog number were rising, they said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't know how we are going to be able to replenish stocks in any meaningful way during (the fourth) quarter which means this (stock) number is almost as bullish to February as it would have been to old crop August,&quot; Levitt said.</p>
<p>Levitt noted that the carryover of stocks in the crop season will likely be one of the smallest numbers ever.</p>
<p>Analysts also cited the low supply of hams in storage, which along with low belly stocks should support hog futures. Ham stocks declined about a 1.0 million lbs during July when they normally rise to accommodate seasonal usage during the fall and winter holidays.  </p>
<p>The storage report also showed a decline in frozen beef stocks to 291 million lbs from 359.3 million last year, which should add to the expected strength in live cattle futures.</p>
<p>Frozen beef stocks declined about 10 percent during July despite production up five percent during the period and reduced export demand due to beef scares in Japan and &quot;Mad Cow&quot; concerns worldwide, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to take the assumption that we have seen a fairly dramatic increase in domestic beef consumption because of the lower prices,&quot; said Dale Benson, vice president and senior livestock analyst for Dean Witter.</p>
<p>--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8720</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
