<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11389" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Big Band singer Alyce King Clarke dies at age 81.</title>
<headline>Big Band singer Alyce King Clarke dies at age 81.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alyce King Clarke, a member of the Big Band-era singing group known for decades as the King Sisters, has died. She was 81.</p>
<p>&quot;She had the best voice. It was a big, rich alto voice and she was the heart of the family,&quot; her sister Donna King said Friday.</p>
<p>Clark, who died Wednesday in North Hollywood Medical Centre of chronic bronchial asthma, was featured along with her sisters in the 1960s ABC television programme &quot;The King Family.&quot;</p>
<p>Born the fourth of eight children in Payson, Utah, Clarke started performing with two of her sisters during the Great Depression to increase the family's income.</p>
<p>&quot;We have sung for 60 years. We started in 1932 as little children. Our father was a musician,&quot; her 77-year-old sister said.</p>
<p>The group ultimately evolved into a quartet, known as the King Sisters, which sang on major radio variety programmes in the 1930s and 1940s and was later featured on the Ed Sullivan Show.</p>
<p>The group also earned a Grammy award for their recording of &quot;Imagination.&quot;</p>
<p>Last year, Capitol Records released a compact disc called &quot;Spotlight on the King Sisters&quot; as part of the series honouring &quot;The Great Ladies of Song.&quot;</p>
<p>Clarke is survived by husband Robert Clarke, three sons, five sisters, 11 grandchildren and four great grandchildren.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
