<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11399" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT corn ends mostly firm as tour data waited.</title>
<headline>CBOT corn ends mostly firm as tour data waited.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT corn futures closed mostly higher in anticipation of a bullish report from a Midwest crop tour of key corn states, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;They were waiting for the Pro Farmer report. People bought the market in anticipation of a bullish number,&quot; said Steve Bruce of E.D. and F. Man International.</p>
<p>Crop scouts overnight pegged Iowa's crop crop yield potential this year at 126.0 bushels, below USDA's August forecast for 129.0 bushels per acre.</p>
<p>The Professional Farmers of America tour ends late Friday in Des Moines, Iowa.</p>
<p>Weather patterns were still alive as a market topic.</p>
<p>There was some talk that a private meteorologist was forecasting warm weather in September. That scenario would help boost the maturity pace and possibly enhance yield potential of the U.S. corn crop.</p>
<p>But most traders said today's market was mainly a position squaring affair amid thin volume.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just chopping around and the volume is low,&quot; said Steve Bruce of E.D. and F. Man International.</p>
<p>Corn closed two cents per bushel lower to 1-1/2 higher, with September down two at $3.65-1/2.</p>
<p>ADM Investor Services bought three million bushels of March, Griffin Trading bought 1.5 million December and Rand Financial sold two million bushels of March, the traders said.</p>
<p>Corn futures volume was estimated at 47,000, down from 53,040 contracts Thursday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>Corn options trading was relatively quiet and the September expired quietly at 1201 CDT.</p>
<p>Corn options volume was estimated at 15,000, up from 13,819 contracts Thursday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
