<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11398" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soybeans close lower reflecting weather.</title>
<headline>CBOT soybeans close lower reflecting weather.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT soybean futures closed lower, reflecting the current satisfactory crop weather in the U.S. Midwest, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Weather looks good for now and the crop conditions should improve,&quot; said Ron Kucha of O'Connor and Co.</p>
<p>Pressure also came from a report that a private meteorologist saw warm weather during September in the U.S. Midwest, which could boost crop production prospects.</p>
<p>Meteorologists early Friday said the Midwest should be normal to below normal next week but warming is expected by the Labor Day weekend.</p>
<p>Profit taking and position squaring were noted after the rally during late dealings Thursday linked to reports from a crop tour indicating Iowa's crop potential was below expectations.</p>
<p>But crop scouts overnight said the state's soybean pod count at 1,087.6 per three-foot by three-foot section was above the estimate in 1995 at 1,059.3.</p>
<p>The Professional Farmers of America crop tour of the Midwest ends late today in Des Moines, Iowa.</p>
<p>Soybeans closed five to 7-1/2 cents per bushel lower, with September down 5-1/2 at $8.03-1/4.</p>
<p>Prudential Securities sold three million bushels of November and Goldenberg Hehmeyer bought two million November, they said. In late dealings Smith Barney bought one million bushels of November, the traders said.</p>
<p>Soybean futures volume was estimated at 42,000, down from 46,156 Thursday.</p>
<p>Options trading was relatively routine and the September expired quietly at 1201 CDT, they said.</p>
<p>Soybean options volume was estimated at 15,000, down from 15,896 Thursday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
