<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11392" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - ends off as much as a point.</title>
<headline>U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - ends off as much as a point.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. municipal bond prices ended the week with full point losses in spots on Friday, after the figure for July durable goods was a little too good.</p>
<p>The U.S. Commerce Department reported that orders for big ticket items in July rose 1.6 percent, much higher than the forecast for a 0.3 percent increase.</p>
<p>Prices opened 1/4 to 3/8 softer on the news, then extended those losses throughout the day. By the end of the day, the market was down 3/4 overall and a point on certain names, one trader said.  </p>
<p>Trading at the new levels was not very active, however, and was especially light in the afternoon.</p>
<p>In the secondary, bids on Cook County, Ill., FGIC 5-7/8s of 2022 were off 1/2 point at 99-1/4. Yields jumped six basis points, to 5.83 percent, on Lakeland, Fla., electric 5-1/2s of 2026.</p>
<p>The Treasury long bond was hit by durable goods as well, with the long bond heading into the New York close off 1-4/32 at 97-23/32 to yield 6.93 percent.  </p>
<p>Municipal futures followed the same downward trend, with the September contract ending off 1-1/32 to 114-15/32. The September T-bond contract lost the same amount, leaving the MOB spread unchanged at 158 ticks.</p>
<p>Next week's new issue action will again be light, with the week's competitive calendar totaling $291 million and the largest single offering only $25 million. Bergen County, N.J., takes credit for that deal, set for 1100 EDT Monday.</p>
<p>The largest negotiated issue next week is expected to be the New York State Dormitory Authority's $377 million issue through Smith Barney Inc. The total negotiated calendar is approximately $1.7 billion for the week, with another $769 million on the day-to-day list.</p>
<p>Next week's data releases include Monday's existing home sales for July, Tuesday's consumer confidence report from the Conference Board, and new home sales for July on Thursday.</p>
<p>--Steven Dickson, 212-859-1652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
