<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11401" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FORECAST-Experts eye U.S. GDP, home sales Aug 26.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Experts eye U.S. GDP, home sales Aug 26.</headline>
<byline>Scott Gerlach</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Next week's report on revised second quarter gross domestic product (GDP) may suggest the U.S. economy continues to grow strongly in the third quarter, said economists in a Reuters poll.</p>
<p>On average, 25 economists surveyed on Friday forecast Commerce's second estimate at last quarter's GDP will be unchanged at 4.2 percent.</p>
<p>While a GDP revision might normally get little attention, economists said they were looking to components of the report for hints at third-quarter growth.  </p>
<p>Even if the headline GDP figure remains the same, some experts said, upward revisions in other aspects of the report could point to faster-than-expected economic growth in the current quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;We see final sales being revised higher, which means inventories are lower and growth could be stronger in the third quarter,&quot; said Jonathan Basile, an economist at HSBC Securities Inc.</p>
<p>Friday's report on July durable goods orders and the recently reported rise in July industrial production suggested third quarter growth would remain swift, Basile said.  </p>
<p>Economists ascribed some of the rise in second-quarter GDP to a healthy housing market and they said next week's home sales reports could offset certain portions of the GDP report.</p>
<p>Respondents forecast existing home sales fell to a 4.1 million unit annual rate in July from 4.18 million in June.</p>
<p>&quot;The housing market remains relatively healthy, (but) we could get some fallback as the year progresses,&quot; said Raphael Marrone, a senior analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>The July existing homes report is scheduled for Monday at 1000EDT/1400GMT and GDP is set for release on Thursday at 0830EDT/1230GMT.</p>
<p>--212-859-1868</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E61">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
