<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11405" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: P.T. Tri Polyta concludes propylene deal.</title>
<headline>P.T. Tri Polyta concludes propylene deal.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>P.T. Tri Polyta Indonesia Tbk said Friday it concluded a five-year propylene supply deal, effective August 1, with  P.T. Chandra Asri.</p>
<p>The company's statement did not disclose financial terms.</p>
<p>Chandra Asri is partly owned by Indonesia President Suharto's second son Bambang Trihatmodjo and timber executive Prajogo Pangestu.  </p>
<p>Under the propylene supply agreement, pricing is established by a fixed formula linked to the average quoted ICIS-LOR South East Asia spot price for propylene in the month of consumption with declining year to year volume purchase commitments, a statement from the company said.</p>
<p>During the first year of effect, Tri Polyta said it has committed to purchasing 240,000 metric tons of propylene at the average quoted ICIS-LOR South East Asia spot price for propylene in the month of consumption plus 19.5 percent, representing a discount of up to 8 percent over imports subject to full tariff and landing charges.  </p>
<p>The pricing formula will provide the company with significant savings over the life of the agreement, in comparison to imports under the current tariff levels, the company said.</p>
<p>Had this agreement been in place during the second quarter of 1996, the company said the effect would have been an increase of $2.3 million in the cost of the 49,639 metric tons of propylene purchases from Chandra Asri. After tax effects are taken into account, the net effect per American Depository Receipts (ADR) would have been a decrease in earnings per ADR of $0.06.</p>
<p>Commenting on this agreement, Sudwikatmono, president director of Tri Polyta, said, &quot;Management negotiated the propylene agreement to minimize long-term supply risk on our feedstock requirements at a discount to the cost of imported propylene, particularly so given the unreliability of spot supplies in Southeast Asia.  We are satisfied that the agreement is advantageous in light of the current tariff structure, market conditions and alternatives available to the company.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
