<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11402" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Simpson case judge urged to allow TV coverage.</title>
<headline>Simpson case judge urged to allow TV coverage.</headline>
<byline>Dan Whitcomb</byline>
<dateline>SANTA MONICA, Calif. 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The judge presiding over the wrongful-death civil case against O.J. Simpson was urged Friday to allow live television coverage of the upcoming trial.</p>
<p>Judge Hiroshi Fujisaki listened to eight lawyers representing the families of murder victims Nicole Brown Simpson and Ronald Goldman, arguing why there should be a TV camera in the courtroom.</p>
<p>The former football star's attorney, Robert Baker, was the sole dissenting voice, arguing against live television coverage. Fujisaki was expected to issue his ruling later Friday.</p>
<p>Simpson was acquitted by a criminal court jury last October of the June 1994 murders of his ex-wife and her friend, who were viciously stabbed to death outside her luxury Brentwood townhouse.</p>
<p>That trial received live, gavel-to-gavel TV coverage and kept America enthralled for about nine months.</p>
<p>The families are now suing him for damages in civil court, charging that Simpson was responsible for the deaths of their loved ones. Trial is set to begin Sept. 17.</p>
<p>Attorney Kelli Sager, representing several news organisations, told the judge, &quot;There will be coverage of this case regardless of the court's decision. The best possible coverage is for the public to see what happens in the courtroom.&quot;</p>
<p>Sager said that at the very least there should be a closed circuit television feed to the press room so that reporters not in court would be able to report on the proceedings. &quot;There's not even enough room in the courtroom to accommodate all the media who want to be present,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Friday's hearing was so crowded with lawyers and reporters that some of the 19 attorneys present had to be seated in the jury box.</p>
<p>Floyd Abrams, an attorney for Court TV, which provided the video feed for live coverage of the criminal case, argued, &quot;It is very important that a public that has become cynical and suspicious about the way the (judicial) system works see the way it really works.&quot;</p>
<p>But Baker said to argue that a camera was necessary in the courtroom for a fair trial &quot;would belie 200 years of history.&quot;</p>
<p>Some lawyers asked Fujisaki to modify his wide-ranging &quot;gag&quot; order prohibiting lawyers, witnesses and anyone else connected to the case from speaking about it in public, but Baker argued that it should stay intact.</p>
<p>Attorney Daniel Petrocelli, representing the Goldman family, urged the judge to modify the order to allow Fred Goldman, Ronald Goldman's father, to speak publicly about the case.</p>
<p>&quot;My client has lost a son and this case is his last chance to get justice,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA MONICA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
