<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11400" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT wheat ends up on Egypt talk, China hopes.</title>
<headline>CBOT wheat ends up on Egypt talk, China hopes.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Talk that Egypt may be in the market late Friday or over the weekend for U.S. wheat boosted CBOT wheat futures to a higher close, traders said.</p>
<p>After the close it was confirmed Egypt was seeking 50,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat for September or October shipment.</p>
<p>Support also may have come from hopes for U.S. wheat business with China this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Glickman says China might buy U.S. wheat and that may have helped wheat a bit,&quot; said Vic Lespinasse of Dean Witter Reynolds, referring to USDA Secretary Dan Glickman's remark that China may return to the U.S. wheat market this marketing year. But Glickman also cast a cautious pall on his remarks.</p>
<p>&quot;I still think they'll be in the market, but it does seem to be a more competitive marketplace out there,&quot; Glickman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Refco Inc bought 1.5 million bushels of December and SAK Futures bought two million December, they said.</p>
<p>Gains in wheat were limited by a recent slowdown in U.S. wheat exports and diminished fears about weather threats to the U.S. and Canadian spring wheat crops.</p>
<p>Wheat closed two to four cents per bushel higher, with September up 2-1/4 at $4.52-3/4.</p>
<p>Wheat futures volume was estimated at 13,000, up from 9,648 Thursday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>In the wheat options pit the September expired without fanfare and the focus was on put demand in the December, they said. Lind Waldock bought 500 December $4.80 puts and bought 250 December $4.60 puts, they said. Lind Waldock also was a fairly active buyer of wheat futures, which may have been a hedge against the put demand, they said.</p>
<p>Wheat options volume was estimated at 6,000, up from 4,334 Thursday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
