<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11418" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYCE cotton ends firmer on fund buying, off highs.</title>
<headline>NYCE cotton ends firmer on fund buying, off highs.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Technically-driven fund buying fueled NYCE cotton futures sharply higher in afternoon trade, but steady trade selling blocked gains from accumulating the 3.00-cent daily limit, dealers said.</p>
<p>The action carried the benchmark December contract over resistance seen at 75.00, to reach a high of 76.00 on the day. The contract closed at 74.95, up 1.50, after ranging from 76.00 to 73.80. October ended 1.37 firmer at 74.30, while the back months finished 1.50 to 1.10 higher.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at a brisk 15,000 lots.</p>
<p>The U.S. Census Bureau noted a drop in imports for the week ended August 18, but analysts said it is too soon to gauge whether the report marks the beginning of a steady decline. Imports were 24,784 bales compared with 53,861 bales a week ago.</p>
<p>Flooding in Pakistan also lent support to the market, while players ignored Hurricane Dolly as it landed in Mexico's eastern state of Veracruz, sources said.</p>
<p>The storm is expected to move west-northwest, losing force as it moves over land, the National Meteorological Service said.  </p>
<p>Despite today's move, several analysts forecast lower prices based on an improving U.S. crop. &quot;Nothing short of a weather disaster (early frost, hurricane, wet harvesting season) is likely to lower the U.S. crop below 18.6 million bales,&quot; said O.A. Cleveland, a cotton marketing specialist with Mississippi State University.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Agriculture pegged the crop at 18.577 million bales August 12.</p>
<p>-- Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities 212-859-1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
