<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11427" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FCOJ futures ends sharply up on spec, fund buying.</title>
<headline>FCOJ futures ends sharply up on spec, fund buying.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>FCOJ futures continued to rack up gains and closed just under the day's highs on speculative and fund buying, floor sources said.</p>
<p>The market made its of 123.85 basis September after stops were taken out at 122.10. Dealers pegged the next level of resistance at 124.00.</p>
<p>September rose 2.15 on the day to finish at 123.25, having ranged from 123.85 to 120.80. November ended 2.75 firmer at 118.40, while the remaining months closed 1.60 to 3.50 higher.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at 4,000 lots.</p>
<p>While weekly movement remains above 5 million gallons, Merrill Lynch analyst Judith Ganes forecast lower near-term prices based on prospects for increased Brazilian exports in 1996/97, and a stronger Florida crop.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Agriculture will release its next estimate for the Florida crop in October.</p>
<p>&quot;High cash prices reflected through a firm EFP market and strong premium on the September position ahead of the delivery period, runs counter to this fundamental outlook and could be one explanation for the market not dropping,&quot; Ganes said.</p>
<p>Another analyst said several technical indicators, including the stochastics and the relative strength index, pointed to an overbought market.</p>
<p>September 3 is the first notice day and September 10 the last trading day for the spot contract.</p>
<p>--Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities Desk 212-859-1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
