<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11420" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee reverses to end higher as funds buy.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee reverses to end higher as funds buy.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures ended moderately higher Friday, as a late round of fund buying erased early losses and lifted the December contract to a fresh three-month high, traders said.</p>
<p>Origin selling and local profit-taking pressured values from the outset, but after the most-active December contract survived a test of 118.00 cents a lb support, dealers said downward momentum came to a halt.</p>
<p>Benchmark December coffee closed up 1.75 cents, at 122.55 cents, its highest settlement since May 20, after ranging between 123.00 and 118.10. Front-month September ended up 1.15 cents a lb, at 132.25, while the remaining months gained 0.05 to 2.10. Volume reached an estimated 8,577 lots.</p>
<p>Market sources said today's upturn reflected persistant concerns about tight nearby supplies.</p>
<p>They noted that there were still no delivery notices issued against the spot September contract, and although September's open interest continued to decline, Exchange warehouses hold a meager 34,516 bags of coffee.</p>
<p>On Thursday, September's open interest declined 631 lots, to 2,137 lots, the equivalent of over 500,000 bags of coffee.  </p>
<p>While the nearby September/December switch eased to 9.70 cents today, compared to 10.30 cents on Thursday, traders noted strength in the December/March switch, which widened to 6.50 cents versus 6.10 cents at Thursday's close.</p>
<p>The December contract posted gains every day this week, rising 11.00 cents -- or nearly 10 percent -- since last Friday.</p>
<p>-Patricia Avidan, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
