<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11423" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. shrugs off reported electoral fraud in Bosnia.</title>
<headline>U.S. shrugs off reported electoral fraud in Bosnia.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Friday shrugged off allegations of fraud in the landmark Bosnian election campaign, saying it believed international monitors were correcting problems.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Glyn Davies was speaking after the international community's high representative in Bosnia, Carl Bildt, expressed &quot;deep disquiet&quot; over reports of Serb manipulation of voter registration for the Sept. 14 vote.</p>
<p>Davies said Washington was concerned about evidence of &quot;quite glaring&quot; malpractices, but added: &quot;We have confidence that the OSCE has taken proper action to correct these irregularities.&quot; The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) is supervising the election.</p>
<p>The OSCE's Provisional Election Commission met in Sarajevo on Friday to consider whether to postpone some municipal voting in response to the alleged registration rigging but failed to reach a final decision, a spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Bosnians are to elect local assemblies in municipalities, Moslem-Croat and Serb parliaments, a national House of Representatives and a collective presidency. But monitors say many refugees have been actively discouraged from registering to vote in the community in which they originally lived.</p>
<p>Davies said the United States had not &quot;had any illusions that the elections in Bosnia are going to be perfect&quot;.</p>
<p>But, he added, &quot;these elections are a pre-requisite to creating the multi-ethnic government institutions which will put Bosnia on the road to a lasting peace&quot;.</p>
<p>Bosnia's main Moslem party, the SDA, has asked the OSCE to postpone the municipal elections and has warned that if its demands are not met it will reconsider participating in them.</p>
<p>But Davies noted that Secretary of State Warren Christopher, during a visit to Bosnia last week, had stressed that boycotting the vote would simply reduce the choice of leaders available to the Bosnian people.</p>
<p>The United States is anxious for the elections to take place because it fears that otherwise the NATO-led peace force in Bosnia, which includes 18,000 American troops, will not be able to return home as scheduled at the end of the year.</p>
<p>Davies meanwhile welcomed Friday's mutual recognition between Croatia and rump Yugoslavia as &quot;a positive step toward establishing lasting stability in the Balkans&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
