<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11428" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ohio legislature to weigh second turnpike agency.</title>
<headline>Ohio legislature to weigh second turnpike agency.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>- Ohio lawmakers will take up a bill this fall that would create a second state turnpike commission to oversee a new north-south toll road.</p>
<p>State Rep. William Ogg, D-Portsmouth, the chief sponsor of the bill, said it would charge the new commission with building an approximately 240-mile toll road between Toledo and Portsmouth.</p>
<p>He estimated the cost between $1 billion and $1.5 billion. The project would be financed through a mixture of federal funds available under the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 and toll revenue bonds sold by the new commission, he added.</p>
<p>The idea for a new commission arose after lawmakers earlier this year passed a reform bill that among other things prohibited the current Ohio Turnpike Commission from expending toll revenues on projects outside of the existing 241-mile turnpike. That measure, which Gov. George Voinovich signed into law in July, was triggered by the commission's vote in April 1995 to hike tolls by 80 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;That's why I felt I had to do this because I could no longer use the Ohio Turnpike Commission,&quot; Ogg said, referring to why he introduced the bill.</p>
<p>Ogg said that prior to the reform bill, the existing turnpike commission had done a preliminary examination of the north-south turnpike project, which is part of a proposed national highway network linking Great Lakes and Mid-Atlantic states.</p>
<p>Ogg said he has bipartisan support for the bill.</p>
<p>--Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
