<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11433" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMF may ask China to release jailed employee early.</title>
<headline>IMF may ask China to release jailed employee early.</headline>
<byline>Alver Carlson</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Monetary Fund said on Friday it was assessing what more it could do to help an employee convicted of corruption and given a reduced sentence of five years in jail by a Chinese court.</p>
<p>The Fund said while no decision had yet been taken, it could ask the court to grant an early release to Hong Yang, a Chinese national arrested while on an IMF mission to Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;Management is assessing the situation in consultation with its lawyers and with Mr. Hong's family and will decide very soon on what further actions could be taken,&quot; an IMF spokesman said. These &quot;could include a petition for early release,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In a rare move, a Chinese appeals court on Friday halved the 44-year-old Hong's original prison sentence to five years after he was convicted of accepting bribes totaling $12,000 in 1993, before he joined the IMF, the Xinhua news agency said.</p>
<p>&quot;The sentence was dealt with leniently ... and according to law,&quot; Xinhua quoted the court as saying.</p>
<p>The court's decision followed a brief suspension of technical assistance to China by the IMF and a hurried Beijing visit by IMF Managing Director Michel Camdessus to voice concern over what he described as judicial shortcomings in the case.</p>
<p>The detention in December of Hong, a former employee of the People's Bank of China, the country's central bank, stunned and angered IMF employees, some of whom complained bitterly that the lending agency did little to protect its people while they were away from home.</p>
<p>IMF management was also distressed, since it had yielded to Chinese insistence that Hong, a staff member in Washington, be included in the mission to China.</p>
<p>Camdessus, in a July statement, said Chinese authorities had maintained they did not know about the charge against Hong when they requested he join the mission staff.</p>
<p>Hong was found guilty on June 28. Beijing sources said the original sentence was for 10 years, although statements by the IMF put it at 11 years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
