<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11441" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME pork bellies end up after wild late trade.</title>
<headline>CME pork bellies end up after wild late trade.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME pork belly futures went into a sharply swinging price range late before ending higher.</p>
<p>August pork bellies came off its limit gain of 2.000 cents and plunged for a net loss of 1.850 cents before rallying again by the close to finish 1.150 higher at 92.525 cents. The wild price moves in August influenced back months and February also fell for a net loss before closing 1.075 higher at 85.225 cents. Other contracts ended up 1.050 to off 0.025 cent.</p>
<p>Light selling by Merrill Lynch in August met little standing buy orders despite being locked up the daily limit much of the day. This sparked a late selloff, traders said.</p>
<p>However, prices ran back up at shortly before the close as fundamental strength from tight storage stocks continued to support the market. August showed strength as shorts realized there will be no more bellies put into storage that can be delivered, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no way you can take bellies now out of fresh production and get them cerfified in time to deliver against the futures,&quot; said Chuck Levitt, senior livestock analyst for Alaron Trading Corp.</p>
<p>Technicals and the Cold Storage report due to be released after the close influenced back months early.  </p>
<p>Estimates on the Cold Storage report ranged from 35.1 to 38.7 million lbs of frozen bellies in U.S. warehouses as of August 1 versus 47.1 on hand a year ago.</p>
<p>Hog futures finished mixed with nearbys strong on expectations of steady to firmer cash markets Monday. Packer demand has improved for hogs, especially to meet increased kill plans over the weekend. Cash pork products may also firm as there is some speculation that the normal October pork promotions will start early, traders said.</p>
<p>However, lean contracts finished mixed in mostly light dealings, they added.</p>
<p>In hog options, there was scattered put buying in February early. R.J. O'Brien bought October 54 puts and ADM Investor Services bought December 50 puts, pit sources added.</p>
<p>August showed a fairly wide price range before expiring at noon at 60.400 cents, up 0.025 for the day. Other months finished 0.675 cent higher to 0.175 lower with October up most at 54.375 cents.</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
