<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11449" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE world sugar ends unchanged, still rangebound.</title>
<headline>CSCE world sugar ends unchanged, still rangebound.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE world sugar futures closed barely budged from opening levels, as producer selling and trade buying framed the day's activity.</p>
<p>After trading slightly lower for most of the session, the October contract slipped over unchanged on light trade buying in the afternoon, but promptly fell back.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was limited on the upside because producers lowered their pricing ideas from recent days...but there was no followthrough selling which kept the market limited on the downside,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>Activity was extremely light amid a dearth of news and a seasonal lull. Anticipation of Monday's holiday in London contributed to the market's dull tone.</p>
<p>One dealer cited fund buy stops around 11.89, and scale-down trade buying beginning at 11.77 in October.</p>
<p>The benchmark October contract settled unchanged at 11.85, having ranged from 11.87 to 11.79. March ended 0.01 higher at 11.46, while the back months finished flat to 0.06 higher.</p>
<p>London white sugar futures ended slightly firmer. October settled 70 cents higher to $352.40 while December closed unchanged at $345.90.</p>
<p>-- Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities, 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
