<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11442" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME live cattle close easier ahead of report.</title>
<headline>CME live cattle close easier ahead of report.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME live cattle futures closed mostly lower on evening up ahead of the Cattle-on-Feed report, traders said.</p>
<p>Profit taking following recent sharp advances weighed on the market despite expectations of a bullish report. Much of the report was already in the market, they said.</p>
<p>Estimates for on-feed supplies in the seven-state feedlot areas averaged 86.2 percent in a range of 84 to 88 percent. July placement estimates averaged 110.5 percent in a range of 100 to 116 percent and July marketings averaged 102.4 percent in a range of 100.5 to 106 percent.</p>
<p>August expired earlier and fell at its close as last minute long liquidation met little buying interest. Cash markets remain strong but some longs needed to exit the market and this was offsetting ideas for tight feedlot supplies and higher cash markets the next couple of weeks. December showed weakness on expectations that feedlot supplies will start to rise by then, they added.</p>
<p>Live cattle closed 0.300 cent lower to 0.025 higher with October off 0.175 at 71.000 cents. August expired at 69.125 cents, down 0.650 cents on the day.  </p>
<p>In live cattle options, trading was also slow ahead of the report. There was some out-of-the-money call selling in October early, pit sources said.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle turned mixed as evening up developed ahead of the report, but prices finished mostly higher. Futures showed early support following the decline in corn futures but slipped when live cattle moved lower and buying interest subsided, traders said.</p>
<p>Lind-Waldock and E.D.&amp;F. Man bought October early while ADM Investor Services, R.J. O'Brien and LIT division of First Options sold, pit sources said.</p>
<p>The latest CME feeder cattle index was up $0.14 at $63.09 per cwt.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle closed 0.225 lower to 0.175 higher with October unchanged at 63.375 cents.</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
