<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11463" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dolly makes landfall, Edouard nearly a hurricane.</title>
<headline>Dolly makes landfall, Edouard nearly a hurricane.</headline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hurricane Dolly made landfall in Mexico on Friday with 75 mph (120 kph) winds but was expected to weaken as it moved inland, forecasters at the National Hurricane Centre said.</p>
<p>Tropical Storm Edouard, moving through the Atlantic Ocean, strengthened but remained far from land and was a threat only to shipping interests.</p>
<p>At 11 a.m. EDT (1500 GMT), the centre of Dolly was located at latitude 21.9 north, longitude 98.1 west, just south of Tampico, Mexico, and was moving west-northwest at 13 mph (21 kph).</p>
<p>A hurricane warning was in effect from Veracruz north to La Pesca.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect it to move into the mountains and weaken, but it poses a threat of torrential rains and flash floods,&quot; Mike Hopkins, a meteorologist at the National Hurricane Centre, said.</p>
<p>The storm was expected to dump six to 12 inches (15-30 cm) of rain on parts of Mexico.</p>
<p>Tropical Storm Edouard strengthened, and forecasters said it could become a hurricane later on Friday.</p>
<p>At 11 a.m. EDT (1500 GMT), the centre of Edouard was located at latitude 13.9 north, longitude 39.1 west, about 1,500 miles (2,400 km) east of the Lesser Antilles and moving west at 15 mph (24 kph).</p>
<p>Maximum sustained winds had climbed to 70 mph (112 kph), just 5 mph (8 kph) below hurricane strength.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
