<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11462" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FORECAST -- Aug payrolls seen spelling Fed rate hike.</title>
<headline>FORECAST -- Aug payrolls seen spelling Fed rate hike.</headline>
<byline>Scott Gerlach</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A sharp increase in non-farm payrolls in the August U.S. employment report should show continued economic strength and increase fears of an interest rate hike, according to economists in a Reuters poll.</p>
<p>On average, the 21 experts surveyed Friday forecast 238,000 new jobs were created this month, a figure that would show further pressure on the labor market on the heels of the 193,000 jobs created in July.  </p>
<p>&quot;Anything over 200,000 is going to tighten the labor market (and) would show further upward pressure on wage inflation,&quot; said Donald Maude, chief U.S. economist at Scotia Capital Markets Inc.</p>
<p>In addition to boosted payrolls, economists projected the unemployment rate slipped back to 5.3 percent from 5.4 percent in July and average hourly earnings grew 0.3 percent after a 0.2 percent decline in July.</p>
<p>The survey marked a preliminary look at August payrolls ahead of the data's release by the Labor Department on September 6, two weeks from  Friday.  </p>
<p>Over the past month, lower-than-expected initial jobless claims coupled with rises in retail sales and durable goods has shown demand for labor remains high, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a strong underlying trend, and we had the (jobless) claims data that haven't rebounded since coming down in July,&quot; explained Craig Prochaska, an economist at First Chicago Capital Markets Inc.</p>
<p>If the experts are right, the August employment report, set for release Friday September 6, will show the rapid economic growth of the second quarter has not slowed as the third quarter progresses.  </p>
<p>&quot;It shows an exceptionally strong labor market,&quot; said Maude. &quot;No stronger than the second quarter, but the second quarter was exceedingly strong.&quot;</p>
<p>The expected pickup in payrolls, hourly earnings and the workweek would intensify wage inflation anxiety. Consequently, the financial markets would begin pricing in an interest rate hike, Maude said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the markets would discount an entire 25 basis points, but they'll start moving in that direction&quot; as investors' inflation expectations rise, he said.  </p>
<p>A Reuters survey on Tuesday showed a majority of economists expect the Federal Reserve to tighten monetary policy at the November 13 Federal Open Market Committee meeting.</p>
<p>Responses to the payrolls survey ranged from a low of 150,000 to a high of 350,000. Economists calling for a payrolls increase of 200,000 or less generally said such a figure would not worry the central bank.</p>
<p>&quot;A number like ours would keep the Fed on hold,&quot; said Cheryl Katz, senior economist at Merrill Lynch Government Securities Inc, who projected 200,000 new jobs.</p>
<p>Respondents stressed their forecasts are preliminary and could change in the next two weks, particularly in response to weekly jobless claims and the National Association of Purchasing Management's August survey.  </p>
<p>Participating     Non-Farm   Unemployment    Average   Hourly</p>
<p>Firm		  Payrolls	Rate	  Workweek  Earnings</p>
<p>     AVERAGES:    +238,000     5.3 pct	 34.5 hrs  +0.3 pct</p>
<p>Bank of Tokyo-    +230,000     5.3 pct	   NA	  NA</p>
<p> Mitsubishi</p>
<p>BT Securities     +225,000     5.4 pct	 34.5 hrs  +0.3 pct</p>
<p>BZW Gov Sec'ties  +275,000     5.4 pct	   NA	  NA</p>
<p>CS First Boston   +220,000     5.4 pct	 34.4 hrs  +0.2 pct</p>
<p>Daiwa		 +270,000     5.3 pct	   NA	  NA</p>
<p>Dean Witter	 +225,000     5.3 pct	   NA	  NA</p>
<p>Deutsche MG	 +150,000     5.4 pct	 34.4 hrs  +0.3 pct</p>
<p>DKB Securities    +225,000     5.4 pct	   NA	  NA</p>
<p>DLJ Securities    +200,000	 NA		NA	  NA</p>
<p>First Chicago     +270,000     5.3 pct	 34.6 hrs  +0.4 pct</p>
<p>I.D.E.A. Inc	+350,000     5.1 pct	 34.5 hrs  +0.3 pct</p>
<p>Lanston, Aubrey   +225,000	 NA		NA	  NA</p>
<p>Lehman Gov Sec    +325,000     5.2 pct	 34.3 hrs  +0.3 pct</p>
<p>MCM MoneyWatch    +225,000     5.3 pct	 34.4 hrs  +0.2 pct</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch     +200,000     5.4 pct	  NA	   NA</p>
<p>MMS Int'l	   +185,000     5.3 pct	 34.4 hrs  +0.2 pct</p>
<p>JP Morgan	   +225,000     5.3 pct	 34.4 hrs  +0.4 pct</p>
<p>Nomura		+240,000     5.4 pct	  NA	   NA</p>
<p>Painewebber	 +200,000	 NA	     NA	   NA</p>
<p>Sanwa Securities  +270,000     5.4 pct	  NA	   NA</p>
<p>Scotia Cap Mkts   +275,000     5.3 pct	 34.6 hrs  +0.3 pct</p>
<p>  -- 212-859-1868 (c) Reuters Limited 1996</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
