<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11460" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: One teen left dead by attack on U.S. slumber party.</title>
<headline>One teen left dead by attack on U.S. slumber party.</headline>
<dateline>CHESAPEAKE, Va. 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A knife-wielding neighbour apparently intent on sexual assault invaded a teenage slumber party on Friday, killing one girl and wounding three others, police said.</p>
<p>At about 4 a.m. EDT (0800 GMT), a group of teenaged girls were having the overnight party in the Camelot subdivision of this eastern Virginia city, when a man entered the house, wielding a knife, threatening to sexually assault the girls.</p>
<p>Detective Richard Black of the Chesapeake Police Department, said a neighbour, Curtis Lee White II, 19, was arrested in the attack, but had not been charged by late morning on Friday.</p>
<p>There were apparently no adults at the party as the father of the family who lived in the house was out of town and the mother died more than a year ago, Black said.</p>
<p>The detective said details were sketchy, but two of the teenagers were reportedly downstairs watching television when White allegedly entered the house and told the girls to take off their clothes.</p>
<p>He said a male teenager sleeping upstairs reportedly heard the commotion and came downstairs and confronted White, who allegedly stabbed him more than once.</p>
<p>The other teenagers also confronted the assailant and three girls, all under 18,  were stabbed, one fatally.</p>
<p>&quot;At least two of them were sexually molested,&quot; Black said. He said all of the wounded teenagers were taken to a hospital but none of the injuries were considered life-threatening.</p>
<p>Police said the girl who died was identified as Michelle Harper. Her age was not given.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHESAPEAKE, Va."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
