<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11472" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: High-yld telecom debt mounts, buyers make demands.</title>
<headline>High-yld telecom debt mounts, buyers make demands.</headline>
<byline>Al Yoon</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>It's a buyer's market for high-yielding telecommunication debt.</p>
<p>Burgeoning supply of telecommunication debt over the past few years has resulted in a simple over-supply, analysts said, especially in the zero coupon structure the industry favors. Buyers are poised with an undeniable upper hand, they said, demanding new structures and higher rates -- at times beyond the reach of more speculative projects.  </p>
<p>Total outstanding debt in the sector has exploded to $18 billion currently from $2 billion in 1993, spurred by massive changes on the regulatory front, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;All of a sudden you've got very substantial exposure to a sector that you had no exposure to before,&quot;  said Robert Waldman, head of corporate bond research at Salomon Brothers. He that the sector is &quot;dominated by these zero coupon bonds that have more volatile characteristics ... making the investors much more choosy.&quot;</p>
<p>Zero coupons make up almost $8 billion of this year's close to $12 billion in telecom debt issues Waldman said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Accounts are more discerning credit-wise; they're looking for higher returns on more speculative issues and they have tended to shy away from zero coupon paper,&quot; said Les Levi, high-yield media and telecom analyst at Merrill Lynch &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Buyers of zero couponed telecom issues have watched the value of their investment drop as the issues trade poorly in the aftermarket, their yields backing up significantly, Levi said.</p>
<p>&quot;Buyers have said they want issues priced cheaply enough so it's not going to back up, and you've had some dramatically cheap pricings,&quot; Levi said.  </p>
<p>Sprint Spectrum -- a company with billions in equity and backed by parents Sprint Corp, TCI Communications, Comcast Corp and Cox Communications -- offered a 12.5 percent yield on zero coupon discount notes in a $523 million two-tranche deal. Only one similarly-rated company, Intercel Inc, offered bonds at a wider spread this year, noted John Lonski, senior economist at Moody's Investors Service.</p>
<p>The Sprint Spectrum deal was also a workout situation for managers, traders noted.  </p>
<p>The zero coupon tranche, downsized to $273 million from $500 million, was done only after parent Sprint Corp put in for $100 million and managers upped the call price to 110, traders said.</p>
<p>Investors also demanded and won higher yields than suggested in early price talk.</p>
<p>The deal bucked a down market on Wednesday and traded up when freed, signifying investor satisfaction, sources said.</p>
<p>Indigestion in the sector has already forced several issuers to reassess market access or retreat altogether.  </p>
<p>In the past month, large issues from PCS Development, WinStar Communications and Advanced Radio Telecom have been pulled, while issues from Orbcomm and Ionica Plc were substantially downsized and converted from zeros to cash pay deals.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, prospects for profit in a newly accessible $100 billion cable, wireless and local telephone market have kept investors interested, analysts said. In fact, some managers are more keen to capitalize on the current state of the market.  </p>
<p>&quot;As a longer-term buyer, I generally view these market conditions as an opportunity,&quot; said Christopher Molumphy, senior portfolio manager of the $2.3 billion Franklin Age High-Income Fund.</p>
<p>&quot;Because the buyer has more leverage with regard to this sector at this point in time,&quot; he said, &quot;you can extract a much more favorable price on these securities.&quot;</p>
<p>Molumphy noted the concentration of zero coupons in funds is higher than it has been historically. Therein lies an opportunity for the longer-term investor, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We would prefer to buy a 'out of favor' structured security of a high-quality company than a cash-pay security of a lesser quality company,&quot; he said. &quot;In the short term, these securities may continue to underperform but in the long-term that's how you make money.&quot;</p>
<p>Indeed, Levi noted early start-ups have begun to pay off. Nextel Communications, for instance, is attractive with more than one million subscribers and a recently secured $1.55 billion bank credit facility agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;The reality is the (indigestion) is temporary,&quot; Levi said. &quot;Remember, all these start-ups are going to start showing results. At the same time the revenue pool for these things is growing.&quot;</p>
<p>Near-term, Waldman said the market may react negatively to telecom issuance, possibly prompting more postponements.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will be extremely picky, particularly on these wireless companies that are absolute start-ups where no one is certain of demand at this point,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--212-859-1672</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
