<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11471" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT levies fine, reprimands in March wheat expiry.</title>
<headline>CBOT levies fine, reprimands in March wheat expiry.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chicago Board of Trade said it fined  Louis Dreyfus Corp and its CBOT clearing member Term Commodities Inc $10,000 and issued reprimands to member firm  Produce Grain Inc and five traders after a probe into trading at expiration of the March 1996 wheat contract.</p>
<p>On March 20, the CBOT March wheat contract soared more than $2.00 in the final minutes before expiration to a record $7.50 per bushel as Produce, a unit of  Bunge Corp, scrambled to cover an exposed short position, pit sources have said.</p>
<p>The contract expired at 12:01 CDT but trades registered at $7.00 and $7.50 at 12:02 pm, CBOT ticker records showed.  </p>
<p>In a notice to members, the CBOT cited several exchange rules on after-market trading as the basis for its actions.</p>
<p>Dreyfus and Term agreed to the fine for originating and executing a new order from off the floor after the close, the CBOT said. A Louis Dreyfus spokesman declined comment.</p>
<p>Produce Grain was reprimanded for authorizing an order after the close. CBOT said Produce did not admit or deny a rules violation. A Bunge Corp spokesman declined comment.</p>
<p>On March 22, Bunge Corp officials had issued a statement confirming that the company was involved in the March wheat expiry and sustained a trading loss of about $300,000.</p>
<p>The CBOT also issued reprimands for after-market trading to individual traders John C. Bedore, George F. Frey, Jay P. Ieronimo, Brian J. Schaer, and Donald W. Scheck.</p>
<p>The exchange said the parties accepted the reprimands without admitting or denying any rules violations. The traders were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>The volatile expiry of the March wheat contract also drew the attention of Congress and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission to issues concerning the wheat futures market's stability and regulatory oversight.</p>
<p>(Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
