<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11475" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. aluminum shipments tumble in first half.</title>
<headline>U.S. aluminum shipments tumble in first half.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Net shipments of aluminum mill products in the United States tumbled 10.5 percent in the first half of the year as orders also weakend slightly, the Aluminum Association reported in its latest Aluminum Situation.</p>
<p>Preliminary figures for the first half of 1996 indicated that industry net shipments of aluminum mill products totaled 7.585 billion pounds (3,440,502 million tonnes), compared to 8.473 billion in the same period last year.</p>
<p>Domestic shipments of ingot and mill products totaled 8.717 billion pounds in the first half, off by 9.7 percent.  </p>
<p>The biggest fall in domestic shipments was for sheet, plate and foil, down 12.1 percent.</p>
<p>U.S. exports of aluminum ingot and mill products totaled 1.467 billion pounds in the first half, just 0.5 percent below last year's figure.</p>
<p>Imports, however, slumped by 16.5 percent to 2.9 billion pounds over the same period.</p>
<p>Estimated industry net new orders totaled 8.460 billion pounds in January through July, 2.9 percent down from the comparable period last year.</p>
<p>July orders of 1.060 billion pounds were down 4.9 percent on June. New orders on domestic can stock fell 18.1 percent in July compared to a dip of 15.5 percent for the first seven months as a whole.</p>
<p>U.S producer inventories rose 30 million pounds in June to 4.356 billion from May's revised 4.326 billion pound total.</p>
<p>Aluminum scrap consumption rose to 674 million pounds in June compared to 666 million pounds in the same month last year.</p>
<p>Scrap consumption rose 4.2 percent to 4.175 billion pounds in the first half of the year, the Aluminum Association said.</p>
<p>-- New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
