<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11482" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French police seize African protesters in church.</title>
<headline>French police seize African protesters in church.</headline>
<byline>Francois Raitberger</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Riot police stormed a Paris church on Friday and seized 220 African migrants, including 10 on a 50-day-old hunger strike, to crush their protest against expulsion orders.</p>
<p>The raid by police using batons and tear-gas on Saint-Bernard church in the heavily immigrant Goutte d'Or district sparked protests against the centre-right government, including a rally of at least 6,000 people in Paris.</p>
<p>One opposition union said the government was preparing to fly an initial group of the Africans home early on Saturday.</p>
<p>Most of the migrants are from Mali, Senegal and Zaire.</p>
<p>The Saint-Bernard church bells sounded the alarm early on Friday as hundreds of helmeted police moved in, struggling with sympathisers who had surrounded the church in recent days to back the Africans' demand for residence papers.</p>
<p>Police broke down the church's main gate and burst through a makeshift barricade of chairs and pews to remove the hunger strikers on stretchers and bundle the others, including about 70 terrified children, into vans.</p>
<p>Police said about 50 of the 300 African protesters originally holed up in the church had slipped away before the raid. A total of about 1,500 police took part in the operation, sealing off roads in the area.</p>
<p>The 10 hunger strikers, carried out on stretchers, were taken to hospital and the other protesters were detained.</p>
<p>Conservative Prime Minister Alain Juppe said on Thursday that none of the Africans was legally entitled to stay but he would review each case on humanitarian grounds. His right-wing allies applauded a show of firmness against illegal immigration.</p>
<p>On Friday night, demonstrators including leftist politicians, union leaders, human rights activists and film stars marched in Paris to urge the government to grant the protesters residence permits and soften 1993 immigration laws.</p>
<p>&quot;We're all children of immigrants,&quot; they chanted. Some wore stickers saying: &quot;I'm ashamed of being French&quot;. One man burned the red, white and blue French flag. Police said 6,000 attended, organisers estimated more than 10,000.</p>
<p>The march was headed by Socialist and Communist opposition politicians and celebrities including actresses Emmanuelle Beart and Marina Vlady, dissident French bishop Jacques Gaillot and human rights activist and cancer specialist Leon Schwartzenberg.</p>
<p>Beart, co-star of the U.S. summer blockbuster &quot;Mission Impossible&quot;, was at the church during the raid and accused police of profanation. Marches were organised in other cities, including Lyon, Toulouse and Rouen.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre said 30 to 40 percent of the protesters qualified for residence permits. Some were still under review, but others would be expelled.</p>
<p>The Defence Ministry declined comment on reports by the Socialist CFDT union that a military plane would deport a first group of Africans from an airbase at Creil north of Paris on Saturday at 6 a.m. (0400 GMT).</p>
<p>French TF1 television said none of the fasters needed hospital treatment. The hunger strikers had said they were surviving on sugared tea and vitamins for 50 days.</p>
<p>Debre said there were no injuries and &quot;no serious incident&quot; in the storming. Police said 40 people were being held and six could be prosecuted for assaulting police.</p>
<p>Opposition Socialist Party leader Lionel Jospin condemned the raid and said the 1993 tightening of immigration laws was injust because it made outlaws of many foreigners until then legally in France.</p>
<p>&quot;The style of this government is to smash things,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFRICA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
