<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11484" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Police end African protest by raiding church.</title>
<headline>Police end African protest by raiding church.</headline>
<byline>Francois Raitberger</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police using batons and teargas stormed a Paris church on Friday and seized 300 African migrants including 10 on a 50-day-old hunger strike, crushing their protest against expulsion orders.</p>
<p>The Saint-Bernard church bells sounded the alarm as hundreds of helmeted police moved in, struggling with sympathisers who had surrounded the church in recent days to back the Africans' demand for residence papers.</p>
<p>Police broke down the church's main gate and burst through a makeshift barricade of chairs and pews to remove the hunger strikers on stretchers and bundle the others, including some 100 terrified children, into vans.</p>
<p>A total of about 1,500 police took part in the operation, sealing off roads in the heavily immigrant Goutte d'Or district.</p>
<p>The raid was greeted with an outcry on the Left and plaudits on the Right. Prime Minister Alain Juppe said on Thursday none of the Africans was legally entitled to stay but he would review their cases individually on humanitarian grounds.</p>
<p>On Friday evening several thousand people, from opposition politicians to film stars who have long backed the Africans, marched through central Paris to urge the government to grant the protesters' demands for residence permits.</p>
<p>&quot;We're all children of immigrants,&quot; they chanted. Some wore stickers saying: &quot;I'm ashamed of being French&quot;. One man burned the red, white and blue French flag.</p>
<p>The march was headed by celebrities including actresses Emmanuelle Beart and Marina Vlady, dissident French bishop Jacques Gaillot and human rights activist and cancer specialist Leon Schwartzenberg.</p>
<p>Beart, co-star of the U.S. summer blockbuster &quot;Mission Impossible&quot;, was at the church during the raid and accused police of profanation. Other marches were organised in cities including Lyon, Toulouse, Rouen and Narbonne.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre said 30 to 40 percent of the protesters qualified for residence permits. Some were still under review, but others would be expelled.</p>
<p>The Defence Ministry declined to comment on reports that the military was preparing police to fly a first batch of protesters home on Saturday -- most are from Mali, Senegal and Zaire.</p>
<p>The hunger strikers were rushed to hospital and the other protesters were detained. The immigrant support group GISTI said two of the fasters refused treatment and had joined the other protesters in detention at Vincennes outside Paris.</p>
<p>Debre said there were no injuries and &quot;no serious incident&quot; in the storming.</p>
<p>Police said 40 people were being held and six could be prosecuted for assaulting police. Police said about 50 of the Africans slipped away from the church, eluding arrest as police closed in.</p>
<p>Opposition Socialist Party leader Lionel Jospin and Communist Party boss Robert Hue were among those who strongly condemned the government for the raid. Juppe's conservative Rally for the Republic (RPR) party praised his &quot;courage&quot;.</p>
<p>The fasters, who like the other protesters had been in the church since June 28, had been drinking sweet tea and taking vitamin pills, but two were said to be in a serious condition.</p>
<p>Juppe had said France's highest administrative court, the Council of State, endorsed his view that the 300 Africans were not legally entitled to stay. But he pledged that families would not be broken up and ill individuals would not be expelled.</p>
<p>Many of the protesters say they once had residence rights and were plunged into illegality by hardline 1993 immigration laws. Lawyers say loopholes in the laws, which also tightened conditions for citizenship, have created a legal nightmare.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFRICA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
