<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11485" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian police dig into night in child sex case.</title>
<headline>Belgian police dig into night in child sex case.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police using dogs trained to find bodies dug until the early hours of Friday at the house in southern Belgium where two young victims of a paedophile gang were found dead at the weekend, Belgian radio said.</p>
<p>&quot;The excavations at Sars-La-Buisierre continued until three o'clock in the morning (0100 GMT)...apparently without success,&quot; the radio said.</p>
<p>It said Superintendent John Bennett, the British police officer who oversaw the excavations at the homes of Fred and Rosemary West in Britain's &quot;House of Horrors&quot; murders, was present at the new digging. He refused to comment.</p>
<p>The dogs were let loose in various parts of the property, owned by convicted child rapist Marc Dutroux. All the dogs rapidly converged on one area where digging immediately started.</p>
<p>Police did not use any of the sophisticated radar imaging equipment used by the British in the West case, and loaned to the Belgians.</p>
<p>The radio said investigators would meet again later on Friday, and that digging was likely to resume.</p>
<p>Belgium went into mourning on Thursday as eight-year-olds Julie Lejeune and Melissa Russo were buried after a highly emotional public service in the eastern city of Liege.</p>
<p>Dutroux led police to the bodies at the weekend. He said the girls had starved to death early this year, some nine months after being abducted in June 1995.</p>
<p>Police had earlier rescued two girls from another house owned by Dutroux in the southern city of Charleroi and have stepped up the search for two others -- An Marchal and Eefje Lambrecks -- who Dutroux admits kidnapping last August.</p>
<p>The search for the girls has spread to other countries, notably the Czech Republic and Slovakia which Dutroux visited frequently.</p>
<p>Dutroux and associate Michel Lelievre have been charged with abduction and illegal imprisonment of children. Dutroux' second wife Michelle Martin has been charged as an accomplice and Jean-Michel Nihoul with criminal association.</p>
<p>Police arrested a fifth person, Michael Diakostavrianos, on Thursday. He is due to appear before magistrates on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Dutroux, an unemployed father of three, owns at least six houses. Underground cells and dungeons to hold kidnapped children have been found in some of them.</p>
<p>In total police have searched 11 houses, removing quantities of video tapes and magazines as well as childrens' clothing and a gun.</p>
<p>Le Soir newspaper said on Thursday that some of the seized tapes showed Dutroux sexually abusing children.</p>
<p>At least 15 children have vanished in Belgium in the past six years. Seven have been found dead, six are still missing and two have been rescued.</p>
<p>The deaths of Julie and Melissa have triggered calls for the reeinstatement of the death penalty or at least no early release for convicted child sex offenders.</p>
<p>Dutroux was released 10 years early in 1992 for good behaviour from a 13-year sentence for multiple child rape.</p>
<p>There has also been a national outcry over revelations of bungling by police during their 14-month search for Julie and Melissa, with police in one region failing to pass on information about Dutroux' activities to investigators in another searching for the two girls.</p>
<p>Justice Minister Stefaan de Clerck has admitted mistakes were made and has promised a full inquiry including the possibility of disciplinary actions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
