<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11489" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Albright to visit Central and Latin American states.</title>
<headline>Albright to visit Central and Latin American states.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Madeleine Albright, the U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, intends to travel to Uruguay, Chile, Bolivia, Honduras and Guatemala next week to discuss reforms Washington wants the world body to adopt in the coming year, her spokesman said.</p>
<p>Both Chile and Honduras are members of the 15-member Security Council and diplomats expect Albright to hammer home Washington's opposition to a second term for Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali.</p>
<p>Chile's ambassador, Juan Somavia, is particularly influential among developing countries in the United Nations since he initiated and organised a poverty summit in Copenhagen in late 1994.</p>
<p>Honduras will be president of the Security Council in October, when most of the arrangements for electing a secretary-general have to be made. Boutros-Ghali assumed office in 1992 for a five-year term.</p>
<p>Albright has accused the Egyptian diplomat of not initiating enough reforms to cut down the U.N. bureaucracy. Many U.N. members dispute this, saying the Clinton administration's stand is a reaction to Republican criticism of the United Nations.</p>
<p>Washington owes more than half of the $1.9 billion U.N. debt for regular dues and peacekeeping, which has nearly bankrupted the United Nations.</p>
<p>Albright will be in Uruguay August 28-30 to meet government officials and observe a peacekeeping exercise involving troops from Argentina, Brazil, Paraguay, Uruguay and the United States, spokesman Walter Douglas said in a statement.</p>
<p>She goes to Santiago on August 30 to meet Chilean government officials and then to Cochabamba, Bolivia, to attend a September 3 and 4 meeting of several heads of state belonging to the Rio Group.</p>
<p>Albright arrives in Honduras on September 5 to consult on Security Council issues with President Carlos Roberto Reina. She completes her trip on September 7 in Guatemala City where she will meet government officials and U.N. human rights envoys who have facilitated talks to end decades of civil war.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="URU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
