<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11490" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Former Iran leader says Tehran has slain 60 foes.</title>
<headline>Former Iran leader says Tehran has slain 60 foes.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Iranian president Abolhassan Banisadr said on Friday at least 60 dissidents had been killed on the orders of the Iranian government in the last 15 years and warned there would be more bloodshed.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters at a secret location in Berlin on Friday evening, Banisadr said the Tehran government would continue to liquidate political opponents inside and outside the country until Western states began to act with greater resolve.</p>
<p>&quot;There were at least 60 people murdered by the regime since the coup against me,&quot; said Banisadr, speaking in French and seated in a small two-room apartment crowded with more than a dozen heavily armed security guards.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, there will be more (assassinations) if the Western states do not act with resolve and with greater transparency against the regime,&quot; said the former president, who has lived in exile in Paris since his ouster in 1981.</p>
<p>He criticised the United States' approach to dealing with Iran, saying economic sanctions and military threats were counterproductive. But he also condemned the European stance &quot;because everything is done too secretly&quot;.</p>
<p>Banisadr, 63, had just finished giving testimony for two days in a German court where five men are on trial for murdering four Iranian dissidents in a gangland-style shooting at a Berlin restaurant in 1992.</p>
<p>Saying he was satisfied with the German court's handling of the case and the questions he answered over the last two days, Banisadr appeared relaxed.</p>
<p>He told the court he had information from three independent sources that the 1992 execution of three Iranian Kurd leaders and their translator at the &quot;Mykonos&quot; restaurant was ordered by Iran's religous leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei.</p>
<p>He said the execution was also approved by Iranian President Akbar Hashemi and Intelligence Minister Ali Fallahiyan.</p>
<p>But in Tehran, Iran's top judge urged Germany to refuse to admit Banisadr's testimony, to guard its judicial reputation and avoid politicising the trial.</p>
<p>&quot;What is the judicial validity of a ruling that would be based, even for a few hundredths of percent, on the testimony of a deposed person who has fled this country?&quot; Ayatollah Mohammad Yazdi asked in a mass prayer sermon.</p>
<p>German justice authorities issued an arrest warrant against Fallahiyan in March and federal prosecutor Bruno Jost said after hearing Banisadr's testimony he would also examine the possibility of filing charges against Khamenei and Rafsanjani.</p>
<p>&quot;Khamenei and Rafsanjani are the ones responsible for the murders,&quot; Banisadr said.</p>
<p>The short, soft-spoken Banisadr said he was eager to come to Berlin to testify because he is worried Germany has struck a deal with Iran to free the defendants ahead of time if they are convicted, an allegation that Bonn immediately rejected.</p>
<p>&quot;I have proof of this,&quot; Banisadr said. &quot;I have to ask if (German Foreign Minister Klaus) Kinkel is the attorney for Rafsanjani.&quot;</p>
<p>Although mostly upbeat during the 45-minute interview, Banisadr's trademark grin disappeared when recounting how he had delivered an advance warning to the murdered Iranian Kurd leaders in Germany about the threat of an attack.</p>
<p>&quot;They were informed about the danger, but they did not take it seriously enough,&quot; he said. &quot;They did not take any security precautions.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
