<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11506" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU, Germany fail to resolve VW aid dispute.</title>
<headline>EU, Germany fail to resolve VW aid dispute.</headline>
<byline>Fredrik Dahl</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission and Germany failed on Friday to defuse a politically sensitive row over subsidies granted in the ex-communist east to car giant Volkswagen as both sides threatened to take legal action.</p>
<p>European Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert and German Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt met in Brussels but could agree only to continue their efforts to find a solution.</p>
<p>The row has worried Bonn by arousing anti-European Union sentiment in the bloc's largest member state.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think you can say we were able to overcome the problems today,&quot; Van Miert told a news conference.</p>
<p>Van Miert and Rexrodt, who just returned to work after 10-weeks off due to malaria, were obviously wide apart on the issue of aid for Volkswagen to develop plants in the state of Saxony, which struggles with a jobless rate of more than 15 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as the specific case of Volkswagen is concerned our views differ from those of the Commission,&quot; Rexrodt said.</p>
<p>Reflecting the controversial nature of the issue, he said there was a strong possibility that Bonn would decide to challenge the Commission in the European Court of Justice.</p>
<p>Van Miert, who says Saxony has paid illegal aid to Volkswagen, also reiterated his threat to take the case to the Luxembourg-based court to stop the money from being used.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we can't say we have made enough progress -- an illegal situation still exists in our view,&quot; Van Miert said.</p>
<p>The Commission is due to discuss the case on September 4.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Bonn and the Commission would continue their talks to try and reach &quot;a pragmatic settlement&quot;, Rexrodt said. &quot;This is the begining of a discussion process that I hope will lead to an end which both sides can be happy with.&quot;</p>
<p>The row erupted last month when Saxony state premier Kurt Biedenkopf overrode Commission objections to the size of the aid package size and paid out extra funds.</p>
<p>Biedenkopf, a Christian Democrat (CDU) ally of Chancellor Helmut Kohl, warned that the state stood to lose thousands of jobs in the towns of Mosel and Chemnitz if it did not pay.</p>
<p>VW had suspended plans to develop plants in the two towns after the Commission rejected 241 million marks ($161.7 million) of a total promised aid package of some 780 million.</p>
<p>The company has threatened to relocate its investment to a lower-cost country if the subsidies are not granted in full.</p>
<p>Van Miert reacted furiously to Saxony's defiant move, saying that the decision to pay 91 million marks in unauthorised support to VW could touch off an EU &quot;subsidy war&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;If there were no discipline it would undermine our whole aid policy which would lead to total anarchy,&quot; he said. &quot;The German government has been asking for carte blanche, which is not acceptable.&quot;</p>
<p>According to Brussels, Saxony paid out 142 million marks to VW after the Commission's June decision. Of this amount, it says 91 million was unauthorised. In total, Volkswagen has received at least 522 million marks from Saxony.</p>
<p>Van Miert accepted that former east Germany would need significant aid for some time but said that if it were awarded illegally it would be a major risk to the EU's internal market.</p>
<p>Almost six years after unification, eastern Germany still relies on annual net transfers of about 140 billion marks.</p>
<p>Rexrodt, however, said the area's situation could not be compared with the rest of the EU.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't want anarchy either, we don't want each state to do what it likes, but we must insist that we are in a very special situation,&quot; Rexrodt said.</p>
<p>The VW case was special, he said, and that was why Germany believed that special EU rules allowing aid to areas affected by the division of Germany should be applied.</p>
<p>He was referring to article 92 paragraph 2C of the EC treaty which says that aid &quot;granted to the economy of certain areas of the Federal Republic of Germany affected by the division in Germany, in so far as such aid is required in order to compensate for the economic disadvantages caused by that division&quot; is permissible.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
