<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11509" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Guatemalan sides to sign truce in Norway - report.</title>
<headline>Guatemalan sides to sign truce in Norway - report.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Guatemalan government and guerrilla negotiators will travel to Norway in October for the formal signing of a ceasefire declared earlier this year, Norway's national news agency NTB said on Friday.</p>
<p>It quoted Norwegian junior foreign minister Jan Egeland as saying the signing ceremony, a date for which had yet to be set, would take the parties another step on the long road to peace after 36 years of civil war in Guatemala.</p>
<p>&quot;A final formal agreement on a ceasefire in Guatemala will be signed in Norway in October,&quot; NTB quoted Egeland, who was in Guatemala for talks with the parties, as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;In the six years that I have been engaged in the peace process in Guatemala I have never heard the parties speaking with such agreement that things are going in the right direction,&quot; Egeland said.</p>
<p>The rebel Guatemalan National Revolutionary Unit (URNG) has met government peace negotiators regularly since January, and both sides plan to sign a definitive peace agreement this year,</p>
<p>The guerrillas declared a unilateral ceasefire in March and the Guatemalan army is under presidential orders to cease all counter-insurgency measures.</p>
<p>The peace process accelerated this year with the signing of major social and economic agreements and the ceasefire.</p>
<p>More than 100,000 people have died and tens of thousands more have disappeared in the conflict.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
