<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11504" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian shares seen consolidating after dip.</title>
<headline>Belgian shares seen consolidating after dip.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian shares are seen consolidating in coming weeks despite the slight dip on Friday as joy over Thursday's German repo rate cut was undermined by strong U.S. durable goods figures, traders said.</p>
<p>Durable goods orders for July rose a stronger-than-expected 1.6 percent, dashing hopes that the German rate cut might not have been the last of the current cycle.</p>
<p>&quot;There was euphoria yesterday and again this morning. But the durable goods figures reversed that,&quot; one trader said. &quot;But although more rate cuts are out, there are no rises near either. So we see shares edging higher.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Bel-20 share index ended the day 2.12 points or 0.12 percent down at 1,767.53 having traded in a 1,776.46/1,763.59 range.</p>
<p>Total market volume was 1.8 billion francs, of which 1.4 billion was in stocks in the index.</p>
<p>Traders said the Belgian bourse simply emulated its European neighbours which rose early on Friday but then drifted back on dollar weakness and lack of followthrough buying, before deflating again on the U.S. figures.</p>
<p>They noted that bonds also fell, further unnerving what some described as a still fragile share market.  </p>
<p>Energy stock Petrofina was the volume leader, falling 0.2 percent to 9,820 francs.</p>
<p>Film finisher Spector was the top percentage gainer, climbing 2.6 percent to 2,000 francs.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
