<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11508" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian Natl Bank more cheerful on state finances.</title>
<headline>Belgian Natl Bank more cheerful on state finances.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Belgian National Bank on Friday turned more optimistic on the state of Belgium's public finances, lowering its forecast for the 1996 net borrowing requirement as a percentage of national output to 3.1 percent.</p>
<p>The forecast was slashed from the 4.5 percent level predicted in June. The new level is just below the 3.2 percent forecast by the European Union in May and the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development in June.</p>
<p>The central bank announced the change in its weekly report on economic indicators for Belgium.</p>
<p>The National Bank raised its forecast for the primary balance -- the difference between government spending and revenues before debt servicing costs -- to 5.6 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) from June's 4.7 percent.</p>
<p>The changes come hot on the heels of Thursday's round of Europe-wide interest rate cuts, sparked off by the Bundesbank, in which the Belgian central bank took part.</p>
<p>The cuts should, among other things, lower non-fixed borrowing costs for the government, while cheaper lending rates should stimulate economic growth, boosting revenues, analysts said.</p>
<p>The expected improvement in government finances should also bolster Belgium's chances of joining Europe's single currency union, due to be formed from 1999.</p>
<p>A borrowing requirement of three percent of GDP, or just above, is one of the criteria listed in the Maastricht Treaty on economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>The National Bank slightly lowered its forecast for the trade surplus of Belgium and Luxembourg, who are already in a currency union, to 5.7 percent of GDP from the 5.8 percent level predicted in June.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
