<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11505" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian bonds/futures.</title>
<headline>Italian bonds/futures.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian bond futures held to lower levels in late trading, but were off the day's lowest level as BTPs outperformed many European bonds markets against a picture of falling domestic inflation, dealers said.</p>
<p>Futures had opened easier on profit-taking after Thursday's rise but strong U.S. July durable goods in the afternoon pushed many bond markets into a slide pulling BTPs with them. However, the Italian mood remained largely positive, dealers added.</p>
<p>&quot;This was a pretty resilient performance from Italian bonds after the U.S. data. Most players are still keeping the inflation figures in mind,&quot; said one LIFFE dealer.  </p>
<p>However, some pointed out that although the short-term mood was positive there was still uncertainty in Italy over political concerns with the government facing battles this autumn over its 1997 financial budget, jobs and privatisations.</p>
<p>Analysts said the surpringly strong U.S. durable goods figures suggested the U.S. economic slowdown was not all that slow and the economy may be hanging on to some of its second quarter strength, and this all weighed heavily on T-bonds.</p>
<p>But with the London LIFFE market closed for a bank holiday on Monday there was some short covering of positions ahead of the long weekend which helped futures prices recover.  </p>
<p>Dealers said that next week will likely start off quiet with LIFFE closed on Monday, but that investors minds could shift to the troubles the government has in store for the autumn and futures could be set to test some key support levels.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsrooom +392 66129502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
