<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11517" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>pakistan: Emergency declared as floods kill three in Lahore.</title>
<headline>Emergency declared as floods kill three in Lahore.</headline>
<byline>Aurang Zeb</byline>
<dateline>LAHORE, Pakistan 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistani authorities called out troops and declared a state of emergency in the city of Lahore on Friday after torrential rain caused floods and at least three deaths.</p>
<p>Police said a woman and her two children were killed when their house collapsed after heavy rains in Shahadra, a suburb of Lahore, capital of the populous province of Punjab.</p>
<p>&quot;Due to continuous rain, an emergency has been declared and the army has been called in for help,&quot; a statement by the district magistrate's office said.</p>
<p>&quot;Police and civil defence forces have been mobilised to rescue people and an emergency cell has been set up at the deputy commissioner's office,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Witnesses said many houses had collapsed in Lahore and army troops were helping to evacuate residents from low-lying areas.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Flood Forecasting Bureau in Lahore said the Ravi and Chenab rivers were in exceptionally high flood at several points after heavy rain in catchment areas.</p>
<p>&quot;The rains in the upper and lower catchment area have not stopped for the last 36 hours,&quot; the spokesman said, adding that the department had warned all concerned government agencies.</p>
<p>He said the Ravi, which runs past Lahore, would be in medium to high flood during the night, but was unlikely to break its banks.</p>
<p>In Lahore, life came to a near-standstill after torrential rain left water up to one metre (three feet) deep. Motor vehicles could not be used and only horse-drawn carriages and wagons were on the streets.</p>
<p>The Meteorological Department said 373 mm (more than 14-1/2 inches) of rain had fallen in Lahore in the past 36 hours.</p>
<p>Pakistan receives an average of 140 mm (5-1/2 inches) during the whole of the three-month monsoon season. Officials said they could not say whether the Lahore downpour had broken records.</p>
<p>&quot;We are too busy to check right now, but it is certainly extraordinarily high,&quot; said one official at the department.</p>
<p>&quot;I've never seen anything like it in 50 years,&quot; said Tahir Mashadi, 70, stranded at home like most Lahore residents.</p>
<p>Last year floods inundated parts of Pakistan, damaging thousands of houses, destroying crops and killing cattle.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAHORE, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
