<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11514" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Hindu pilgrims die on Himalaya trek.</title>
<headline>Hindu pilgrims die on Himalaya trek.</headline>
<byline>Sheikh Mushtaq</byline>
<dateline>SRINAGAR, India 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nearly three dozen Hindu pilgrims have died of exposure while trekking to a holy cave in Kashmir, Indian police said on Friday.</p>
<p>Police in Srinagar, summer capital of Jammu and Kashmir state, said 34 devotees had died since Thursday after heavy rain and snow stranded some 70,000 pilgrims on the route to the 3,880 metre (12,725-ft) high cave.</p>
<p>A further 12 pilgrims had died earlier on the annual pilgrimage, which started on August 16 and ends next Wednesday.</p>
<p>Officials said some 112,000 Hindus had arrived in Kashmir this year to visit the Amarnath cave, where devotees worship an ice stalagmite believed to be a manifestation of the &quot;lingam&quot;, or phallus, of the Hindu god Shiva.</p>
<p>Movement along the route came to a standstill as 50 cm (20 in) of rain fell over 24 hours beginning on Thursday, officials said.</p>
<p>The temperature in Pahalgam, the last staging point along the pilgrims' route some 100 km (60 miles) south of Srinagar, had fallen to freezing, they said.</p>
<p>The trek snakes past Pahalgam, through the Lidder valley and 48 km (30 miles) through the mountains to the cave.</p>
<p>&quot;People walking through the forests of Pahalgam have been exposed to extreme cold,&quot; a police official said. &quot;It is raining heavily along the route. All the roads to Pahalgam are flooded. There are snowfalls in the upper reaches of the mountains.&quot;</p>
<p>Last year the pilgrimage was threatened by Moslem separatist guerrillas, who staged two bomb attacks on the heavily guarded pilgrims, who rely on ponies to climb the upper reaches. A state civil servant was killed in one of the blasts.</p>
<p>Some 20,000 people have died since a separatist revolt broke out in 1990 in Jammu and Kashmir, mainly-Hindu India's only Moslem majority state.</p>
<p>This year guerrillas issued no ban on the pilgrimage. Instead, the weather has posed a challenge. At some points along the route, the snow was 13 inches thick, officials said.</p>
<p>In the state's winter capital Jammu, authorities said floods and landslides set off by torrential rains had forced them to close the 300-km (185-mile) highway to Srinagar.</p>
<p>&quot;It will take more than three days to clear the landslides and only after that can normal traffic be restored,&quot; said Mohammed Shafi Wani, a senior police official.</p>
<p>The flooding disrupted the traditional procession of the &quot;charri mubarak&quot;, or the maces that symbolise Lord Shiva and his consort Parvati. They are taken from Jammu each year by road to Srinagar as part of the trek.</p>
<p>State officials said they were arranging to have the maces flown to Srinagar.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SRINAGAR, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
