<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11516" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>India: Indian shares finish mostly higher on fund bids.</title>
<headline>Indian shares finish mostly higher on fund bids.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian shares ended higher on Friday as domestic funds bid blue chips across-the-board, traders said.</p>
<p>In Bombay, punters squared oversold position in end-account trade, they said. Domestic funds -- including the Unit Trust of India -- were net buyers.</p>
<p>&quot;Domestic funds were picking up leading stocks but some foreign funds set firm limits one to two percent below market prices,&quot; said a trader at a foreign brokerage.</p>
<p>The 30-share index of the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) closed 42.60 points higher at 3431.40.  </p>
<p>Traders said there were buyers in Arvind Mills, Bajaj Auto, Hindalco, Grasim, ICICI, TELCO, IPCL and Indian Hotels.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to be just a relief rally and people are bound to exit at slightly higher levels,&quot; one trader said, adding prices were likely to stay rangebound on Monday due to a market holiday in Hong Kong and London.</p>
<p>Some traders said the mood was cheered by a steady rise in prices of Indian global depositary receipts (GDRs) listed in London.</p>
<p>&quot;GDR premiums to the underlying have gone up since last week and that has helped sentiment,&quot; another trader said.  </p>
<p>The National Stock Exchange (NSE)-50 index closed 11 points higher at 1013 with net traded value at 8.18 billion rupees.</p>
<p>In Delhi, the index closed 5.21 points higher at 797.24 on bids led by the Unit Trust of India, traders said.</p>
<p>Calcutta shares ended a touch lower in low volumes.</p>
<p>Auto firm Mahindra &amp; Mahindra gained across Indian bourses.</p>
<p>M&amp;M said vehicle sales were up 23 percent at 26,701 units during April 1-August 22 from the year ago.</p>
<p>Chairman Keshub Mahindra told shareholders, demand continued to be &quot;very strong.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Priya Ramani, Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
