<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11511" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks end up slightly after profit-taking.</title>
<headline>French stocks end up slightly after profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>French shares ended slightly higher on Friday after spending most of the day in the red on profit-taking after a big rise on Thursday on unexpected interest rate cuts. Wall Street's recovery from a lower start on higher than expected July durable good data pulled shares back.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index closed up 3.06 points or 0.15 percent at 2,020.82 while the CAC-40 futures contract was down at 2,023.5 from 2,025 on Thursday's close.</p>
<p>The August account, which closed today, showed a respectable 66.72 point gain over the July account, the worst since September 1995, which closed at 1.954.1.  </p>
<p>&quot;There are still too many uncertainties to really start buying French shares,&quot; a dealer said, noting upcoming budget talks and threatened social unrest in September.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe is due to meet President Jacques Chirac at his summer residence this weekend to hammer out budget and tax cut details. Finance Minister Jean Arthuis on Thursday lowered his 1997 GDP growth forecast to between 2.25 and 2.5 percent from up to 2.8 percent.</p>
<p>Juppe attracted opposition and labour union protests about the eviction of 300 African immigrants from a church on Friday but government parties expressed their support.  </p>
<p>* Volume was 3.2 billion francs.</p>
<p>* Promodes closed 2.58 percent higher at 1,270 francs, though off its highs, after a newspaper reported the retailer could soon sell its German assets to Spar AG.</p>
<p>A spokesman said the German dossier would be closed in early September or October. First half results due on September 10.</p>
<p>* CSFB said it had made Elf-Aquitaine, up 0.39 percent to 387.5, and Michelin, up 0.45 percent at 243.9, its top French stock picks for August. It also recommended LVMH, Rorer, Canal Plus, AXA, AGF and Usinor.  </p>
<p>* Pathe adds another 4.47 percent to 1,403 on the back of results of BSkyB, in which it has a 17 percent stake. &quot;We're looking into it again. We don't really see why there is such a difference with Canal Plus&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Canal Plus fell 1.25 percent TO 1,189. Brokers Jean-Pierre Pinatton said that Pathe &quot;with a share valuation below its BSkyB stake&quot; should be able to rise to 1,500 francs. It recommended to go underweight on Canal Plus and M6.</p>
<p>* The broker advised to buy TF1, Pathe and Generale des Eaux and to keep Lyonnaise des Eaux. Pinatton was neutral on Havas. </p>
<p>* Coflexip rises 3.03 percent to 221 francs after publishing a first half net loss of 35 million francs against a profit of 22 million last year. Dealers said the loss was less pronounced as feared while a rise in the orderbook was welcomed.</p>
<p>* Total slips 0.27 percent to 376 francs after having made a good run on Thursday on the back of 20 percent higher first half sales.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
