<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11520" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: PRESS DIGEST - Pakistan newspapers - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Pakistan newspapers - Aug 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main stories in Friday's Pakistani newspapers.</p>
<p>DAWN</p>
<p>- A foreign office spokesman said that Pakistan would not accept the Biharis stranded in Bangladesh and denied that it had agreed to take them back.</p>
<p>- The United States has not yet decided to sell the nine Pakistani F-16 jet fighters to Indonesia, the State Department said on Wednesday, amid reports that the administration was considering cancelling the deal.</p>
<p>- The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has no complaints against the 1996/97 (July-June) budget, the prime minister's adviser on finance and economic affairs V.A. Jaffery said.</p>
<p>- Former senator Yousuf Shaheen, who was arrested at his office in Karachi on Wednesday, has been charged with drawing 60 million rupees fraudulently from United Bank Limited.</p>
<p>- The Privatisation Commission will shortly launch an &quot;aggressive&quot; marketing campaign before formally offering a 26 percent management stake in Pakistan Telecommunication Co Ltd.</p>
<p>- The army's Burn Hall College, Abbottabad, one of the most presitigious educational institutions of the country, was ransacked by students on Wednesday night to protest against the expulsion of three students from the college.</p>
<p>- Pakistan's four state-owned commercial banks and two specialised banks offered the lowest average of 11.6 percent rate of return on one-year deposits out of the 44 commercial banks operating in the country.</p>
<p>- Heavy rain badly disrupted normal life in Lahore and several other cities in Punjab province.</p>
<p>BUSINESS RECORDER</p>
<p>- The government has offered withholding tax exemption for General Sales Tax (GST) payers and the payment of interest if the GST refund is delayed beyond 30 days.</p>
<p>- A foreign office spokesman said there was no adverse reaction from abroad on the signing of $1.2 billion oil refinery agreement between Pakistan and Iran.</p>
<p>- The government has prepared a plan for palm oil cultivation on a total of 2.8 million hectares.</p>
<p>THE NEWS</p>
<p>- Pakistan, striving to cut its budget deficit and shore up its balance of payments, has made a shaky start to fiscal 1996/97 (July-June), a former commerce minister said.</p>
<p>- The rebel Taleban Islamic militia has captured a pro-government military base in the eastern Afghan province of Paktia, a Pakistan-based Afghan news service said.</p>
<p>- The first arms shipment from the United States to Pakistan after a gap of six years is expected to reach Karachi on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Islamabad newsroom 9251-274757</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
