<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11528" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Mother Teresa's condition said still unstable.</title>
<headline>Mother Teresa's condition said still unstable.</headline>
<byline>Rupam Banerjee</byline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mother Teresa, who is being treated in a Calcutta hospital for a heart condition and malaria, showed slight signs of improvement on Friday but her cardiac status remained unstable for most of the day, a member of her religious order said.</p>
<p>&quot;She is now responding to treatment, her temperature is going down,&quot; the sister of the Missionaries of Charity said at Woodlands Nursing Home where the world's most famous Roman Catholic nun remained on a respirator in intensive care two days after suffering heart failure.</p>
<p>The sister, who requested anynomity, said the condition of the Nobel peace laureate, who turns 86 next Tuesday, had improved slightly from earlier in the day.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue to keep our fingers crossed as long as she takes respiratory support,&quot; Dr A.K. Bardhan, head of a six-doctor panel attending her, told Reuters.</p>
<p>An official at the hospital had earlier told Reuters after the initial signs of deterioration that &quot;we are now worried&quot;.</p>
<p>Mother Teresa's heart, which has a pacemaker, had weakened on Friday when doctors administered medicine for a recurrence of malaria, which she first contracted in 1993.</p>
<p>She remained conscious throughout Friday but was unable to speak. &quot;She mumbled something when the Bishop of Calcutta came to visit her,&quot; a nurse said, adding that she also recognised West Bengal's Marxist chief minister, Jyoti Basu, when he came to visit her in the afternoon.</p>
<p>Mother Teresa, known as a living saint for her work for the destitute and poor, was admitted to Woodlands on Tuesday with a temperature of 103 Fahrendheit (39.4 Celcius) and severe vomiting. She developed heart problems on Wednesday, but had responded to treatment and was in stable condition until Friday morning. While the vomiting had stopped, Mother Teresa continued to run a fever on Friday, Bardhan said.</p>
<p>Dozens of nuns gathered in Calcutta for round-the-clock prayers for Mother Teresa's recovery.</p>
<p>The message &quot;Please pray for the Mother&quot; was written on a blackboard outside the main prayer hall of The Missionaries of Charity, the apex organisation housed in a sprawling complex in the heart of Calcutta.</p>
<p>Members of the Charity, wearing white gowns, were seen kneeling on the floor, offering silent prayers.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a special prayer, we have been having it in groups since yesterday,&quot; Sister Christene, a member in the Missionaries of Charity order, told Reuters.</p>
<p>A constant cluster of people could be seen outside the chamber of Sister Priscilla, a senior member of the order, who was keeping in touch with hospital officials.</p>
<p>&quot;We know the doctors are trying hard. It is all in God's hands. We can only pray,&quot; said Sister Pricilla, spokeswoman and a senior memnber of Mother Teresa's order, who spent most of her day handling queries from abroad.</p>
<p>Sister Christene said they were told various churches worldwide were offering prayers for Mother Teresa's recovery.</p>
<p>Outside the gates of the order, a group of slum dwellers, the main beneficiaries of Mother Teresa's work, gathered for the latest news of her condition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
