<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11527" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Afghan rebels attack pro-government base.</title>
<headline>Afghan rebels attack pro-government base.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The rebel Islamic Taleban militia said it had attacked a key military base of Afghan Prime Minister Gulbuddin Hekmatyar's Hezb-i-Islami party on Friday in the eastern province of Paktiya.</p>
<p>A Taleban spokesman, Maulvi Ahmad Jan, told the Pakistan-based Afghan Islamic Press agency that 800 to 1,000 Islamic warriors, backed by artillery, had been thrown into a three-pronged assault on Spina Shega, on the Pakistani border.</p>
<p>He said Spina Shega, used as a main supply depot for Afghan guerrillas during the fight against Soviet troops in the 1980s, was Hezb-i-Islami's last and biggest position in the province.</p>
<p>Jan said the Taleban had earlier seized several other posts and large quantities of ammunition from Hezb-i-Islami in the Jaji district of Paktiya.</p>
<p>There was no independent account of the fighting and Hezb-i-Islami officials could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>Hekmatyar, once a main opponent of Afghan President Burhanuddin Rabbani, rejoined the Kabul government in June as prime minister after a peace pact between the two men.</p>
<p>The Taleban movement has sworn to oust Rabbani and install a purist Islamic order throughout Afghanistan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
