<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11544" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Calcutta shares end shade lower on low volumes.</title>
<headline>Calcutta shares end shade lower on low volumes.</headline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Calcutta shares moved in a narrow range and closed a shade lower on Friday although technical support levels maintained mild buying support from foreign institutional investors (FIIs), brokers said.</p>
<p>They said that volumes fell as orders from Bombay traders were low. FIIs picked up select blue-chips like TISCO, L&amp;T and ITC in small lots but local speculative interest was down.</p>
<p>Brokers said speculative sellers retreated in anticipation of a stiff backwardation charge likely to be levied at close of accounting period of the Calcutta exchange today.</p>
<p>Traders expected a backwardation charge of five rupees per share of Reliance Industries and one rupee per share on State Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices have fallen too much in too short a time. I am expecting a technical rally in prices of blue-chips in the short term. But higher levels are unlikely to sustain in the face of profit-taking thereafter,&quot; said Rishi Dhanuka of brokers Ratnabali Securities Ltd.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
