<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11554" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Mother Teresa stable but still in intensive care.</title>
<headline>Mother Teresa stable but still in intensive care.</headline>
<byline>Arindam Nag</byline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mother Teresa remained on a respirator in the intensive care unit of an Indian nursing home on Friday after suffering heart failure earlier in the week, officials said.</p>
<p>An official at Woodlands Nursing Home in the eastern city of Calcutta said no fresh health bulletin had been issued since late on Thursday when a team of specialists monitoring the Nobel Prize winner's condition said she was conscious and stable.</p>
<p>But the official confirmed that Mother Teresa, regarded by many as a living saint for her devotion to the world's destitute, still needed respiratory support.</p>
<p>The 85-year-old Roman Catholic missionary, who won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1979, was admitted to the nursing home on Tuesday with a temperature of 103 degrees Fahrenheit (39.4 degrees Celsius) and severe vomiting.</p>
<p>On Wednesday she developed cardio-respiratory complications which Dr A.K. Bardhan, one of her attending physicians, described as heart failure.</p>
<p>He said Mother Teresa, fitted with a heart pacemaker in 1989, had suffered heart failure in the past and responded to treatment.</p>
<p>This time, too, her heart problems &quot;were handled and corrected quickly&quot;, Bardhan said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Arguably the best known Roman Catholic missionary and one of the world's most widely recognised figures, Mother Teresa of Albanian descent turns 86 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In 1949 she founded a network of missions for the poor and the sick in Calcutta, India's most densely populated city.</p>
<p>The Missionaries of Charity order now has nearly 3,000 people ministering to the needy, dying and orphaned in the slums of 200 cities.</p>
<p>Her health began to deteriorate in 1989 when she was fitted with the pacemaker. In 1991, she was treated at a California hospital for heart disease and bacterial pneumonia.</p>
<p>In Rome in May 1993, she fell, breaking three ribs. In August the same year, while in New Delhi to receive an award, she developed malaria, complicated by her heart and lung problems.</p>
<p>A Calcutta newspaper said Mother Teresa's persistent fever could indicate she had again contracted malaria, a mosquito-borne disease which thrives in hot, humid climates.</p>
<p>But the nursing home official said doctors had not indicated she had malaria.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
