<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11568" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: ANTI-SMOKING CAMPAIGN LEAVES E.EUROPE SMOKERS UNFAZED.</title>
<headline>ANTI-SMOKING CAMPAIGN LEAVES E.EUROPE SMOKERS UNFAZED.</headline>
<byline>George Georgiopoulos</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>It's a routine day at the press ministry as reporters light up greeting the government spokesman with a thick cloud of smoke. Welcome to Marlboro country.</p>
<p>Greece leads in per capita cigarette consumption followed by Japan, Poland, Switzerland and South Korea, according to the Economist. On average, Greek smokers puff away over 2,700 cigarettes a year and they are not about to quit.</p>
<p>&quot;Greeks are avid smokers. They enjoy smoking just like their cup of thick Greek coffee and island sunsets. The hope now is for the younger generations... to never pick up the habit,&quot; says businesswoman Yianna Tsirimonaki, exhaling.</p>
<p>And while there's talk that the domestic market is hitting a peak, major tobacco companies like Papastratos are looking to neighbouring Balkan markets where smokers, thirsty for Western brands, are still wondering what the fuss is all about.</p>
<p>Tsirimonaki who does business in the Balkans thinks all underdeveloped countries are Marlboro countries with advertising there playing a major role. &quot;Kids usually start with Marlboros then try Camels,&quot; she says.</p>
<p>Increasingly, as health fears, restrictions on smoking in public and high taxation are hurting tobacco markets in the West, big manufacturers are heading East in a shift away from the developed countries.</p>
<p>While former tobacco bulls are growing wary on Western tobacco stocks, strong growth prospects in the Balkans and Eastern Europe are prompting buy recommendations by investment analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;We view Papastratos as one of the most attractive vehicles through which to gain exposure to Greece and the rapidly developing Balkan, primarily Romania and Bulgaria, and Eastern European markets,&quot; says Salomon Brothers in its buy rating for Papastratos.</p>
<p>With annual sales of $350 million, Papastratos is the largest importer in Romania where it enjoys a 15 percent market share with its Assos International. It also has the largest presence in the highly fragmented Ukranian market thanks to its President brand, Salomon says.</p>
<p>Producers in Romania's 21 billion cigarette a year market -- East Europe's second largest after Poland -- still see scope for growth, with lax post-communist anti-tobacco laws.</p>
<p>&quot;We have an extraordinarily high demand and I don't see how it could be affected for the time being,&quot; says Sorin Muntnau, Romanian Tobacco Authority Manager.</p>
<p>&quot;If the market falls in the West, tobacco producers will rush in force to the East,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Last year RJ Reynolds opened a greenfield plant near Bucharest and BAT also plans to build a plant in a country where one out of four Romanians is a smoker and where health warnings on cigarettes are not yet compulsory.</p>
<p>&quot;Papastratos' dynamic marketing approach will ensure strong export growth. A 40 percent volume increase is projected in 1996 to 20.2 billion units and a conservative 35 percent growth forecast for 1997,&quot; says Salomon Brothers analyst Stacy Adams.</p>
<p>In retrospect, Balkan and Eastern European cigarette sales growth has risen exponentially, notes Salomon. &quot;Papastratos saw exports increase exponentially from 1.1 billion units in 1989 to 14.4 billion in 1995, reflecting the opening up of Eastern European markets.&quot;</p>
<p>And while in the U.S. the attack on cigarette makers is heating up as states begin to sue tobacco law firms, in the Czech Republic, analysts remain cool expecting no impact on the local market.</p>
<p>They say shares in leading cigarette maker Tabak A.S., majority-owned by Philip Morris, will not be affected by a spate of events that are hitting hard tobacco issues in western markets.</p>
<p>&quot;It is unlikely that there will be a negative reaction by domestic investors (over the court case) with regard to Tabak,&quot; says Leos Jirman of BH Securities in Prague. Tabak's dominant position in the expanding domestic market is not threatened, other analysts agree.</p>
<p>In Greece where tobacco is still touted in grade school books as a major product along with olives and raisins there is no major concern that the West's anti-smoking hysteria will catch on fast, smokers say.</p>
<p>While TV and radio cigarette ads are prohibited, most companies do not have an official policy on smoking in the work place. Measures avoid extremes practiced in the West where smokers are relegated to second-class citizens.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a limited anti-tobacco campaign and it has not been shocking. Perhaps because it accomodates the tobacco industry. Separating smokers in restaurants would not go down well,&quot; says Tsirimonaki.</p>
<p>Jokes abound of U.S. smokers coming down from skyscraper offices to have a puff, as if they were practicing a sin, increasingly marginalised. Even the passive smoking argument is seen as extreme.</p>
<p>&quot;Passive smoking bothers you in Athens? Come on, what about all the pollution you inhale, its extreme,&quot; says Tsirimonaki, exhaling.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
