<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11580" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Britain's blue chips climb to new heights.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Britain's blue chips climb to new heights.</headline>
<byline>Duncan Hollobone</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Britain's leading companies powered to new heights on Friday, establishing a fresh peak above the 3,900 level on the blue chip FTSE 100 share index for the first time.</p>
<p>The continuation of the market's upward trend was helped by a strong 43-point rise from Wall Street and an agggressive cut by the Bundesbank in one of Germany's key interest rates on Thursday.</p>
<p>By 1330 GMT the FTSE 100 had drifted back to just below 3,900, pressured by strong U.S. durable goods data, having hit a trading high of 3,911.6 shortly after the opening.</p>
<p>The German central bank's action on Thursday sparked a round of similar reductions in many continental European countries.</p>
<p>&quot;The (German) rate cut is another notch in the argument for lower UK rates,&quot; said Corey Miller, equity strategist at Credit Loyannais Laing.</p>
<p>Britain has cut interest rates four times since December, the last time in June when they fell to their present 5.75 percent level.</p>
<p>Along with other strategists, Miller believes the stock market has mostly factored in the possibility of an opposition Labour Party success in a general election that must be held by the Spring of 1997.</p>
<p>Dealers expect that for the short term, the London stock market is likely to consolidate its recent gains. But the underlying tone remains firm, backed by encouraging company profits and an improved interest rate environment.</p>
<p>Relatively high liquidity levels held by institutional investors were also cited as a supportive factor for the market.</p>
<p>&quot;You have a background of benign long term interest rates, ....good profitability setting the main driver for the market over the medium term, and high institutional cash levels,&quot; Mark Tinker, equity strategist at HSBC James Capel, said.</p>
<p>He said the return on the equity market remained a compelling attraction.</p>
<p>&quot;So far this year the equity market has returned 10 percent total which is double the level on cash for the entire year. The opportunity cost of being out of the market is very high.&quot;</p>
<p>Tinker is sticking to a year-end FTSE 100 target of 4,000 points.</p>
<p>Technical analysts also saw further gains for the London market in the short to medium term.</p>
<p>Tom Pelc, technical analyst at MMS International, said the FTSE 100 was likely to test the 4,000 level before the year end and could challenge 4,300 in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
