<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11584" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Europe oil products outlook - Firm on run cuts.</title>
<headline>Europe oil products outlook - Firm on run cuts.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>European oil products are likely to firm next week as reduced refinery runs and imminent autumn maintenance keep supplies tight, oil traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>Maintenance shutdowns in September are expected to be particularly severe in northern Europe, and a handful of plants Britain, Sweden, France and Italy this week announced run cuts totalling 150,000 barrels per day (bpd) to combat poor margins.</p>
<p>In gasoline markets, the bullish supply picture is matched by 100,000 tonnes of demand in eastern Europe in September and steady U.S. arbitrage sales.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's got to look constructive. There are not too many cargoes on offer and the U.S. is showing interest,&quot; a trader at a European major said.</p>
<p>Eurograde barges were worth $208 a tonne in Rotterdam on Friday, some $40 above year-ago levels. &quot;I see us heading for the mid-teens next week,&quot; said a broker.</p>
<p>But a trader said the discount of regular to premium unleaded could widen because of reduced West African demand for low octane and increasing Russian exports of super-low octane.  </p>
<p>Algeria's refinery shutdown at Skikda has already tightened European naphtha supply, but traders said lower crude throughputs could also boost demand for heavy naphtha.</p>
<p>&quot;It certainly looks pretty bullish at the moment, unfortunately,&quot; a large European end-user said.</p>
<p>&quot;As time goes on it is bad news for petrochemical margins unless there is significant rise in ethylene prices.&quot;</p>
<p>He said northern Europe was better supplied than the Mediterranean, with condensate available from Brayford Bay and small cargoes from refineries in Immingham, Grangemouth, Mongstad and Russia.  </p>
<p>Set against that, some refineries which have reduced crude runs could increase imports of high N+A naphtha for reforming.</p>
<p>Physical gas oil premiums are expected to hold steady, but dealers expect a firmer tone on IPE futures.</p>
<p>Buying interest in 0.05 percent sulphur looked set to increase over the next week as the market gears up for the introduction of new EU low sulphur regulations in October, but dealers did not expect a jump in premiums, now at $11 cif NWE.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we'll see the market exploding. The market's known about this for about a year and is pretty well prepared,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>With the underlying September contract holding just above $190 a tonne, some dealers are eyeing $200 in the near term.</p>
<p>In both the gas oil and naphtha markets, a renewed Brazilian buying spree could light a fire under prices, traders said.</p>
<p>Fuel oil markets were very tight and could easily rise sharply if any unexpected demand appears, traders said.</p>
<p>Dealers expect Portugal to buy about six cargoes for September delivery, possibly next week, and this could provide the trigger. Indeed, cargoes were so scarce that traders were buying oil on the barge market to make up cargoes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
