<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11592" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London gold dozes ahead of holiday weekend.</title>
<headline>London gold dozes ahead of holiday weekend.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold prices stagnated in a tiny range on Friday, unruffled by strong U.S. durable goods figures which sent bonds in a tailspin.</p>
<p>Bullion fixed unchanged from the morning fixing at $387.50 an ounce, against $387.00 on Thursday afternoon.</p>
<p>Dealers said they were preoccupied with squaring their books ahead of the market holiday on Monday in Britain and Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Comex December gold was unchanged at $392.50 an ounce, after trading in an early $392.10-$392.70 range.</p>
<p>The market ignored a surprising 1.6 percent rise in U.S. July durable goods orders, against an expected 0.3 percent rise.  </p>
<p>The data caused bonds to tumble and shares were also expected to come under pressure.</p>
<p>Analysts said the jump suggested the manufacturing sector was growing gradually and the economy was holding on to some of its second-quarter strength.</p>
<p>Gold and silver had popped a little higher on Thursday on New York-driven buying funds and locals following the Bundesbank's cut in a key money market rate.</p>
<p>Analysts said that easier global monetary policy might encourage demand for precious metals in the medium term. But dealers said it had had virtually no immediate effect.  </p>
<p>Summer lethargy, along with upcoming over-the-counter options expiry on Wednesday, were behind gold's statis in a narrow $386-$388 range, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have OTC options expiring on Wedneday and a long weekend ahead. Gold's been in a narrow range and I don't think anyone sees it moving up in the next few days,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Silver was indicated unchanged from Thursday's London close at $5.23/$5.25 an ounce. Bids were between $5.24 and $5.20.</p>
<p>Like gold, it was expected to stay within its $5.15-$5.25 range near term after failing in an attempt to break past key resistance at $5.25-$5.26 on Thursday afternoon.  </p>
<p>But silver's rally at the start of the week, which took it well above previous resistance at $5.15, was keeping the market slightly on edge.</p>
<p>&quot;It's high enough to have to come back, but there's a slimmer chance of it going up and if we break through $5.27, we'll see $5.35,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Platinum was unchanged from Thursday's close at $398.75/$399.75, but off the day's modestly firmer highs.</p>
<p>Palladium was up $0.75 at $124.00/$125.00.</p>
<p>-- Lida Poletz London newsroom +44 171 542 2936</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
