<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11606" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: From the Flightdeck - the Air Cargo Week in Review.</title>
<headline>From the Flightdeck - the Air Cargo Week in Review.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>This is Reuters' look back at the major developments in the global air cargo industry in the week August 19 - August 23.</p>
<p>**AUGUST 19**</p>
<p>BELGRADE - An air traffic controller says a Russian-built Ilyushin-76 cargo aircraft crashed close to Belgrade airport killing all twelve on-board.</p>
<p>ASHGABAT - An airlines spokesman says Turkmenistan's state-owned national air carrier NUGAT has bought two new Boeing 757 passenger aircraft..</p>
<p>PARIS - Air France says its global cargo traffic, last month, was up 5.7 percent on July 1995 at 410.4 million FTK.</p>
<p>PARIS - Airport authority figures show air cargo traffic handled at Montpellier airport in the first seven months of 1996 totalled 3,016 tonnes, up 3.7 percent on the same period last year.</p>
<p>PARIS - Bordeaux's Merignac airport says it handled 4,561 tonnes of air cargo traffic in the first seven months of 1996, compared to 4,544 tonnes in the same period last year.</p>
<p>SINGAPORE - Singapore Airlines says its subsidiary, the Singapore Airport Terminal Services, has opened the first phase of its second maintenance centre.</p>
<p>PARIS - Airport authority figures show Lille-Lesquin airport handled 2,209 tonnes of cargo traffic last month, up 20 percent on July 1995 levels.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - The Hesse transport ministry says a 50 percent cut in night freighter fees at Frankfurt airport has been approved.</p>
<p>PARIS - A spokeswoman for Air France declined comment on a French newspaper report that it was in alliance talks with Northwest Airlines and USAir.</p>
<p>TORONTO - Bombardier Inc says its regional jet division won an order for 16 50-seater Canadair jets worth US$320 million from Farmington, New Mexico-based Mesa Air Group.</p>
<p>ATLANTA - UPS says its has introduced its UPS Online tracking software.</p>
<p>PRAGUE - Czech airlines Ceskoslovenske Aeroline says its first half preliminary loss, accordingly to Czech accounting standards totalled 180 million crowns, down 25 percent compared with the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>NEW YORK - Continental Airlines spokesman David Messing, says it has raised its benchmark domestic fares by 10 percent.</p>
<p>REYKJAVIK - Officials says Iceland's Keflavik International airport is planning a 650 million crown expansion project to handle anticipated increased passenger capacity.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - TNT says it had restructured its European management subsidiary TNT Europe Ltd.</p>
<p>* TNT says it plans to expand logistics services in eastern Europe as part of new cross-border responsibilities.</p>
<p>PARIS - Air Gabon says it will operate its own air cargo office at Paris-CDG airport, effective next month.</p>
<p>ZURICH - Swissair says it would offer a weekly cargo-only flight from Basle to Sao Paulo beginning September 23, its first cargo flight to South America.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Airport authority Flughafen Muenchen says Munich airport maintained its double-figured cargo growth in July due to an imports boom.</p>
<p>PARIS - Airport authority provisional figures show air cargo traffic handled at Toulouse-Blagnac airport in the first seven month of 1996 totalled 14,480 tonnes, a decrease of 14 percent on the same period last year.</p>
<p>NEW YORK - USAir Group declined to comment on a French newspaper report that it was in alliance talks with Air France.</p>
<p>CHICAGO - UAL spokesman Tony Molinaro says it and Northwest Airlines have raised their base U.S. airfares by 10 percent, following the lead of Continental Airlines.</p>
<p>NEW YORK - Airline Analyst Julius Maldutis says major U.S. airlines are testing the market with higher fares as they quietly raise domestic fares 10 percent and prepared to pass along the renewed 10 percent federal passenger excise tax.</p>
<p>CHICAGO - Northwest Airlines says it had no comment on a French newspaper report that it may be in talks to form an alliance with Air France.</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - TWA says it urged the Transportation department to act quickly on its request for three daily non-stop service routes between New York's Kennedy airport and Heathrow.</p>
<p>CHICAGO - TWA says it did, in fact, raise base airfares 10 percent over the weekend, following an industry trend.</p>
<p>BOSTON - Korean Airlines says that it will start flying from Boston and Newark, New Jersey to Seoul, South Korea, this week.</p>
<p>LONDON - The Financial times reported United Airlines is close to announcing a $3 billion order for up to 50 aircraft from both Boeing Co. and Airbus Industrie.</p>
<p>**AUGUST 20**</p>
<p>NEW DELHI - An Indian newspaper says that the Civil Aviation ministry had rejected a proposal to allow foreign companies to take equity stakes in domestic airlines.</p>
<p>LONDON - The Financial Times says Britain is taking a tough line in negotiations for an aviation trade pact with the U.S. and will not agree a U.S. &quot;open skies&quot; deal similar to one agreed with Germany.</p>
<p>VANCOUVER - The airport authority says June freight traffic at Vancouver international airport was 20 percent higher than June 1995, led by one-third gain in imports.</p>
<p>DENVER - The airport authority says cargo traffic at Denver international airport increased by 3.9 percent in the first half of 1996, with the strongest growth reported by passenger airlines.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Hong Kong's airport authority says that some construction work was behind schedule but Hong Kong's new airport at Chek Lap Lok was on course to open as planned in April 1998.</p>
<p>DARIEN, Connecticut - AEI says it has been awarded a multi-million dollar contract to handle air and ocean freight movements from Europe of Bristol-Myers Squibb Co.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - El Al Israel Airlines general manager for China, Hong Kong and east Asia, Abraham Roter says it is considering using a Boeing 747 aircraft for its weekly Tel Aviv to Hong Kong service, providing another seven tonnes of cargo capacity and a non-stop service.</p>
<p>PARIS - The state-owned Aerospatiale group says it aims to agree merger terms with warplane maker Dassault Aviation by the end of 1996r, as previously announced.</p>
<p>CAPE TOWN - Trade and transport minister Alec Erwin says the South African government has earmarked transport as the second sector to be assessed for privatisation with air transport on the agenda for a meeting on August 23.</p>
<p>SYDNEY - BA says that it had no plans for new alliances over the next few years, but would extend it global reach by franchising its popular brand name to smaller airlines.</p>
<p>LAGOS - Cash-strapped Nigeria Airways says it has signed an agreement with private carrier Bellview Airlines to operate some of its unutilised routes.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Acting Indian commissioner in Hong Kong, Dipak Mallik, says he expects a new air services agreement to be signed &quot;any day now&quot; opening up potential for more flights between the two countries.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Phoenix airport officials says they foresee a air cargo boom from new non-stop European services from Britain and Germany.</p>
<p>LONDON - A Manchester airport statement says Cargolux has launched a scheduled freighter service operating between Manchester airport to Hartford, Connecticut.</p>
<p>TIRANA - Albanian Airlines denied a report by the country's newspaper that it would suspend flights in September because it was going bankrupt.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Qantas Airways general manager Peter Barry says the airline's recently restarted service to Bombay is already a success.</p>
<p>* Barry added it has begun a regular air cargo service into China with the opening of a new route to Shanghai.</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - A U.S. appeals court denied UPS's appeal that it be subject to the jurisdiction of the National Mediation Board rather than the National Labour Relations Board.</p>
<p>PARIS - Aeroport de Paris figures show Air France increased its share of global air cargo tonnage handled at the two Paris airports, Charles de Gaulle and Orly, in the first six months of 1996 compared to 1995 as a whole.</p>
<p>* Figures also show postal traffic at the two Paris airports last month totalled 11,490 tonnes, an increase of 19.8 percent in July 1995.</p>
<p>* The percentage of global air cargo traffic handled at the two airports in the first seven months of 1996, arriving and departing on full-freighter flights was higher than in the same period last year.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Frankfurt airport and Lufthansa Cargo say the 10th International Frankfurt Airfreight days international cargo conference will take place on September 24-25, 1997.</p>
<p>NEW YORK - American Airlines says it was optimistic that the U.S. and Britain would reach an &quot;open skies&quot; aviation agreement, despite a report that British officials were taking a tough line in the negotiations.</p>
<p>LONDON - The Guardian newspaper reports the chief executive of BA Robert Ayling, has rejected suggestions that talks between Britain and the U.S. for a new open skies agreement would collapse.</p>
<p>LONDON - The Financial Times reported that Virgin Group is planning to expand into South Africa, taking all of the sprawling group's major brand into the country -- Virgin Airlines is already scheduled to begin regular service to Johannesburg in October.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
