<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11602" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - NYMEX crude may fill gap before weekend.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - NYMEX crude may fill gap before weekend.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX October crude's strong rally and settlement on Thursday may translate into further gains today that would allow prices to completely fill an upside gap on the continuation chart left by September's expiry, technical analysts said.</p>
<p>The contract closed on Thursday at $22.30 a barrel and rose to $22.37 in overnight ACCESS trading, further closing the chart space that extends to the low from Tuesday at $22.60.</p>
<p>The quick resumption to the upside into the gap after a two-day correction also means the long-term uptrend is intact.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, the September heating oil and gasoline contracts continue to bounce off support at the lower end of their uptrend channels dating back to late July, the analysts said. This means any consolidation or selloff is likely to be limited.</p>
<p>&quot;I think technically you've got to say this market is going higher,&quot; said an oil trader in Washington. &quot;I would not be surprised to see the highs taken out sooner rather than later.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think that the steps back in the market were very orderly, were not excessive considering the ground we covered, and there was not panic selling,&quot; she added. &quot;The technicals look positive.&quot;  </p>
<p>She said the technical retracement on Tuesday, when prices posted an inside trading day by staying within Monday's session range, and on Wednesday, when an uptrend line was maintained, prove that the bias is still higher.</p>
<p>The stochastics on the daily chart are overbought but other momentum indicators such as oscillators, which are used as a filter, continue to make higher highs and are showing no signs of divergence, she said.</p>
<p>In addition, the stochastics on the weekly chart, which itself looks set to close in a bullish mode today, are not at overbought levels, she added.  </p>
<p>October crude ended on Thursday at $22.30 and hit a contract high of $22.55 on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The question today is whether October WTI can fill the gap on the continuous chart up to $22.60, beyond which $23 and then $23.35 become the targets,&quot; brokers at GNI Ltd said in a report.</p>
<p>&quot;However, there is room for prices to correct without damaging the uptrend and the first level to look for if this takes place is $21.90.&quot;</p>
<p>The Washington trader said September heating oil continues to lead the complex and remains bullish as long as its uptrend line from mid- to late-July is not violated.</p>
<p>She said support comes in today at 61.10-61.20 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>&quot;Gasoline is and has been your weak sister on the board,&quot; said a NYMEX products trader.</p>
<p>&quot;It's considerably off of contract highs where as crude and heating oil are much closer...Gasoline is going to run into resistance at 64.30 to 64.40 cents.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Today I'm a little bearish only because we've had a week up and we may get some profit taking,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- John Hanley, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8185</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
