<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11622" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Metals look to autumn as rate cut fails to excite.</title>
<headline>Metals look to autumn as rate cut fails to excite.</headline>
<byline>Martin Hayes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Metal prices will continue to slumber until the nights start drawing in, after a round of interest rate cuts in Europe failed to excite the market.</p>
<p>Germany's Bundesbank made an above-forecast cut in its repo (securities re-purchase) rate to three pct from 3.3 pct on Thursday, prompting other European central banks to follow.</p>
<p>&quot;It is welcome as the economy is not gaining much strength... but it is symptomatic of how weak the economy is,&quot; analyst Robin Bhar of London Metal Exchange (LME) trader Brandeis (Brokers) Ltd said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank rate cut was a surprise and is probably the best news that the market has heard for some time...it will be a good stimulus for growth,&quot; broker GNI Ltd said in its daily review.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, LME prices and sentiment were unmoved by the economic developments, as the non-ferrous metals market is be-devilled by slow summer trading conditions at present.</p>
<p>&quot;In the very short-term it (Buba cut) makes no difference, as nobody wants to take these markets on at the moment. Long-term -- if it feeds through into offtake, then yes it is positive,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>But even this might take some time to transpire, as the second half of the year is not looking particularly promising so far for metals.</p>
<p>&quot;The European economies will not do much this year...we have a global economy that is chugging along at the bottom. The U.S. is the only bright spot really,&quot; said Bhar.</p>
<p>Traders are hoping that the end of the summer lull -- a period when manufacturers run down activities for annual maintainance and holidays -- will bring some interest and turnover back on to the LME.</p>
<p>This is likely to be a few weeks yet, as there are holidays in the UK next Monday and in the U.S. next weekend.</p>
<p>Once these are out of the way end-users will be looking at their likely requirements for the final quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom, +44 171 542 8080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
