<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11621" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LME traders look to stock data for clue from China.</title>
<headline>LME traders look to stock data for clue from China.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Metal traders and analysts were scouring warehouse inventory data on Friday to see if the 5,675-tonne increase in LME stocks signalled any movement that &quot;hidden&quot; stocks in China might be returned to the market.</p>
<p>Up to 100,000 tonnes of copper was said to be held in Shanghai bonded warehouses. Its ownership is uncertain, but probably belongs to the Chinese Strategic Reserve, industry sources said in Hong Kong on Friday.</p>
<p>There has been concern that this copper, taken out of various LME warehouses over the last few months, may be sold back on to the LME.</p>
<p>If so, metal should show up in the Singapore warehouse. On Friday, however, there were no arrivals, while 100 tonnes were taken out.</p>
<p>Earlier this week industry analyst Peter Hollands of Bloomsbury Minerals Economics, in his latest review, noted that China's reserve may not need to take back 85,000 tonnes of stockpiled copper lent to the West until early 1997.</p>
<p>Some doubted whether this copper would be sold back into the market and shipped out of China once more. Senior traders say the Chinese need more physical metal, as restrictions have been placed on scrap imports.</p>
<p>&quot;Given that demand currently far exceeds internal supply, the Chinese would appear to need to continue importing concentrate and refined product to meet needs for the foreseeable future,&quot; Chris Pearson of the Flemings Global Mining Group said earlier this week.</p>
<p>-- Martin Hayes London Newsroom, +44 171 542 8080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
