<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11630" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: S&amp;P affirms, assigns Cross Timbers ratings.</title>
<headline>S&amp;P affirms, assigns Cross Timbers ratings.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's said on Friday it assigned its B rating to Cross Timbers Oil Co.'s (XTO) proposed issue of convertible preferred stock series A.</p>
<p>&quot;At the same time, Standard &amp; Poor's has affirmed its B rating on the company's 5.25 percent convertible subordinated notes due 2003 and its BB minus corporate credit rating.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The ratings outlook is stable,&quot; an S&amp;P statement said.  </p>
<p>Pro forma the new issue, about $296 million in total debt and preferred stock will be outstanding, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>&quot;The affirmation follows XTO's announcement of an exchange offer, whereby the company plans to replace up to 2.75 million shares of its common stock with new series A convertible preferred stock.</p>
<p>&quot;This transaction modestly weakens the capital structure and financial flexibility. Upon completion of the exchange offer, total debt to capitalisation will remain aggressive at about 66 percent and preferred stock will represent a fairly high 16 percent of total capital,&quot; the agency said.  </p>
<p>Yet XTO's long-lived reserve base, low-risk growth strategy and discretionary portion of capital expenditures should allow it to generate adequate cash flow through the cycle, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>&quot;The ratings reflect XTO's position as an independent oil and gas company with a small asset base (100 million boe, 62 percent gas) and an aggressive capital structure, partly mitigated by a relatively low-risk operating strategy.&quot;</p>
<p>XTO benefits from its relatively balanced reserve and production profiles, as well as better than average finding costs and adequate margins, S&amp;P said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Despite a volatile financial profile, reflecting an active acquisition programme Standard &amp; Poor's expects XTO to increase output and improve cash flow generation while strengthening the balance sheet over time,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>--International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6784</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
