<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11647" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FORECAST-No good news seen in T&amp;N H1 results.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-No good news seen in T&amp;N H1 results.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Half-year results from components and engineering group T&amp;N Plc next Thursday are not expected to contain any good news, analysts said, although the gloom is already largely discounted in the group's depressed share price.</p>
<p>&quot;These shares are flat on their back and they got there partly in anticipation that T&amp;N will show a poor first half,&quot; said one engineering analyst, who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>Chairman Sir Colin Hope warned in May that destocking and the timing of asbestos disposals in Africa would depress the first-half pretax profits below the 77.7 million stg reported in the same 1995 period. Analysts see a drop to around 60 million.  </p>
<p>However, the forecasts for the period are in a wide range, with several grouped around 55 million stg at the bottom and a few out near 70 million stg at the top.</p>
<p>A number of analysts said that there was uncertainty in the market over how the African disposals would be accounted.</p>
<p>Hope said in May the sale &quot;will result in an 8.0 million stg adverse profit effect on the first half&quot;, and said benefits will only flow after 1997 after the disposal proceeds are received.</p>
<p>Analysts said the fact the company had cut back production and reduced stocks during the period must also affect profits now but should position it well for any second half upturn.  </p>
<p>Nevertheless, many automotive analysts remain unsure when car demand and production will pick up again in Europe and say they cannot predict what the second half will bring the sector.</p>
<p>That leaves a vague fundamental trading outlook for T&amp;N -- except that anything should be better than the weak second half of 1995 -- and is the reason some brokers are pessimistic on the company's ability to afford any increase in its interim dividend over last year's 3.0 pence per share.</p>
<p>Others took a more bullish view on the payout, however, and said they saw a chance of a rise, perhaps as high as 3.5 pence.</p>
<p>More than anything, however, analysts want news on asbestos.  </p>
<p>They say enormous uncertainty over its asbestos liabilities is what continues to make T&amp;N's prospects unique among UK firms.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the real, main issue is still asbestos,&quot; said another analyst, who also asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Fears of a collapse of the Georgine settlement, which provides a limit on potential exposure to claims from U.S. sufferers of asbestos-related disease, overshadow the shares.</p>
<p>Analysts said clarification of Georgine's status is unlikely before October and, meanwhile, they call the possibility of T&amp;N finding a new insurance package &quot;a slim lifeline&quot; for the stock.</p>
<p>-- Andrew Huddart, London Newsroom, +44 171 542 8716</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
