<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11645" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Kiwi Eurobonds boom as Australia, Canada lose shine.</title>
<headline>Kiwi Eurobonds boom as Australia, Canada lose shine.</headline>
<byline>Aline van Duyn</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Surging Australian and Canadian government bond markets have left interest rates too low to attract Eurobond investors, new issue traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>Instead, cash has flooded into higher-yielding New Zealand dollar bonds, they said, and this trend is likely to continue.</p>
<p>&quot;The Aussie market rally has made life really tough for Eurobonds,&quot; said the syndicate head at an Australian bank here.</p>
<p>&quot;The sector has been struggling, both in terms of spreads and the drop in retail-targeted issuance,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Similarly, low yields in Canadian dollars have sent coupon-sensitive retail investors elsewhere.</p>
<p>&quot;Canadian dollar Eurobonds have lost their attraction as an alternative to U.S. dollars,&quot; said a syndicate manager at a British bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Yields have dropped below the U.S. at the short end of the curve. Retail investors, who focus on two to five years, can see little appeal, as seen by the lack of issuance,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But issuance of higher-yielding New Zealand dollars has exploded, so much so that Euromarket activity exceeds government bond issuance, dealers said.</p>
<p>The first eight months of this year saw US$2.45 billion equivalent of Eurobonds issued, up from a palty $260 million for the whole of 1995, Capital DATA Bondware figures show.</p>
<p>&quot;Kiwis are an easy sell at the moment,&quot; said a syndicate manager active in the sector.</p>
<p>&quot;All these currencies are seen as alternatives to each other to some extent. A lot of investors are buying U.S. dollars instead of Canadian dollars, and there are also switches from Canadian dollars into the Kiwi market,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Although Australian dollars provide a pick-up to U.S. dollars, New Zealand dollars add even more (see tables).</p>
<p>Around one percent is gained by buying Kiwi over Aussie paper at three years, but at 10 years the gap narrows to about 20 basis points.</p>
<p>Although mainly a retail currency, New Zealand dollars have also been boosted recently by institutional plays in the market, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not just retail. Institutions, especially in Canada and Japan think interest rates will fall in New Zealand,&quot; said the Australian bank syndicate manager. &quot;The question is when.&quot;</p>
<p>Further Kiwi deals are likely in the coming weeks, as retail investors start looking to reinvest maturing paper.</p>
<p>&quot;There are quite a lot of redemptions coming up in September and October. We expect some rollover into Aussie dollars, but also quite a lot of switching into Kiwis,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>* * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * *</p>
<p>-----------------THREE-YEAR SPREADS----------------------</p>
<p>(IN PERCENT)     CURRENT	ONE MONTH AGO  ONE YEAR AGO</p>
<p>USD VS AUD	 -0.906	 0.850	    1.056</p>
<p>USD VS CAD	  0.343	 0.476	    1.767</p>
<p>USD VS NZD	 -2.033	 0.413	   -0.220</p>
<p>-----------------10-YEAR SPREADS-------------------------</p>
<p>(IN PERCENT)     CURRENT	ONE MONTH AGO  ONE YEAR AGO</p>
<p>USD VS AUD	 -1.162	 0.560	    1.344</p>
<p>USD VS CAD	 -0.644	 0.224	    1.071</p>
<p>USD VS NZD	 -1.426	 0.242	    0.074</p>
<p>Source: Datastream International Ltd -- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7748</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
