<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11642" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: E.Europe up in debt market, Latam awaits US numbers.</title>
<headline>E.Europe up in debt market, Latam awaits US numbers.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia and Poland debt prices were firmer on Friday but Latin American paper was steady ahead of U.S. durable good figures for July, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is pretty quiet. The only action is in non-Latin paper. There is good buying in Poland and Russia,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>But, he added, Latin American Bradys were quiet ahead of US durable good figures for July, expected at 1230 GMT, with forecasts predicting 0.3 percent growth from June.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are waiting to see what effect the figure will have on US treasuries before taking positions,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Polish paper was buoyed on Friday by unconfirmed talk that certain paper had received an investment grade from the U.S. National Association of Insurance Commissioners (NAIC).</p>
<p>&quot;If it has received an NAIC rating, the move is significant because it would allow U.S. insurers to invest in those Polish debt instruments and would broaden the investor base,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>In London, Poland Pars were trading at 52.365/52.875 while Poland Discs were trading at 95.000/95.375.</p>
<p>The yields, said traders, were on Friday at their lowest level since issuance but could narrow further.</p>
<p>Russian paper also made headway as renewed jitters over President Boris Yeltsin's health were quelled by his television apperance and return to the Kremlin on Thursday.</p>
<p>Analysts said cooling tension in Chechnya had also helped.</p>
<p>Peter West, economic adviser at West Merchant Bank, said now Yeltsin is back in the Kremlin and the crisis over Chechnya had been diffused, political concern had waned.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors have Russia in their sights. If all goes according to plan, there is plenty more room the upside,&quot; said West.</p>
<p>--Julia Meehan, London newsroom +44 542 27 34</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
