<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11649" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British criminals released early seek compensation.</title>
<headline>British criminals released early seek compensation.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of prisoners in England and Wales looked forward on Friday to an earlier-than-expected release following an embarrassing blunder by their jailers.</p>
<p>And Home Secretary Michael Howard, Britain's interior minister, said many of them may be entitled to compensation for having been kept too long behind bars.</p>
<p>A legal challenge brought by inmates last year led to a ruling by Britain's Court of Appeal that the Prison Service was miscalculating the time due to be served by many prisoners given consecutive sentences for a number of offences.</p>
<p>For instance, a prisoner who spent a month in a remand centre before trial, and was then given three consecutive sentences, should have the total period he had to serve in jail reduced by three months, not one, it ruled.</p>
<p>The Prison Service has only just started to act on this ruling and this week released 45 inmates from three jails.</p>
<p>Asked how many others would be affected, a Prison Service spokeswoman said: &quot;The number could reach double or triple figures, but we are certainly not talking about thousands.&quot;</p>
<p>The Times newspaper reported that prisoners could receive 95 pounds ($147) a day in compensation for the blunder. The bill for the taxpayer could thus run into millions of pounds.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who have been affected and have been kept in prison for longer than they should have been might well be entitled to compensation.&quot; Howard told BBC radio.</p>
<p>He described the error as &quot;extremely regrettable&quot; and said it now needed putting right as soon as possible.</p>
<p>The bungling is a further blow for Howard who has been embarrassed in the past year by a string of adverse court rulings and by critical inquiries into break-outs from two top high-security prisons.</p>
<p>Late last year Howard dismissed the head of the Prison Service, Derek Lewis, after Lewis had criticised him for interfering in the day-to-day running of jails.</p>
<p>Opposition parties seized on the new blunder. &quot;He has been organising the service in a way in which minds have been concentrating on gimmicks... which has taken their eye off the ball,&quot; said Alan Beith of the minority Liberal Democrats.</p>
<p>But Prison Service acting director-general Alan Walker denied Howard was to blame: &quot;It is not the Home Secretary who does the (sentencing) calculations. It is the Prison Service.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
