<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11663" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: PRESS DIGEST - Canada - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Canada - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are top headlines from selected  Canadian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE GLOBE AND MAIL:</p>
<p>- Provincial premiers give Ottawa deadline: All but Quebec back 8-point plan to negotiate new social-policy standards.</p>
<p>- Traces of explosive found on jet debris: TWA craft split near site of residue.</p>
<p>- Prime rate drops to 5.75 percent, some banks trim mortgage rates. The Bank of Canada has again lowered its key interest rate, in what many analysts believe will be its final attempt this year to kick-start a stubborn economy.</p>
<p>- Education system broken, Ontario Education Minister John Snobelen declares: Minister calls costs too high, cites study blaming teachers' pay.</p>
<p>- Ottawa Rough Riders third and long with no time left: Canadian Football League governors will meet on Monday to decide fate of struggling 120-year-old football club.</p>
<p>Report on Business Section:</p>
<p>- CT Financial sells First Federal Savings &amp; Loan: Trust says market conditions right to move U.S. unit to Marine Midland for C$935 million.</p>
<p>- Plot thickens in book war: Chapters Inc's response to the hiring of former employees in a bold attempt to create a national chain has evolved into a strange tale of intrigue involving gumshoes and lawsuits.</p>
<p>- Hudson's Bay profit plunges: Department store chain blames weather, sluggish economy.</p>
<p>- Tide turning against U.S. tobacco giants: President Bill Clinton is placing new limits on cigarette makers and the industry has plenty to lose as smoking becomes an election issue.</p>
<p>THE FINANCIAL POST:</p>
<p>- New low-rate era in sight: Latest prime drop to 5.75 percent could usher in prolonged period of lower-than-U.S. rates.</p>
<p>- CT Financial withdraws from U.S. with C$935-million sale of New York savings and loan.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
