<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11668" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Army watches peaceful Friday prayers in Jordan.</title>
<headline>Army watches peaceful Friday prayers in Jordan.</headline>
<byline>Suleiman al-Khalidi</byline>
<dateline>KARAK, Jordan 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The main Friday prayers that were the starting point for bread riots in Jordan a week ago passed peacefully under tight security imposed by the Jordanian army with only brief demonstrations reported.</p>
<p>In the hilly town of Salt, 25 km (15 miles) north west of Amman, 300 men marched in a main street demanding the release of a handful of residents held in connection with unrest. Some threw stones at police, but the security forces did not intervene.</p>
<p>In Karak, where two days of riots flared last Friday, a few hundred young men lingered outside Omari mosque on leaving, shouting slogans for about 15 minutes.</p>
<p>They did not repeat last week's protests against higher bread prices that turned into the worst unrest in Jordan since 1989.</p>
<p>&quot;Disperse, abstain from forming groups and help maintain order,&quot; the army, which has enforced a loose curfew since the riots, told the crowd through loudspeakers.</p>
<p>The men shouted &quot;Allahu Akbar (God is Greatest)&quot; as a former Islamist deputy, Ahmed Kafawin, told soldiers the crowd would not cause trouble. He had earlier mounted the mosque's pulpit to demand release of detainees, an end to raids on houses and a reversal of the decision to double bread prices.</p>
<p>Armoured vehicles had patrolled streets and guarded entrances to the hill-top city famed for its Crusader castle in tight security before the prayers.</p>
<p>There was also heavy security in the crowded centre of Amman, where smaller clashes had erupted last Saturday, but Friday prayers at the main mosque ended quietly as police in full riot gear looked on.</p>
<p>Many Karak residents said a conciliatory speech by King Hussein on Thursday appeared to ease the tension fuelled by his &quot;iron fist&quot; policy of mass arrests and a military curfew after riots last Friday and Saturday.</p>
<p>The king defended the new bread prices but told parliament deputies -- most opposed to the price increase -- he remained committed to democracy, public freedoms and fighting corruption and abuses of power.</p>
<p>&quot;The king's speech was very clever, he was more lenient and talked about a process of reviewing policies that caused the unrest and re-evaluating prices,&quot; said Mohammad Rawashdeh, a teacher. &quot;He sounded more reprimanding than threatening.&quot;</p>
<p>Farmer Salem Kassassbeh, standing by the mosque doors as worshippers entered, said the Friday prayers were a key test: &quot;There is a state of anticipation for the noon prayers, and if nothing happens after that, then people will be quiet and accept the situation.&quot;</p>
<p>Government officials said authorities would start freeing some of the 200 detainees -- more than half in Karak -- late on Friday if there is no further trouble and expect the king to summon the parliament suspended over the riots by October 1.</p>
<p>While some Karak residents ruled out further unrest because &quot;inciters&quot; were in jail or had fled, many warned of trouble after the army leaves if economic grievances are not tackled and detainees freed.</p>
<p>The king blamed Iraq and a local pro-Baghdad group for the riots after the government raised bread prices under IMF-agreed economic reforms.</p>
<p>But critics blame the riots on poverty and unemployment. Bread is a staple food for the poor who form a majority of Jordan's 4.2 million people.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARAK, Jordan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
