<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11673" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Oman tells Israel to stick to peace principles.</title>
<headline>Oman tells Israel to stick to peace principles.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oman on Friday urged Israel to resume negotiations with Arabs on the agreed principles of the Middle East peace process which paved the way for an exchange of trade missions between the two countries, the official Oman News Agency reported.</p>
<p>&quot;Oman and Israel signed an agreement to open trade missions in the two countries based on the peace process and the peace process is based on the principle of land for peace and United Nations resolutions,&quot; it quoted Minister of State for Foreign Affairs Youssef bin Alawi bin Abdullah as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;And all of these resolutions are in the agreement to open trade offices,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Omani minister &quot;called on Israel not to delay the resumption of negotiations with the Arab sides on the basis of agreed upon principles such as land for peace, (U.N.) Security Council resolutions and the withdrawal from occupied Arab land.&quot;</p>
<p>Oman and Qatar have forged ahead of other Gulf states in opening economic ties with the Jewish state but have stopped short of establishing full diplomatic relations.</p>
<p>Oman opened a commercial interest office in Tel Aviv on August 11, making the energy-rich sultanate the first Gulf Arab state with economic representation in Israel.</p>
<p>The two countries agreed in January to exchange trade missions in a step towards normalising relations. Israel opened its office in Muscat in May.</p>
<p>Other Arab states, led by Syria, have said normalisation must wait until Israel withdraws from all Arab lands it occupied in the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
<p>Hardline Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has angered Arab states by rejecting the principle of trading occupied Arab lands in return for peace, the basis of the 1991 U.S.-led Madrid peace conference.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
