<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11688" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Merger creates Turkey's biggest cement group.</title>
<headline>Merger creates Turkey's biggest cement group.</headline>
<byline>Osman Senkul</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The merger of two big cement producers -- Canakkale Cimento Sanayii A.S. of Cementeries CBR SA/Belgium, and Akcimento Ticaret A.S. of Sabanci Group -- will create Turkey's biggest group in the sector.</p>
<p>Akcansa, the name given to the new company which will be formally formed after Canakkale's extraordinary annual meeting on Friday, will have two plants with a total production capacity of 3.78 million tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;The merger is a big step towards the consolidation of the Turkish cement industry,&quot; Emir Adiguzel, deputy general manager of Canakkale Cimento, told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>The merger makes the group of Cementeries CBR SA/Belgium and the Sabanci Group Turkey's biggest cement producer with a total production capacity of 5.982 million tonnes of cement.</p>
<p>Total sales of the two companies in the first seven months of 1996 were 2.698 million tonnes, including 814,000 tonnes of exports.</p>
<p>Other major cement producer groups in Turkey are the Rumeli Group with a capacity of 4.09 million tonnes, Oyak 3.67 million tonnes, Lafarge-Coppe of France 3.18 million tonnes, SET of France 2.62 million tonnes, Bati Anadolu 1.84 million tonnes and Vicat Cementeries of France 1.33 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Akcimsa and the six companies control 75 percent of Turkey's total production.</p>
<p>&quot;The merger operation will be under the umberella of Canakkale Cimento,&quot; Adiguzel said.</p>
<p>The president of the company is expected to be choosen from Sabanci Group and the vice president from the CBR Group.</p>
<p>&quot;The Canakkale plant will be the export gate of the company, which has its own port with a 10,000 tonnes loading capacity per day,&quot; Adiguzel said. &quot;The plant has a warehouse with 82,000 tonnes storage capacity and bulkers with a maximum capacity of 82,000 DWT can be loaded at its port.&quot;</p>
<p>Canakkale Cimento has a share of about 30 percent in Turkey's total cement exports of 2.156 million tonnes in the first seven months of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;On the other hand, Akcimento is very active in the regional market, the Thrace and Istanbul regions with a very effective chain of dealers,&quot; Adiguzel said, &quot;Akcimento will be our locomotive in the domestic market.&quot;</p>
<p>Akcimento sold 964,788 tonnes of its total sales of 1,097,116 tonnes to the domestic market and exported 132,328 tonnes in the first seven months.</p>
<p>Canakkale Cimento reported 3.60 trillion lira net sales in the first half, up from 2.11 trillion in the same period of 1995.</p>
<p>The company reported a loss of 307 billion lira in the first six months of this year against a 13.9 billion profit in the same 1995 period.</p>
<p>Akcimento reported 2.97 trillion lira net sales in the first half, up from 1.85 trillion last year. The company's net profit soared to 801 billion lira from 78 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
