<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11680" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: SOLIDERE end week up on market.</title>
<headline>SOLIDERE end week up on market.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>SOLIDERE shares rose on the Beirut Secondary Market (BSM) amid quiet trade in the week ended on Friday and dealers did not expect prices to start firming up before the end of August.</p>
<p>A shares rose to $104.625 on Friday on the privately-operated BSM from a record low of $103.00 last Friday and B shares rose to $106.5 from $105.00.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing exceptional is going on at this point,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the trend is still continuing. Prices haven't firmed up yet. I don't expect much to happen before at least end of August, as most people are still on vacation,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>On the official Beirut Stock Exchange, there was trade in only one of the four listed companies throughout the week.</p>
<p>Ciments Libanais closed at $1.1875 on Friday unchanged from last week. Total turnover on the BSE was 7,121 shares worth $8,456.</p>
<p>There was no trade throughout the week in the shares of the three other listed firms, Eternit's, Ciments Blancs' and and Uniceramic's, and.</p>
<p>The BLOM Stock Index (BSI) rose 1.00 percent during the week to 903.09 and the Lebanon Invest Share Price Index (LISPI) rose 0.09 percent to 81.58. Both indexes cover both markets.</p>
<p>Weekly turnover on the BSM rose to 43,208 shares from 29,471 last week and value was $4,318,363 against $3,087,942.</p>
<p>&quot;Long-term investors are still on the sidelines. They are neither interested in selling nor buying at the time being,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>--Beirut editorial, (9611) 864148 602056</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
