<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11686" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan army watches Karak residents go to mosque.</title>
<headline>Jordan army watches Karak residents go to mosque.</headline>
<byline>Suleiman al-Khalidi</byline>
<dateline>KARAK, Jordan 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Authorities mounted heavy security in Karak in advance of Friday prayers, the starting point a week ago for protests against higher bread prices that turned into the worst unrest in Jordan since 1989.</p>
<p>Armoured vehicles patrolled streets and guarded entrances to the hill-top city famed for its Crusader castle as Moslems headed for prayers at the main al-Omari mosque under the eyes of soldiers.</p>
<p>There was also heavy security in the crowded centre of Amman, where smaller clashes erupted last Saturday, in advance of Friday prayers at the main mosque.</p>
<p>However, many Karak residents said a conciliatory speech by King Hussein on Thursday appeared to ease the tension fuelled by his &quot;iron fist&quot; policy of mass arrests and a military curfew after riots last Friday and Saturday.</p>
<p>The king defended the decision to double bread prices but told parliament deputies -- most of them opposed to the price increase -- he remained committed to democracy, public freedoms and fighting corruption and abuses of power.</p>
<p>&quot;The king's speech was very clever, he was more lenient and talked about a process of reviewing policies that caused the unrest and re-evaluating prices,&quot; said Mohammad Rawashdeh, a teacher. &quot;He sounded more reprimanding than threatening.&quot;</p>
<p>Farmer Salem Kassassbeh, standing next to the mosque doors, agreed: &quot;There is a state of anticipation for the noon prayers, and if nothing happens after that, then people will be quiet and accept the situation.&quot;</p>
<p>Government officials said authorities will start freeing some of the 200 detainees -- more than half in Karak -- late on Friday if there is no further trouble and expect the king to summon the parliament suspended over the riots by October 1.</p>
<p>While some Karak residents ruled out further unrest because &quot;inciters&quot; were in jail or had fled, many warned of fresh trouble after the army leaves if economic grievances are not tackled through dialogue and detainees freed.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe people have fled for fear for arrest, or maybe they have become more accepting of the situation,&quot; said Samih Adayleh, carrying bags of fruit and vegetables. &quot;But this could also cause pent up frustrations, even more than before.&quot;</p>
<p>The king blamed Iraq and a local pro-Baghdad group for the protests after the government raised bread prices last Tuesday under IMF-agreed economic reforms. The king has reversed Jordan's close ties with Iraq since he gave asylum to President Saddam Hussein's sons-in-law a year ago.</p>
<p>But critics blame the riots on rising poverty and unemployment. Bread is a staple food for the poor who form a majority of Jordan's 4.2 million people.</p>
<p>The riots began in the Karak and quickly spread to other southern centres last week. By Saturday night there were clashes in Amman.</p>
<p>It was the worst unrest in Jordan since 1989, when riots followed another government decision to raise prices. Then the king dumped his prime minister and began reforms.</p>
<p>So far the king has shown solid support for Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti even though the Islamic-led opposition demanded his removal.</p>
<p>The king's initial uncompromising response to the riots angered many Jordanians but since the unrest was contained he has been meeting deputies and local dignitaries to rebuild links and stage displays of unity.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARAK, Jordan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
