<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11691" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Zenith lands $1 billion contract, plans $100 million plant.</title>
<headline>Zenith lands $1 billion contract, plans $100 million plant.</headline>
<byline>Susan Nadeau</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A consortium of telephone companies and The Walt Disney Co. said Thursday it had signed a $1 billion contract with Zenith to make digital televison set-top boxes for its home entertainment service.</p>
<p>The announcement of the contract for 3 million set-top boxes gave new hope to Zenith, which has struggled with years of losses.</p>
<p>&quot;This really indicates we're back in the business,&quot; William Luehrs, president of the Glenview, Ill.-based company's Networks Services Division, said in a telephone interview. &quot;Anytime somebody gets the opportunity to enter the next era with such a big bang has got to be seen as a strong message to the industry.&quot;</p>
<p>Following the announcement, Zenith's stock soared $5.50 to $16.875 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The consortium, called Americast, said the contract was part of its strategy to develop and market the next generation in home entertainment.</p>
<p>In addition to Disney, Americast's partners are phone companies Ameritech Corp., BellSouth Corp., GTE Corp. and SBC Communications. Americast said Southern New England Telecommunications Corp. has signed a letter of intent to join the group, which plans to provide a home entertainment service similar to cable television.</p>
<p>Zenith also said it planned to build a new $100 million plant in Woodridge, Ill., to make picture tubes for 32- and 35-inch screen TV sets. The company currently buys the tubes from competitors.</p>
<p>The new plant, which is dependent on obtaining financing, will create about 280 new jobs, Zenith said.</p>
<p>The contract calls for production of the set-top boxes over five years. Luehrs said manufacturing will begin and revenue will start to roll in during the first half of next year. The boxes will be made on a build-to-order basis.</p>
<p>Zenith will convert its Chihuahua, Mexico, analogue set-top box plant to manufacture the digital boxes. Luehrs declined to say when the operation was expected to be profitable.</p>
<p>Americast will provide the boxes to subscribers as part of the service. Its service is being introduced in selected markets across the United States.</p>
<p>Luehrs said digital technology in set-top boxes is only the beginning and said the technology will eventually show up in retail consumer electronics.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll build a lot of these devices into television sets, for digital television,&quot; he said. &quot;Although that is not where this particular contract is headed, the fact that there is a strong Zenith presence will pay us dividends in the future.&quot;</p>
<p>Zenith has been plagued by generally soft conditions in the colour television industry, reporting full-year losses since 1989. Last month, it reported a second-quarter loss of $33.2 million, or 51 cents a share, vs. a loss of $45.3 million, or 97 cents a share, a year earlier.</p>
<p>Last November, South Korea-based LG Electronics Inc. bought a majority stake in Zenith.</p>
<p>Robert Gutenstein, an analyst for Kalf, Voorhis &amp; Co., said the contract was &quot;not unique, but it's big.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Digital is coming, it's economic and the question is what will make the consumer happy and at what price.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
