<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11692" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: United orders jets worth $4.4 billion.</title>
<headline>United orders jets worth $4.4 billion.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Drawbaugh</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Airlines has ordered $4.4 billion worth of airplanes from Boeing Co. and Europe's Airbus Industrie, with the the lion's share going to Boeing, the airline announced Thursday.</p>
<p>United ordered 27 wide-body jets -- 19 jumbo 747-400s, six 757s and two 777s -- valued at about $3.5 billion from Boeing and 24 narrow-body Airbus A319s valued at $900 million.</p>
<p>The Chicago-based UAL Corp. unit is the first U.S. airline to order Airbus' latest model, United and Airbus said.</p>
<p>United chose the Airbus planes over competing Boeing 737-700s and 737-300s after evaluating both, a UAL spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;United benefited from substantial discounts to the prices from both manufacturers,&quot; the airline said, noting that the order values it quoted were based on manufacturers' list prices.</p>
<p>United said the planes will be part of its &quot;retire and replace&quot; programme to update its fleet.</p>
<p>&quot;By 2000, the programme is expected to generate more than $100 million in annual operating cost savings, reducing fuel, maintenance and labour costs,&quot; the airline said.</p>
<p>The programme will also ensure that United meets certain noise reduction requirements.</p>
<p>Delivery of all aircraft is scheduled to be completed by 2002, United said.</p>
<p>The carrier said it placed orders with United Technologies Corp.'s Pratt &amp; Whitney unit for engines for the Boeing aircraft and with International Aero Engines AG for engines for the Airbus jets. United Technologies owns 33 percent of International Aero Engines.</p>
<p>The Airbus A319s will replace United's older Boeing 737-200s, the airline and Airbus said. The new planes are configured to seat 126 passengers.</p>
<p>The A319 is a smaller derivative of the Airbus A320. United already operates 34 A320s and will take delivery of 16 more by the end of 1998, they said.</p>
<p>United joins German airline Deutsche Lufthansa AG as the largest airline customers for the A320 family, each with 74 planes.</p>
<p>Airbus Industrie is a consortium made up of French-owned Societe Nationale Industrielle, British Aerospace Plc, Daimler-Benz Aerospace, a unit of Germany's Daimler-Benz AG, and Construcciones Aeronauticas SA of Spain.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
