<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11715" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NOTICE OF SALE - Mass. Health and Educational.</title>
<headline>NOTICE OF SALE - Mass. Health and Educational.</headline>
<text>
<p>SUMMARY NOTICE OF SALE</p>
<p>				  $7,580,000*</p>
<p>		 Massachusetts Health and Educational</p>
<p>			   Facilities Authority</p>
<p>		   Stonehill College Issue, Series F</p>
<p>Notice is hereby given  that sealed bids  will be received by  the  Massachusetts  Health  and  Educational  Facilities Authority at its  offices at 99  Summer Street, Suite  1000, 10th Floor, Boston, Massachusetts 02110 on</p>
<p>				August 27, 1996</p>
<p> until  11:00  a.m.  New  York  time  for  the  purchase   of</p>
<p>$7,580,000* principal amount of its Revenue Bonds, Stonehill College Issue, Series F (the Bonds'').</p>
<p>The Bonds offered for  sale will be dated  as of August 1, 1996 and will mature or have sinking fund redemption on July 1 in the years 1997 through 2026, as more fully described in the Official Notice of Sale.</p>
<p>The Bonds will be awarded to the bidder complying with the terms of the Official Notice ofSale and offering to purchase all of the Bonds at the lowest interest cost, calculated  in accordance with  the true  interest cost  (TIC) method.  All bids must be accompanied by  a certified or cashier's  check or surety  bond in  the amount  of $151,600  payable to  the Massachusetts Health and Educational Facilities Authority or naming it as the beneficiary, in the case of a surety bond.</p>
<p>Copies of the Preliminary Official Statement, the Official Notice of Sale  and the Official  Bid Form  relating to  the  Bonds  may  be  obtained  from  Patricia  A.  Fahy  at   the</p>
<p>Authority, 99 Summer St., Suite 1000, Boston,  Massachusetts 02110 (617) 737-8377 or Public Financial Management, Inc. at 99 Summer Street,  Suite 1020,  Boston, Massachusetts  02110 (617) 330-6914.</p>
<p>Massachusetts Health and Educational Facilities Authority</p>
<p>		By: Robert J. Ciolek, Executive Director</p>
<p>Dated: August 22, 1996</p>
<p>*Preliminary,  subject  to  change  as  described  in  the Official Notice of Sale.</p>
<p>			  (From The Bond Buyer)</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
