<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11749" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US late cash products bounce higher with NYMEX.</title>
<headline>US late cash products bounce higher with NYMEX.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. cash products bounced sharply higher with NYMEX futures by late Thursday, with distillates gaining over 1.25 cents in both centers amid continuing low domestic heating oil stocks.</p>
<p>Although differentials remained stable on heating oil in both centers, absolute prices vaulted 1.50 cents higher with NYMEX.</p>
<p>New York Harbor conventional unleaded M2-grade gasoline gained about 0.60 cent, meanwhile, as differentials weakened about 0.15 cent amid expectations of cargos from Europe and South America, players said.</p>
<p>&quot;Cargoes look like they'll be arriving soon so differentials are coming off a bit,&quot; said one East Coast trader. But he added that NYH reformulated A2-grade remained firm with offers at about 0.85 cent over the print.</p>
<p>As predicted earlier by traders, the market seemed to shrug off news of Wednesday's brief fire at Tosco's refinery in Bayway, New Jersey.</p>
<p>Tosco said late Wednesday that the small fire in the refinery's crude unit had been quickly extinguished and did not affect operations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
