<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11745" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natural Law Party says it can meditate problems away.</title>
<headline>Natural Law Party says it can meditate problems away.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>From the people who brought you hundreds of &quot;yogic fliers&quot; who claimed to defy nature by levitating comes The Natural Law Party, a minor political party that nominated a presidential candidate on Thursday.</p>
<p>At a hotel convention here, the party associated with the Transcendental Meditation (TM) movement named physicist John Hagelin as its presidential nominee for the Nov. 5 election.</p>
<p>The party is running on a platform claiming it can ward off problems before they occur through techniques such as mass meditation that would reduce stress, crime, terrorism and even wars.</p>
<p>&quot;Social stress can be reduced and problems such as crime and violence will automatically decrease,&quot; said a party paper.</p>
<p>Many party members are practitioners of TM, which involves meditating to a repeated word or phrase, called a mantra.</p>
<p>Some advanced TM followers contend they can actually mediate to such a point that they fly. But in a demonstration of &quot;yogic flying&quot; several years ago, critics said the people were merely bouncing off the ground from a sitting position.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
