<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11754" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lumber prices hit 2-year high on strong cash, oil gains.</title>
<headline>Lumber prices hit 2-year high on strong cash, oil gains.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lumber prices hit a two-year high Thursday as strong demand from homebuilders had lumberyards scrambling for wood.</p>
<p>Crude oil closed higher, but gains were pared in late trading on news the United Nations may soon allow Iraq to sell oil. Corn and soybean prices closed higher on news of poor crops in Iowa.</p>
<p>The Commodity Research Bureau's index of 17 futures contracts closed down 0.08 at 249.76 points.</p>
<p>Lumber for September delivery at the Chicago Mercantile Exchange closed up the daily limit of $10 at $396.50 per thousand board feet, the highest price since $397.00 in June 1994.</p>
<p>Analysts and traders said cash lumber dealers let inventories run low this summer in anticipation of lower prices, and now they are scrambling to supply homebuilders.</p>
<p>&quot;There is not enough wood out there; people are snapping it up,&quot; said Roger Champagne, cash dealer for Capital Forest Products Inc. in Annapolis, Md. &quot;Demand far exceeds supply right now.&quot;</p>
<p>In the cash market spruce was quoted from $417.00 to $420.00 per thousand board feet Thursday, up from $412.00 Wednesday.</p>
<p>Crude oil at the New York Mercantile Exchange closed higher, supported by tight inventories of heating oil. But, gains were trimmed in late trading on news that the United Nations may soon approve the final details of a deal to allow Iraq to sell oil to buy food.</p>
<p>&quot;The news came and then we fell some and held,&quot; said a trader, who did not see further price weakness from the news.</p>
<p>A U.N. official estimated it would take seven to 10 days to complete final details to allow Iraq to sell $2 billion worth of oil over a six-month period in exchange for food and aid.</p>
<p>October crude closed up 58 cents to $22.30 a barrel after hitting a high of $22.35.</p>
<p>Before the U.N. news, oil and heating oil prices rose due to continued concerns about low heating oil stocks ahead of winter.</p>
<p>&quot;It's (heating oil) going to continue to lead the way until there is a serious buildup in inventories,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>September heating oil closed up 1.50 cents at 62.48 cents per gallon, after peaking earlier at 62.55 cents.</p>
<p>September gasoline lagged to close up 0.76 cent at 63.88.</p>
<p>At the Chicago Board of Trade, corn and soybean futures turned around in late trading to close higher on news of slow-developing crops in Iowa.</p>
<p>Crop scouts touring northeastern Iowa said corn ears were small and soybean pod counts low.</p>
<p>&quot;Once that came out, we took off,&quot; Vic Lespinasse of Dean Witter Reynolds said of the CBOT futures.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year was also a late year (for crops), but by this time it was starting to catch up,&quot; said Weather Services Corp. President Peter Leavitt, a 20-year veteran of the crop tour. &quot;This is the latest I've seen it in Illinois and Iowa.&quot;</p>
<p>The CBOT December corn contract closed up 3/4 cent at $3.38-1/2 and the November soybean contract closed up 6-1/4 cents at $7.85-1/4. Both contracts reflect the prices at harvest this fall.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
