<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11759" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMF welcomes Yugoslavia's moves to obtain membership.</title>
<headline>IMF welcomes Yugoslavia's moves to obtain membership.</headline>
<byline>Alver Carlson</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Monetary Fund on Thursday welcomed reported measures by Yugoslavia to remove barriers to IMF membership, but made clear that these were only first steps to it being added to the rolls.</p>
<p>&quot;We welcome the measures and hope the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia can fulfill all the necessary conditions to be one of the successors to the former Yugoslavia but this will also require the support of members of the (IMF's) executive board,&quot; a spokesman said.</p>
<p>Earlier, a prominent economist in Belgrade reported Yugoslavia had quietly dropped previous demands and accepted conditions set out by the IMF for restoring its membership in the international lending agency.</p>
<p>The government had adopted an unpublicized decree and will present it to the federal parliament at its August 29 session, the economist said.</p>
<p>&quot;The decree accepts identical conditions presented by the IMF in March. We have lost precious six months and now face a real problem of how to restructure our debts,&quot; Miroljub Labus, a chief economist of the Economic Institute, told reporters in Belgrade.</p>
<p>In 1992, the IMF said that its then-member, Yugoslavia, had ceased to exist and it would be succeeded by five republics -- Bosnia and Herzegovina, Croatia, Macedonia, Slovenia, and Yugoslavia -- once they met the conditions of membership.</p>
<p>Only the reconstituted Yugoslavia, made up of Serbia and Montenegro, has yet to meet the conditions layed out by the IMF to obtain representation in the international body.</p>
<p>The decree reported from Belgrade on Thursday does not contain a word on the legal continuity of rump Yugoslavia -- Belgrade wanted to be seen as the legal successor to old Yugoslavia -- which was at the heart of a dispute with the IMF.</p>
<p>The Yugoslav government said in a statement that the decree  &quot;means Yugoslavia has ratified the IMF document and that its membership with the Fund is recognised without any interruption since 1945.&quot;</p>
<p>Besides agreeing to the legal steps necessary for membership, the IMF said the new Yugoslavia would have to repay or make arrangements for its share of debt carried over from the former Yugoslavia and get the blessing the IMF's executive board, including the United States and other Group of Seven industrial countries.</p>
<p>The former Yugoslavia owed the lending agency about $215 million when it ceased to exist, of which about 37 percent was slated to become a debt of the rump Yugoslavia as an obligation of membership, according to the 1992 IMF statement.</p>
<p>The rest was spread among the other four republics, according their economic size.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
