<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11753" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. denounces jailing of dissidents in Burma.</title>
<headline>U.S. denounces jailing of dissidents in Burma.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Thursday denounced the reported jailing of 11 Burmese dissidents and called on Burma's military rulers to start a dialogue with the opposition.</p>
<p>The opposition National League for Democracy (NLD) reported the seven-year sentences on Wednesday. It said those jailed included Win Htein, personal assistant to the party's Nobel Peace prize-winning leader, Aung San Suu Kyi.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Glyn Davies said Washington was concerned by the reports.</p>
<p>&quot;We view this as another in a series of oppressive actions by the regime to prevent Aung San Suu Kyi and her supporters from exercising their rights,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Davies described as ominous recent actions by Burma's ruling State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC). &quot;The SLORC has violated with impunity the human rights of the Burmese people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;What remains to happen in Burma ... is that (the authorities) enter into a genuine dialogue with the National League for Democracy ... That is the key to reconciliation in that country,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Davies said the United States had not ruled out sanctions against Burma and continued to discuss firmer measures against the Rangoon government with regional powers including Japan, Thailand and Australia.</p>
<p>Washington gained little support for such measures, however, at a meeting last month of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN).</p>
<p>In a separate development, Davies said deputy assistant secretary of state Kent Wiedemann had been appointed new U.S. charge d'affaires in Burma and would take up his post in October. He succeeds Marilyn Meyers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
