<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11756" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dolly set to drop needed rains on S.Texas farms.</title>
<headline>Dolly set to drop needed rains on S.Texas farms.</headline>
<byline>Greg Frost</byline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo. 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Parched farming regions of southern Texas looked set to receive a much-needed dose of rain from Hurricane Dolly, but meteorologists said it may not be enough to relieve months of drought.</p>
<p>Although Dolly has so far missed Texas and has battered Mexico's Yucatan Peninsula instead, it has spun off beneficial rains that fell Thursday throughout southern Texas.</p>
<p>&quot;The next three days or so will be probably be the wettest period that South Texas has seen all year,&quot; said Mike Palmerino, Weather Services Corp meteorologist.  </p>
<p>Palmerino said between 1/2 and 1-1/2 inches of rain fell Wednesday night in the area between Brownsville and Corpus Christi, and that another 3/4 to 2-1/2 inches could fall there over the next three days.</p>
<p>This came as good news to people like Tommy Joe Crutch, a grain elevator manager in McAllen, Texas, who said some fields in his area had received no moisture since last November.</p>
<p>&quot;If Dolly was to come in, it would tickle everybody to death here -- at least the agriculture people,&quot; Crutch said.  </p>
<p>&quot;That would just be ideal for us because not only do we need to replenish the moisture in our soil, we need to get water in our reservoirs for irrigation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ray Prewett, executive vice president of the Texas Vegetable Association in Mission, Texas, said the rains would provide temporary relief to the region's major crops -- citrus fruits, vegetables and sugar cane.</p>
<p>But Prewett said the larger issue was whether the rains would replenish Amistad and Falcon international reservoirs, the two lakes on the U.S.-Mexico border that serve the water needs of the entire lower Rio Grande Valley.  </p>
<p>Prewett said months of drought had left the reservoirs at only about 25 percent of capacity, and that certain irrigation water districts were out of water.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not a solution to our overall irrigation water supply unless Dolly puts rainfall in the watershed of those two reservoirs,&quot; Prewett said.</p>
<p>Of the state's agriculture community, at least one group was not exactly welcoming Dolly's rains.</p>
<p>David Oefinger, executive director of the South Texas Cotton and Grain Association, in Victoria, Texas, said the rains would keep some cotton producers from harvesting.  </p>
<p>&quot;This soaking rain is going to help the drought conditions and the pastures. The cattlemen and ranchers are real pleased with it, but right now we're trying to get the cotton in, and those folks aren't real happy,&quot; Oefinger said.</p>
<p>Oefinger said most of the cotton between Corpus Christi and Victoria was cut before the rains arrived, but that the cotton harvest between Victoria and Houston would likely be delayed by rain.</p>
<p>But the cotton harvest delays may not last long, according to WSC's Palmerino.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like you could very easily go back into a drier pattern there next week,&quot; Palmerino said.</p>
<p>--Kansas City bureau, 816 561-8671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
