<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11768" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Plains feedlot cattle market seen quiet - trade.</title>
<headline>Plains feedlot cattle market seen quiet - trade.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Plains feedlot cattle markets were expected to remain quiet Friday, following this week's record-setting heavy volume, feedlot sources said.</p>
<p>The bulk of this week's sales took place Tuesday at $68.00 per cwt, up $2.00 from the previous week, but many showlists were lighter by then because of active sales late last week and finished the week practically depleted, they said.</p>
<p>Those cattle not sold were being priced at $69.00 to $70.00, but considered too 'green' or unfinished, while packer inquiry was light, with a few bids at $68.00.  </p>
<p>USDA confirmed sales on 155,000 head for the week to date through midday Thursday in the Texas Panhandle/western Oklahoma area, which broke the previous record high of 136,800 the week ended Feb 22 this year, USDA said.</p>
<p>Week-to-date sales in Kansas were pegged at 130,700 head, which snapped the previous record high of 115,059 set the week ended July 28, 1995, according to USDA.</p>
<p>Feedlot cattle prices also were buoyed by a bounce in wholesale boxed beef prices this week, market sources said.</p>
<p>--Bob Janis 312-983-7347--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
