<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11771" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Midwest hogs seen mostly steady Friday - trade.</title>
<headline>U.S. Midwest hogs seen mostly steady Friday - trade.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Midwest direct cash hog prices early Friday were seen mostly steady, instances $0.50 per cwt lower as producers start cutting off the hog flow in response to this week's steep price drop, livestock dealers said.</p>
<p>Declines this week of up to $2.00 were tied to a seasonal increase in hog supplies that was expanding fresh pork production and weighing on wholesale pork prices, sources said.</p>
<p>Top prices in Iowa and Minnesota on hogs delivered to plants Friday were seen ranging from $58.00 to $58.50 and Illinois hogs may match Friday's $59.00 top.  </p>
<p>Indiana buyers said hog prices Friday were expected down $0.50, with a possible top of $56.50.</p>
<p>Light support Friday in the Midwest could surface if demand for Saturday slaughter picks up, sources said.</p>
<p>Early estimates for Saturday's slaughter were at 60,000 head, but could get larger if operations resume at  Cargill Inc's Excel pork plant in Beardstown, Ill, sources said. Operations at the plant was suspended at the end of the first shift Wednesday due to problems with a water pipe. Operations were expected to resume during the second shift Thursday, a company official said Thursday.</p>
<p>--Bob Janis  312-983-7347--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
