<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11777" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US corp bond players plan vacations amid no supply.</title>
<headline>US corp bond players plan vacations amid no supply.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>With nothing on the horizon for upcoming debt issues, corporate bond players are mapping out vacations plans rather than new business, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't have any bond issues on the plate for today or next week. Even our preferreds (deals) have been pretty much cleaned up this week,&quot; said one high-grade syndicate source.</p>
<p>Dealers said that going into next week issuance is expected to be next to nil with skeleton crews on deck ahead of the U.S. Labor Day holiday on September 2.  </p>
<p>Another factor hurting potential debt issuance is the backup in U.S. Treasury yields after this morning's U.S. durable goods report, dealers added.</p>
<p>&quot;The selloff in the Treasury market isn't helping anybody either,&quot; said another syndicate source.</p>
<p>Earlier, the Labor Department reported a stronger-than-expected 1.6 percent rise in July durable goods which triggered a drop in U.S. Treasuries and sent yields, which move in the opposite direction, higher.</p>
<p>Currently, the benchmark 30-year Treasury bond stands at 98-6/32 off 21/32 to yield 6.89 percent compared with 6.84 percent at Thursday's close.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market is extremely quiet. It should stay that way straight through the (Labor Day) holiday and into the next batch of (U.S.) employment data,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Labor Department will release its next batch of employment data on Friday, September 6.</p>
<p>Turning to upcoming yankeee issues, ANZ-Australian New Zealand Bank is still expected to tap the new issue market with a $300 to $450 million in 10-year debt via Merrill Lynch &amp; Co, sources said.</p>
<p>In Thursday's business, the U.S. Agency for International Development for Israel priced $1.0 billion total in zero coupon and fixed-rate debt, via Merrill Lynch and Lehman Brothers, respectively.</p>
<p>--Nancy Leinfuss, 212-859-1675</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
