<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11779" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Midwest seen warming up late next week.</title>
<headline>U.S. Midwest seen warming up late next week.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Temperatures in the U.S. Midwest should be normal to below normal next week though the region is expected to warm up by the Labor Day weekend, meteorologists said.</p>
<p>Earlier forecasts had called for a cooler long-term outlook, but Weather Express Inc chief forecaster Fred Gesser said temperatures next weekend should be two to four degrees (Fahrenheit) above normal.  </p>
<p>The frontal system that brought 0.25 to 1.50 inches of rain to southeast Iowa and northwest Illinois on Thursday will move into the eastern Corn Belt on Friday. The rains should favor southern Illinois, Indiana and Ohio, with amounts of 0.50 to 1.00 inch and 60 percent coverage, Gesser said.</p>
<p>&quot;For the most part, it will be fair, dry, cooler and much less humid from Saturday through Monday,&quot; said Smith Barney meteorologist Jon Davis in his daily weather report.</p>
<p>Another front should move in next Tuesday and Wednesday, but shouldn't bring as much rain as the current front, Davis said.</p>
<p>Gesser said temperatures early next week should average about two to four degrees below normal, with lows in the low 50s and most highs in the low to mid-70s. Highs in the southern Corn Belt should reach into the low 80s.</p>
<p>Temperatures should start rising by midweek, with highs in the mid 80s to lower 90s over the weekend, Davis said.</p>
<p>--Alby Gallun 312-983-7294</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
