<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11773" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Phelps presents final offer to Chino miners.</title>
<headline>Phelps presents final offer to Chino miners.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Phelps Dodge Corp said it has presented its final labor contract offer to unionized employees at the company's Chino copper mine in New Mexico.</p>
<p>A Phelps spokeswoman said the deal - revised since earlier in the week - was presented to the union negotiators on Thursday afternoon. &quot;This is our final offer,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>&quot;The talks have officially adjourned and the unions have indicated they want some time to review these proposals,&quot; the Phelps spokeswoman said. The company has not given the union any deadline to come back to the bargaining table.  </p>
<p>The company's final offer, however, still sought a base pay freeze over a period ending on November 15, 2000 - indicating a contract over four years in length.</p>
<p>The United Steelworkers of America, which represents most of the 670 unionized workers at Chino and is leading the negotiations, wanted a three-year deal with an hourly pay hike in each of the contract years.</p>
<p>USWA officials were unavailable for comment.</p>
<p>The previous three-year labor deal expired on June 30. The 170,000 tonnes per year contained copper mine is operating normally.  </p>
<p>The first of the two key pay changes Phelps made in Thursday's final offer was to raise from $300 to $500 the amount paid to each employee each year of the contract if the price of copper averaged at least 90 cents per pound over a year.</p>
<p>The second change was to reinstate one of the two bonus price bands originally eliminated.</p>
<p>In the previous wage deal employees began receiving bonuses if the price of copper averaged 80 cents or above over a quarterly period.</p>
<p>Initially Phelps wanted the bonus in the new contract to kick in when copper was over 100 cents per pound, but in Thursday's final offer, bonuses would be paid when copper was 90 cents or above.</p>
<p>A higher level of bonuses were also offered along with pension improvements, the Phelps spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>-- New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
