<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11772" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW -  Grupo Minsa seeks strategic partner.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW -  Grupo Minsa seeks strategic partner.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grupo Minsa SA de CV, Mexico's second largest corn flour miller, is looking for a partner to help it with corn purchasing, merchandising and hedging.</p>
<p>In an interview here, Antonio Hernandez Caloca, corporate director of purchasing for Minsa, said discussions with potential partners have been ongoing for four to six months.</p>
<p>He declined to name potential partners Minsa has talked to, adding that no official announcement has been made. Asked if grain merchandiser and processor  Cargill Inc is a potential partner, Hernandez said, &quot;It's a possibility.&quot;</p>
<p>Cargill was not immediately available for comment.  </p>
<p>Minsa already has a corn purchasing agreement with Cargill. In addition, Cargill Investor Services is helping to train Minsa personnel on the use of futures and derivatives.</p>
<p>In addition to finding a strategic partner, Minsa is also shopping for brokers to handle its hedging needs.</p>
<p>Minsa's search for a strategic partner comes on the heels of a partnership announced earlier on Thursday by Gruma SA de CV, Mexico's leading flour miller, and Archer Daniels Midland Co. As part of that deal, ADM will take a 22 percent stake in Gruma and inject $258 million into Gruma, which Gruma said will go toward debt retirement.  </p>
<p>Hernandez said that, like the ADM-Gruma deal, Minsa would likely favor a partner taking a minority stake in the Mexican company, which is majority owned by Raymundo Gomez Flores.</p>
<p>Minsa, which currently produces about 70,000 tonnes of corn flour a month at six Mexican plants, has captured about 26 to 28 percent in market share since the company was formed in October 1993. Its competitor in Mexico is Grupo Industrial Maseca SA de CV, a Gruma subsidiary.</p>
<p>Minsa's Mexican plants have a total capacity of 90,000 tonnes a month. In addition, a Minsa corn flour plant in Red Oak, Iowa, has a capacity of about 4,000 tonnes a month.  </p>
<p>Hernandez said Minsa's focus is on increasing its share of the corn flour market in Mexico and gaining a presence in the U.S. market for tortillas, which has been growing with the popularity of Mexican food in the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;These are our main objectives,&quot; Hernandez said.</p>
<p>Efforts to increase production in Mexico are hampered, however, as the Mexican government attempts to sort out tortilla subsidies in an effort to ease pressure on the government's budget.</p>
<p>Hernandez said one solution may be to offer subsidies to buy tortillas only to certain groups in the Mexican population, such as the elderly or unemployed, or to those who live in outlying areas.</p>
<p>Later, a Cargill spokeswoman declined comment on the possibility of a partnership with Minsa.</p>
<p>Patricia Commins, Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
