<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11783" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Plains feedlot cattle remain at standstill - trade.</title>
<headline>Plains feedlot cattle remain at standstill - trade.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Plains feedlot cattle markets were at a standstill early Friday, and expected to remain quiet well into next week following this week's record-setting large sales volume, feedlot sources said.</p>
<p>Packers reportedly were well supplied with live inventory for next week and will not be looking to buy cattle again until Wednesday or Thursday, the sources said.</p>
<p>Most of this week's showlist was sold, but those cattle remaining were being priced at $70.00 per cwt. No packer bids were reported, but if they surface, they will be steady with this week's top price of $68.00, they said.  </p>
<p>Trades next week also could be influenced by the outcome of Friday's USDA cattle on feed report, market sources said.</p>
<p>The report is expected to show active placements during July, along with small on-feed supplies and slightly larger marketings, compared with a year ago.</p>
<p>Feedlot cattle prices next week also could be dictated by wholesale boxed beef values. If they do not remain strong, it will be difficult to get $70.00 for cattle, the sources said.</p>
<p>--Bob Janis 312-983-7347--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
