<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11790" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US debt futures weaken on U.S. durable goods data.</title>
<headline>US debt futures weaken on U.S. durable goods data.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. debt futures weakened in reaction to the surprising 1.6-percent rise in U.S. durable goods orders for July, but losses were contained within ranges, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's funny how quickly the buyers came back in,&quot; one Eurodollar futures floor source said. &quot;I thought March Eurodollars  EDH7 would at least test 94.00.&quot;</p>
<p>However, March did dip below 94.05, the lower end of the contract's 15-day range. December Eurodollars eased to 94.17, still within its own 15-day range which is capped on the downside at the August 15 low of 94.16.</p>
<p>The upper-end of the 15-day range is at the August 13 high of 94.28.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact December fell through 94.17 to 94.18 has no significance whatsoever,&quot; another Eurodollar trader said.</p>
<p>While one large commission firm sold 2,000 March Eurodollars at the day's low of 94.04, he remained positive on the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Once March takes out 93.97, it's off to the races because people will start covering their positions,&quot; he said. &quot;It will just be a great buying opportunity.&quot;  </p>
<p>September T-bonds, meanwhile, flirted around the 110-00 area due to bond options exercise around 1200 CDT/1700 GMT.</p>
<p>Traders said open interest was equally weighted in both September bond 110-00 put and 110-00 call options.</p>
<p>If the contract dipped much below the 109-28/32 level, the intraday low, further selling pressure would be exerted. But so far, traders are impressed September held above the four-month support level of 109-24/32.</p>
<p>Opening weakness was largely attributed to declines in the German bund market, which failed to sustain Thursday's rally.  </p>
<p>Soon after the opening, one firm sold 1,000 September contracts, while another small brokerage house was seen selling selling 2,000 contracts.</p>
<p>The selling pressure at the outset of pit trade pushed September bonds to the three-week low of 110-09/32, which was set on Thursday. The contract then tested 110-05/32, which is a one-third Fibonacci retracement level from the two-month high.</p>
<p>After the report released, the bond market was poised for a further slide. September bonds fell to 110-00 after one foreign-based firm sold 2,000 to 3,000 contracts. In addition, one large firm has sold 5,000 contracts all morning.  </p>
<p>At 0940 CDT/1440 GMT, September T-bonds were down 22/32 at 109-28/32, December Eurodollars were down four basis points at 94.18, March Eurodollars were down seven basis points at 94.03, 10-year notes were down 14/32 at 106-29/32 and munibonds were up 24/32 at 114-24/32.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
