<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11809" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Haitian coast guard makes major drug seizure.</title>
<headline>Haitian coast guard makes major drug seizure.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Haitian Coast Guard on Thursday made a major cocaine seizure aboard a fishing vessel in cooperation with U.S. Coast Guard authorities and arrested seven men, a U.S. Coast Guard official said.</p>
<p>Lt. Cmdr. Marc Woodring said from Miami that a U.S. Coast Guard cutter, the Dallas, based in Charleston, S.C., had come across a Haitian registered ship in international waters on Monday and detected the presence of cocaine on board, although a quick search could not find any.</p>
<p>The U.S. ship then put in a routine request with Haiti to seize the ship, but the newly formed Haitian Coast Guard requested that the ship be brought to Port-au-Prince instead.</p>
<p>When the ship was towed there, the one-month old Haitain Coast Guard force searched the ship and on Thursday discovered 348 kilos (766 pounds) of cocaine on board, Woodring said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Haitian government arrested the seven people on baord and took six kilos as evidence,&quot; he said. &quot;The remaining cocaine was put on our cutter and taken out to sea to be destroyed.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that five of the men arrested were Jamaican, one was Haitian and another was from Ecuador.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
