<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11805" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Washington Post carried the following stories on its front page on August 23:</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - President Clinton signs historic welfare legislation even as women's groups and advocates for the poor protest outside the White House.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>MOSCOW - As fierce fighting in Chechnya ended, a relatively robust looking Boris Yeltsin went on television to rebuke national security chief Alexander Lebed who brokered the shaky ceasefire.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - A D.C. Superior Court judge ruled that six city schools cannot open on time because fire code violations have not been repaired.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - An African-American woman who says two hairstylists at Bloomingdale's refused to serve her because she had &quot;black hair&quot; has filed a federal discrimination lawsuit.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>JOHANNESBURG - The ruling African National Congress admitted to South Africa's truth commission that it tortured and executed renegade militants in its war on apartheid.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - Humana Inc, one of the nation's largest health care corporations, is pulling out of the Washington area becuase of $30 million in losses this year.</p>
<p>---</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
