<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11814" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: State, federal agents probe Arkansas church fires.</title>
<headline>State, federal agents probe Arkansas church fires.</headline>
<byline>Steve Barnes</byline>
<dateline>LITTLE ROCK, Ark. 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>State and federal agents on Thursday sifted through the rubble of two predominantly black Arkansas churches that burned within minutes of one another late Tuesday and early Wednesday.</p>
<p>Both churches were in the Mississippi delta region of Arkansas, about 90 miles (145 kms) southeast of Little Rock, and were located within three miles of one another.</p>
<p>&quot;We're investigating with the idea that both fires may be arson, but that hasn't been conclusively established,&quot; said Wayne Jordan, a spokesman for the Arkansas State Police.</p>
<p>Agents of the F.B.I. and the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms were also at the scene, Jordan said.</p>
<p>Mount Zion Missionary Baptist Church and St. Matthews Missionary Baptist Church were both frame structures, each near Turner, Arkansas, a small community surrounded by cotton and soybean fields.</p>
<p>&quot;This is rural Arkansas. I'm surprised anyone could even find us out here,&quot; said Fannie Johnson, a member of St. Matthew's, who said she believed arson was to blame.</p>
<p>Others connected with the two churches said they shared that suspicion, although all said they knew of no motive and no racial tension in the area.</p>
<p>&quot;It's sad someone would have that kind of spite in their heart,&quot; said Rev. Jerome Turner, pastor of Mount Zion Missionary Baptist Church.</p>
<p>Arkansas has been spared the loss of predominantly black churches to arson, a wave that has claimed an estimated 30 houses of worship across the south in the past several months.</p>
<p>A black church near Camden, Arkansas, about 100 miles (161 kms) south of Little Rock, burned in July, but federal agents have not determined the cause.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LITTLE ROCK, Ark."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
