<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11811" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE - Herbie Hancock seeks a new jazz standard.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Herbie Hancock seeks a new jazz standard.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Fromartz</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Herbie Hancock has always straddled musical worlds, dabbling in genres, creating new ones, mixing and melding pop and jazz in a way that causes his own sound to evolve.</p>
<p>In his earliest hits from the '60s like the blues funk &quot;Watermelon Man&quot; or the brooding &quot;Maiden Voyage,&quot; Hancock fused soul jazz and hard bop so successfully that bands are still dabbling with those classics today.</p>
<p>He always reinvented, reworked and reinterpreted the music, following closely in the path of his onetime mentor -- Miles Davis. It is what Hancock is about, even if it causes some jazz critics to bite their nails.</p>
<p>Now he is at it again.</p>
<p>With his first acoustic jazz recording in years, the pianist has created what he titled &quot;The New Standard&quot; -- turning the compositions of Stevie Wonder, Peter Gabriel, Prince, Sade, and other popular composers into jazz tunes.</p>
<p>Since the golden era of American song, jazz musicians have always mined popular song. One reason the Tin Pan Alley was such a rich lode for jazz was the harmonic complexity and catchy melodies of the tunes, something that was lost as popular music evolved.</p>
<p>&quot;Harmonically the music isn't as rich as it used to be many years ago, and a lot of melodies today really depend on the delivery of the vocalist. If it doesn't depend on that, then it depends on the words and if you just play it instrumentally that vitality is gone,&quot; Hancock said.</p>
<p>&quot;We had to do a lot of work reconstructing these compositions to make them sound as if they were written to be jazz tunes,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>On the Verve CD, the approach shines on the opening cut. Don Henley's &quot;New York Minute&quot; projects an insistence and intensity enlivened by saxophonist Michael Brecker's cutting, metallic sound. Brecker, whose outing last year with pianist McCoy Tyner won a well-deserved Grammy, adds a fierce edge.</p>
<p>Hancock plays vibrantly, applying his gift for melodic interpretation. With complex harmonies, he is like a painter who focuses intently on a shadow, only suggesting the beauty of the object that casts it.</p>
<p>Peter Gabriel's &quot;Mercy Street&quot; also marks a high point on the disc, with percussive rhythms playing off against a warm and eerie melody, a perfect landscape for Hancock's musings.</p>
<p>It takes a strong band for these reinterpretations to work but with Brecker, drummer DeJohnette, guitarist John Scofield, Dave Holland on bass and Don Alias on percussion, the affinity is electric. All the musicians, save Brecker, played with Miles Davis, which might explain their proclivity to take chances. Davis did it continuously.</p>
<p>In fact, the continual urge to explore new ground is more than evident in the seminal Miles Davis band in which Hancock served as pianist. Just listen to &quot;Miles Davis: The Complete Live at the Plugged Nickel 1965,&quot; which was released last year documenting an entire weekend of appearences by the band at the Chicago club.</p>
<p>Hancock said the aim of those dates was to abstract Miles' tunes, to deconstruct standards and play outside convention.</p>
<p>&quot;We had said before we played the Plugged Nickel that we wanted to play anti-music -- in other words, whatever would be the expected response was the last thing we'd play,&quot; Hancock said. &quot;Miles wasn't a part of the plan, but that was the kind of thing he encouraged. The aim was to destroy things and build them up again.&quot;</p>
<p>It was the spontaneity that Hancock said he enjoyed, a sense of invention that was lacking in the studio dates that the band had with Davis. This urge to reconsider and reshape sound goes to the heart of Hancock's musical concept, even when it comes to his own tunes.</p>
<p>Us3, for instance, the British acid jazz group, had a hit a couple of years ago with a unique dance-club version of Hancock's &quot;Cantaloupe Island.&quot; Asked how he liked it, Hancock said: &quot;It's great. In fact I think Us3 enhances the original. They only use two of the three chords in that song but big deal. They beefed up the bass line and rhythm and made it stronger than the original. When I play it live now, I try to play it like the Us3 version, but I use the third chord.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
