<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11861" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chrysler combines division operations.</title>
<headline>Chrysler combines division operations.</headline>
<dateline>AUBURN HILLS, Mich. 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chrysler Corp said it is consolidating the internal operations of its Chrysler/Plymouth and Jeep/Eagle divisions as part of a long-term streamlining plan.</p>
<p>The automaker said Dodge division General Manager Martin Levine was named general manager of the combined Chrysler/Plymouth and Jeep/Eagle unit.</p>
<p>Ray Fisher, formerly Chrysler/Plymouth general manager, will now head the Dodge car and truck operations. Edwin Brust, formerly Jeep/Eagle general manager, will be appointed to a new position that will be announced separately.  </p>
<p>Chrysler spokeswoman Terri Houtman said any reduction in the company's marketing staffs due to the consolidation will be handled through a previously announced early retirement incentive offer to 1,200 U.S. and Canadian salaried employees during the third quarter.</p>
<p>The automaker plans to take a $50 million to $100 million pre-tax charge against third quarter earnings to cover costs of the early retirements.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a complete, top-to-bottom reorganization&quot; that also includes the automaker's Dodge division, Houtman said.</p>
<p>The changes in part are aimed at improving the focus of the automaker's four major brands -- Chrysler, Plymouth, Jeep and Eagle -- and are compatible with the automaker's dealership consolidation effort, she said.</p>
<p>In 1991, Chrysler began to combine its Chrysler/Plymouth and Jeep/Eagle dealerships under a plan called Project 2000. Currently, about half of the dealers selling those brands offer them under a single roof.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUBURN HILLS, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
