<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11875" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Central bankers to mull next move in inflation war.</title>
<headline>Central bankers to mull next move in inflation war.</headline>
<byline>Caren Bohan</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Major industrial nations are far from solving every economic woe in the 1990s but they all are boasting of major strides in the war on inflation.</p>
<p>With memories still fresh of the turbulence brought on by double-digit inflation in the late 1970s and early 1980s, central bankers are determined to lock in the gains.</p>
<p>Is more progress possible? Can it be achieved without sacrificing too much growth? Or are major nations already giving up too much in the effort to stamp out inflation?</p>
<p>A symposium at the scenic mountain resort of Jackson Hole, Wyoming, late next week will provide an opportunity for central bank officials and prominent economists from around the world to examine those questions.</p>
<p>The August 29-31 forum on &quot;Achieving Price Stability&quot; is being sponsored by the Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City and has generated keen interest in financial markets.</p>
<p>Participants say the discussion comes at an ideal time.</p>
<p>&quot;What is so startling and impressive is that in most of the major industrial nations inflation is hovering near 2 or 3 percent and is even lower in Japan,&quot; said Princeton University professor Peter Kenen.  </p>
<p>&quot;Five years ago, if you had said to central banks that they would be at those levels and that they would be there for a considerable amount of time, everyone would have said you were out of your mind,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Economists pointed to a number of forces that helped to set the stage for declining inflation.</p>
<p>Among those are changes in the structure of the labor market that have made workers less inclined to demand higher wages which in turn has eased any inflation pressures that might stem from wages, said Norman Robertson, a professor at Carnegie-Mellon University.</p>
<p>&quot;It does seem that a lack of job security is contributing to the relative stability of wage increases,&quot;  Roberston said.</p>
<p>&quot;The other major element is the globalization of the world economy and the globalization of markets that has helped hold down prices,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Apart from such structural issues, economists gave the central banks a great deal of credit for reining in inflation.  </p>
<p>&quot;It started way back in the 1980s,&quot; said Stephen Axilrod, a former Fed staff director who is now a consultant to the New York firm MFR Inc. &quot;There has been a gradual understanding about the importance of fighting inflation that probably came out of the problems late 1970s when we had a lot of inflation but no growth.&quot;</p>
<p>Even more recently, he added, &quot;Britain has had crisis after crisis as has France. The kind of stability offered by low inflation has a certain appeal so long as you can begin creating jobs.&quot;</p>
<p>The Fed's decision to raise interest rates pre-emptively in 1994 to prevent price pressures was seen as one example of the tendency of central banks to get tougher on inflation.</p>
<p>In Europe, Germany's Bundesbank has been a model of inflation vigilance during the postwar period. In recent years, the requirements for participation in the Economic and Monetary Union have prompted other European central banks to follow Germany's lead.</p>
<p>&quot;The bottom line of all of this is the tradeoff between price stability and real growth,&quot; said Leonard Santow, managing director at the New York firm Griggs and Santow Inc.  </p>
<p>&quot;The trend worldwide is for central banks to concentrate on price stability,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Yet Santow and Kenen questioned whether in Europe in particular the pendulum has swung too far in one direction.</p>
<p>&quot;When you've got inflation down to somewhere in the neighborhood of two percent, you have to ask whether it's worth paying a significant price (in terms of employment and growth) for further gains,&quot; Kenen said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very worried that the Europeans may be overdoing it,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
