<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11885" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Diana sees restructuring by end November.</title>
<headline>Diana sees restructuring by end November.</headline>
<dateline>CHATSWORTH, Calif. 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Diana Corp said Friday that work with its investment advisor Hambrecht &amp; Quist was progressing and it was hoped that there would be some definitive news to report by the end of November.  </p>
<p>Diana officials said the objective of any restructuring would be to make Sattel Communications, of which Diana owns 95 percent, a &quot;pure play,&quot; or the primary focus of Diana's business.</p>
<p>Diana also has a subsidiary which distributes beef and food products.</p>
<p>Sattel  provides telecommunications equipment for use in public switched telephone networks and Internet service providers. It also provides telecommunications equipment to local and long distance carriers, systems integrators, and interconnect companies.  </p>
<p>In late June, Diana said it was considering several restructuring options including splitting its operating units by industry types into independent, publicly traded companies.</p>
<p>Diana officials told shareholders at the company's annual meeting here Thursday that there are no assurances that any transaction will take place, and there are no assurances as to the timing or value of any such transaction.</p>
<p>After the annual meeting, James Fiedler, chairman and chief executive officer of Sattel, was elected to the Diana board of directors for a one-year term ending in 1997.</p>
<p>	     Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHATSWORTH, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
