<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11884" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mylan Labs adopts shareholder rights plan.</title>
<headline>Mylan Labs adopts shareholder rights plan.</headline>
<dateline>PITTSBURGH 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mylan Laboratories Inc said Friday its board had adopted a shareholder rights plan to give it time to react to any takeover bid.</p>
<p>Mylan said the plan was not adopted in response to any specific takeover bid.</p>
<p>It said the plan would not prevent an acquisition of the company on terms that were fair to all shareholders.</p>
<p>&quot;The plan is designed to deal with the serious problem of unilateral actions by persons that are calculated to deprive the board and the shareholders of their ability to determine the destiny of the company, or to enrich some shareholders at the expense of the other shareholders,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the plan, preferred stock purchase rights will be distributed as a dividend at the rate of one right for each share of common stock held as of the close of business on September 5, 1996, it said.</p>
<p>Mylan said rights would be exercisable and would trade separately from common stock only if a person or group came to own 15 percent or more of the stock or made a tender or exchange offer that would lead to them owning 15 percent or The company also said the board had adopted advance notice provisions in its bylaws, while removing another provision that allowed shareholders to call special meetings.</p>
<p>Advance notice provisions require a shareholder who wants to address an issue to ask the board 60 days before holding a meeting, it said.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PITTSBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
