<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11892" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American Trans Air trims capacity, service.</title>
<headline>American Trans Air trims capacity, service.</headline>
<dateline>INDIANAPOLIS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Amtran Inc, parent of American Trans Air Inc, said Friday it is reducing its lease obligations for Boeing Co's 757 aircraft and also will phase out some scheduled service, including from Boston.</p>
<p>Amtran said the changes result from nearly four months of evaluating its operations in an effort to increase efficiency and ensure stable long-term performance.</p>
<p>Amtran said it signed a letter of intent to cancel leases on five Boeing 757-200s with engines from United Technologies Corp's Pratt and Whitney unit. It will return these aircraft to the lessor by the end of November.</p>
<p>Further reductions in Boeing 757 capacity are expected in the months ahead, Amtran added.</p>
<p>Amtran is also trimming back its scheduled service and, within the next four months, will phase out scheduled service from Boston in spite of good demand there. It cited depressed prices in that market.</p>
<p>Amtran said ATA's scheduled service between Boston and St. Petersburg with connections to three other Florida destinations, including Ft. Myers, Ft. Lauderdale and Miami, will operate through October 26.</p>
<p>Scheduled flights between Boston and Las Vegas will continue through November 14 and flights between Boston and Orlando with connections to Nassau, Bahamas, and Sarasota will operate through December 2.</p>
<p>Other changes include the elimination of service to Grand Cayman and West Palm Beach on September 4, Montego Bay on October 1, and Miami and San Diego on October 27.</p>
<p>Amtran said ATA will assist customers who have purchased tickets in markets affected by the discontinued service.</p>
<p>&quot;Our goal is to deliver high-value service in an increasingly competitive marketplace and to increase our commitment to our charter customers,&quot; Stan Pace, president and chief executive officer, said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's rapidly changing environment requires that all carriers constantly evaluate their routes and schedules to maximize the efficiency of their operations and to best serve their customers,&quot; added Dalen Thomas, senior vice president of sales, marketing and strategic planning.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="INDIANAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
