<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11919" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Daily Variety - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Daily Variety - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tom Cruise will reprise his roles as star and co-producer in the sequel to &quot;Mission: Impossible,&quot; from Viacom Inc's Paramount Pictures, Daily Variety reported on Friday.</p>
<p>Cruise will soon meet with William Goldman, who has been signed to write the screenplay. The picture was the studio's summer blockbuster, grossing $175 million domestically and $338 million worldwide so far.</p>
<p>The newspaper also reported:</p>
<p>* Having lost out on his services once before, Fox and News Corp chief Rupert Murdoch apparently wants former talk show star Arsenio Hall back, this time in a half-hour romantic comedy.</p>
<p>* The 1996-97 TV season start is still about three weeks away, but the new race got under way Wednesday when Fox premiered &quot;Beverly Hills, 90210&quot; and &quot;Party of Five&quot; while the other networks are still for the most part in reruns.</p>
<p>* Former &quot;Late Show&quot; producer Robert Morton said he's changed his mind about a consulting assignment to help revive &quot;Caryl &amp; Marilyn: Real Friends,&quot; a daytime talk show from Capital Cities/ABC Inc's ABC network.</p>
<p>* Stephen Hopkins, who is putting the finishing touches on &quot;Ghost in the Darkness&quot; for Paramount, has signed to direct &quot;Lost in Space&quot; for New Line Cinema with a budget in the $60 million range.</p>
<p>* For a number of reasons, including budget cuts and the proliferation of video and cable, college film programs have over the last decade favored third-run Hollywood blockbusters over foreign films and classics.</p>
<p>* As part of the ongoing restructuring at Warner Brothers' Domestic Television Distribution's &quot;Extra,&quot; about 10 members of the production staff have been let go since Aug 1.</p>
<p>* BBC World, a 24-hour, English-language news network, became the first foreign channel to be launched on a terrestrial frequency in Europe on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- New York newsroom, (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
