<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11918" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: EMERGENCY WEATHER CONDITIONS -  WSC - 23-AUG.</title>
<headline>EMERGENCY WEATHER CONDITIONS -  WSC - 23-AUG.</headline>
<text>
<p>Tropical Storm Niki has been downgraded from a Typhoon as it made landfall over northern Vietnam. Niki will continue to dissipate over land over the next 12 hours. Heavy rains have likely caused flooding. High winds have likely caused wind damage. Heavy rains will linger over northern Vietnam and portions of Indochina over the next 6 hours as Niki dissipates further heightening flooding concerns and the possibility of mudslides. Niki is no longer a primary threat to shipping.  </p>
<p>Hurricane Dolly is centered 180 miles east southeast of Tampico, Mexico, moving west northwest at about 10 mph. Top winds continue at 75 mph. A hurricane warning is up for Mexico from Veracruz to La Pesca. Dolly is expected to make landfall in 6-12 hours with top winds of 80 mph. Dolly is a significant threat to shipping in the southwestern Gulf of Mexico. Heavy rains of 6-12 inches and locally heavier are expected likely causing flooding and mudslids. Storm surge flooding of 3 to 5 feet above noraml tide levels are likely at and around the point of landfall.  </p>
<p>Tropical Storm Edouard is in the open Atlantic about 800 miles west-southwest of the Cape Verde Islands, moving west at 14 mph. It has top winds of 50 mph and is expected to strengthen slightly during the next 24-36 hours while tracking to the west. This system only threatens shipping at this time.</p>
<p>Tropical Storm Orson will be a moderate threat to shipping as it drifts over open waters from near 23n/143e to near 24n/143e during the next 48 hours while steadily intensifying. Orson will likely strengthen to typhoon status by 72 hours. This system will primarily be a threat to shipping this period.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
