<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11917" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton to announce new measures against tobacco.</title>
<headline>Clinton to announce new measures against tobacco.</headline>
<byline>Steve Holland</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton was set on Friday to announce a new series of restrictions on the sale and advertising of tobacco products in the biggest challenge to cigarette makers in over 30 years.</p>
<p>White House officials, speaking on condition of anonymity, said Clinton would make the announcement during a midday Rose Garden ceremony attended by a number of anti-smoking, consumer and health groups.</p>
<p>Clinton's aim is to stop what he considers the tobacco industry's attempts to coax young people into taking up the smoking habit.</p>
<p>He would approve recommendations from the Food and Drug Administration that White House officials said closely parallel the proposals the president sent to the FDA for review last August.</p>
<p>Under those proposals, cigarette companies would be barred from placing billboard advertising near schools and playgrounds.</p>
<p>He also proposed to require age-verified and face-to-face sales and eliminate mail-order sales, vending machines, free samples, self-service displays and sales of fewer than 20 cigarettes.</p>
<p>He also urged that sales or giveaways of caps or gym bags with tobacco company logos be prohibited, as well as brand-name sponsorship of sporting or entertainment events.</p>
<p>White House officials said the new regulations will have some modifications to Clinton's proposals to reflect some of the comments the FDA heard during a review period.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, this major set of restraints on the sale and advertising of tobacco products to minors will mark the first time that the federal government would have asserted jurisdiction over tobacco products.</p>
<p>It is also the biggest government challenge to the tobacco industry since the 1964 Surgeon General's report that linked smoking to lung cancer.</p>
<p>Tobacco companies, already facing assault on many fronts, have made clear they will fight the regulations in court by claiming the FDA does not have the authority to regulate nicotine.</p>
<p>Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole's spokesman Nelson Warfield called the announcement an &quot;election-year gimmick&quot; that could delay a teen-smoking crackdown since lawsuits are already pending against Clinton's proposals.</p>
<p>Clinton campaign spokesman Joe Lockhart fired back that Dole's criticism showed that he &quot;seems more interested in protecting the tobacco lobby than protecting children.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole had come under heavy criticism in June when he said tobacco was not necessarily addictive and that he did not believe the FDA has the authority to regulate nicotine.</p>
<p>The union that represents most tobacco workers said the restrictions could cost thousands of jobs and eventually prompt tobacco companies to move operations out of America.</p>
<p>The Freedom to Advertise Coalition, a group of advertising and publishing associations, said the regulations were overly broad and unconstitutional and poorly targeted.</p>
<p>The White House on Thursday denied Republican charges that the announcement was timed to steer attention away from a government report that drug abuse among teen-agers has skyrocketed during his term.</p>
<p>Republicans also charged that Clinton was timing the announcement to gain maximum publicity ahead of next week's Democratic National Convention.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
