<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11924" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Kohl aims to cut tax burden through reform.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Kohl aims to cut tax burden through reform.</headline>
<byline>Terence Gallagher</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chancellor Helmut Kohl, hoping to blunt criticism of his plans to raise value-added tax (VAT), said on Friday the aim of his planned reform was to reduce the burden on taxpayers.</p>
<p>Kohl, who returned to Germany on Friday from his summer holiday, was hoping to head off an issue that kept simmering through parliament's recess.</p>
<p>A German television poll showed that 60 percent of Germans oppose the chancellor's plan to raise VAT to finance income tax cuts, while only 27 percent think it is a good idea.</p>
<p>&quot;The policy goal of the government and above all, the Christian Democrats (CDU) and Christian Social Union (CSU), is a clear reduction of the burden on taxpayers within the framework of the planned tax reform,&quot; Kohl said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Lowering the burden is of the greatest importance in reviving the economy, creating jobs and strengthening Germany as a production location.&quot;</p>
<p>The public, needless to say, strongly favours tax cuts. But in a mid-August interview from his Austrian holiday home, Kohl said he viewed a VAT increase as unavoidable, to keep a proper balance between direct and indirect taxes.</p>
<p>On Friday, he said VAT would not be raised in the current legislative period, which ends in 1998, and it remained to be seen how much it would have to be increased in 1999.</p>
<p>Kohl said overall tax reform, planned for 1999, would not be financed through an increase in government deficits. Bonn has set up a tax reform commission to draft proposals.</p>
<p>Germans are clamouring for lower rates and a simpler tax system. The business community says the country's extensive social safety net and high taxes hobble companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Tax rates must be reduced for all on a broad front,&quot; Franz Schoser, general manager of the Federation of German Chambers of Commerce, told the Express newspaper.</p>
<p>A cut in corporate tax rates to a maximum 35 percent is vital for the international competitiveness of German industry as well as growth and employment, Schoser said.</p>
<p>The chancellor has come under fire from both his Free Democrat coalition partners and the opposition Social Democrats (SPD) for his tax reform plans.</p>
<p>Rudolf Scharping, parliamentary leader of the SPD, said this month his party would consider a cut in Germany's top personal income tax rate of 53 percent, although it put higher priority on cutting rates in lower brackets.</p>
<p>The government may want to lower taxes to stimulate the economy, but it cannot afford to let its deficit rise if it hopes to qualify for European monetary union in 1999. -- Bonn newsroom, 49-228-2609750</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
