<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11921" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USWC light crudes firm on WTI, Alaskan diffs fall.</title>
<headline>USWC light crudes firm on WTI, Alaskan diffs fall.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast Alaska North Slope (ANS) crude moved up in line with tighter WTI late on Thursday, despite a 10 cent fall in differentials caused by perceptions of excess supplies, traders said.</p>
<p>WTI prices gained at the close on bullish heating oil and fears that Hurricane Dolly would delay Mexican exports.</p>
<p>Traders switched focus to October deliveries of ANS, with outright prices gaining 35 to 40 cents to end at $20.05/20.35. Differentials widened to $2.05 late after a deal was widely reported done, though the buyer was not available for comment.  </p>
<p>The last deal was done at October minus $1.95 a barrel.</p>
<p>Prices for Line 63 also followed WTI higher, but no fixed deals were seen. Arco on Wednesday limited crude oil shipments on Line 63 to 46.81 percent of nominations for September.</p>
<p>Kern River and Wilmington grades were unchanged.</p>
<p>Prices for Canadian light imports rose relative to ANS, on expectations the grades will be kept in midwestern pipelines for maintenance purposes, traders said.</p>
<p>Interprovincial Pipe Line asked shippers to trim nominations on Line 1 by 12 percent. The line runs mixed blend sweet crudes 1,098 miles from Edmonton to the Lake Superior area.</p>
<p>Line 2 shippers must cut back requests by 23 percent. The line carries light, medium, and synthetic crudes along with condesates. Line 2 is a companion to Line 1.</p>
<p>Line 3, which runs from Hardisty to Clearbrook, must trim 20 percent from nominations, the company said.</p>
<p>-- David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles bureau +1 213 380 2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
