<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11922" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: California Senate okays castration of molesters.</title>
<headline>California Senate okays castration of molesters.</headline>
<byline>Adam Entous</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>California's state Senate approved controversial legislation on Thursday permitting the &quot;chemical castration&quot; of child molesters by injecting them regularly with a drug to reduce their sex drive.</p>
<p>The Senate passed the measure by a vote of 25-to-1 and then sent it back to the state Assembly for its approval of certain amendments, one of which would allow doctors to refuse to perform the procedure.</p>
<p>The Assembly, which had approved the measure without the amendments in May, was expected to act on the proposed adjustments by the end of the month.</p>
<p>If signed into law, the California program would the first of its kind in the nation, according to the bill's author, Assemblyman Bill Hoge, a Republican.</p>
<p>Gov. Pete Wilson's office indicated the governor would back the measure. &quot;This is a measure that the Governor can support,&quot; a spokesman said.</p>
<p>Civil rights and psychiatric groups blasted the proposal.</p>
<p>&quot;It's terrible,&quot; said American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) lobbyist Valerie Small Navarro of the bill. &quot;It's unconstitutional. The bill has no due process protections.&quot;</p>
<p>She said ACLU attorneys were mulling legal action.</p>
<p>The legislation mandates that an offender convicted twice of certain sex crimes be chemically castrated unless the felon voluntarily submits to surgical castration. Under the legislation, first time offenders may also be castrated at the discretion of the court.</p>
<p>The child molesters would begin receiving chemical castration &quot;treatments&quot; one week before release from prison and would continue receiving the treatments while on parole.</p>
<p>The cost would be $2,380 per parolee for biweekly injections of the drug Depo-Provera. Some of the side affects of taking the drug are diabetes and hypertension, opponents of the legislation said.</p>
<p>The injections would dramatically reduce the sex drive of the offenders, thereby reducing the risk that they would commit new sex crimes against children, Hoge said.</p>
<p>&quot;Chemical castration has proved to be the most effective treatment available to treat sex offenders,&quot; Hoge said. &quot;It's almost 100 percent effective.&quot;</p>
<p>The legislation was inspired in large part by recent high-profile child molestation cases in the state. Hoge said he authored the bill at the behest of a conservative women's group in southern California.</p>
<p>&quot;We've had so many victims that have come forward on this legislation,&quot; Hoge said in an interview. &quot;It gives them hope. It gives all of those that have been affected by the terrible crime of child molestation hope for the future.&quot;</p>
<p>The state Department of Corrections estimates there are about 680 individuals on parole in California for the type of sex crimes specified in the legislation, including sodomy by force where the victim is under 13 years of age as well as certain cases of child molestation where foreign objects are used.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
