<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11928" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: FOCUS - Dutch PTT first half net up 8.5 pct.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Dutch PTT first half net up 8.5 pct.</headline>
<byline>Keiron Henderson</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 45 percent government-owned Dutch PTT announced higher first half net profit on Friday and restated its confidence in growth at the company for 1996.</p>
<p>Post and telecoms group Koninklijke PTT Nederland NV said net profit in the first half to June 30 rose 8.5 percent to 1.209 billion guilders ($724 million) from 1.114 billion in the first half of 1995. Analysts' forecasts had ranged from 1.210 billion to 1.236 billion.</p>
<p>The interim dividend rose to 1.00 guilder per share, up from the previous 0.90 guilder, while net sales rose to 9.94 billion guilders from 9.41 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;We're very happy, what we've seen in the first half year is an extremely strong half year for PTT Post and a very satisfactory half year for PTT Telecom,&quot; Dutch PTT finance director Cees Griffioen said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Dutch PTT said the postal and telecoms units had both had a good first half with volumes increasing in all sectors and sales growing despite significant price cuts in telecommunications.</p>
<p>&quot;On the basis of what we see...in the first half year, we feel confident that the second half is going to show more growth in volume in post, not necessarily the sort of peak we've seen in the first half but we feel very confident that we will be able to expand further,&quot; said Griffioen.</p>
<p>&quot;Cost control is an extremely important thing for telecom in the second half year but the volume expansion is showing some very encouraging developments, so unless something happens that we don't expect we feel confident that the second half year will see some further growth in earnings per share,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earnings per share in the first half rose to 2.61 guilders from 2.42 guilders. The company made a full year profit of 2.26 billion guilders in 1995.</p>
<p>Operating profit at the postal arm PTT Post BV soared to 418 million guilders from 291 million in the first half of 1995, while PTT Telecom BV increased first half operating profit to 1.77 billion guilders from 1.60 billion.</p>
<p>The 8.5 percent rise in first half net came below the 10.2 percent increase in the first half of 1995, reflecting higher financing expenses and reduced income on investments in affiliated and associated companies.</p>
<p>Interest charges rose to 204 million from 165 million guilders while associates' losses increased to 57 million guilders from 40 million.</p>
<p>Dutch PTT said the results from associates were depressed by an increase in start-up costs incurred by the Unisource business telecoms venture owned jointly with Telia of Sweden, Swiss Telecom and Spain's Telefonica.</p>
<p>&quot;This contrasts with the first half profit achieved by the Czech telecom operator SPT, which has been included in the results for the first time,&quot; Dutch PTT said.</p>
<p>A Dutch PTT/Swiss Telecom consortium took a 27 percent stake in SPT last year.</p>
<p>Share analysts said that at first sight there seemed little reason to change their full year forecasts. &quot;Coming just a million guilders under the forecast range isn't overwhelmingly surprising,&quot; said ING analyst Steven Vrolijk who is continuing to look for a nine to 10 percent rise in 1996 earnings.</p>
<p>Shares in the group fell 0.90 guilders to 61.80 guilders, dipping in a generally weaker Amsterdam bourse.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
