<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11948" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German Bonds weaker, sideways trading seen.</title>
<headline>German Bonds weaker, sideways trading seen.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>German bonds slid to losses on Friday after failing to breach resistance around 98.00. The support level at 97.60 has given way. Trading range today was between 97.37 and 98.06.</p>
<p>At 1447 GMT the September future stood at 97.48 compared to 97.79 at Thursday's close. The 2006 Bund stood at 99.30, yielding 6.34 percent compared to Thursday's close at 99.69.</p>
<p>Traders said they had tested 98.05 today but a level above 98.00 could not be maintained. A technically motivated downward trend set in and brought the future to 97.85 fast. The market has now positioned itself around the level of 97.50.  </p>
<p>The level was reached after traders had tested 97.37/40 on the low side and resistance there held firm.</p>
<p>&quot;The longer we will stay between 97.50 and 98.00 the sooner we will leave the upward trend and move into sideways trading,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Shortly before the weekend and the bank holiday in Britain on Monday traders were not willing to build up big positions. Dealers said the market was set for a quiet start next week with the London futures market closed on Monday.</p>
<p>Bunds will look at the US for further guidance, but not much movement is expected on Wall Street either.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the Bundesbank's surprise repo rate cut to three percent from 3.30 percent would still be the dominating theme next week. Analysts are divided whether all hopes for yet another rate cut are gone.</p>
<p>DG Bank Bond Research said in its weekly commentary that the chances for another cut depend on German economic developments. Should the bullish Ifo business climate report hold true and the economy improve, a cut was very unlikely.</p>
<p>However SBC Warburg in its weekly report argued that a further cut in official interest rates must be ruled out.</p>
<p>- Hannfried von Hindenburg, Fft Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
