<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11959" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Balloon bursts for Belgian OLOs.</title>
<headline>Balloon bursts for Belgian OLOs.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The balloon, inflated by a bigger-than-expected German repo rate cut on Thursday, burst with a bang less than 24-hours later when Belgian OLOs were felled by a technical correction in Bunds.</p>
<p>&quot;We're almost back where we were yesterday,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The benchmark 2006 OLO yield, which closed at 6.56 percent on Thursday, dipped to 6.55 early Friday with the market still in good spirits. But the tables turned quickly when Bunds failed to breach resistance at 98.00, sending the 10-year OLO yield to 6.61 percent in the afternoon.  </p>
<p>One trader said investors preferred to take their profit now instead of building up long positions, believing the Bundesbank gave the wrong signal to markets by cutting its repo rate by 30 basis points.</p>
<p>&quot;It now looks like the Bundesbank is telling the market nothing's going to happen any more for quite some time,&quot; he said. &quot;They overdid it, they should have cut by 10 basis points if they wanted to keep a minimum of confidence in the market,&quot; he said. The fact London would be closed on Monday also helped convince players to decide in favour of profit-taking, the trader said.  </p>
<p>The OLO/Bund yield spread was down one basis point at 27, after briefly narrowing to 25 in morning trade. Traders said it was unlikely to slip further to below 25.</p>
<p>They said they expected the market to consolidate next week, but did not exclude a further weakening either.</p>
<p>On Friday, business was generally quiet with pressure mainly on the section up to five years.</p>
<p>&quot;We've seen people shifting from five to 10 years,&quot; a trader said. &quot;It just shows they want to play it safe,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Bert Lauwers, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6815, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
