<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11958" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Lufthansa Cargo makes Dm48.2mln H1 loss.</title>
<headline>Lufthansa Cargo makes Dm48.2mln H1 loss.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo AG(LCAG) made a half-year loss of 48.2 million marks, including a second quarter loss of 3.5 million marks, the Lufthansa in-house newspaper Lufthanseat said.</p>
<p>LCAG, the autonomous cargo arm of Deutsche Lufthansa AG, said on August 15 it would record a 1996 half-year loss in the 45-50 million marks range.</p>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo spokesman Dietrich Seidl said he could not comment on the figures at present, adding that the airline would first publish official half-year results in a shareholders' report due in late August.</p>
<p>The company made a half-year pre-tax profit of 2.8 million marks last year and a full-year profit of 20.4 million marks.</p>
<p>Half-year earnings dropped one percent to 1.6 billion marks and the airline's cargo load factor also fell one percent to 68.1 percent, the newspaper said added.</p>
<p>Higher cargo volumes were not able to compensate for an average yield fall generated by an increased market capacity and strong rates pressure, it saidthe report noted.</p>
<p>The Asia/Pacific region suffered revenue problems in particular, it said.</p>
<p>Expenditure on fuel and airport charges rose compared to first-half 1995 although by less than budgeted for, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>--Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44-171-542-7706 Fax +44-171-542-5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
