<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11965" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Telefonica jumps on broker recommendations.</title>
<headline>Telefonica jumps on broker recommendations.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Spanish telecoms operator Telefonica de Espana SA were sharply higher in moderately heavy trade, bucking the market trend on the back of broker recommendations and positive sentiment, dealers said.</p>
<p>At 1400 GMT Telefonica was up 55 pesetas, 2.37 percent, to 2,375, while the Ibex-35 general index was down 4.76 percent, 0.12 points, to 4,055.39.</p>
<p>&quot;There's been a lot of strong recommendations on the stock and we saw a lot of real volume this morning. But what we're seeing now seems to be a lot of trading, with many people jumping on the bandwagon as the stock's climbed more than 100 pesetas in two days,&quot; said a trader at Merill Lynch.</p>
<p>This week Caspian Securities recommended buying Telefonica shares, estimating earnings growth of 32 percent in 1997 and setting a &quot;conservative&quot; 12-month price target of US$71 per ADR.</p>
<p>The Merill trader added that news of a preliminary deal with Germany's Kirch-Gruppe to develop digital television in Spain had also possibly helped boost the stock.</p>
<p>&quot;The (television) sector is in vogue at the moment, and seems to have a lot of growth potential,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>However another trader disagreed that the TV deal was affecting the stock directly. &quot;No-one's had time really to evaluate the deal yet,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Telefonica's chairman Juan Villalonga said recently that the sale of the Spanish government's remaining 20 percent in the company to foreign institutions will be carried out in the first half of 1997.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom +341 585 2160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
