<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11962" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Analysts hold Dutch PTT estimates.</title>
<headline>Analysts hold Dutch PTT estimates.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch post and telecoms group Koninklijke PTT Nederland NV's (Dutch PTT) first half results came marginally below most analysts' forecasts, giving scant grounds to adjust full year estimates, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>PTT earlier announced an 8.5 percent rise in net profit for the first six months of 1996 to 1.209 billion guilders, a hair's breadth below the 1.210-1.236 billion forecast range.</p>
<p>&quot;They were pretty much in line with our estimate of 1.210 billion,&quot; said Peter Roe, at Paribas in London. &quot;As we expected volume growth was quite good...there's really no reason to change our forecast and our largely positive view on the stock.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Coming just a million guilders under the forecast range isn't overwhelmingly surprising,&quot; said ING analyst Steven Vrolijk, who is continuing to look for a nine to 10 percent rise in 1996 earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;They've got a very sound domestic business which is doing very well, we remain positive on the stock,&quot; said Roe. &quot;We think it's a solid performer in the Dutch market.&quot;</p>
<p>Roe said he was sticking by his forecast of a 2.45 billion guilder net for 1996. Dutch PTT earlier on Friday repeated a forecast it would improve on 1995's 2.26 billion guilder net profit for the whole year of 1996.</p>
<p>By 1403 GMT the shares were down 1.70 guilders to 61.00 guilders, falling in a weaker Amsterdam bourse. -- Keiron Henderson, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
