<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11977" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: N.Europe rapeseed market sees Scandinavian buyers.</title>
<headline>N.Europe rapeseed market sees Scandinavian buyers.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish and Danish crushers appeared in northern European rapeseed markets where trade buyers were also active, brokers said on Friday.</p>
<p>Rapeseed prices steadied due to rising demand and in sympathy with higher overnight Chicago soycomplex levels.</p>
<p>A lower 1996 rapeseed crop report also lent support.</p>
<p>Trader Toepfer today estimated the German crop at 2.5-2.6 million tonnes, down from 3.1 million last year, and down from June estimates of 2.5-2.7 milion tonnes.</p>
<p>Harvesting is in full swing across the country and yield outlooks are generally lower than last year's 3.2 tonnes/ha.</p>
<p>In addition, farmers complained about uneven ripening as well as high moisture and weed levels.</p>
<p>New crop seed was in short supply as traders and farmers either delivered against pre-harvest contracts or stored seed.</p>
<p>Trade buyers in the north offered 452.50 marks for August seed, five marks more than a week ago and ten marks up from levels four weeks ago.</p>
<p>The Scandinavian consumers reportedly paid 450 marks fob and 465 marks cif a tonne basis 2,000 tonne shipments.</p>
<p>German crushers were more reluctant because they were unhappy with oil and meal crush margins.</p>
<p>Rapeseed buyers at points other than Hamburg offered 447-455 marks for August and 460 for September fob Mittellandkanal.</p>
<p>French rapeseed fob Moselle cost 1,530 francs.</p>
<p>The November position on the Paris Matif futures exchange was last in a 451-456 marks bid/offer range in slim volume.</p>
<p>Local rape meal sellers quoted Aug/October (34 percent protein) at 27.50 marks/100 kg while Nov/Jan was at 28.25 marks. Prices were underpinned by latent feed mixer demand.</p>
<p>Sept rape oil was at 83.25 marks/100 kg, Oct at 84.50, and Nov-Jan at 86.50. --Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
