<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11987" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Strong markka not behind rate cut - Finland Bank.</title>
<headline>Strong markka not behind rate cut - Finland Bank.</headline>
<byline>Peter Starck</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Concerns over the markka's strength were not behind the Bank of Finland's move on Friday to follow the Bundesbank in easing monetary policy, central bank director and board member Matti Vanhala said on Friday.</p>
<p>The Bank's decision to trim the tender rate, its chief monetary policy tool, by 25 basis points to 3.25 percent was based on reports saying inflation should stay subdued, he said.</p>
<p>Asked whether the Bank would feel obliged to act, if needed, in line with Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen's view that the markka should not be any stronger, Vanhala said &quot;No.</p>
<p>&quot;And I don't think that was, even for a moment, the intention behind his remark,&quot; Vanhala told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>Speaking in connection with a Social Democratic Party (SDP) meeting on Wednesday evening, Lipponen said a further strengthening of the markka was not justified when one looked at purchasing power parities.</p>
<p>The markka has strengthened by four percent against the mark and seven percent against the dollar since early May.</p>
<p>Lipponen's view echoed Finnish industry, which has recently repeatedly called for a quick fixing of the markka to Europe's exchange rate mechanism (ERM) before the markka gets a further boost from solid macroeconomic fundamentals.</p>
<p>Finnish industry fears a stronger markka will undermine its competitiveness, particularly against neighbouring Sweden, which is not expected to link the crown to ERM.</p>
<p>But Vanhala said the Bank of Finland has felt no pressure to use the tender rate to hold back a possible firming of the markka after the Bundesbank on Thursday cut its key repo rate and the mark fell against other European units.</p>
<p>&quot;Our commitment is strong, that in this (floating exchange rate) regime our objective is not to determine the trends of the markka on the forex markets,&quot; he said. The markka has floated since September 1992.</p>
<p>But some analysts noted an ERM membership would require living up to the exchange rate stability criterion for the third stage of Economic and Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>A decision from Finland whether to link the markka to ERM is due this autumn.</p>
<p>Vanhala declined to comment on the timetable. He said nobody could object if the prime minister or other politicians responsible for ERM discussed a decision to link, &quot;if any such decision ever becomes topical.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It befits a pluralistic market economy to have many views. I understand those who say the markka is too strong, and I understand those who say it could maybe strengthen,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's good to have debate. That's no problem,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The markka's rise this summer showed confidence in macroeconomic fundamentals like the sizeable current account surplus, Vanhala said.</p>
<p>&quot;We see quite a good picture, a picture of solid confidence in the markka,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Referring to a two percent gaol for core inflation, Vanhala said &quot;We beliveve strongly in our inflation target. It is a good and modern tool ... it fits well into the deregulated world we live in.&quot;</p>
<p>--Helsinki Newsroom +358 - 0 - 680 50 245</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
