<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11983" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch PTT H1 boosted by volume increases.</title>
<headline>Dutch PTT H1 boosted by volume increases.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch post and telecoms group Koninklijke PTT Nederland NV said in a statement with first half results on Friday that volumes increased in all its sectors, while sales grew despite telecoms price cuts.</p>
<p>The company earlier announced first half 1996 net profit rose 8.5 percent to 1.209 billion guilders, just below the analysts' forecast range of 1.210 billion to 1.236 billion.</p>
<p>Operating income at the company rose 12.7 percent to 2.19 billion guilders. &quot;The growth is attributable in part to a relatively small increase of 3.6 percent in operating expenses,&quot; the company said in its results statement.</p>
<p>The company said operating expenses were curbed by tight control over labour costs.</p>
<p>&quot;Additionally, smaller additions to reorganisation provisions than in the first half of 1995 had a positive effect on the growth of operating income,&quot; Dutch PTT said.</p>
<p>It said the 8.5 percent rise in first half net came below the 10.2 percent increase in the first half of 1995, reflecting higher financing expenses and reduced income on investments in affiliated and associated companies.</p>
<p>Interest charges rose to 204 million from 165 million guilders while associates' losses increased to 57 million guilders from 40 million.</p>
<p>Dutch PTT said the results from associates were depressed by an increase in start-up costs incurred by the Unisource telecoms joint venture owned jointly with Telia of Sweden, Swiss Telecom and Spain's Telefonica.</p>
<p>&quot;This contrasts with the first half profit achieved by the Czech telecom operator SPT, which has been included in the results for the first time,&quot; Dutch PTT said.</p>
<p>A Dutch PTT/Swiss Telecom consortium took a 27 percent stake in SPT last year. -- Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
