<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11990" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Toepfer sees lower wheat trade activity in 1996/97.</title>
<headline>Toepfer sees lower wheat trade activity in 1996/97.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Global wheat trade should fall in 1996/97 amid declining import orders from China, German trader Alfred Toepfer said in its newsletter on Friday.</p>
<p>It put global imports at 90.5 million tonnes, compared with 92.6 million in the 1995/96 season.</p>
<p>China was likely to reduce imports by four million tonnes to eight million as its 1996 crop rose by five million tonnes to 107 million.</p>
<p>Ouptut losses in Eastern Europe would not result in additional world market demand, it added.</p>
<p>Russia was likely to keep wheat imports steady at 2.0-2.5 million tonnes. Its total grains crop was expected to rise to about 73 million tonnes, and domestic demand was stagnant.</p>
<p>Most of its wheat imports would come from Kazakhstan, and Russia might have an exportable feed barley surplus.</p>
<p>Ukraine would be able to shrug off a wheat crop reduction of 2.5 million tonnes to 14 million because domestic consumption was still declining.</p>
<p>Toepfer said Ukraine might import bread wheat to make up for quality shortfalls but might export feed wheat, feed barley, feed peas and sunflower.</p>
<p>Wheat demand losses would hit exporters in the U.S., Canada, Argentina, Australia and the EU.</p>
<p>These countries had expanded wheat areas for 1996, especially Argentina, where the 1996 crop might be up five million tonnes at 14 million.</p>
<p>Against this background, the world market could easily cope with a lower than expected U.S. wheat harvest, which would reduce U.S. exports to 26.5 million tonnes from 33.8 million.</p>
<p>Toepfer said world feed grain markets would be tighter than wheat in 1996/97, but demand should be stagnant and prices might ease along with those of wheat.</p>
<p>The trader cited higher barley availability, which might help offset maize shortfalls if U.S. corn output proved to be lower than expected.</p>
<p>Also, Argentina would produce more maize this year and China might reduce imports to a minimum.</p>
<p>-Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
