<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="11992" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: INTERVIEW-Dutch PTT confident of 96 growth.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Dutch PTT confident of 96 growth.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strong first half developments at the main units of Dutch post and telecoms group Koninklijke PTT Nederland NV (Dutch PTT) gave the company grounds for confidence over full year profit, Dutch PTT said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Cost control is an extremely important thing for telecom in the second half year but the volume expansion is showing some very encouraging developments. So unless something happens that we don't expect we feel confident that the second half year will see some further growth in earnings per share,&quot; said finance director Cees Griffioen in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Dutch PTT earlier announced an 8.5 percent rise in half year net profit to 1.209 billion guilders.</p>
<p>The figure came in slightly below the analysts' forecast range of 1.210-1.236 billion guilders.</p>
<p>Operating profit at the postal arm PTT Post BV soared to 418 million guilders from 291 million in the first half of 1995, while PTT Telecom BV increased first half operating profit to 1.77 billion guilders from 1.60 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;On the basis of what we see...in the first half year, we feel confident that the second half is going to show more growth in volume in post, not necessarily the sort of peak we've seen in the first half but we feel very confident that we will be able to expand further,&quot; said Griffieon.</p>
<p>&quot;We're very happy -- what we've seen in the first half year is an extremely strong half year for PTT Post and a very satisfactory half year for PTT Telecom,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Griffioen picked out new European listings for Dutch PTT and its Aa1 rating from Moody's Investors Service and Standard and Poor's AA plus long-term and A1 plus short term corporate credit ratings as first half highlights.</p>
<p>&quot;We're happy that we've been able to obtain two new listings in London and Frankfurt which may enhance the value and liquidity for our European investors. We're happy with the ratings we've received,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>First half earnings per share at Dutch PTT announced earlier were 2.61 guilders a share, up from 2.42 guilders.</p>
<p>The 45 percent Dutch state-owned company made a 1995 net profit of 2.26 billion guilders.</p>
<p>&quot;The board of management of KPN continues to expect a further growth of sales and an increase in net income in 1996,&quot; the company said with its earlier results announcement. -- Keiron Henderson, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
