<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12007" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek stocks hail elections with gains of 1.86pct.</title>
<headline>Greek stocks hail elections with gains of 1.86pct.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek equities greeted early elections with gains for the fifth consequtive day on expectations that snap polls will bring about a strong government that will steer the economy towards its EMU goal.</p>
<p>&quot;Retail, foreign and domestic institutional investors were buying heavily today on expectations that early elections will produce a strong government with a commitment to EMU,&quot; said Costas Panagidis, investment director at Axon Securities SA.</p>
<p>The Athens general share index finished 1.86 percent, or 17.22 points higher at 940.85 from Thursday's 923.63 close after opening at 923.41 points. Turnover jumped to 12.2 billion drachmas on volume of 5.10 million shares.</p>
<p>Greek President Costis Stephanopoulos signed a decree today ordering the dissolution of the 300-seat parliament ahead of early elections on September.</p>
<p>&quot;All sectors showed strength today with construction stocks putting on a brilliant performance that might continue into the fall,&quot; said Panagidis.</p>
<p>Profit taking and corrections would take place before snap elections, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect the bourse to form a base before it heads higher,&quot; he added. &quot;Whether this is the beginning of a rally that will last for a long time is still a question mark.&quot;</p>
<p>Gainers led losers 151 to 69 with 22 issues unchanged on 242 traded. Banks gained 1.47 percent, industrials ended 0.98 percent higher with construction rising 4.34 percent. Small-caps ended with losses of 1.13 percent at 82.07 on the parallel market index.</p>
<p>The Merrill Lynch call spread warrant on OTE with a strike price of 3,800 drachmas was quoted at 585-603 at the close. Shares of OTE telecom, the underlying, ended firmer, up 180 drachmas at 4,085 on heavy volume.</p>
<p>Brokers said Nuntius Securities bought a block of 100,000 shares around 4,000 drachmas.</p>
<p>The recently launched Merrill Lynch stock index call warrant based on a basket of 23 shares was quoted at 222.80-234.50 drachmas. It expires on January 9 1998 with a strike price of 1000. It was in the money at 1038.3.</p>
<p>The Morgan Stanley Hellenic Blue Chip Warrant, which has a strike price of 100 marks, was quoted at 3,733-3,969 drachmas at the close. --Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
