<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12002" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Police raid may mar French image but lure voters.</title>
<headline>Police raid may mar French image but lure voters.</headline>
<byline>Irwin Arieff</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The French government traded an image-loss abroad for domestic political gain on Friday by a police raid on 300 Africans protesting against an increasingly rigid immigration policy.</p>
<p>In ordering a crackdown likely to mar France's reputation as a cradle of human rights, the government focused more on bolstering its conservative credentials ahead of 1998 general elections.</p>
<p>The anti-immigrant far right is threatening to make major gains in these polls, political analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;This morning we have seen the dignity of France. Thank you very much,&quot; said an African woman, one of the 300 holed up in a Paris church for the past two months in hopes of remaining legally in France, as police dragged her to a waiting van.</p>
<p>Later Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre said about one-third of the the 300 would be allowed to stay in France.</p>
<p>Activists, labour leaders and opposition politicians rushed to condemn the decision to storm the church and drag out the immigrants, including 10 on the 50th day of a hunger strike.</p>
<p>The Information and Support Group for Immigrant Workers (GISTI) called for a minute of silence &quot;in memory of democracy&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Domestically, it seems that points of friction and conflict will inevitably multiply. Overseas, the image of our country will long be tarnished,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>But Renaud Muselier, a senior official of the ruling RPR party, said the raid was long overdue.</p>
<p>&quot;The images broadcast around the world should serve as a lesson to others considering illegal immigration,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreigners in France are not at home, but in our home,&quot; RPR deputy Bernard Carayon said. &quot;They have no right to residency, much less a right to challenge our democratic institutions.&quot;</p>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe, ironically a former deputy from the Goutte d'Or neighbourhood where the Saint-Bernard church stands, had repeatedly insisted that he was merely obeying the law in deporting people not entitled to legal residency.</p>
<p>He said he would never use expulsions to break up a family or deport someone who was seriously ill.</p>
<p>But the protesting Africans nonetheless accused the Juppe government of making an example of them because it fears inroads by the fiercely anti-immigrant National Front in the general elections two years away.</p>
<p>The night before the raid, the Front had taunted Juppe for using words instead of actions in hopes of ending the protest.</p>
<p>Following the raid, the Front congratulated him for &quot;adopting the attitude we have strongly advised him to take&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a shame that it took seven weeks for the decision to act, as the National Front would have taken action in 24 hours,&quot; Front official Bruno Gollnisch said.</p>
<p>The government had found itself between a rock and a hard place in dealing with the protest.</p>
<p>The Africans' plight had dominated the news during the quiet summer holiday season, and the government's hardening stance against illegal immigration had threatened to become a volatile issue on the Left even before the raid was called.</p>
<p>Union leaders have threatened new protests -- and perhaps fresh strikes -- in September and October in protest at feared public sector job losses and budget cuts. France is still shaking from a wave of strikes prompted by a government austerity drive which paralysed France last winter.</p>
<p>Yet the same labour unions expressing sympathy for the Africans have been hammering on the government's door for months for a solution to persistent unemployment, which has worsened since President Jacques Chirac took office in May 1995 though he had made jobs his top priority.</p>
<p>In groping for a coherent policy on immigration, France has found itself in the same boat as other industrial powers who eagerly recruited foreign workers during better economic times, only to encounter a rising tide of voter rage when unemployment later soared, along with the cost of public services like health care and education.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
