<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12013" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Bank Italy seen sticking to own agenda on rates.</title>
<headline>Bank Italy seen sticking to own agenda on rates.</headline>
<byline>Charlotte Cooper</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Italy will stick doggedly to its own agenda on lowering interest rates, with no easing likely for months despite European partners' cuts this week and further slowing in Italian inflation, economists said.</p>
<p>Bank of Italy governor Antonio Fazio has constantly stressed monetary conditions were aimed at subduing inflation and the central bank has shown repeatedly in the past year that domestic factors were more important than what its neighbours were doing.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank's move doesn't change things for the Bank of Italy all that much. Obviously, it helps a bit, but it doesn't dramatically alter the position,&quot; said Darren Williams, European economist at UBS in London.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank prompted a round of interest rates cuts among several European partners on Thursday when it lowered its key repo rate 30 basis points to 3.0 percent.</p>
<p>But analysts remember Fazio's determination to beat inflation below 4.0 percent before making the first rate change in more than a year in late July, cutting the discount and fixed-term advances rates 75 basis points to 8.25 and 9.75 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>Many said his latest goal of three percent in coming months meant he was unlikely to budge until November or December.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bank won't ignore the performance of the lira in any rate decision, but at the end of the day, it has told us clearly it's really domestic conditions which are key,&quot; Williams said.</p>
<p>Preliminary consumer prices data from 10 sample cities late on Thursday showed inflation at an estimated 3.3 to 3.4 percent year over year this month after 3.6 percent in July. Month-on-month July inflation was seen rising 0.1 percent compared with a 0.2-percent fall, previously.</p>
<p>Robert Prior, economist at HSBC in London, said &quot;The Bank of Italy won't move in the short term. Inflation is not yet low enough for the bank to move rates down. They've talked about a three-percent target, and we're a little way from that.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;They'll manoeuvre rates looking at average inflation and at the cyclical conditions in the economy,&quot; said Marco Ratti, economist at Banca Commerciale Italiana in Milan.</p>
<p>Estimates on the size of a cut varied from 25 to 50 basis points, with few seeing more than one easing before December.</p>
<p>Another factor that could support an early rate cut was the 1997 budget, which must be presented to parliament by the end of September and passed into law by the end of December.</p>
<p>The ruling centre-left Olive Tree coalition has been warned by the hard-left Communist Refoundation party that it can expect a rough ride over the budget. Communist Refoundation is not in the coalition, but its backing is vital to the government in the lower house of parliament.</p>
<p>Any financial market volatility and lira weakness as a result of political concerns will deter the Bank of Italy from loosening its monetary grip, economists said.</p>
<p>Thus, the timing of any interest rate cut was hard to predict. &quot;The logical view is that it will come very much towards the end of the year,&quot; Williams said. By then, the budget will be in place and inflation will have eased further, he said.</p>
<p>But Giuseppe Abbotto at Banque Indosuez here said if the government and Communist Refoundation could resolve some key policy differences, there was no reason why the Bank of Italy should wait for parliament to pass the budget before cutting.</p>
<p>He forecast a 50 basis-point rate cut in October, led by a gradual decrease in money market rates and slowing inflation.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +39 2 66129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
