<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12028" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: FOCUS-Denmark joins wave of European rate cuts.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Denmark joins wave of European rate cuts.</headline>
<byline>Steve Weizman</byline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Denmark on Friday joined a wave of European countries in cutting interest, dropping its 14-day Certificate of Deposit (CD) rate to 3.50 percent from 3.70 percent.</p>
<p>Denmark's central bank said it decided on the cut as a result of similar moves by Germany, France, Austria, Belgium and the Netherlands on Thursday. Finland and Greece followed suit on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have reduced the rate in the wake of cuts by key European nations.&quot; a central bank spokeswoman said. It was the ninth 14-day rate cut this year, the last of which was on June 6.</p>
<p>The securities repurchase, or repo, rate is expected to fall to match the CD rate at the next repo offer next Thursday.</p>
<p>The deposit and discount rate, cut three times so far this year, was left unchanged at 3.25 pct.</p>
<p>The cut had little effect on the bond market, which had already anticipated the move. Two hours after the midmorning announcement the 10-year bond was one point above its opening 105.14.</p>
<p>The yield gap with the German benchmark rate narrowed to 92 basis points from Thursday's 94 basis points. The Danish crown strengthened slightly to 3.8632 to the mark from its opening rate of 3.8635.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Mogens Lykketoft said the cuts, particularly Germany's, were a sign of renewed growth in European economies -- vital for export-dependent Denmark.</p>
<p>&quot;This can only strengthen the impression that things are going the right way. It is vital for Denmark that the nascent upturn in Europe, and specially in Germany, is growing stronger,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It is of key importance for Denmark that the German trend improves.&quot;</p>
<p>A senior banker welcomed the narrowed gap between the Danish CD and discount rates.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very positive that the difference has been reduced. The distance was very great when the repo and CD rates were 3.70 percent,&quot; Den Danske Bank director Mads Jacobsen told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said that the Danish central bank's decision to cut by 0.20 point, compared with Thursdsay's German cut of 0.30 point, did not neccessarily mean a further 0.10 point Danish cut.</p>
<p>&quot;There is room to cut a further 10 basis points but that is not something I would immediately expect,&quot; Jacobsen said.</p>
<p>&quot;I would imagine that now the gap between the discount and the repo has narrowed there is no longer a great need for isolated adjustment of Danish rates,&quot; he added. --Steve Weizman, Copenhagen newsroom +45 33969650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
