<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12039" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German press says &quot;high time&quot; after repo rate cut.</title>
<headline>German press says &quot;high time&quot; after repo rate cut.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Editorials in German newspapers on Friday mostly praised the German central bank for cutting its main money market rate, the repo, by 3/10 of a percentage point to three percent on Thursday.</p>
<p>Some were critical of the central bank for failing to act four weeks ago, when market speculation of a rate cut had been intense partly because central bank officials had hinted a move was on the cards.</p>
<p>But the papers welcomed that fact that the larger than expected move had cleared the air and defused market speculation of further easings in the near term.</p>
<p>Several newspapers saw the move as positive gesture in support of European Economic and Monetary Union and welcomed the fact that upward pressure on the mark had reduced.</p>
<p>The Handelsblatt business daily said it had been &quot;high time&quot; for the Bundesbank to act.</p>
<p>But it added: &quot;The central bank council more than made up for its failure to act in its final discussions before the summer break with this unexpectedly strong step.</p>
<p>&quot;...The important thing is that the Bundesbank has now given a certain support to the U.S. dollar, which has been weak for weeks, with its interest rate step.</p>
<p>&quot;The European currencies have also gained a certain amount of room to manoeuvre against the strong mark and with France in the lead quickly used (this room) for their own interest rate cuts -- a notable contribution to the European monetary union.&quot;</p>
<p>The Boersen-Zeitung specialist business daily said that the interest rate cut would not act as a panacea for the German economy or dismiss budget deficit problems.</p>
<p>But it added, &quot;At least the tensions in the European Monetary System should be dispelled for some time.</p>
<p>&quot;With the cyclical rapprochement of (European Union) economies and the generally parallel course of their monetary policies the Europeans are gradually becoming a community with a single fate.</p>
<p>&quot;That is a preliminary step to life in the monetary union. Even before its start we are experiencing the good and bad sides of the communality.&quot;</p>
<p>The influential Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung welcomed the decision to cut the repo, but bemoaned the fact that the central bank had made so little effort to explain and justify its move.</p>
<p>It also signalled fear that the Bundesbank was straying from its strict discipline of orienting rate policy to domestic factors.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank made no detailed official statement when it annnounced its move. Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer simply made a brief statement to news agencies, and there was no news conference to present the decision.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing against the reduction of the repo rate in this situation -- which met with much approval,&quot; the FAZ said.</p>
<p>&quot;But there is a certain air of uncertainty about its justification. The impression is strengthened that external economic considerations -- the German economy's exchange rate worries, the exchange rate efforts of its European neighbours -- are gaining importance for Bundesbank decisions.</p>
<p>&quot;...But the charm of German monetary policy lies precisely in its money supply orientation which frees it of politics. That is a process which it is worth salvaging in the 'Euro&quot;-regime which is possibly coming. We should guard it carefully.&quot;</p>
<p>The Sueddeutsche Zeitung and Frankfurter Rundschau focused their comments on the timing of the move.</p>
<p>&quot;One really cannot contest the tactical skill and sense of timing of the central bank council,&quot; the Sueddeutsche said.</p>
<p>Noting that market expectations of a move had waned due to strong economic data in advance of the meeting, it added, &quot;The surprise was complete&quot;.  REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
