<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12040" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain's CEPSA to sell butane by Oct-press.</title>
<headline>Spain's CEPSA to sell butane by Oct-press.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Compania Espanola de Petroleos SA (CEPSA) ) plans to start sales of butane gas in cannisters to Spanish homes sometime from October onwards, press reports said on Friday.</p>
<p>No-one at CEPSA was immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>To date, this market has been dominated by energy group Repsol SA.</p>
<p>Analysts said Repsol's share price should not be particularly adversely affected by the entry of CEPSA into the market, which has been known for some time.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the share price has been affected because of that. As of some time ago what is weighing on (Repsol) is upcoming first half results, which are not expected to be particularly good,&quot; said an analyst at ODDO Securities.</p>
<p>At 0940 GMT CEPSA was up 5 pesetas to 3,925, while Repsol was down 40 pesetas to 4,055. The Ibex-35 was up 0.29 points, 0.01 percent, to 4,060.44.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been known since a while ago that CEPSA-Elf wanted to compete in the butane market&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Repsol has an around 98 percent market share at the moment. It's a big market, but its starting to disappear and be substituted by natural gas and liquid petroleum gas. In fact Repsol Butano is downsizing and readjusting its factories as it is difficult to increase in this market.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom +341 585 2160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
