<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12043" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: INSTANT VIEW - Finland Bank key rate cut.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - Finland Bank key rate cut.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Economists' comments after the Bank of Finland followed the Bundesbank with a cut in its key tender rate on Friday:</p>
<p>OKOBANK Treasury economist Teijo Rantatupa:</p>
<p>&quot;This was a clear sign that Finland is part of Europe and trends in Europe. It was a very good move.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if the rate cut signalled that Finland was in earnest moving towards closer convergence with core European countries in the run-up to EMU, he said: &quot;This is it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I'm surprised the markka did not fall more, only half a penni.&quot;  </p>
<p>The current environment in Finland, as in many other European countries hoping to join EMU was marked by &quot;tight fiscal policy and loose monetary policy,&quot; Rantatupa said.</p>
<p>&quot;Finland is ahead of most of Europe in the business cycle and it is possible that we will be leading the way by perhaps being the first to hike rates next year.&quot;</p>
<p>Jukka Lepomaki, Merita Bank:</p>
<p>Asked if the Bank of Finland had been led by Buba: &quot;I don't believe that has been the motivation. The main motivation was that there is no inflationary pressure and the Bank of Finland has been criticised for too tight monetary policy.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think (this cut) might be the last one, but the interesting thing is at least I see no reason to hike rates until next summer, so March and June FRA rates could come down significantly.</p>
<p>(June FRAs fell to arounf 4.24 percent from 4.33 percent before the cut).</p>
<p>Lepomaki said speculation about an imminent ERM linkage is being fuelled by employers anxious to pressurise the Bank of Finland into ensuring the markka does not link to ERM at too strong a level. @</p>
<p>&quot;I had expected a cut of 10-15 (bps), but Buba moved more aggressively which increased the size of the Finnish cut.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;My personal expectation is that (a markka-ERM link) will come by end-September. When (Prime Minister Paavo) Lipponen said 'in the near future' I think it's a question of weeks, not months.&quot;  </p>
<p>Handelsbanken Finland chief economist Carlo Erakallio:</p>
<p>&quot;We said it would be foolish of the Bank of Finland not to use the opportunity created by the Bundesbank rate cut to lower the tender rate by 25 basis points.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This was very widely expected. It was as discounted as a rate cut could be.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I do not see an imminent ERM link, I don't expect one until late October-Novemer. In my ERM world, there is still room to lower the tender rate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked whether there could be room for another rate cut even if the markka were linked to the ERM within a few weeks, he said:</p>
<p>&quot;Fundamentally, there should be no pressure for the markka to weaken. I think there could be room for (monetary)  easing after a fixing,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>	 -- Helsinki newsroom +35 80 6805 0247</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
