<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12068" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - London Evening Standard - AUG 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - London Evening Standard - AUG 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>EVENING STANDARD</p>
<p>25 MILLION STG BILL FOR JAIL BLUNDER</p>
<p>In an amazing Home Office blunder five thousand prisoners are to be set free at a cost of 25 million stg to the taxpayer. Multiple offenders are to be released after the government admitted it had miscalculated sentences with prisoners who were serving consecutive sentences being kept inside longer than necessary.</p>
<p>ONE-2-ONE SEEKING ONE BILLION STG TO GROW</p>
<p>The mobile phone company One-2-One jointly owned by Cable &amp; Wireless and US West, is understood to be seeking to raise one billion stg from the debt and equity markets. The company wants fresh funds to finance its expansion in the highly competitive mobile phones market.</p>
<p>DATE FOR LUCAS VARITY SHARES DEBUT</p>
<p>Lucas, the components giant will today confirm that trading in the combined group LucasVarity, the combined group with Varity the US brakes and diesel engine manufacturer, will start on 6 September in London and New York.</p>
<p>TELEWEST MOVES TO OFFER PHONES THROUGHOUT UK</p>
<p>Britain's largest cable television company Telewest is to step up its drive into the telephony market by seeking a licence to offer its services nationally and internationally. Oftel is expected to approve the move.</p>
<p>GENCOR TARGETS GFSA FOR 2.5 BILLION DEAL</p>
<p>In a deal that could be worth 2.5bn, South African mining conglomerate Gencor is in discussions about acquiring Gold Fields of South Africa one of the last remnants of the Cons-Gold empire built by Cecil Rhodes.</p>
<p>--For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC on -- BMC +44 71 377 1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
