<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12061" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREECE - AUG 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREECE - AUG 23.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek financial press:</p>
<p>FINANCIAL KATHEMERINI</p>
<p>-- New, favourable restructuring of debts by the National Bank of Greece. The writing-off of debts incurred by finacially troubled firms is probable</p>
<p>-- Macroeconomic fundamentals will work to the socialists' advantage say the economics ministers</p>
<p>IMERISIA</p>
<p>-- Elections to attain EU convergence. The conservatives promise the abolition of objective tax criteria</p>
<p>-- Conditions are ripe for a new interest rate cut</p>
<p>KERDOS</p>
<p>-- First skirmishes between the socialists and the conservatives over the economy</p>
<p>-- The pre-election campaign started on TV. Shots aimed at the government's credibility</p>
<p>EXPRESS</p>
<p>-- The &quot;battle&quot; starts from the economy and the finance minister assures that the tax collection mechanisms will not slacken their efforts</p>
<p>-- 33.5 billion drachmas will be given for improving health services in the Aegean</p>
<p>-- OTE will decide about the digital switches procurement after the elections</p>
<p>NAFTEMBORIKI</p>
<p>-- Convergence with the European Union is the most important national reason for early elections</p>
<p>-- Tax revenues were running at 30 percent in the first 20 days of August. Optimism about expenditures --Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
