<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12063" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: ALANDSBANKEN SEES SMALLER 96 CREDIT LOSSES.</title>
<headline>ALANDSBANKEN SEES SMALLER 96 CREDIT LOSSES.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alandsbanken Ab said in a statement on Friday it expected its full-year credit losses to fall compared with 1995 while net income from financial operations was expected to remain largely unchanged.</p>
<p>The bank's new branches would burden the result somewhat, Alandsbanken said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Net income from financial operations is not expected to changed markedly compared to last year,&quot; Alandsbanken said in its first half interim report. In 1995, net income from financial operations was 113.9 million markka.</p>
<p>In the first six months, net income from financial operations rose two percent to 58.0 million markka.</p>
<p>&quot;Credit losses are expected to fall slightly,&quot; it said. In full-year 1995, credit losses totalled 19.6 million markka.</p>
<p>In January-June, Alandsbanken's credit losses fell to 4.8 million markka from 6.6 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The new branches on the mainland will burden the bank's result somewhat during 1996,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>In January-June, Alandsbanken said total costs excluding credit losses increased 14.6 percent, &quot;mainly as a result of new branches set up on the mainland.&quot;</p>
<p>Operating profit fell 16 percent to 28.6 million markka in the first half. In full-year 1995, it was 45.9 million markka.</p>
<p>--Helsinki Newsroom  +358 - 0 - 680 50 245</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
