<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12077" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FORECAST -W H Smith set for first loss.</title>
<headline>FORECAST -W H Smith set for first loss.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>High street bookshop to music retailer W H Smith Group Plc is set to announce a full-year loss for the first time in its 204-year history on Wednesday, as the company struggles to turn over a new leaf.</p>
<p>Smiths has undergone a sweeping overhall since Bill Cockburn left the Post Office to become chief executive in January. Since then he has sold off the company's stake in the loss-making Do It All do-it-yourself chain, cut the number of business suppliers and made more than 1,000 staff redundant.</p>
<p>The restructuring should result in a full-year loss of about 200 million stg after exceptional charges of 285 million stg.  </p>
<p>The company is making a one-off charge of 140 million stg, the bulk of which covers stock write-offs, redundancy payments and property costs. Another 145 million stg is being written off in goodwill.</p>
<p>Excluding the exceptionals, the consensus of analysts forecasts is for a pre-tax profit figure of 85 million stg, with a range of 75 to 85 million stg.</p>
<p>The group has struggled in recent years with low margins, stores cluttered with too many product lines and increasing competition from supermarkets which have snatched market share in newspapers, magazines, music and video, analysts said.  </p>
<p>In June, Cockburn said his recovery plan, which includes cutting product lines from 49,000 to 35,000 and reducing administration costs, could take four years to bear fruit.</p>
<p>Up to now, the market has given the retailer the benefit of the doubt, with the shares only a few pence below the year's best level. But that could change if Cockburn fails to convince analysts that the company is on the right track.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market will want to here about how the changes are going but this time round, whatever Cockburn says will be accepted,&quot; said Robert Snaith, stores analyst at SG Strauss Turnbull.  </p>
<p>&quot;What will be more important is what Cockburn has to say a year from now,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Snaith believes the market will be unforgiving if Smith's does not make some concrete progress in a year's time.</p>
<p>&quot;Cockburn won't be allowed to keep saying it will take four years to turn things around, especially if you're a shareholder and your fingers are getting burnt,&quot; Snaith said.</p>
<p>Like Snaith, Paribas Capital Markets analyst William Cullum believes Cockburn has &quot;done the right things&quot; by selling off peripheral businesses and concentrating on building up core operations.  </p>
<p>At next week's analysts meeting, Cullum said the Smith's chief executive could announce further disposals. &quot;It would be interesting to see whether Cockburn talks about selling some of the U.S. operations,&quot; Cullum said.</p>
<p>Cullum expects the company to maintain the full-year dividend at 15.65p, the same as a year ago. The market range for the full-year payout is 15.65 to 15.70p.</p>
<p>--Dale Faulken, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
