<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12072" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Aug 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>-- B.A.T SHARES PLUNGE ON US RULING</p>
<p>B.A.T Industries  BAT.L shares fell 24p to 422p yesterday on continued fears over the outlook for its US tobacco interests. Shares have fallen 78p since a Florida court awarded 480,000 stg in damages to a former smoker 10 days ago and wiped out 2.65 billion stg off the tobacco and insurance giant's market value.</p>
<p>-- NATIONWIDE REFUSES TO HELP PERFORMANCE TABLE COMPILERS</p>
<p>Soon to be Britain's biggest building society, the Nationwide, is refusing to help with a major insurance report. The report which ranks the performance of the 20 largest building societies and is produced by UBS, is due out in September. UBS sells the report mainly to bond investors but in the past it has been seen as a shopping list for acquisitive banks looking to buy societies perceived from the list to be good value. Nationwide is currently disputing the credibility of the report.</p>
<p>-- RUSH BY FARMERS STIRS DAIRY CREST FLOTATION</p>
<p>The flotation of Dairy Crest was given a fresh boost yesterday when the company disclosed that dairy farmers have opted for the maximum number of shares allocated to them. Nearly 88 percent of the eligible producers opted for shares rather than cash in the former Milk Marketing Board processing arm. Prospects for the company have been helped by a compromise on raw milk pricing reached two days ago between the Office of Fair Trading and Milk Marque.</p>
<p>THE TIMES</p>
<p>-- GERMAN RATE CUT STARTS A CHAIN REACTION</p>
<p>Financial markets were yesterday surprised by the Bundesbank's aggressive cut in interest rates, a move widely interpreted as an attempt to keep single currency plans on track. Germany's central bank said that it was cutting its repo rate from 3.3 percent to 3 percent and its official discount and Lombard rates were held unchanged. The move was followed by the Bank of France cutting its key intervention rate from 3.55 percent to 3.35 percent. Rates were also cut by Belgium, the Netherlands and Austria.</p>
<p>-- RENTOKIL RULES OUT ANY LARGE DISPOSALS OF BET BET.L</p>
<p>Rentokil surprised the City yesterday by revealing that it was not planning to sell off major parts of BET, the rival business services group it bought earlier this year saying that any disposals would be a refining of the portfolio as distinct from any major sale. Rentokil, the pest control and personnel services company reported pre-tax profits up 35.6 percent to 134.5 million stg in the six months to June 30.</p>
<p>-- NEWS INTERNATIONAL PLC PRETAX SHRINKS</p>
<p>News International announced yesterday a 25 percent rise in operating profit to 153.1 million stg for the year to June 30, on sales up from 841.3 million to 1,007.1 million stg. Its pretax profit, however, fell to 415.9 million stg from 778.7 million. Executive chairman of News International, owner of The Times, said that the results had been achieved in an environment of fierce competition and rising raw material costs.  </p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>-- CBI PREDICTS FEWER TAX CUTS</p>
<p>In a report released today, the Confederation of British Industry has reduced its forecast for tax cuts in the budget, as signs that rising consumer spending will offer a foundation for stronger growth next year. The CBI believe that the Chancellor, Kenneth Clarke, will give away only 2.0 billion stg in tax cuts and this will be more than matched by a 4.5 billion stg reduction in public spending.</p>
<p>-- BASS SET TO CLINCH LONG-BREWING DEAL WITH ALLIED</p>
<p>Bass and Allied Domecq last night put the finishing touches to a deal that will see Bass re-emerge as Britain's biggest brewer, after buying a half share in Carlsberg-Tetley from Allied. An announcement was expected today on the 205 million stg deal but sources said there had been so many postponements that negotiations could extend a little longer.</p>
<p>-- GRID LINES UP SHAREHOLDERS AGAINST REGULATOR'S PLAN</p>
<p>The dispute between the electricity industry regulator and the National Grid intensified yesterday as National Grid called on its million small shareholders to write to Professor Stephen Littlechild, the industry regulator, in protest at his plans to curb its profits. Trade unions are also drafting a joint letter to Professor Littlechild warning about the effect on Grid jobs of the proposed cut in revenues by 1.2 billion stg over a four year period.</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>-- LABOUR ATTACKS UNITED SPENDING</p>
<p>Labour yesterday staged a demonstration outside the London base of United Utilities, the company formed by the takeover of Norweb by North West Water  NWW.L last year. The attack on the excesses of the privatised utilities was stepped up by Ian McCartney, the party's employment spokesman, who claimed the building at 43 Grosvenor Street, Mayfair, would cost 376,000 stg a year to rent, while only two or three rooms are being occupied.</p>
<p>-- GEHE MAY MAKE NEW OFFER FOR LLOYDS CHEMISTS</p>
<p>The German pharmaceutical giant Gehe, said yesterday it might make a renewed offer for Lloyds Chemist at the end of September. Chairman of Gehe's management board, Dieter Kaemmerer, said that the size of the bid would depend on cash raised from the disposal of several Lloyds warehouses. The office of Fair Trading and the Monopolies and Mergers commission made the sale of seven Lloyds warehouses a condition for Gehe to acquire the UK company.</p>
<p>-- PRU SHARES UP ON RUMOURS OF M&amp;G SELL-OFF</p>
<p>Shares in Prudential rose sharply yesterday on expectations that it might abandon its planned 500 million stg float of reinsurance subsidiary Mercantile &amp; General in favour of a trade sale. It was pointed out by analysts that a quick sell-off would allow the Prudential to concentrate on a sudden takeover bid for Woolwich Building Society. Buoyed by the market talk, the insurer's shares close up 17p at 442p.</p>
<p>For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
