<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12076" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Sea lion paparazzi to keep tabs on whales.</title>
<headline>Sea lion paparazzi to keep tabs on whales.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. marine biologists have trained a pair of sea lions to tag and photograph elusive whales as they cruise through the Pacific depths, New Scientist magazine reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>James Harvey and Jennifer Hurley of the Moss Landing Marine Laboratories in California say their sea lions, natural companions of many species of whale, can go where no man or woman has ever gone before.</p>
<p>&quot;Any diver knows that when a whale gets going you can't keep up,&quot; Harvey told the magazine. &quot;That is why we know only about five percent of what whales do.&quot;</p>
<p>The sea lions -- 17-year-old Beaver and nine-year-old Sake -- have undergone six years of training for their mission. Beaver once worked for the U.S. Navy and Sake is an amusement park veteran.</p>
<p>Harvey said they could accurately tag whales with a radio transmitter, and could also swim all the way around one of the giant mammals, filming it with a video camera.</p>
<p>Their first assignment, later this year, will be documenting humpback whale migration off Monterey, California.</p>
<p>The article did not spell out exactly how the sea lions manage to tag the whales but said in training they were taught to stick a radio transmitter on to a plastic model of a whale using suction cups.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
