<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12073" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - NYMEX crude set to test overhanging gap.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - NYMEX crude set to test overhanging gap.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX October crude looks set to test a large gap on the daily spot continuation chart that was left by the expired September contract and hangs just above where prices last traded on ACCESS, technical analysts said.</p>
<p>October crude ended the electronic trading session at $21.99 a barrel and the chart space extends from Wednesday's high of $22.09 all the way up to $22.60, the low from Tuesday when September expired. This includes ACCESS price action.</p>
<p>At the same time, the analysts said they will be watching closely to see if crude's uptrend dating back to July 29 is resuming or if further consolidation is needed to alleviate some overbought indicators.</p>
<p>&quot;If the momentum to this rise is to be maintained, prices need to hold just below yesterday's lows and rally soon,&quot; Elli Gifford at Investment Research Cambridge said in a daily report.</p>
<p>&quot;Indeed, this is quite possible on several of the contracts -- Brent and WTI in particular,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;But it looks less likely as far as unleaded gasoline and heating oil are concerned.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;But none of the indicators has given a major sell. If immediate support does fail, the likelihood is consolidation will set in.&quot;</p>
<p>One commission house vice-president in New York expected crude to trade between $21.50 and $22.25 over the next two days.</p>
<p>He said stochastics and Relative Strength Index levels on the hourly charts had become oversold, so a very near-term bounce was probable, but those indicators on the daily charts have not yet bottomed out.</p>
<p>&quot;We got a little oversold on the short-term stochastic and momentum indicators...But time wise, I would not be surprised to stay between $21.50 and $22.25 and just consolidate in this range for a few days until we see the long-term indicators bottom,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>October crude and heating oil both were able to hold their uptrend lines dating back to late July, which crossed Wednesday near $21.60 and 60.75 cents a gallon, respectively, he said.</p>
<p>He put resistance for heating oil at 61.65 and its contract high of 62.85.</p>
<p>-- John Hanley, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8185</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
