<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12074" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Prisoners get freedom after British blunder found.</title>
<headline>Prisoners get freedom after British blunder found.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of British prisoners on Thursday looked forward to freedom earlier than expected after a blunder in calculating their sentences was uncovered.</p>
<p>Prison sources estimated that between 400 and 500 prisoners would be freed and another 4,000-5,000 would have their release dates brought forward because of the mistake.</p>
<p>The error, brought to light by a series of legal challenges by inmates, stemmed from the prison service's failure to take full account of time served on remand in the case of prisoners given consecutive sentences.</p>
<p>The prison service confirmed that 33 prisoners were released on Wednesday from a jail in northern England and that the sentences of other inmates were being checked.</p>
<p>&quot;We're seeing hundreds of prisoners being released early, most of them convicted of many offences. They're turning up at probation offices, according to phone calls I've had today, completely unexpectedly,&quot; Harry Fletcher of the Probation Officers Association told ITN News.</p>
<p>Those unfairly jailed could be entitled to sue the government for compensation.</p>
<p>The bungling is a further blow for Home Secretary Michael Howard, Britain's interior minister, who has been embarrassed in the past year by a string of adverse court rulings and by break-outs from two top high-security prisons.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
