<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12097" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: DIARY - Changes to Worldwide flight schedules.</title>
<headline>DIARY - Changes to Worldwide flight schedules.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>This is a Reuters diary of changes to worldwide flight schedules.</p>
<p>If you wish to contribute to the diary contact: Air cargo newsroom, Tel: +44 171 542 7706 Fax: +44 171 542 5017.</p>
<p>**AUGUST 18**</p>
<p>- PSA, who operate under the USAir banner start operations three-daily services between Huntsville, Alabama and Washington from Heathrow.</p>
<p>**AUGUST 19**</p>
<p>- Codesharing pact begin between Finnair and Lithuanian Airlines.</p>
<p>**AUGUST 26**</p>
<p>- Maersk Air increases flights between Birmingham and Milan with three weekday services linking the two cities.</p>
<p>**SEPTEMBER 2**</p>
<p>- Malmo Aviation starts two flight daily service (on weekdays) from Sturup, southern Sweden to London City airport.</p>
<p>- Eurowings Luftverkehrs AG launch a five time per week non-stop service from Dusseldorf to Katowice, Poland.</p>
<p>- Virgin Express introduce low-cost daily flights from Geneva to Brussels.</p>
<p>- Virgin Express begin daily scheduled service between Rome and Madrid, Virgin will operate B737-300 aircraft for this new service.</p>
<p>**SEPTEMBER 4**</p>
<p>American Airlines introduce new nonstop service between Austin and Boston, and Austin and Los Angeles. Both routes will be serviced by 139-seat McDonnell Douglas Super 80 jets.</p>
<p>**SEPTEMBER 5**</p>
<p>- Virgin Express introduce low-cost daily flights between Copenhagen and Brussels.</p>
<p>- America West Airlines introduce daily Los Angeles-Columbus flight</p>
<p>- All Nippon Airways begin once weekly service from Bombay to Kansai.</p>
<p>**SEPTEMBER 6**</p>
<p>- Western-Pacific airlines begin service from Colorado to Orlando and Ontario.</p>
<p>** SEPTEMBER 11**</p>
<p>- Polar Air Cargo start new service from Taipei and Singapore to San Francisco and los Angeles.</p>
<p>**SEPTEMBER 12**</p>
<p>- Royal Brunei Airlines start twice-weekly Boeing 767 service linking Brunei with Burma and London. The new service increases the number of London-Brunei flights from four to six days a week.</p>
<p>SEPTEMBER 23</p>
<p>- Swissair introduce weekly cargo-only flight from Basle to Sao Paulo -- its first cargo flight to South America.</p>
<p>**OCTOBER 1**</p>
<p>- Debonair introduce connections from Newcastle via Luton to Munich, Dusseldorf, Barcelona and Copenhagen.</p>
<p>**OCTOBER 2**</p>
<p>- Virgin launches new service from London-Heathrow to Johannesburg.</p>
<p>**OCTOBER 3**</p>
<p>- Malev Rt introduce twice-weekly flights from Hungary to Bangkok.</p>
<p>**OCTOBER 4**</p>
<p>- America West airlines start two daily Seattle-Santa Ana nonstop service.</p>
<p>- America Trans Air introduce Santo Domingo as its newsest destination</p>
<p>- All Nippon Airways begin twice-weekly service from Narita to New Delhi.</p>
<p>**OCTOBER 27**</p>
<p>- Finnair ceases flights fron Helsinki to Geneva.</p>
<p>-Swissair introduce new timetable which allow it to add a &quot;forth daily peak&quot; and offer more daily departures from Zurich</p>
<p>- Lufthansa suspends passenger flights from Frankfurt to Bahrain.</p>
<p>- Southwest Airlines begin service from T.F.Green airport in Rhode Island with 14 nonstop flights to five cities: Baltimore/Washington, Chicago Midway, Nashville, Orlando and Tampa Bay.</p>
<p>**OCTOBER 28**</p>
<p>- Korean Airlines begin thrice-weekly Seoul-Denver service as an extension of the airlines Seoul-Los Angeles flights sharing belly space with Los Angeles.</p>
<p>**OCTOBER 31**</p>
<p>- United Airlines expand service to six new cities.</p>
<p>- AirWays Corp stop service to Nashville.</p>
<p>**NOVEMBER 1**</p>
<p>- South African Airways introduces scheduled service between South Africa and Japan twice weekly.</p>
<p>- Delta airlines start a second daily round-trip service between Cincinnati and Frankfurt.</p>
<p>- Cyprus Airways and Alitalia begin using joint flight code numbers for flights to and from Rome and Larnaca during the winter period only.</p>
<p>- South African Airways postpone inauguration of service between Kansai International airport and Johannesburg -- the postponement is due to the airline's failure to get needed slots at Kansai airport.</p>
<p>**NOVEMBER 3**</p>
<p>- Canadian Airlines International increase service between Las Vegas and Vancover from twice a week to daily.</p>
<p>**NOVEMBER 4**</p>
<p>- South African Airways increase weekly service to Accra to twiuce-weekly.</p>
<p>**NOVEMBER 5**</p>
<p>- South African Airways introduce a twice-weekly service between Johannesburg and Abidjan.</p>
<p>**NOVEMBER 6**</p>
<p>- USAir add second daily roundtrip nonstop between Philadelphia and San Juan.</p>
<p>**NOVEMBER 22**</p>
<p>- American West airlines introduce service to Acapulo, Mexico, linking Phoenix with one daily nonstop.</p>
<p>**DECEMBER 2**</p>
<p>- AirWays Corp end service to Hartford and Providence.</p>
<p>**DECEMBER 12**</p>
<p>- Continental Airlines begin daily nonstop service from Newark to Panama with continuing service to Guayaquil, Equador.</p>
<p>- Continental Airlines begin new route from Houston to Lima, Peru</p>
<p>**1997**</p>
<p>**JANUARY 9**</p>
<p>- American West Airlines begin service to Cleveland, Ohio, with two daily flights from Phoenix and one per day from Las Vegas.</p>
<p>**MARCH 17**</p>
<p>- British Airways switch 13 weekly flights to Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Columbia, Mexico and Venezuela to Gatwick's north terminal from Heathrow.</p>
<p>**APRIL 1**</p>
<p>- Transaero start conde-sharing programme with American Airlines.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
