<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12106" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: STOCKS -- Closing stock market indices, Aug 22.</title>
<headline>STOCKS -- Closing stock market indices, Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here is how major stock markets outside the United States ended on Thursday.</p>
<p>LONDON - London shares chalked up another record closing high, helped by a deeper than expected cut in Germany's repo rate.</p>
<p>The FTSE 100 index of leading shares closed up 19.0 points at 3,891.1, surpassing Tuesday's record close of 3,883.2.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - German shares ended bourse trade over half a percentage point higher after the Bundesbank cut its main money market interest rate by a larger-than-expected 30 basis points.</p>
<p>The 30-share blue chip DAX index closed 13.52 points, or 0.53 percent, higher at 2,557.26 points. In post-bourse trading the DAX stood at 2,559.42, up 24.98.</p>
<p>PARIS - The Paris bourse closed with sharp gains, cheered by a surprise interest rate cut by the Bank of France, which followed an equally unexpected easing by the Bundesbank.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index closed up 17.12 points or 0.86 percent at 2,017.76.</p>
<p>ZURICH - Swiss shares ended markedly higher on the back of a strong rise in Roche certificates and an unexpectedly large German repo rate cut.</p>
<p>The blue-chip Swiss Market Index advanced 29.2 points, or 0.79 percent, to 3,713.0 points. The Broad Swiss Performance Index added 16.86 points, or 0.71 percent, to 2,376.50.</p>
<p>TOKYO - Stocks closed marginally higher, extending their recent recovery streak to a fourth day. But the market lacked confidence about the strength of the current rebound.</p>
<p>The key 225-share Nikkei average closed up 88.22 points, or 0.41 percent, at 21,363.24.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Stocks ended moderately higher, with property shares leading a healthy rebound in late afternoon.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index ended 42.27 points, or 0.37 percent, higher at 11,478.77. At its lowest point in morning trading the index was down 23 points.</p>
<p>SYDNEY - A late bout of profit-taking triggered by fears of a weaker session on Wall Street saw the share market close near its lows.</p>
<p>The key share market barometer, the All Ordinaries index, finished 11.4 points lower at 2,274.6, just off its intra-day bottom of 2,272.0.</p>
<p>JOHANNESBURG - Sentiment in industrials was boosted as offshore and local buyers returned to the market, while golds came under pressure throughout the day, ending weaker.</p>
<p>At the official close, the industrial index had risen 89.2 points to 7.681.6, the gold index lost 22.6 points to 1,703.8 and the all share index rose 58.2 points to 6,479.2.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
