<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12105" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Free, rich and single - but where does Diana go now?.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Free, rich and single - but where does Diana go now?.</headline>
<byline>Jill Serjeant</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rich, glamorous and single once more, Princess Diana finally emerges from her gilded royal cage on Wednesday to become the most eligible woman in the world.</p>
<p>But that red-letter day, when her divorce from heir to the throne Prince Charles becomes final, casts Diana into a stormy sea with her only life-raft being her undisputed position as mother of a future British king.</p>
<p>Denied her chance of becoming queen, having quit most of her charity posts and lost all the men she was ever close to, Diana's prospects look bleak despite the consolations of a 17 million pound ($26 million) divorce settlement.</p>
<p>&quot;She needs something new to fill her life with. The children are gone, that's it, boarding school, goodbye. She's got her charity work which makes her very busy, but she needs something else,&quot; said image consultant Mary Spillane.</p>
<p>&quot;She needs to develop an expertise in something that's real rather than being a Florence Nightingale figure and a clothes horse; that would fill this tremendous void that's within her,&quot; said Spillane in the book &quot;Diana on the Edge&quot;.</p>
<p>Diana, 35, may be rich but she is also lonely and freedom is likely to remain just a word for her.</p>
<p>Like Jackie Kennedy Onassis, America's trend-setting First Lady widowed at the age of 34, Diana is destined to spend the rest of her life in the relentless media spotlight whether she likes it or not.</p>
<p>&quot;She will still be the top-selling royal until her son Prince William gets a girlfriend,&quot; said Judy Wade of &quot;Hello&quot; magazine.</p>
<p>Friends say Diana would dearly like another child -- particularly a daughter -- and the astrologers she likes to consult say re-marriage is in her stars.</p>
<p>But as the princess herself made clear in a dramatic television interview last November which sealed her fate as an ex-royal, there's no new Prince Charming on the horizon.</p>
<p>&quot;Any gentleman that's been past my door, we've instantly been put together by the media and all hell's broken lose.</p>
<p>&quot;You know, people think that at the end of the day, a man is the only answer. Actually a fulfilling job is better for me,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Since then however Diana has resigned from almost 100 charities, drawing back from her high-profile role among the sick and afflicted that earned her the nickname &quot;Saint Di&quot;.</p>
<p>She will retain her links with just six charities, including those connected with AIDS, cancer, leprosy and sick children.</p>
<p>Thwarted by government and royal officialdom in her ambition to become a roving ambassador for Britain, she has nevertheless lined up charity work trips to Italy, the United States and Australia in the next three months.</p>
<p>&quot;She is determined to show them that she doesn't need them and that she will get some sort of ambassadorial role of her own making,&quot; said Wade.</p>
<p>Much of her daily diary appears to be filled with shopping, workouts at an exclusive London gym -- where she met three of her recent admirers -- and visits to a bevy of counsellors, aromatherapists, osteopaths and specialists in colonic irrigation.</p>
<p>Some commentators have voiced concern about the psychological state of the princess, whose own mother deserted her at the age of six and who has admitted throwing herself down the stairs.</p>
<p>But the shy virgin who married Charles in 1981 and blossomed into a world superstar has always been one step ahead of the media.</p>
<p>As a young bride, she applied herself with determination to master the art of public speaking and carved out a starring role for herself as the new kid on the block in the ancient British monarchy.</p>
<p>She has already ditched her royal bodyguards, despite security objections, and last month fired her press spokeswoman making it clear there would be no immediate replacement.</p>
<p>Some reports say she may go into a sort of voluntary exile -- possibly to New York where the press is kinder, the public still adoring and she has several close friends.</p>
<p>Her formidable talent for public relations has ensured worldwide sympathy for her plight as a wronged wife, despite admitting that, like Charles, she enjoyed an illicit affair.</p>
<p>Only last week she used her love-hate relationship with the press to win a court order against a troublesome paparazzo photographer and then turned the case into a headline-grabbing example of stalking.</p>
<p>Diana has proved herself to be strong and single-minded -- a woman who in her own words &quot;would not go quietly&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't feel sorry for myself in any way,&quot; she said in her revealing television interview last November. &quot;I've got my work that I choose to do, and I've got my boys, and I've got lots of opportunities coming up in the next year.&quot;</p>
<p>(1=.6460 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
