<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12109" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Afternoon Update.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Afternoon Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>INDIGENOUS ELECTORAL CUTS &quot;CALLOUS&quot; SAYS OPPOSITION</p>
<p>The Federal Opposition has described as callous, Government cuts to</p>
<p>an Australian Electoral Commission programme to help indigenous</p>
<p>people take part in the electoral process.</p>
<p>The Coalition has cut the Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander</p>
<p>Electoral Information Service, worth two million dollars a year.</p>
<p>Nineteen staff were employed to help indigenous Australians,</p>
<p>particularly in remote areas, to understand their electoral rights</p>
<p>and obligations.</p>
<p>Labor Senator Bob Collins says closing the programme, which was</p>
<p>initiated by the Fraser Government, is another example of the</p>
<p>Coalition's callous disregard for reconciliation.</p>
<p>Senator Collins says it turns the clock back two decades.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>COMMONWEALTH STAFF WITHDRAW FROM PUBLIC CONTACT</p>
<p>Commonwealth public servants have voted to refuse to make contact</p>
<p>with the public for two hours every Friday morning.</p>
<p>Members of the Community and Public Sector Union approved the</p>
<p>action today, as part of their campaign against spending cuts</p>
<p>announced in the budget.</p>
<p>Besides the restriction on public contact hours, union members have</p>
<p>also voted to impose work bans.</p>
<p>The union says 30 thousand jobs will be lost.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>NATIONAL CRIME AUTHORITY DEFENDED</p>
<p>A member of the Joint Statutory Committee overseeing the National</p>
<p>Crime Authority has defended the authority from attacks in the wake</p>
<p>of the acquittal of businessman John Elliot yesterday.</p>
<p>Federal Independent MP, Paul Filing, says there are problems with</p>
<p>the N-C-A's operation, but he says it shouldn't be disbanded, as</p>
<p>advocated by Victorian Premier, Jeff Kennett.</p>
<p>Mr Elliot was acquitted of fraud charges brought by the N-C-A after</p>
<p>a judge ruled the authority had acted illegally during its</p>
<p>investigation.</p>
<p>Federal Attorney-General Daryl Williams has ordered his department</p>
<p>to review the NCA's role in the case.</p>
<p>Mr Filing says the references given to the N-C-A by the committee</p>
<p>of state and federal MPs which oversees it are in need of review.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>WINEMAKERS MISS OUT ON COMPENSATION</p>
<p>Winemakers in the Hunter Valley, in New South Wales, are to miss</p>
<p>out on a quarter of a million dollars in compensation promised by</p>
<p>the Keating Government.</p>
<p>Primary Industries Minister, John Anderson, has told the wineries</p>
<p>that budget measures will be enough to replace the payments.</p>
<p>Most wineries in the Hunter would have received six thousand</p>
<p>dollars each this year as part of a three year deal with the ALP</p>
<p>to compensate wineries which pay tax on promotional wines.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CPSU MEMBERS RALLY AROUND AUSTRALIA</p>
<p>Members of the public sector union have attended lunchtime rallies</p>
<p>around the country today, protesting against public sector cuts.</p>
<p>In some states, Community and Public Sector Union members attending</p>
<p>rallies have voted not to return to work.</p>
<p>In Victoria, about six hundred CPSU members have voted in favour</p>
<p>of starting an industrial campaign against the cuts, beginning with</p>
<p>a strike this afternoon.</p>
<p>In Canberra, CPSU members have been told they need to embark on</p>
<p>a long-haul industrial campaign to combat lob losses and</p>
<p>outsourcing.</p>
<p>The public servants have proposed lightning pickets at Parliament</p>
<p>House, sit-ins and letter writing campaigns to stiffen-up the</p>
<p>industrial response to the Federal Budget.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>RESORT GO-AHEAD &quot;PAY BACK FOR GUNS&quot;, SAYS CONSERVATIONISTS</p>
<p>Conservationists say the Federal Government's allowed the Port</p>
<p>Hinchinbrook resort to go ahead to pay back rural North</p>
<p>Queenslanders hit by tougher national gun laws.</p>
<p>Queensland Conservation Council co-ordinator, Imogen Zethoven, says</p>
<p>National Party Leader Tim Fischer indicated the resort would be</p>
<p>allowed to go ahead at a time when he was under extreme pressure.</p>
<p>Ms Zethoven says this means World Heritage values have been</p>
<p>sacrificed to provide jobs for North Queesland.</p>
<p>The council and the Wilderness Society have vowed to fight the</p>
<p>decision.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>WILDERNESS SOCIETY TARGETS COMPANIES</p>
<p>The Wilderness Society is welcoming the Prime Minister to Hobart by</p>
<p>staging what it calls a theatrical &quot;corporate orgy&quot;.</p>
<p>The Society's members say the performance aims to protest against</p>
<p>the Federal Government's involvement with multinational companies,</p>
<p>Boral and North Limited.</p>
<p>The Wilderness Society says the companies are involved in the</p>
<p>destruction of Australia's forests, which the Federal Government is</p>
<p>allowing to occur.</p>
<p>John Howard is due in Hobart today as the guest of honour at a</p>
<p>state Liberal Party dinner.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ENDANGERED ANTELOPE BORN IN SOUTH AUSTRALIA</p>
<p>Monarto Zoo in South Australia says it's achieved the births of two</p>
<p>addax, an endangered species of antelope.</p>
<p>A female calf was born three weeks ago and a second calf last</p>
<p>night.</p>
<p>Zoo director David Langdon says it's believed there are only about</p>
<p>a thousand addax still surviving, most in captivity.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>WA SHIRE RECONSIDERS GROG LAWS</p>
<p>Last Thursday's riot at the remote Kimberley town of Halls Creeks</p>
<p>has prompted a review of alcohol related laws by the local Shire</p>
<p>Council.</p>
<p>Shire President, Josie Farrer, says options for tightening drinking</p>
<p>regulations include closing liquor outlets on pay days, and having</p>
<p>dry area restrictions similar to those in the Northern Territory.</p>
<p>Ms Farrer says the Council agrees that alcohol ignites problems</p>
<p>such as violence, and sees the only way of stopping it is by</p>
<p>limiting the number of hours alcohol is available.</p>
<p>Last week about 150 people went on an alcohol induced rampage</p>
<p>through the town causing an estimated one million dollars damage.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PETROL STATION OWNERS CRITICISE NEW PETROL PRICING CONTROLS The Competition and Consumer Commission's recommendation to remove</p>
<p>petrol price controls is being criticised by service station</p>
<p>operators.</p>
<p>The Commission says with only four oil companies dominating the</p>
<p>petrol industry, price controls are having a minimal effect.</p>
<p>But the Motor Trades Association says some of the recommendations</p>
<p>appear to entrench the oil companies' market power.</p>
<p>It's called on the Government to issue a pricing guideline so</p>
<p>wholesale pricing is more open and transparent.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
