<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12111" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Morning Update.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Morning Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>DEANE CALLS FOR RECONCILIATION</p>
<p>The Governor-General has called on Australia's politicians to reaffirm their commitment to Aboriginal reconciliation.</p>
<p>The call was made during a speech in Darwin to mark 30 years of Aboriginal struggle for land rights:</p>
<p>Sir William Deane called on Commonwealth and State legislatures to pass formal resolutions expressing support for reconciliation with aborigines.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>HOWARD ATTACKS KELTY AND GEORGE</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard has told a Liberal Party gathering in Canberra, that union leaders Jennie George and Bill Kelty could not wipe their hands of any responsibility for Monday's violent protest outside Parliament House.</p>
<p>Nearly one-hundred Police officers and several protestors were injured, and some arrested, when demonstrators stormed the building, and wrecked the Parliamentary gift shop.</p>
<p>ACTU Secretary Bill Kelty described the rally as the most successful union demonstration in Australian history, while President Jennie George dissociated the union movement from the violence.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PUBLIC SERVANTS TO HOLD MEETINGS TODAY</p>
<p>Commonwealth public servants will today hold meetings and rallies across the country in protest against job cuts which could reach as high as 30-thousand by the end of next year.</p>
<p>The CPSU is focussing on a community awareness campaign, to try to soften the blow.</p>
<p>The union's also concerned other aspects of the budget, such as contracting out job placement to the private sector, will disadvantage both the unemployed and taxpayers.</p>
<p>The meetings and rallies, to be held in all capital cities and some regional centres, will decide on a future industrial strategy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BABY SNATCHED IN SYDNEY</p>
<p>Police are investigating the abduction yesterday of a nine week old baby from Sydney's Westmead Hospital.</p>
<p>The boy, from Coffs Harbour, was taken to hospital two weeks ago after developing a serious respiratory condition while on a family holiday in Sydney.</p>
<p>At around five o'clock yesterday afternoon, an unknown woman described as being in her late twenties took the baby from a Westmead childrens ward.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
