<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12110" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-TIMELINES-Today in History - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>RTRS-TIMELINES-Today in History - Aug 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>**BIRTHDAYS**</p>
<p>Australian classical pianist and composer ROY AGNEW was born in 1891. He wrote &quot;The Breaking of the Drought&quot;.</p>
<p>American dancer, actor, choreographer and director GENE KELLY was born in 1912. He starred in Hollywood musicals including &quot;Singin' in the Rain&quot; and &quot;Invitation to Dance&quot;. He died earlier this year, aged 83.</p>
<p>Australian artist DAVID BOYD was born in 1924.</p>
<p>Australian golfer PETER THOMPSON was born in Melbourne in 1929. He won five British and three Australian Opens - the first Australian at the age of 18. He also won the New Zealand Open in 1950.</p>
<p>American singer ANTHONY MICALE, who had the hit &quot;(Just Like) Romeo And Juliet&quot; in 1964 with 'The Reflections', was born in 1942.</p>
<p>Australian actor GIL TUCKER was born in 1947.</p>
<p>British drummer with 'The Who', KEITH MOON, was born in 1947. He died on the 7th of September, 1978.</p>
<p>English playwright WILLY RUSSELL, who wrote &quot;Educating Rita&quot;, was born in 1947.</p>
<p>Australian pop singer and daytime soapie star RICK SPRINGFIELD (RICHARD SPRINGTHORPE) was born in 1949. He began playing guitar at the age of 14 and then recorded with the band 'Zoot' in the late 1960s. He went solo in 1971 and went to the United States where he scored a major role in the popular serial &quot;General Hospital&quot;.</p>
<p>Swimmer JUSTON LEMBERG was born in 1963. He set a new world record for the 400 metres freestyle at the 1984 Los Angeles Olympics. His time was three minutes 51.79 seconds.</p>
<p>			   **EVENTS**</p>
<p>    1680 :    Captain BLOOD died. He was remembered for his</p>
<p>attempt to steal the Crown Jewels from the Tower of London in May 1671.</p>
<p>    1818 :    The first steam ship service began on the Great</p>
<p>Lakes in North America.</p>
<p>    1902 :    The American buffalo population was estimated at</p>
<p>more than one thousand. Thirteen years earlier there were only 551 buffalo and it seemed the breed was heading for extinction. The Government said the Federal game laws of 1889 had had the desired effect.</p>
<p>    1926 :    The idol of millions, RUDOLPH VALENTINO, died. The</p>
<p>31-year-old screen actor died in the New York Polyclinic Hospital of peritonitis. &quot;The great lover&quot; was in New York to publicise his latest film &quot;The Son of the Sheikh&quot;. Italian-born VALENTINO cultivated an image of himself as the epitome of virility. However the revelation that both his ex-wives were lesbians caused speculation about his own sexual orientation. News of his death reportedly provoked a rash of suicides.</p>
<p>    1939 :    British driver JOHN COBB reached 590 kilometres</p>
<p>per hour at Bonneville Flats at Utah.</p>
<p>    1939 :    Germany and USSR signed a non-aggression pact.</p>
<p>    1940 :    German bombers began night raids on London.</p>
<p>    1957 :    Ansett Airways bought ANA for 3.3 million pounds</p>
<p>to become TAA's chief rival.</p>
<p>    1960 :    American songwriter OSCAR HAMMERSTEIN died (born</p>
<p>12th July, 1895). He and RICHARD ROGERS formed one of the world's most successful musical writing teams.</p>
<p>    1976 :    Australia's Prime Minister MALCOLM FRASER was</p>
<p>trapped for one hour in a basement office at Monash University by one thousand protesters.</p>
<p>    1982 :    Queensland unions declared a general strike in a</p>
<p>&quot;war&quot; against the BJELKE-PETERSEN government. The State's first general strike in 70 years stopped trains, petrol deliveries, port operations and closed mines and factories. The dispute was over the push for the 38-hour week.</p>
<p>    1985 :    Bond Corp took over the Castlemaine Tooheys</p>
<p>brewery.</p>
<p>    1990 :    The German states selected October 3rd 1990 as the</p>
<p>date for unification.</p>
<p>(Compiled from ABC ARCHIVES, ABC RADIO NATIONAL, &quot;On This Day&quot; published by REED INTERNATIONAL BOOKS LIMITED, &quot;The Chronicle Of The 20th Century&quot; published by PENGUIN BOOKS and &quot;Rock And Pop (Day By Day)&quot; published by BLANDFORD BOOKS)</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
