<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12118" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ share mkt closes up 1.05 pct at 2-1/2 yr high.</title>
<headline>NZ share mkt closes up 1.05 pct at 2-1/2 yr high.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>* NZ share market pushes to 2-1/2 year high</p>
<p>* Telecom jumps to all-time high, Fletcher Forests strong</p>
<p>* Negative opinion poll for government shrugged off  </p>
<p>The bulls were running again in the New Zealand share market on Friday as it surged a further one percent to end on a 2-1/2 year high.</p>
<p>Even the publication of a political opinion poll negative for the ruling conservative government just seven weeks ahead of the election failed to dampen enthusiasm.</p>
<p>The top 40 index ended 23.05 points ahead at 2222.59, its highest point since March 1994. Volume was a healthy $56 million.</p>
<p>And despite the market's 3.3 percent rise this week, brokers remain in bullish mood for the week ahead.  </p>
<p>&quot;There could be a correction, but I don't think you will see it upsetting the uptrend,&quot; said Cavill White's Don Turkington.</p>
<p>&quot;The market doesn't seem worried about the prospect of the October 12 election,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>It was led up by the leaders, which brokers said was typical of a bull run. Firmly in the van was Telecom which jumped eight cents to an all-time high of $6.90.</p>
<p>Turkington said the break through previous highs was highly significant from a chart view as it had failed previously to break through the $6.80 and another failure would have seen that as an upper limit.  </p>
<p>Telecom has risen 8.5 percent since its well received first quarter result last week.</p>
<p>Another star was Fletcher Forests which resumed its heavenly march since it and Brierley Investments won the bidding for Forestry Corporation on Tuesday. It closed up 10 cents at $2.04.</p>
<p>Carter Holt Harvey, one of the unsuccessful bidders, still rose strongly, up six cents to $3.26.</p>
<p>Even Wilson &amp; Horton, which posted a below forecast half year profit on Thursday evening, rose 10 cents to $9.35.</p>
<p>Analysts were told by the company it was upbeat about its second half prospects.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
