<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12119" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-OPINION - Louthean on Australian Mining: Canadian capers.</title>
<headline>RTRS-OPINION - Louthean on Australian Mining: Canadian capers.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Ross Louthean*</p>
<p>With some any deals being arranged between Australian juniors and active Canadian companies with greater access to capital it will be interesting to see how many miners of the new millennium evolve from these marriages.</p>
<p>The other side of this optimistic scenario is whether the tyranny of distance, differing philosophies and plain bad luck singes investors on both continents.</p>
<p>Australian companies have ingenuity and low price-earnings ratios (P/Es) but frequent problems in raising capital back home, while the Canadians are in a more volatile market, have greater capital raising avenues but as stocks have high P/Es.</p>
<p>This column has pointed out before that acquisitions by North Americans -- Canadians in particular -- of Australian companies have produced a re-rating back home that virtually covers or exceeds the cost of the acquisition.</p>
<p>One of the best litmus tests of Australian-Canadian mining marriages is Kalgoorlie's Croesus Mining NL and Vancouver's Eldorado Gold Corporation Inc.</p>
<p>Both are in growth mode. Croesus has just doubled its resources at the Binduli mine near Kalgoorlie, has a blueprint to build a larger treatment plant and has lifted its exploration activity outside of Western Australia.</p>
<p>Eldorado caused a ripple of interest back home with the Croesus acquisition and then really raised eyebrows through a deal with Gencor Ltd, resulting in Gencor becoming a major shareholder but also giving Eldorado the key to developing some of its non South African mining assets.</p>
<p>STORY OF TRUE GRIT</p>
<p>The Croesus story is one of true grit.</p>
<p>The company evolved as a callow explorer, one of many churned out before the 1987 sharemarket crash, by which time it has grasped the opportunity to graduate from explorer to miner by taking up some of the gold assets in Western Australia's Eastern Goldfields being sold by CRA Ltd.</p>
<p>The company has been singularly identified with its energetic executive chairman Ron Manners but that picture is changing as Manners -- now a director of Eldorado -- deliberately steps back to allow general manager and director Steve Johnston and exploration manager Mike Ivey the opportunity to show their acumen.</p>
<p>The company, named after Greek king Croesus who around 640 BC created a monetary role for gold (coincidentally Manners lives in Croesus Street, Kalgoorlie), became a gold producer through the Hannans South mine and mill purchased from CRA.</p>
<p>But while it lived beyond its established reserves, the Hannans South mill soon became hungry and Croesus lived with a hand-to-mouth basis picking up small deposits within reasonable trucking distance of plant, situated between Kalgoorlie and Kambalda.</p>
<p>WHAM-BAM BINDULI</p>
<p>One of the wham-bam mining exercises picked up was the Binduli leases just west of Kalgoorlie where the Pitman and Walsh deposits -- so named after two gold stealing squad detectives murdered and dumped at the site -- were available.</p>
<p>The Pitman zone lived up to its expected life of about three months mining, but Mike Ivey felt the area's geology had been misunderstood by preceding explorers and started an aggressive drilling programme.</p>
<p>Today Binduli is a model for other regional explorers and last month Croesus doubled its resources to 15.4 million tonnes grading 1.52 grams/tonne for a contained 752,000 ounces.</p>
<p>Within this there is already a proven-provable 6.8 mt at 1.7 g/t for 360,000 oz.</p>
<p>Based on the blueprint for establishing a new mill at Binduli, to negate trucking costs, at 750,000 tonnes per annum milling will have a mining life of at least eight years, and there is strong confidence in the Croesus camp that new discoveries will be picked up along strike and at depth.</p>
<p>The biggest success recently was the decision by Ivey to drill deeper to find a source to supergene ore being mined in the pits, and this picked up higher grade ore below the Choctaw pit and leading into the bigger Centurion open cut.</p>
<p>BLUE SKY AT BINDULI</p>
<p>The blue sky at Binduli is the scope for more high grade sulphide mineralisation along a black shale contact, so far traced for about four kilometres north and south of Choctaw.</p>
<p>Eldorado entered the scene when Manners this year sold his private company Mannkal which had a 19.8 percent Croesus stake.</p>
<p>Eldorado was in growth mode at the time through its big gold-silver developments in Mexico, and the Canadians are keen to see Croesus expand its mining horizons away from Binduli.</p>
<p>The company has a large number of holdings and joint ventures in the Eastern Goldfields and two strong candidates are the Ellen Dam leases, south of Binduli which are joint ventured with Newcrest Mining Ltd ; and the Telegraph Dam prospect in partnership with the Cogema group from France.</p>
<p>I understands that Croesus may soon end up in Paris to propose a buy-out of Cogema or alternatively stepping on the pedal to have a mine started, utilising one of the existing mills in he region.</p>
<p>MOVING INTO NEW SOUTH WALES</p>
<p>Through director Bob Berven, Croesus has moved strongly into the New South Wales prospecting scene, picking up eight exploration licence applications -- mainly on the Lachlan Fold Belt near and looking at models of the North Parkes gold-copper project and in the Cobar copper and copper-gold belt in the state's north.</p>
<p>To have a more direct contact with Croesus and to look for more opportunities in Australia Eldorado Gold director Marco Romero has moved from Canada to Perth to establish an office.</p>
<p>Apart from looking at the Australian scene, including joint venturing with Croesus on properties in New South Wales, Romero intends having a close look at opportunities in Indonesia and New Zealand.</p>
<p>The Croesus deal and the big deal to take up projects with Gencor, some on a joint venture basis known as Genel (Gencor and Eldorado 50/50) has prompted some re-ratings by Canadian broking houses.</p>
<p>Whalen Beliveau &amp; Associates suggested the new deals could see Eldorado's price double to $C15 from $C7.50 at the time of analysis early in August.</p>
<p>What Whalen Beliveau likes is the deal Eldorado has struck involving North American rights to Gencor's BIOX process for treating complex sulphide gold ores and eliminating the need for conventional and environmentally unfriendly roasting techniques.</p>
<p>This process is now working effectively at four major mines, including the Ashanti operations in Ghana and Wiluna in Western Australia and so far has not been properly marketed in North America.</p>
<p>The broker also likes a Dominican Republic gold mine called Pueblo Flea in which Gencor has a right to.</p>
<p>Despite the phenomenal size of this project it is run inefficiently -- for the complex sulphides are being treated by a plant suited to shallower ores and current recoveries has been only 20 percent whereas BIOX could take the recovery to above 86 percent.</p>
<p>Peublo Vlejo, run as a state-owned mine has reserves of 120 million tons grading 2.9 grams.</p>
<p>*Ross Louthean is editor of Paydirt, and publisher of Gold Mining Journal and the Australian Mines Handbook</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
