<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12123" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-RESEARCH ALERT - Australian wines outlook mixed.</title>
<headline>RTRS-RESEARCH ALERT - Australian wines outlook mixed.</headline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Adelaide broker Day Cutten said reduced grape prices in 1997 and 1998 will lower costs and boost sales volumes for Australian wine companies but margins may be tempered by some price pressures and a rising dollar.</p>
<p>Writing in the broker's 1996 Wine Companies Review, analyst Roly Michelmore said discounting of semi-premium white wines was likely in the next 18 months, following the bumper 1996 vintage, which would put pressure on margins in those categories.  </p>
<p>Michelmore said the most positive aspect of the vintage is the capacity it will give exporters to market increased volumes at reasonable cost, with 1996/97 (June 30) revenue growth to be mainly volume growth, also in domestic but especially in export markets.</p>
<p>Surveying six local wine companies, Day Cutten recommended accumulating stock in bulk producer Australian Vintage Ltd and holding for Australia's third largest producer BRL Hardy Ltd (buying at A$2.20), Peter Lehmann Wines Ltd, and bulk producer Simeon Wines Ltd.  </p>
<p>Michelmore said Australian Vintage (Thursday close A$2.05) provided an opportunistic exposure to the medium term rapid growth of the industry through its core bulk processing business.</p>
<p>Earnings diversity and long term growth would arise as vineyard development matured and bottled wine sales expanded.</p>
<p>For BRL Hardy (close A$2.85) Michelmore said price rises throughout the product range indicated improving brand images and skilful marketing, while forecast earnings per share (EPS) growth of nine percent to 16.5 cents from 15.2 cents was sound.  </p>
<p>Estimating a A$19.6 million net profit for the 1996 calendar year and A$22 million in 1997, up from 1995's A$17.3 million, he said the expected boost to earnings in 1997 and beyond would be sourced in the company's extensive premium vinyeard investment.</p>
<p>For Peter Lehmann Wines (close A$0.95), good performance from both branded and bulk wine operations were expected to result in EPS growth of 16 percent to 6.02 cents for 1995/96, while Simeon Wines (close A$2.36) was forecast to produce a 15 percent rise in net earnings above prospectus in 1995/96 to A$3.44 million.  </p>
<p>Day Cutten advised selling shares in Normans Wines Ltd (close $0.80), saying poor performance and excessive costs in the company's agency business were largely responsible for an estimated 87 percent slump in EPS to 1.9 cents in 1995/96.</p>
<p>Michelmore forecast Normans would produce only a A$320,000 net profit in 1995/96, rising to A$1.74 million in 1996/97, down from its maiden A$2.08 million profit in 1994/95.  </p>
<p>He also recommended lightening in Petaluma Wines Ltd (close A$7.24), saying the current market premium in the stock was excessive, despite the quality of assets and management.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect further expansion through acquisition or merger in the relatively near term,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Michelmore said acqusition of established brands was seen by many in the industry as the quickest and cheapest means to access export growth, which appeared to be limited by Australia's ability to supply rather than level of demand.  </p>
<p>The most imminent industry move was the likelihood that Foster's Brewing Group Ltd would seek to significantly expand its wine business, with BRL Hardy and Southcorp Holdings Ltd's wine division suitable choices, he said.</p>
<p>Michelmore said the greatest challenge for the industry would be to attract and service the estimated A$5 billion required to develop vineyard and processing capacity to produce 6.5 percent of the projected world wine output, up from two percent, as detailed under the industry's 30 year strategy.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
