<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12136" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Aussie dlr shored by sea change in sentiment.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Aussie dlr shored by sea change in sentiment.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar kept a steady grip on 79 cents through a relatively quiet Friday as the market wound down after a week of solid progress.</p>
<p>The currency could not quite take the key US$0.7935 barrier, well defended by profit-takers, but was still 3/4 cent up on the week and far above the US$0.7680 lows plumbed in early August. Dealers said foreign confidence in Australia had been boosted by Tuesday's fiscally prudent budget and Japanese investors remained keen buyers of A$-debt, although a big issue rumoured for today failed to appear. That led most to expect renewed strength next week, with 80 cents a not impossible dream.  </p>
<p>By 5.00 pm (0700 GMT) the local currency was had settled at US$0.7907/12 after drifting back from an early US$0.7915/20, and was steady on Thursday's late US$0.7906/11.</p>
<p>That was well up on last Friday's US$0.7824/29 finish and its highest weekly close since July 21.</p>
<p>Traders said a break of key US$0.7935 resistance was needed to signal a new phase of the dollar's three week-old rally and set up a re-test of the 80 cent barrier which so frustrated bulls in early July.</p>
<p>Support was seen at US$0.7890 and US$0.7850, with many viewing US$0.7810 as the pivotal level once again.  </p>
<p>On the crosses, the dollar had sailed to 1.1783/95 marks from 1.1732/43 thanks to the Bundesbank's unlooked for generosity in cutting its key repurchase rate by 30 basis point to 3.00 percent. The move spurred easings across Europe and widened the local currency's yield premium to its advantage.</p>
<p>It was steady on the yen at 85.63/73 from 85.72/82 late Thursday, having climbed steadily from last Friday's 84.25/35 finish on the back of Japanese retail demand for A$-denominated dual currency samurai issues. A rumoured 50 billion yen-plus bond from IBM had failed to appear today, much to the bulls' disappointment, but they had hopes for next week.  </p>
<p>In trade weighted terms the currency was unchanged from Thursday at 58.0 and 0.7 point higher for the week.</p>
<p>Traders said the dollar had also benefited from an offshore rush into Australian government bonds following the government's pledge to balance the country's budget deficit in three years.</p>
<p>The government's budget cuts were credible enough to draw a positive ratings outlook from Standard &amp; Poor's and to narrow the yield gap between Australian and U.S. 10-year bonds to 124 basis points from 150 a few weeks ago.</p>
<p>Analysts were also reasonably confident the budget would pass the Senate without a repeat of 1993's damaging deadlock.  </p>
<p>The outlook was not without risks, however, as many expected the Reserve Bank to cut official interest rates once more before year-end. The surprise easing in July lopped two cents off the currency and a repeat performance was quite possible.</p>
<p>Perhaps the biggest uncertainty surrounded commodity prices which had shown recent signs of a modest revival after slumping mid-year. The influential Commodity Research Bureau index had recovered four percent so far this month from a 240.09 low in July, but remained well short of April's 263.79 peak.</p>
<p>Much now depended on whether fledgling recoveries in Japan and Germany blossomed into a synchronised world upturn.  </p>
<p>That uncertainty was largely behind the broad range of expectations for the dollar found in a Reuters survey of analysts today.</p>
<p>Forecasts for the dollar by year-end ranged from 75 to 80 cents, with the median not far from current levels at US$0.7875.</p>
<p>Domestic economic data next week includes the current account for July, which is expected to stay down around June's benign A$1.29 billion level, July retail trade and building approvals.</p>
<p>-- Wayne Cole 61-2 373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
