<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12135" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Sugar seen facing consumer taste challenge.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Sugar seen facing consumer taste challenge.</headline>
<byline>Graeme James</byline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's sugar industry faces an uncertain economic future unless it responds quickly to changing world diet and health habits, a leading Australian research scientist said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Development in diets, health and genetic engineering are likely to substantially change the sugar industry,&quot; Colin Adam, deputy chief executive of the Commonwealth Scientific and Industrial Research Organisation, the Australian government's peak research body, told the Sugar 2000 conference in Brisbane.  </p>
<p>&quot;Our economic future depends on responding quickly and co-operatively,&quot; Adam said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sugar must become part of changing world trends - in diet and health, sugar in some parts is seen as a negative,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Adam said he echoed earlier speakers who called for the creation and value-adding of sugar by-products including bio-active foods, additives and pharmaceuticals.</p>
<p>Adam said sugar was now part of the fast-growing food and pharmaceutical markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Lone-wolf corporations face the prospect of a short-term life,&quot; Adam said.  </p>
<p>He said Japanese giant Mitsui and Co Ltd had integrated its commodities and food businesses to create five Japanese companies, three U.S. groups, one Dutch company and one Thailand-based group.</p>
<p>&quot;Research and development is now market-driven rather than technology-driven,&quot; Adam said.</p>
<p>He said it still took about 15 years to change research ideas into &quot;a cash-flow positive business.&quot;  </p>
<p>Both Adam and Robert Clements, director of the Australian Centre for International Agricultural Research, told the conference that international sugar-producing countries were putting increasing competitive pressure on Australia's industry.</p>
<p>By the year 2020, world sugar production was estimated to rise to 190 million tonnes annually but sucrose and sugar beet would be less than 70 percent of world sweetener consumption, Clements said.</p>
<p>Australia was still expected to still dominate international world trade with an estimated 10 million tonnes a year, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;But more than half of the world's sugar by that time will be produced and consumed in Asia,&quot; Clements said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100128">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100136">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
