<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12138" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Qantas hopeful on more union deals.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Qantas hopeful on more union deals.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Qantas Airways Ltd said it was hopeful of reaching wage deals soon with other unions after striking an agreement for en eight percent pay rise over two years with the Transport Workers Union (TWU) earlier on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are optismistic that we will be able to get an agreement with the other unions in the near future,&quot; said Ian Oldmeadow group executive manager operations.</p>
<p>Oldmeadow said the airline was in talks with Australian Services Union (ASU), Flight Attendants Association of Australia (FAAA), Licence Aircraft Engineers Association and four unions representing metal workers.  </p>
<p>Oldmeadow said all the unions, including the TWU, represent about 20,000 of the airline's staff. He said the current union talks would be for a similar wage deal struck with the TWU.</p>
<p>&quot;What we have said that that amount is available subject to us reaching changes in the workplace and we are close to an agreement with a number of those unions on a number of those changes,&quot; Oldmeadow said.</p>
<p>He said workplace changes include part-time employment, flexibility in the workplace and hours worked. Qantas would meet next Thursday with the Australian Council of Trade Union (ACTU) to give a progress report to the union-body, he added.  </p>
<p>Oldmeadow said there was no productivity bargaining with any of the unions.</p>
<p>Qantas, 25 percent owned by British Airways Plc, issued a cautious outlook for the year to June 30, 1997 on Thursday, despite a 37 percent rise in net profit to A$246 million for the year to June 30, 1996.</p>
<p>Qantas shares closed six cents lower at A$2.08.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
