<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12137" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-APEC energy meeting to eye private sector.</title>
<headline>RTRS-APEC energy meeting to eye private sector.</headline>
<byline>James Regan</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The role of private investment in the expanding energy industries of Asia will be a key topic among the business and government representatives from 18 countries gathering in Sydney next week to attend the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) energy ministers meeting.</p>
<p>A high level of private sector participation in the meeting and related functions under the umbrella of &quot;APEC Energy Week&quot; reflects concerns over ways of financing new power projects to meet forecast increases in energy demand in Asia, industry officials said on Friday.  </p>
<p>Energy ministers also will consider endorsing 14 non-binding principles agreed to in 1994 to stimulate regional initiatves to reform industry policies.</p>
<p>The principles broadly cover a range of issues, including the opening of energy markets, removal of subsidies, environmental costs and cross-member cooperation to reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</p>
<p>APEC estimates its member economies consume about half the world's energy and that demand will expand in line with forecast economic growth of 3.3 percent a year to 2010 in the region.  </p>
<p>APEC expects energy consumption among its members to grow by around 2.2 percent a year to 2010, compared with only 1.0 percent a year for the area represented under the Organization of Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD).</p>
<p>Against this backdrop, APEC members must struggle with the reality that as a whole they are net importers of energy, countered only partially by coal exports.</p>
<p>&quot;The challenge for sustained growth in the Asian Pacific region over the next decade is an adequate supply of energy, particularly electricity,&quot; Australiam Resources and Energy Minister Warwick Parer said in a statement.  </p>
<p>A separate forum headed by Parer will next week propose a programme to reduce risks among private industry in participating in power infrastructure projects in the region.</p>
<p>The growth in demand for newly-industrialising APEC economies is higher at over four percent a year, APEC said.</p>
<p>Ministers and representatives from the United States, Mexico, Thailand and China plan to address regional electricty market reforms, focusing on deregualtion issues, privatisation and project financing options.</p>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John Howard is scheduled to deliver a keynote address to the conference on August 28.  </p>
<p>APEC groups Australia, Brunei, Canada, Chile, China, Hong Kong, Indonesia, Japan, South Korea, Malaysia, Mexico, New Zealand, Papua New Guinea, the Philippines, Singapore, Chinese Taipei, Thailand, and the United States.</p>
<p>-- James Regan, Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I11000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
