<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12134" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Mineral Commodities in smelter talks.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Mineral Commodities in smelter talks.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mineral Commodities NL is in talks with Japanese resources companies over building a copper smelter in the Mount Isa region of Queensland, Australia, a company official told Reuters on Friday.</p>
<p>The project is the subject of a prefeasibility study underway by smelting engineering firm Ausmelt Ltd, which due for completion in about a week, David Ogg, a director of Mineral Commodities said.  </p>
<p>Ogg said the study was looking at building a smelter with an annual production capacity of between 150,000 and 200,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Total capital cost of the project is estimated at around A$80 million, he said.</p>
<p>Ogg said it was in talks with Japanese groups, which he declined to name for confidenatiality reasons, and with copper mining companies with operations in central Queensland about building the smelter.  </p>
<p>He said development of the Ernest Henry copper project and expansions of the Mount Isa copper mine meant other copper miners in Queensland could face difficulties in smelting their material.</p>
<p>These include Placer Pacific Ltd's Osborne mine, Australian Resources Ltd's Selwyn mine, Amalg Resources NL's Eloise mine,  Ogg's own company with the proposed Trekelano mine.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the concentrates used to go to Mount Isa, but they're not goiing there now because they don't appear to be able to take it,&quot; Ogg said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
