<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12143" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ dollar closes firmer despite negative poll.</title>
<headline>NZ dollar closes firmer despite negative poll.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand dollar closed firmer on Friday despite an opinion poll published which was negative for the ruling conservative National Party.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market was underpinned by a succession of eurokiwi issues and this was more likely to set the tone for the currency than political sentiment.</p>
<p>The Kiwi ended at US$0.6914/21 at 5.00 pm (0500 GMT), against its 0.6907/14 close while the Trade-Weighted Index closed exactly on its opening at 65.49.  </p>
<p>Dealers estimate there is around NZ$600 million of kiwi to be bought for settlement between September 11-17 and they anticipate buying ahead of that will underpin the Kiwi.</p>
<p>Some interbank players attempted to get short after the National Business Review poll showed National party support falling three points to 34 percent. A general election will be held on October 12.</p>
<p>Dealers said there was a high degree of scepticism about the poll and traders squaring up at the end of the session were partly responsible for the firm tone at the close.  </p>
<p>There was little exporter interest with most flows capital based, dealers said.</p>
<p>Dealers will be watching the Australian dollar which was close to a triple top at US$0.7930. A failure to penetrate that level could see some technical selling of the Kiwi which could feed demand for further eurokiwi issues.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
