<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12149" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS- Qantas, union agree on 8 pct wage rise.</title>
<headline>RTRS- Qantas, union agree on 8 pct wage rise.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian transport workers and Qantas Airways Ltd have struck a deal for an eight percent wage rise, the Transport Workers Union (TWU) said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The TWU and Qantas have reached an in principle deal for a wage increase of eight percent over the next two years for the TWU's 5,500 members at Qantas,&quot; union federal secretary John Allan said in a statement.  </p>
<p>&quot;The TWU's delegates have endorsed the in principle deal which, if accepted by the rank and file, will ensure that these members are paid a fair wage through to mid-1998,&quot; Allan said.</p>
<p>The union had sought a 10 percent wage increase over each of the next two years.</p>
<p>Qantas had offered a total eight percent wage increase over two years in return for productivity offsets.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite earlier demands by Qantas which were unreasonable, we now believe that the modified trade-offs mean the agreement with Qantas is fair,&quot; Allan said.  </p>
<p>The carrier and the union also agreed to review the classification structure in the labour agreement, or award, Allan said.</p>
<p>&quot;An important consideration in this deal is that it will ensure Qantas' ongoing competitiveness and long term jobs for our members,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Neither Allan nor a union spokesman could be immediately contacted to say when union members would consider the deal, or give further details.</p>
<p>There are no details on Qantas' negotiations with other unions covering its workforce.  </p>
<p>&quot;There are now a few unresolved matters which are being dealt with at an Australian Council of Trade Unions level, namely the development of a protocol for outsourcing, a company position on redundancy, and the employee share option,&quot; Allan said.</p>
<p>&quot;I plan to call upon the ACTU to finalise these matters with Qantas as a matter of urgency.&quot;</p>
<p>Qantas, 25 percent owned by British Airways Plc, issued a cautious outlook for the year to June 30, 1997, despite a 37 percent rise in net profit to A$246 million for the year to June 30, 1996.  -- Canberra bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
