<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12145" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: FORECAST - FCL Energy profit seen down.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - FCL Energy profit seen down.</headline>
<byline>James Gray</byline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fletcher Energy is expected to report a decline in annual profit before abnormal items, largely due to the operation its Maui B platform, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>Energy made a NZ$32 million profit on the sale of its interest in Bay of Plenty Electricity, but the sale happened after balance data and was unlikely to be included.</p>
<p>Analysts expect a net profit of around NZ$45-6 million, down from $64 million last June year.</p>
<p>Maui B was likely to cause an increase in depreciation and amortisation charges, but cash flows were expected to be strong.</p>
<p>Oil prices did not have much of an impact, although they were bettter in U.S. dollar terms.</p>
<p>Doyle Paterson Brown analyst David Stanley is forecasting a profit of NZ$46 million before abnormals.</p>
<p>Paul Richardson, energy analyst at SBC Warburg, said earnings before interest before tax would be around NZ$120 million, but the underlying profit was going to be lower than last year's. He expects a fall to around NZ$50 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically they will probably spend a bit more on exploration or account for it in that (second) half, offsetting whatever they've got out of better oil prices as well,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He expects exploration expendutire to be higher, up at around NZ$70 million.</p>
<p>The focus now would be on new projects. Analysts would be keen to see progress on the Brunei field and the drilling timetable for New Zealand.</p>
<p>There may be further utility divestments further down the track after the exit from Bay of Plenty Electricity.</p>
<p>Energy owns one third of utility Natural Gas Corp. The Australian Gas Light Co also owns a third and the public own the rest.</p>
<p>But Natural Gas was a strong performer and Energy was not likely to be in any rush to sell, analysts said.</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64-4-4734746)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
