<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12142" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Oil Search says Moran-1X oil-bearing.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Oil Search says Moran-1X oil-bearing.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil Search Ltd said on Friday that data collected from the Moran-1X well in the central Papuan highlands showed it was oil-bearing.  </p>
<p>&quot;RFT data has been obtained over the sandstone interval 2,926 metres to 2,975 metres in the Moran-1X well, and this data indicates that the interval is oil bearing,&quot; Oil Search said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday Oil Search said its initial tests had had shown the interval was hydrocarbon bearing.</p>
<p>Moran-1X, in permit PDL-2, is located 11 km north of the Agogo processing facilities which form the northernmost extension of the Kutubu facilities and is five km west of the 1996 Paua-1X oil discovery.</p>
<p>The main objective of the Moran-1X well are to evaluate the Toro, Digimu and Iagifu Sandstones, Oil Search said.  </p>
<p>On Wednesday Oil Search said its initial tests had shown the interval was hydrocarbon bearing.</p>
<p>No sample was recovered from the interval because of the failure of a tool.</p>
<p>&quot;Electric logs run over the bottom section of the well indicate that the other sandstone reservoirs in the well were water-bearing,&quot; Oil Search said.  </p>
<p>The current programme is for 7-inch casing to be set and the well drilled to an anticipated total depth of 3,960 metres, Oil Search said.</p>
<p>Subsequent to the well reaching total depth, a number of drill stem tests are planned for the interval 2,926 to 2,975 metres.</p>
<p>PDL-2 licence holders participating in the well are Oil Search 7.763 percent, the PNG-state owned Petroleum Resources Kutubu Pty Ltd 22.50 percent, JPP 4.844 percent and units of Chevron Corp (operator) 19.375 percent, Mobil Corp's Ampolex Ltd, 16.455 percent, The British  </p>
<p>Petroleum Co Plc 19.375 percent and The Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd 9.688 percent.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
