<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12146" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: FORECAST- FCL Building yr profit to rise.</title>
<headline>FORECAST- FCL Building yr profit to rise.</headline>
<byline>James Gray</byline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fletcher Challenge Building, fresh from cost cutting measures and a move out of unprofitable businesses, is expected to produce a healthy improvement in annual earnings when it reports next week, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>Many of those initiatives have occurred since balance date, namely the decision in July to sell down its international construction activities and exit some unprofitable Australian engineering businesses.  </p>
<p>Analysts expect a result in the region of NZ$137-8 million before abnormals, up substantially from $117 million a year earlier, and are generally positive about prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;It is one of the best examples of the benefits that are accruing to these divisions by separating them out and having them more clearly responsible, with management able to focus on those businesses and be answerable to the market,&quot; David Stanley at Doyle Paterson Brown said.</p>
<p>Fletcher Building, along with Energy and Paper, were separated into &quot;letter&quot; stocks in March.</p>
<p>Building had re-appraised many of its activities.  </p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of changes that are going to be of benefit to shareholders and I think that's been reflected in the share price,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said there will be costs in the short term associated with those moves, so there may be some abnormal items. Stanley expects a profit of around NZ$137 million.</p>
<p>The economic downturn would have an impact on the second half, but not by much. Activity had been buoyant for most of the year, slowing down just towards the end.  </p>
<p>&quot;What you will see is a lot of progress in reducing costs and there will be more benefits to come. The full beneifts will not be completely realised until next year,&quot; Stanley said.</p>
<p>Denis Lee at Hendry Hay McIntosh said one-off factors may affect earnings, such as the restructuring at the company's Taupo mill, but he agreed they would have positive long-term implications. Building reports on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64-4-4734746)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
