<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12144" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Canberra says can cut Sydney aircraft noise.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Canberra says can cut Sydney aircraft noise.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Transport Minister John Sharp said a substantial reduction in aircraft noise for those to the north of Sydney airport could be delivered if the recommendations of a new report were introduced.</p>
<p>&quot;The report...proves that it is both safe and feasible for aircraft to take off to the north on the new third new runway at Sydney's Mascot airport,&quot; Sharp told reporters on Friday.</p>
<p>The report, commissioned in May, showed that it was possible for aircraft to take off to the north on the third runway and then turn right and follow existing flight paths out to sea, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;What it also proves is that if this plan is implemented, then people living to the north of the airport...will experience a dramatic reduction in the aircraft noise,&quot; Sharp said.</p>
<p>However, this would be at the expense of people to the airport's east, although Sharp said &quot;the total number falling within a noise-affected and would actually be less than when the east-west runway was regularly used in the early 1990s.&quot;</p>
<p>Sharp said it would take four weeks to implement the recommendaions once the government was in a position to make a decision, which would depend on advice they would receive over the next few weeks, including on environmental considerations.  </p>
<p>&quot;If we can get that advice fairly quickly, then it's quite possible that this could be implemented in the next couple of months,&quot; Sharp said.</p>
<p>The Liberal National government reopened the east-west runway soon after gaining power at the March elections, lifting the previous government's policy of only using the runway when crosswind prevented use of the two north-south runways.</p>
<p>The former government said the use of parallel runways was safer, but its successor said the limit was political and removed it with the aim of sharing noise among nearby residents.  </p>
<p>Sharp said the east-west runway accounted for about 17 percent of all movements, slightly above the 15 percent target the government set.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273 2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
