<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12140" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FORECAST - Healthy Foster's profit seen.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FORECAST - Healthy Foster's profit seen.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's aspiring world brewer Foster's Brewing Group Ltd will again rely on its home market to post a solid profit for 1995/96, but shareholders will keep their sights fixed firmly offshore, stock analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>The analysts tipped Foster's to announce on Monday a net profit before abnormals of around A$270 million for the year to June 30, mainly due to earnings growth from local brewing arm Carlton and United Breweries (CUB).  </p>
<p>The average forecast for the group is much lower than the 1994/95 pre-abnormal net profit of A$350 million, but the previous result included the full contribution of British unit Courage, sold to Scottish and Newcastle in late 1995.</p>
<p>In 1994/95, Courage contributed 40 percent of Foster's earnings before interest and tax of A$496 million.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a fair bit of growth there,&quot; one Sydney-based analyst told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;CUB, I guess, is the highlight,&quot; added another.  </p>
<p>In the first half of 1995/96, CUB's earnings before interest and tax (EBIT) climbed 10 percent to A$169 million and held its market share at 53 percent.</p>
<p>In a head-to-head branding and marketing battle with New Zealand rival Lion Nathan Ltd, CUB is reported to have built its market share to 56 percent in the second half.</p>
<p>Despite CUB's success at home, the real interest in Foster's results will focus on the group's offshore operations, which analysts said held the key to the group's long-term growth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
