<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12151" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-CANBERRA WATCH - Costello fudges on A$8 bln cut.</title>
<headline>RTRS-CANBERRA WATCH - Costello fudges on A$8 bln cut.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Perrett</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Treasurer Peter Costello is fudging on the A$8 billion of promised spending cuts.</p>
<p>This number has been fiscal policy's Rock of Gibraltar since a supposed black hole of those dimensions was revealed on March 12.</p>
<p>On Friday this exchange occurred between Costello and a reporter at a Melbourne doorstop news conference.</p>
<p>Reporter: &quot;Do you plan to implement A$8 billion in savings next year despite anything the Senate does this year?&quot;</p>
<p>Costello: &quot;I put down A$7.2 billion. It's a two year programme, I'm asking (for) the right of the elected government to implement that programme in the parliament and what we do after that, we'll have a look.&quot;</p>
<p>If nothing had changed Costello would have answered &quot;Yes, of course.&quot;</p>
<p>Instead he said wait and see.</p>
<p>This is a startling turnaround from what everyone has been assuming since Tuesday's budget.</p>
<p>The budget produced almost exactly the half of A$8 billion savings that Costello had long promised, rising to A$7.2 billion in 1997/98, which we have taken as a substantial downpayment on the entire fiscal programme.</p>
<p>That is, we have assumed there is a Costello IOU for A$800 million in annual savings plus whatever the Senate knocks out when budget legislation goes before it.</p>
<p>But there are two reasons to suspect that the government might see whatever survives the Senate as good enough.</p>
<p>First, the announced programme is already enough to meet the target year for an underlying balance, which slipped to 1998/99 when the worse-than-expected 1995/96 deficit was announced on July 16.</p>
<p>Providing Senate obstruction does not cost too much that target is easily obtainable on current forecasts.</p>
<p>The second reason for thinking Costello might not bother with the rest of the A$8 billion is that those forecasts may be conservative.</p>
<p>Already Prime Minister John Howard has described as conservative the labour force forecasts, which are crucial for pay-as-you-earn tax revenue and social security spending.</p>
<p>Access Economics budget analyst Chris Richardson thinks the budget will be in strong underlying surplus in 1997/98, a year early, largely because he thinks Treasury has underestimated the labour market.</p>
<p>Costello himself hinted that he also thinks the forward estimates may be pessimistic.</p>
<p>Shortly after dodging a commitment on the A$8 billion Costello was asked at a fund-raising lunch how he would like to report on the economy in a year's time.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to be able to say that in the forthcoming year we'll go close to balance, although on current projections it would be a deficit, it'd be a very small deficit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273 2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
