<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12154" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FORECAST - Comalco H1 net, div seen down.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FORECAST - Comalco H1 net, div seen down.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bauxite miner and aluminium and alumina producer Comalco Ltd is expected to report a sharp fall in its 1996 first half net profit on Monday, due to a stronger Australian dollar and a weaker aluminium price, analysts said.</p>
<p>Australian aluminium analysts contacted by Reuters forecast Comalco to report a net profit before abnormals of between A$55 million and A$67 million for the six months to June 30, 1995, compared with A$155.1 million in the 1995 first half.</p>
<p>The analysts also expected Comalco, 67 percent owned by RTZ Corp Plc-CRA Ltd, to slash its first half dividend to about five or six cents from 12 cents a year ago.  </p>
<p>&quot;The key factors are the aluminium price is lower, the A$ dollar is up, therefore in A$ terms it is going to be even lower. The volumes have been okay for the first half,&quot; said Peter O'Connor, a metals analyst at brokers Macquarie Equities.</p>
<p>O'Connor forecast Comalco to report a net profit before abnormals of A$58.8 million in the 1996 first half and a five cent per share dividend payout.</p>
<p>Analysts have been cutting Comalco's 1996 profit forecasts since the start of 1996 due to strength of the Australian dollar and the weakness of the aluminium price.  </p>
<p>Comalco reported a 1995 year net profit of A$232.3 million. The three-month aluminium contract traded on the London Metal Exchange has fallen about 12.5 percent to a current level of 1,484.5 from 1,697.0 at the start of 1996, while the local dollar has strengthen nearly seven percent to about US$0.7900.</p>
<p>Umit Safak at brokers James Capel expected Comalco to report a net profit before abnnormals of A$55 million for the half.</p>
<p>&quot;I see the dividend being close to half of last year's,&quot; Safak told Reuters on Friday.  </p>
<p>One Melbourne-based analyst forecast Comalco to produce a half-year net profit before abnormals of A$67 million, the upper end of expectations.</p>
<p>A Sydney-based analyst said he expected Comalco to report a pre-abnormals net profit of between A$55 million to A$65 million for the six months.</p>
<p>&quot;We are down at the lower end of that range (A$55-A$65 million),&quot; another Melbourne-based analyst said.  </p>
<p>Despite the lower profit forecast, Comalco raised primary aluminium output 3.9 percent to 217,085 tonnes in the 1996 half. Analysts have trimmed back Comalco's earnings forecast for 1996 year profit in light of the aluminium price and strong local dollar, to around A$130 million from estimates of around A$255 million-A$265 million at the start of the year.</p>
<p>Analysts said Comalco shares are looking fully-priced on the current 1996 outlook and most analysts recommended a short-term hold and long-term buy for the Melbourne-based group.  </p>
<p>&quot;The share price is already priced on the basis of a return to much higher aluminium prices in 1997, 1998 and the market is anticipating that turnaround,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>At 2.30 p.m. (0430 GMT), Comalco shares were six cents lower at A$7.50 on light volume. Comalco shares have traded between A$6.30 and A$7.95 this year.</p>
<p>-- Kevin Morrison, Sydney newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
