<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12153" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: FORECAST-FCL Forest year profit to fall.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-FCL Forest year profit to fall.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Abysmal log prices and other factors are likely to combine to drag Fletcher Challenge Forest Division's earnings down to around NZ$65 million in the year to June against $68 million a year ago, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>But the market will not be too concerned.</p>
<p>Forest has been riding the crest of a wave after successfully bidding, along with Brierley Investments Ltd and China's Citic, for Forestry Corp of NZ on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The stock has been powering ahead since the sale announcement, and closed on Friday at NZ$2.03, up nine cents.  </p>
<p>The move almost doubles Forest's estate to around 300,000 hectares.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think people care about the result because they are focusing far more on the implications of the acquisition of Forestry Corp,&quot; David Stanley at Doyle Paterson Brown said.</p>
<p>Analysts have been impressed by the synergistic benefits from the deal.</p>
<p>Forest itself had been assisted by the price the consortium was prepared to pay -- NZ$2.026 billion -- in that it improves the valuation of Forest's existing estate.  </p>
<p>&quot;In terms of the result, it will be pretty awful,&quot; Stanley said. &quot;Log prices have been falling this year, the currency has gone up, and basically this is a U.S. dollar-denominated business based in New Zealand. What that's meant is revenues have gone down quite quickly.&quot;</p>
<p>Stanley expects the company's earnings to come in at NZ$58 million before abnormals.</p>
<p>Denis Lee at Hendry Hay McItonsh said he expected a number around NZ$60 million, but he too was optimstic for the future.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a positive impact on earnings (from the Forestry Corp purchase). The extent of that is yet to be seen.&quot;  </p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64-4-4734746)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
