<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12168" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Govt spending rises may limit RBNZ easing - BTNZ.</title>
<headline>Govt spending rises may limit RBNZ easing - BTNZ.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bankers Trust New Zealand economists said on Friday they expected looser fiscal policy after the October 12 general election and this could limit the extent and duration of any monetary policy easing.</p>
<p>&quot;In our view one of the safe bets to make about the post-election environment is that fiscal policy will be loosened,&quot; BTNZ economists said in a commentary.</p>
<p>&quot;Large increases in spending will require a strong response from the Reserve Bank of New Zealand if low inflation is to be maintained.&quot;  </p>
<p>The economists said that with fiscal policy set to be expansionary for some time, any monetary policy easing in late 1996 or early 1997 was unlikely to be as aggressive or prolonged as in the early 1990s.</p>
<p>&quot;If fiscal policy is loosened too aggressively, then there may be little room for the much anticipated easing -- even in combination with a slightly wider inflation target.&quot;</p>
<p>BTNZ said government spending, excluding debt servicing, rose by more than NZ$1 billion in 1995/96 and was forecast to rise by a similar amount in 1996/97, according to the 1996 budget.  </p>
<p>The government also introduced the first stage of a $3.1 billion two-year tax cut package on July 1 this year.</p>
<p>BTNZ said opposition parties were proposing substantial spending increases and even a government dominated by the conservative National Party was likely to loosen the purse strings.</p>
<p>&quot;We think spending would go up by at least $750 million in 1997/98, on top of the new spending already in expenditure baselines,&quot; the economists said.  </p>
<p>BTNZ currently forecasts 90-day bank bills at 7.5 percent by March 1997 and 10-year bonds at 7.00 percent, from around 9.9 percent and 8.0 percent now. It sees the New Zealand dollar's Trade-Weighted Index easing to 64.0 by March from around 65.5.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the low point in the easing cycle, with interest rates forecast to move higher by the end of 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>These forecasts assumed only a mild fiscal easing with the second round of tax cuts going ahead on July 1, 1997 and spending rising by perhaps $750 million over current baselines.  </p>
<p>A bigger fiscal easing, or a greater focus on spending rises, would put upward pressure on short-term interest rates and, in time, the currency.</p>
<p>If this went hand-in-hand with a widening of the Reserve Bank's zero to two percent inflation band, then a positve yield curve could result. &quot;A widening of the inflation band may initially be negative for the currency,&quot; BTNZ said.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
