<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12167" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: INTERVIEW-Progressive takes pies off menu.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Progressive takes pies off menu.</headline>
<byline>Simon Louisson</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand supermarket operator Progressive Enterprises will be a slimmer and trimmer operation without its Georgie Pie fast food chain, chief executive Graeme Kelly said on Friday.</p>
<p>The company this week announced the McDonalds fast food chain had agreed to buy 17 of Progressive's 32 Georgie Pie sites and Kelly made it clear the remaining ones would also go.</p>
<p>Georgie Pie has been one of the reason's for Progressive's recent poor performance.  </p>
<p>&quot;The financial implications are extremely positive for Progressive,&quot; Kelly said. &quot;The company is a $2.2 billion business, Georgie Pie is a $40 million business sustaining many millions of dollars of losses.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a classic case of a small, non-core business having a very undesirable impact on the whole business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Progressive, 57 percent owned by Foodland Associated, reported a net profit of just NZ$2.2 million in the six months to February and in June forecast a $6 million profit for the second half.  </p>
<p>Kelly was reappointed last year as chief executive to attend to the company's problems. He was CEO in the 1980s.</p>
<p>One of his first major actions was to conduct a review of the Georgie Pie chain.</p>
<p>Progressive had been very bullish about the chain established in the 1970s and two years ago announced aggressive expansion plans.</p>
<p>However, Kelly said that 20 years was long-enough for the chain to have established itself. Market research showed that while people liked the pies they saw them as an alternative to preferred fast food outlets such as McDonalds.  </p>
<p>&quot;There were people who made extemely optimistic and ambitious statements about Georgie Pie but the actual financial performance, and the capital investment required to achieve that performance, were not producing the results that paralleled the enthusiasm with which the business was spoken about.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The company was sustaining losses and the foreseeable future looked as though those would continue for the medium-term at least.&quot;</p>
<p>Kelly said of the 15 restaurants left, four have short-term leases which will not be renewed. The rest, mainly in provincial North Island towns, will be sold.  </p>
<p>McDonalds did not want these as they were mostly beside an existing McDonalds outlet. Kelly said he has had strong expressions of interest from American chains Wendys and Burger King and a South African chain keen to set up in New Zealand.</p>
<p>If Progressive has substantially less than 11 restaurants, it will shut the rest down, Kelly said.</p>
<p>The 17 restaurants sold were at &quot;quite a lot more than book value&quot;.</p>
<p>Kelly said while Progressive would stick to its knitting, it would still investigate new areas within that ambit.  </p>
<p>He said shopping would increasingly be polarised between shopping centres, which provided things related to fashion, entertainment and leisure, and supermarkets, which provided basic necessities purchased regularly.</p>
<p>Photo development, dry cleaning, liquor sales and banking services were areas that supermarkets would increasingly become involved in.</p>
<p>The trend in Britain and Australia of supermarkets selling petrol in the parking lot had even been investigated.</p>
<p>&quot;It is something the industry will move progressively towards,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Generally, retail consumer services businesses such as ours regard this thing positively because the selling of petroleum products, like banking services, the introduction of wine and over-the-counter drugs in supermarkets, improve the services and convenience for the customers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
