<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12160" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: FORECAST-FCL Paper yr profit to improve.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-FCL Paper yr profit to improve.</headline>
<byline>James Gray</byline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fletcher Paper should produce a healthy lift in annual earnings when it reports next week, but the result was likely to mask a malaise in pulp and paper markets where prices have slumped, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>Paper's last four halves show how cyclic its results are.</p>
<p>In the six months to December 1994, FCL paper earned NZ$21 million. The result swelled to NZ$151 million in the ensuing six months and to $186 million in the third.  </p>
<p>In contrast, analysts expect the half to June 30, 1996 to show just a few million in earnings. Some expect Paper to break even and others see a loss over the half.</p>
<p>&quot;What that shows is the impact of a very short upswing in pulp and paper prices and a very rapid downswing,&quot; David Stanley at Doyle Paterson Brown said.</p>
<p>Furthermore, there was little to suggest an improvement in commodity prices in the year ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a very short cycle. Normally you would expect to see earnings go higher and lower over longer time frames,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Paper made $172 million in the year to June 1995 and analysts expect a profit for 1996 of around $190 million. The range of most analysts' expectations is $175-$210 million.</p>
<p>Stanley expects a profit of $190 million before abnormals but said the current half may show a loss.</p>
<p>&quot;The earnings are very cyclical and depend very much on what happens to pulp and paper prices.&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Paper, the biggest of the &quot;letter&quot; stocks, has underperformed the market since the energy, building and paper divisions were split from the group in March, which coincided with a sharp downturn in pulp and paper markets.  </p>
<p>Francis Loo at SBC Warburg expects a profit of around $190 million but said the challenge would be in the year ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly, we would expect the next 12 months to be pretty tough, but individual analysts have different views on that,&quot; Loo said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got a fairly cautious outlook on commodity prices. We are not expecting significant upside and probably more deterioration in newsprint prices, but it is fair to say that commodity prices are somewhere around the bottom,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Denis Lee at Hendry Hay Mcintosh, expects a $185-6 million profit. The result is due on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64-4-4734746)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
