<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12172" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Trans Tasman says NZ CBD rentals firming.</title>
<headline>Trans Tasman says NZ CBD rentals firming.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trans Tasman Properties Ltd said on Friday that New Zealand central business district rentals were continuing to firm as vacancies in the main centres declined, but market rentals were not yet considered sufficient to trigger new development.</p>
<p>The Australian CBD office market was benefiting from a significant fall in interest rates and a rise in business confidence, the company said.  </p>
<p>The company earlier announced a rise in interim net profit to NZ$14.95 million from NZ$9.88 million.</p>
<p>The company said the impact of rising interest rates had been lessened by its policy of maintaining an average of two and a half year swaps on 78 percent of borrowings.</p>
<p>&quot;This policy is cushioning the company through the present period.&quot;</p>
<p>Trans Tasman said net rental return on the Auckland Finance Centre, which it acquired in June for $81.6 million, was $9.8 million, providing a yield of 12 percent.  </p>
<p>The company in January began a selldown of about $150 million worth of small scale and regional properties, of which about a third was either sold and settled during the period under review or under unconditional contract.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand remains strong, despite the interest rate environment, and the company will continue to seek sales at book value or better,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>In Australia, TTP acquired two sites adjoining its Landmark Building on George St, Sydney. &quot;The development potential for these sites is excellent and directors are confident that development plans can be announced to shareholders during the  </p>
<p>second half of 1996,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>TTP last month commissioned a report on the feasibility of an Australian Stock Exchange listing for its subsidiary there, and said it would keep the market informed.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
