<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12179" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian beef seen clawing back in Korea.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian beef seen clawing back in Korea.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia hopes to reverse its declining share of the big South Korean beef import market through greater tonnages being imported direct by the private sector, an Australian meat industry official said.</p>
<p>The view, expressed by Allister Lugsdin, beef programme manager international of the statutory authority Australian Meat and Livestock Corp (AMLC), comes immediately after a short-term increase in Australia's share of the Korean market through a government tender win.  </p>
<p>Australia's winning of the full grassfed section of Korea's latest government tender, for 4,000 tonnes of grassfed quarterbeef and 1,008 tonnes of grassfed fullsets, increased its share of Korea's beef import market to 30.3 percent from about 27 percent. This is still down from the 44 percent share Australia held in 1993.</p>
<p>Lugsdin welcomed the tender win. &quot;It certainly helped our market share and our results in Korea,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>But AMLC is looking toward longer-term trends rather than a single tender win for an improvement in Australia's export performance to South Korea, its third biggest beef market after Japan and the United States.</p>
<p>Longer-term, Australia's exports would grow as the private sector's share of the import market increased, Lugsdin said.</p>
<p>This year Korea's private sector is importing 40 percent of the country's intake, against 60 percent by the government's Livestock Products Marketing Organisation (LPMO).  </p>
<p>Next year, under Korea's commitments to the World Trade Organisation, the balance will tip to a 50/50 split between LPMO and the private sector.</p>
<p>The LPMO share is scheduled to decline further to 30 percent by year 2000, while the private sector's share is scheduled to rise to 70 percent.</p>
<p>This will enable exporters such as Australia to sell directly to independent groups such as supermarkets, hotels, restaurants and other users.  </p>
<p>According to Lugsdin, the LPMO tender system has limited Australia's opportunities in the Korean beef import market through its concentration on grainfed chuck rolls instead of on fullsets, Australia's preference.</p>
<p>&quot;Australia's production is geared toward selling as much of the body as possible in one order, whereas out of America ... they can pull out chuck rolls from their domestic production and sell them to Korea,&quot; Lugsdin said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have difficulty competing with the volume of just one cut like chuck rolls. We're talking about fullsets,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>As the non-government quota grew, it was hoped the government's role would be less in deciding what type of tenders were called, he said.</p>
<p>Australia is also attempting to lift its penetration of the Korean market through exporting vacuum packed cuts of beef under an Australian brand to the wholesale market.</p>
<p>&quot;It helps improve our image and demonstrates what we can supply in terms of a quality product,&quot; Lugsdin said.</p>
<p>--  Michael Byrnes, Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
