<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12171" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ share market rises to 2-1/2 year high.</title>
<headline>NZ share market rises to 2-1/2 year high.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand benchmark NZSE-40 share index on Friday rose 22.14 points, 1.01 percent, to 2,221.67, its highest point since March 1994.  </p>
<p>JB Were broker John Cobb said the market had been powering ahead this week following the government's sale to a Fletcher Forests-Brierley Investments consortium of Forestry Corp.</p>
<p>Recent economic data such as a strong fall in retail sales indicated an easing of monetary policy was in the wind.</p>
<p>&quot;That's all pointing towards an easing in interest rates which the market has been waiting for for a long time.</p>
<p>&quot;Our market has been in a hiatus period for 12 or 18 months waiting for a reduction in rates,&quot; Cobb said.</p>
<p>He said the Australian budget this week was also seen as positive for bonds and equities.  </p>
<p>Investors shrugged off a poll which showed the ruling conservative National Party support slipped three points to 34 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;There are more factors than just the election pushing the market along,&quot; Cobb said. &quot;Economic news, world markets are having a bigger impact currently.&quot;</p>
<p>He said offshore investors had viewed the Fletcher purchase very positively.  </p>
<p>Telecom has run up strongly since its first quarter result last week. The market leader, which has a 25 percent weighting in the New Zealand market, rose eight cents to an all-time high of $6.90.</p>
<p>Fletcher Forests was up nine cents to $2.03 while fellow forestry stock and No.2 in the market, Carter Holt Harvey was up seven to $3.27.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
