<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12170" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Costello says wait and see on A$8 bln cuts.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Costello says wait and see on A$8 bln cuts.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Treasurer Peter Costello said on Friday he would consider later what to do about plans to implement further budget savings.</p>
<p>Asked whether it was still his intention, as stated before Tuesday's budget, to implement A$8 billion in cuts, Costello said: &quot;I put down A$7.2 billion. It's a two year programme, I'm asking (for) the right of the elected government to implement that programme in the parliament and what we do after that, we'll have a look.&quot;  </p>
<p>Costello on Tuesday released the new conservative government's budget for the year to June 30, 1997, halving the underlying deficit to A$5.6 billion from A$10.3 billion in 1995/96.</p>
<p>The underlying measure excludes asset sales and state government debt repayments.</p>
<p>Costello's budget implemented cuts in annual spending that will grow to A$7.2 billion annually over two years.  </p>
<p>But the budget is subject to approval by parliament's upper house, the Senate, where the government does not have a majority and needs the support of at least two non-government senators in the 76-seat chamber.</p>
<p>The Labor opposition and minor parties have expressed concern about some parts of the budget and warned they would block various measures, including increased charges on university students.</p>
<p>-- Canberra bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
