<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12187" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australis confident of bond consents.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australis confident of bond consents.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pay television operator Australis Media Ltd said on Friday it was very confident of receiving the consents from U.S. bondholders needed to go ahead with a further US$225 million bond issue, which is crucial to the company's survival.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very confident that we'll get the consent of all bond holders, including Merrill Lynch,&quot; an Australis spokesman told Reuters after speaking to Australis Managing Director Neil Gamble.  </p>
<p>Earlier on Friday newspapers reported that Merrill Lynch, Australis' largest bond-holder, was concerned that Australis had sold its assets too cheaply under the rescue financing package announced on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Those stories were exaggerated to say the least,&quot; the spokesman said, adding that Australis expected the consents early next week.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't forsee any problem with the funding package,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Packer's Publishing and Broadcasting Ltd, Lenfest Communications Inc of the United States, Ron Brierley's Guinness Peat Group, UIH International Holdings and Television and Radio Services Pty Ltd agreed to inject a further US$105 million into Australis in conjunction with a joint venture agreement with Optus Vision.</p>
<p>Australis needs the approval of the bond holders to proceed with a further issue of US$225 million of bonds.</p>
<p>The US$105 million rescue package came after the bondholders demanded that at least US$100 million was injected before they granted approval.  </p>
<p>Australis shares were two cents lower at 24 cents by 10.40 a.m. (0040 GMT) on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
