<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12186" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Shell Australia to rebuild refinery output.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Shell Australia to rebuild refinery output.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shell Australia Ltd hopes to bring its 115,000 barrels per day (bpd) refinery near Melbourne back to normal production within several days, a Shell source said on Friday after a 10-day strike ended.  </p>
<p>The source told Reuters he could not give a firm schedule for the refinery's return to full output, but said it should take several days.</p>
<p>&quot;The refinery will be progressively starting up during the weekend. Maybe they (refinery management) will go through the weekend before they are up and running, but basically they will be starting up progressively as things proceed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The strike by the refinery's 240 or so operators ended on Thursday afternoon, when Shell and the Australian Workers' Union reached a compromise on their bitter dispute over changes to work practices.  </p>
<p>The operators voted to return to work from 7 p.m. (0900 GMT) on Friday.</p>
<p>The refinery has been operating at around one-third output since late last week with non-union labour.</p>
<p>The operators had shut down the plant before walking off the job on August 13.</p>
<p>One of the two product ships which had been sitting off the Geelong refinery during the strike, waiting to be loaded, had been &quot;redeployed&quot; without lifting, the source said.</p>
<p>He declined to give details.  </p>
<p>Asked if the company had been forced to declare force majeure on any shipments, he declined to comment. The redeployed ship was under a charter arrangement and was to have delivered a cargo of fuel oil and jet oil to Papua New Guinea.</p>
<p>Another product ship would be loaded soon and two tankers carrying a total of 500,000 barrels of Far East crude were also waiting off the refinery, waiting to discharge.</p>
<p>Throughout the strike, Shell agreed to take as much crude oil as possible from its main supplier, a joint venture between Exxon Corp subsidiary Esso Australia Ltd and The Broken Hill Proprietary Co Ltd.  </p>
<p>Gippsland crude producer Esso-BHP normally accounts for up to 60 percent of the refinery's crude.</p>
<p>-- Melbourne bureau 613-9286-1421</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
