<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12193" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: PRESS DIGEST - HK newspaper headlines - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - HK newspaper headlines - Aug 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>-- HONG KONG STANDARD - China cut interest rates by an average 1.2 percentage points on lending and 1.5 percentage points on savings. It was the second reduction in less than four months.</p>
<p>-- MING PAO DAILY NEWS - Hong Kong tycoon Li Ka-shing predicted Hong Kong's property market would pick up towards the end of the year, becoming prosperous in 1997.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG ECONOMIC JOURNAL - The decision by China's central bank, the People's Bank of China, to cut interest rates had boosted Hong Kong H shares to the highest point in the past 12 weeks.</p>
<p>-- SOUTH CHINA MORNING POST - A breakthrough had been announced in the textile dispute between Hong Kong and the United States, which had threatened billions of dollars in exports. U.S. officials would be permitted to visit factories to check allegations that falsely labelled goods were evading quota restrictions.</p>
<p>-- Cheung Kong (Holdings) and Hutchison Whampoa turned in stong interim results thanks to an improved property market and the sale of interests in British telecommunications unit Orange.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG ECONOMIC TIMES - Shanghai Petrochemical Co took advantage of China's interest rates cut to sell 500 million shares at HK$2.07 each. Peregrine Derivatives acted as the distributor.</p>
<p>-- MING PAO DAILY NEWS - Air tickets to Hong Kong from Vancouver, Sydney and London at the end of June next year were almost fully booked. Many people planned to visit Hong Kong to witness its return to Chinese sovereignty. The Hong Kong Tourist Association said the territory was expected to receive tens of thousands of visitors during the handover.</p>
<p>-- TA KUNG PAO - The State Council's Taiwan Affairs Office urged Taiwan to co-operate in starting direct links with China as soon as possible in order to accelerate economic prosperity on both sides of the Taiwan Strait.</p>
<p>-- The living standards of Chinese intellectuals had been upgraded to reflect their level of education, ending the days when the income of rocket scientists was less than that of street hawkers.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
