<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12196" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Killer germ claims 11th victim in Japan.</title>
<headline>Killer germ claims 11th victim in Japan.</headline>
<byline>Yvonne Chang</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A 59-year-old woman died of food poisoning on Friday in western Japan's Nara prefecture, casting a cloud over the country's plans to declare that the threat from a mysterious killer germ was receding.</p>
<p>The woman, a housewife from Yamatotakada city who had been hospitalised since last month, was the 11th person to die from the O-157 colon bacillus.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel very sorry that things turned out so very unfortunate. We did not expect such a rapid change because her condition seemed stable,&quot; Tomofumi Morita, head of the prefecture's health bureau, told a news conference on Friday.</p>
<p>The woman was admitted to the hospital in July after being diagnosed with haemolytic uremic syndrome (HUS), complications associated to infections with the O-157 bacteria.</p>
<p>She suddenly lapsed into critical condition on Wednesday, following heavy bleeding and breathing difficulties, a spokesman for Nara city told Reuters.</p>
<p>The O-157 colon bacillus has been found responsible for a widespread food poisoning epidemic that has also made more than 9,500 people ill this year.</p>
<p>The city of Sakai, near Osaka in western Japan, has been hit hardest by the food poisoning epidemic, with nearly 6,500, mostly school children, affected by the disease.</p>
<p>Health authorities believe school lunches are the source of the food poisoning which hit Sakai. But researchers have been unable to locate the exact source of the infection.</p>
<p>The outbreak has prompted authorities to tighten sanitary standards at slaughterhouses and meatpacking plants and sparked calls for an overhaul of the nation's school lunch programme.</p>
<p>News of the woman's death came as Japanese media reported that health officials were preparing to declare next month that the worst of the epidemic was over as the number of new infections had decreased.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no new cases of infection and I hope we can make public a bright outlook,&quot; Health Minister Naoto Kan said on Thursday while visiting the Osaka prefectural government.</p>
<p>The Education Ministry has started preparations to resume school lunches and encouraged schools to admit children who carry the bacteria but have not developed any symptoms.</p>
<p>But Sakai city officials remain unconvinced about the government's outlook, fearing a further spread of the disease through secondary infections by carriers of the germ.</p>
<p>&quot;There are still threats of secondary infections and the city of Sakai may not be able to do as the Education Ministry requests,&quot; Takeshi Miyazaki, head of Sakai city's education board said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Health Ministry said on Thursday that 9,509 people had fallen ill from the O-157 bacteria in Japan, of which 307 were still hospitalised.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
