<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12191" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Stocks to Watch Today - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Stocks to Watch Today - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some Australian stocks to watch this morning:</p>
<p>* Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd A$17.49 (-0.12)</p>
<p>BHP Copper said on Thursday its San Manuel smelter in Arizona has been restarted and tonnage lost during the shutdown would be minimal.</p>
<p>* WMC Ltd A$8.81 (-0.04)</p>
<p>WMC Ltd said late on Thursday that its petroleum unit, which is up for sale, includes a mix of producing and prospective assets. WMC said it was selling off its petroleum division, except for a 1,380-km gas transmission pipeline leading to the goldfields region of Western Australia.</p>
<p>* Australis Media Ltd A$0.26 (+0.01)</p>
<p>* Seven Network Ltd A$3.87 (-0.05)</p>
<p>* Publishing and Broadcasting Ltd A$5.90 (-0.05)</p>
<p>The financing package announced earlier this week to rescue troubled pay television operator Australis Media Ltd is at risk of being opposed by U.S. bondholders and The Seven Network, newspapers said on Friday. Australis said the reports of a major bond-holder's concern were wrong, but did not comment on The Seven Network aspect of the reports. It said it was very confident of getting consent for a new bond issue.</p>
<p>* CSR Ltd A$4.47 (unch)</p>
<p>CSR's Rinker Materials Corp in Florida said on Thursday it planned to modernize and expand its Miami cement plant, replacing its current wet process production equipment with a new dry system. The project will increase the plant's annual cement production capacity from 640,000 tons to one million tons at a cost exceeding $100 million and should begin operation by the end of 1998, the company said.</p>
<p>* Niugini Mining Ltd A$3.37 (+0.16)</p>
<p>* Lihir Gold Ltd A$2.26 (-0.02)</p>
<p>* Mt Edon Gold Mines Ltd  MEG.AX A$1.57 (+0.05)</p>
<p>Battle Mountain Gold Co said late on Thursday it had held preliminary discussions with its 50.4 percent-owned subsidiary Niugini Mining Ltd that might lead to an offer by Battle Mountain for the Niugini shares it does not already own.  No further discussions about a merger between Mt Edon Gold and Battle Mountain Gold were expected, Battle Mountain also said. Niugini said late on Thursday it was in talks with Battle Mountain.</p>
<p>*Kalamazoo Holdings Ltd  KLZ.AX A$2.27 (+0.02)</p>
<p>Kalamazoo Holdings Ltd said late Thursday it expects continued soft economic conditions for the rest of 1996 and some improvement in the first half of 1997.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
