<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12201" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - August 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - August 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indonesian political and business stories in leading newspapers, prepared by Reuters in Jakarta. Reuters has not checked the stories and does not guarantee their accuracy. Telephone: (6221) 384-6364. Fax: (6221) 344-8404.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>KOMPAS</p>
<p>Indonesia's President Suharto said East Timorese were free to sue Portugal, East Timor's former colonial ruler, in the International Court of Justice for cruelty during its colonisation of the territory.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>JAKARTA POST</p>
<p>The Central Jakarta district court urged Megawati Sukarnoputri, the ousted leader of the Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI), to reach an out-of-court settlement with her opponents. Megawati is suing the government and the military for backing a rebel congress in June which deposed her.</p>
<p>The central bank, Bank Indonesia, has reportedly suffered, for the first time in history, 2.0 billion rupiah ($851,063) in losses from fake transactions believed to have been committed by the bank's employees.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>REPUBLIKA</p>
<p>A police captain will stand trial for alleged negligence which led to the escape of an actress, Zarima, accused of possessing nearly 30,000 Ecstasy pills.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MERDEKA</p>
<p>One kidnapper was killed during a clash with Indonesian soldiers who tried to free 12 forestry workers in remote Irian Jaya province who were kidnapped last Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
