<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12200" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: INSIGHT - Hang Seng breaks out of triangle.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Hang Seng breaks out of triangle.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Hang Seng Index appears to have broken out of its triangle pattern formed over the past six months and is launched on a new pattern, which analysts using Eliot Wave Theory said should take the index above 11,600 toward 12,000.</p>
<p>Chris Roberts, regional technical analyst at HSBC James Capel, said the index's break out from the 11,265 resistance level was significant.</p>
<p>&quot;For the first time since the market began its triangle formation in February, a prior high has been taken out,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the individual charts, you will see that a lot of stocks are moving to new highs and that is very encouraging,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>HSBC Holdings, CITIC Pacific, Henderson Land, have all hit new highs in the past week.</p>
<p>&quot;The market appears to be on course to rise above 12,000 in the fourth quarter,&quot; Roberts said.</p>
<p>This analysis is part of his long-term view -- using Eliot Wave Theory -- that the index's current move is part of the market's bull run, an advance that began in January 1995 and has yet to be completed.</p>
<p>&quot;The bull run that began at 6,890 is still not completed. We are in the fifth wave up now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Roberts said there was a good bit of resistance between 11,900 and 12,599 and the market will need something extra to lift it beyond this all-time, intra-day high.</p>
<p>In line with his view that this is the final leg up, he said he would be watchful above the 12,000 level.</p>
<p>Eliot Wave International, referring to the short and long-term outlook for the market, said in a report: &quot;The market's rise from 10,533 is an extending third wave within the larger advance from 10,230 (on March 13).</p>
<p>&quot;There still should be further upside acceleration within this third wave. Resistance at 11,518 is where the rise from 10,533 equals the 10,230-11,215 rally,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Longer term, the advance from the March 1996 low is wave five and should eventually carry above 11,600 toward 12,000,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>-- Kathleen Kearney (852) 2843-6933</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
