<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12209" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore HSFO traders to raise bids with crude.</title>
<headline>Singapore HSFO traders to raise bids with crude.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>High sulphur fuel oil buyers were expected to raise bids on Friday in line with crude gains overnight although fundamentals remained unchanged, traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;With the crude coming up, trader buying will take the opportunity to push up levels,&quot; said a Japanese trader.</p>
<p>Traders expected 180 cst cargo prices to rise to $103/$105 a tonne. Prices of 180-cst supplies lifting in September were bid/asked at $102.50/$104 on Thursday.  </p>
<p>Singapore paper for September book-out was firmer with bids at $103.50, compared to bids/offers on late Thursday at $102.50/$102.75.</p>
<p>&quot;There is not much change in fundamentals,&quot; said a Singapore trader. &quot;Demand is not so great but on the other hand not so much oil is coming from the MidEast.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said Chinese bids were heard but at low levels of $109/$110 a tonne cost-and-freight South China for September delivery.  </p>
<p>&quot;I am not keen at all to offer at these levels,&quot; said a trader. &quot;It is much easier for South Korean cargoes to work at those prices.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders also said high viscosity Venezuelan cargoes have not emerged in Asia and have stayed in the stronger western market since July which should help to prop up levels.</p>
<p>---Singapore Newsroom (65-8703086)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
