<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12215" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian rupiah stable, swaps down in dull trade.</title>
<headline>Indonesian rupiah stable, swaps down in dull trade.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indonesian rupiah was stable against the dollar in dull late trading on Friday, with swap rates seen under some selling pressure, dealers said.</p>
<p>One European bank dealer said there was not much interest in the market as offshore operators were switching focus to the Thai baht.</p>
<p>He said volume was thin and some weekend short-covering was seen but overall sentiment seemed to support the rupiah as political tensions in the country appeared to ease.</p>
<p>Indonesia's leading opposition figure and the government may reach an accord to settle a protracted row.  </p>
<p>A court case filed by Megawati Sukarnoputri, deposed leader of the Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI), against the government for ousting her as PDI leader was postponed on Thursday and lawyers from both sides said they would try to reach an out-of-court settlement.</p>
<p>&quot;Operators seem to view the case as a non-event. Focus is now on liquidity conditions due to the month-end factor,&quot; one dealer said. He said the dollar-rupiah rate was expected to range between 2,341.0 and 2,343.0 on Monday.</p>
<p>The dealer said underlying sentiment supported the rupiah but upside was limited because of the central bank's ceiling.  </p>
<p>Spot rupiah was quoted at 2,341.8/42.2 at 0850 GMT against an opening of 2,341.50/41.75. Tomorrow and today rupiah closed at 2,341.35/41.80 and 2,339.50/40.50, respectively.</p>
<p>Dealers said swap premiums remained soft but the downside was limited by local profit-taking.</p>
<p>Overnight swap was at 1.3/1.4 and to/next at 0.45/0.55.</p>
<p>One-month swap was at 17.15/17.50, two at 34.5/35.5, three at 53.0/53.5 and six at 106.0/107.0 points.</p>
<p>The central bank raised its intervention rate by one point to 2,337/2,455 and the conversion rate also by one point to 2,337/2,383 on Friday -- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
