<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12224" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: 51 Chinese arrested for illegally entering Japan.</title>
<headline>51 Chinese arrested for illegally entering Japan.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police said on Friday they had arrested 51 Chinese found hiding in saunas for illegally entering Japan.</p>
<p>Fukuoka prefectural police in southern Japan raided four saunas after receiving calls that there were suspicious foreigners there.</p>
<p>The 51 Chinese, all males aged between 16 and 51, were arrested for not carrying passports. They are believed to have reached Japan by boat.</p>
<p>&quot;We still don't know if the four different groups all came on the same boat. We're still in the process of investigating the details,&quot; a spokesman for Fukuoka police told Reuters.</p>
<p>Some of the men told police they arrived in Japan on Thursday night from Fujian Province in southern China as a group and were taken by bus to the saunas, Kyodo news agency reported.</p>
<p>A Japanese man staying with the Chinese at one of the saunas was also arrested for allegedly helping the Chinese enter the country.</p>
<p>Separately, coast guards in Nagasaki Prefecture near Fukuoka seized 14 Vietnamese, including a four-year-old boy, aboard a small wooden boat in waters off the prefecture on suspicion of attempting to illegally enter Japan.</p>
<p>None of the Vietnamese carried passports, and the boy was handed over to immigration authorities, a spokesman for the Nagasaki Maritime Safety Agency said.</p>
<p>The 13 other Vietnamese, of whom 10 were men, were aged between 18 and 35.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
