<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12221" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Actacorp sells Burma project option.</title>
<headline>Actacorp sells Burma project option.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Actacorp Holdings Bhd said on Friday it has entered into an agreement with a former subsidiary's managing director to sell him the option for a project in the Burmese capital Rangoon for 10 million ringgit.</p>
<p>Shares of the company, which makes chemical products among other things, were suspended on Friday pending an announcement.</p>
<p>In a statement, Actacorp said the agreement was with Joseph Chong, former managing director of Actacorp unit Teknik Cekap Sdn Bhd, the national Bernama news agency reported.</p>
<p>Actacorp officials could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>Chong resigned from the company on June 25, 1996.</p>
<p>Actacorp said Teknik Cekap entered into an agreement on the City Square Project with Burma's Yangon City Development Committee on June 26, 1996, to develop land on Pyay Road in Rangoon.</p>
<p>It was to be developed into a mixed use commercial area including modern high-rise offices, hotel service apartments, retail outlets, department stores and supermarkets.</p>
<p>Actacorp said the option was given to Chong for a payment of 5.00 ringgit to Teknik Cekap for the grant and 10 million ringgit on exercise of the option upon the terms and conditions of the option agreement.</p>
<p>Up to August 1996, Teknik Cekap had spent 13.5 million ringgit on the project.</p>
<p>Actacorp said the proposed option was subject to approval of government authorities, if required.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
