<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12239" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan traders may buy 400,000 tonnes of U.S. corn.</title>
<headline>Japan traders may buy 400,000 tonnes of U.S. corn.</headline>
<byline>Eiichiro Tokumoto</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese trading houses and feed makers began purchasing U.S. corn this week for January-March shipment, and are likely to buy up to 400,000 tonnes, traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Traders returned from their summer holidays this week and were looking for the right time to enter the market,&quot; a corn trader at a Tokyo-based trading house said.</p>
<p>&quot;They launched into active U.S. corn buying on Thursday before freight rates go up. They'll cover up to 400,000 tonnes in the next few days,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>The importers are currently covering U.S. corn for January-March shipment and had bought up to 50 percent of their requirements, the traders said.</p>
<p>Japan's corn import premiums were quoted at around 103 U.S. cents a bushel C&amp;F over Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) March futures on Friday, local traders said.</p>
<p>Japan is one of the largest buyers of corn, and was forced to depend heavily on the United States after China suspended corn exports in December 1994 in an attempt to control surging domestic food prices and inflation.  </p>
<p>In 1995, Japan bought 16.35 million tonnes of corn, of which 16.03 million came from the United States, Finance Ministry data showed.</p>
<p>A key factor behind the accelerated buying was the expected rise in freight rates on the U.S. Gulf-Japan route, a key grain shipment route, they said.</p>
<p>The freight rates are now hovering above $22 a tonne, up by $2 to $3 from the end of July.</p>
<p>&quot;Bearish sentiment has dominated the freight rate market since earlier this year,&quot; said a senior purchasing official at a major feed maker.</p>
<p>&quot;But the general feeling is that freight rates have hit bottom and are expected to recover as the new crop from North America creates shipping demand. This triggered active grain buying from Japanese traders,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some shipping companies are offering rates at above $23 a tonne, also because of Japanese coal imports.</p>
<p>Traders said they are carefully watching freight rates, which could trigger further active buying next month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
