<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12232" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul brands student action as terrorism.</title>
<headline>Seoul brands student action as terrorism.</headline>
<byline>Jean Yoon</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A South Korean prosecutor on Friday branded this week's violent student protests as an act of terror and blamed a student group he said supported North Korea's aim of a Communist takover of the entire Korean peninsula for them.</p>
<p>&quot;The students initiated the confrontation by attacking the riot police who were simply keeping guard. They swung iron bars, threw molotov cocktails and destroyed 12 riot police buses,&quot; state prosecutor Koh Young-ju Koh told a news conference.</p>
<p>Nine days of pro-unification agitation at Seoul's Yonsei University masterminded by the outlawed Korean Federation of University Student Councils ended on Tuesday when riot police stormed a teaching block used by the students as a stronghold.</p>
<p>Hundreds of riot policemen and students were hurt in pitched battles and 3,499 students were detained. On Wednesday a young police officer died of head wounds, becoming the first fatality.</p>
<p>&quot;This was an act of terror, not just another demonstration,&quot; said Koh, the public security planning officer at the Supreme Public Prosecutor's Office, outlining the government's legal case for a crackdown on the federation.</p>
<p>&quot;We see the students' actions as activities that benefit the enemy,&quot; Koh said, thus putting the federation in breach of the National Security Law designed to prevent communist subversion by Pyongyang.</p>
<p>South and North Korea have remained technically at war since their 1950-53 conflict ended in a truce.</p>
<p>Koh said the federation was dominated by anti-American radicals who believe Washington is blocking Korean unification and want U.S. military forces expelled from the South.</p>
<p>&quot;They also explicitly support North Korea's unification formula, which in fact is designed to communise the entire Korean peninsula,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The students support the North's vision of a reunified Korea with both governments intact, and slogans and songs adopted by the Yonsei protesters also echo Pyongyang's propaganda line.</p>
<p>Two federation leaders are now staging a hunger strike on the North Korean side of the Panmunjom border crossing village in support of their arrested colleagues in Seoul.</p>
<p>Koh said arrest warrants have been issued for three of the federation's top leaders, while a fourth was in custody. Police are also hunting for two federation members who held senior positions last year.</p>
<p>Koh said the public uproar against the students' violent tactics encourged the police to storm the campus on Tuesday to put an end to the worst campus unrest since President Kim Young-sam took power in 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;We have received endless phone calls from the public expressing outrage over the lack of government action to punish the violent students,&quot; said Koh.</p>
<p>He cited a poll conducted by the Ministry of Information during the unrest that showed 80.2 percent of the public wanting the government to crack down on the students.</p>
<p>&quot;People have looked aside, thinking the young, small in number students can do no harm,&quot; Koh said.</p>
<p>&quot;But look at what they have done now. They have the force of an army, and when the number increases no one can tell what kind of force they'll possess,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On Thursday, the cabinet vowed to break up student rallies and prevent illegal protests from going ahead.</p>
<p>Earlier, President Kim accused radical students of waging urban guerrilla warfare in support of Pyongyang and vowed to sternly punish North Korean sympathisers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
