<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12237" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL overnight falls on Bank Negara intervention.</title>
<headline>KL overnight falls on Bank Negara intervention.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The overnight interbank rate opened at 8.5 percent before immediately slipping to 8.0 percent following an intervention by Bank Negara, dealers said on Friday.</p>
<p>They said the overnight rate was expected to ease further to around 7.5 percent against 5.90/6.00 on Thursday as liquidity pressure was mounting despite support from some principal dealers of the central bank.</p>
<p>They said the market was still liquid despite a central bank intervention in the morning to draw out one-month money for a second time this week.  </p>
<p>&quot;Now the big names are coming into the market to borrow, so rates are dropping,&quot; said a dealer with a local bank.</p>
<p>He said the central bank's principal dealers were supporting the overnight rate at a high level to give a psychological boost to interest rates after the central bank's two interventions this week failed to halt a decline in interest rates.</p>
<p>Dealers said Bank Negara had intervened in the morning to confirm it has raised its intervention level for one-month deposits to 7.05 percent from 6.95.</p>
<p>Short-term rates rose after the intervention, though it did not have much impact on longer-term rates, they said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It (Bank Negara) does not seem to have borrowed too much today. Otherwise the impact would have been seen in the rates,&quot; a dealer with a local bank said.</p>
<p>The dealers said one-week money was at 6.90/7.00 percent against 6.80/85, two-week at 7.00/10 against 6.85/90 and one-month money at 7.10 against 7.05/10.</p>
<p>Three-month money at 7.20/25 and six-month at 7.25/28, were both unchanged from Thursday.</p>
<p>Dealers said one-month money was threatening to fall below 7.05 percent in the morning, which prompted Bank Negara to intervene.  </p>
<p>On Tuesday, Bank Negara Malaysia returned to the market after nearly three months to borrow for a one-month deposit at 6.95 to 7.05 percent against 6.95 previously.</p>
<p>Bank Negara regularly intervenes in the local interbank market to keep a check on liquidity or set interest rates as part of its efforts to fight inflation.</p>
<p>But it has not been in the market since May 24, despite rising liquidity that has pressured rates downward, threatening to thwart the Bank's tight monetary policy.</p>
<p>- Madhav Reddy (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
