<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12242" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: GOLD - Far East gold prices seen rallying into Q4.</title>
<headline>GOLD - Far East gold prices seen rallying into Q4.</headline>
<byline>Mishi Saran</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot gold prices are unlikely to break out of their current moribund range in the short term, but Hong Kong and Singapore bullion dealers were optimistic on Friday that the metal would rally into the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Singapore dealers said a seasonal pick-up in physical gold buying in September, to meet peak year-end jewellery demand, should lift the yellow metal from its current US$386-$389 an ounce range.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we'll see (spot) gold break up to the $390-$394 range in the next couple of months -- by the end of October. Physical demand is still very good and providing good support below the $385 level,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The Chinese central bank's cut in interest rates on Thursday -- its second in four months -- would boost gold consumption in the long term, said Emily Li, Hong Kong and South China manager of the World Gold Council.</p>
<p>Gold sales in China see their zenith in the last quarter of the year, she noted.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the Chinese marrying season,&quot; Li said, noting &quot;People start stocking up for the Chinese New Year in the last quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Gold will trade within a $386-389 range next week with no incentives to move the market out of its range in either direction,&quot; one Hong Kong bullion trader said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong saw some physical gold buying as prices slid toward $386.50 recently, but trading at the Chinese Gold and Silver Exchange Society was marked by fluctuating interest rates throughout the week.</p>
<p>&quot;I think someone was trying to manoeuvre the market,&quot; said one dealer, adding that the interest rate changes were more abrupt than usual.</p>
<p>Gold options business was also limited this week with low price volatility doing little to spark investment interest.</p>
<p>A Singapore dealer said gold would need investment fund buying in futures as well as physical demand to lift the metal out of its present range.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not sure physical demand will be enough. We need the funds and they're more interested in silver at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>Silver closed up five U.S. cents at $5.22 an ounce for the September contract on New York's Comex market overnight on Thursday, while spot gold was indicated slightly firmer at $387.20/90 an ounce in Hong Kong at midday on Friday.</p>
<p>The dealer said silver would need to breach resistance at $5.30 to prompt corresponding gains in gold and he expected the white metal to lead bullion with the gold/silver price ratio dropping towards the 72.50 level from around 74.10 now.</p>
<p>Singapore physical gold premiums drifted lower to between 25-45 U.S. cents an ounce over spot loco London prices for Australian kilo bars, compared with 30-50 cents last week.</p>
<p>Dealers said the erosion in premiums was attributed to the drying up of buying in major Southeast Asian buyer Indonesia, which had not been offset by reasonably good demand in Thailand.</p>
<p>They said a gradual liquidation of Indonesian gold stocks was expected prior to the presidential election in the country in April/May next year.</p>
<p>Singapore premiums for South Korean and Indonesian-origin gold were indicated steady at 10-20 cents an ounce this week.</p>
<p>Dealers said that the flood of South Korean distress sales of gold into Singapore over the past few months, in response to a government crackdown on speculative bullion trade, now appeared to have slowed with imports down to around 25 tonnes of gold a month in June/July from over 30 tonnes in April/May.</p>
<p>&quot;That extra six tonnes of gold was the Korean metal,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
