<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12248" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Sri Lanka buys diesel, jet from Shell in tender.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka buys diesel, jet from Shell in tender.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lanka's state-owned Ceylon Petroleum Corp (CPC) has bought by tender diesel and jet fuel at $1.30 per barrel over Singapore spot quotes from Shell, a CPC official said on Friday.</p>
<p>The 160,000 barrels of 1.0 percent sulphur diesel and 40,000 barrels of jet fuel were for September 9-10 delivery on a cost-and-freight (c-and-f) basis to Colombo.</p>
<p>In its last tender, CPC bought from French oil firm Total 160,000 barrels of diesel at a $1.28-premium and jet fuel at a 73-cent premium for September 3-4 delivery, c-and-f Colombo.  </p>
<p>CPC has another tender to buy 145,000 barrels of diesel for September 19-20 delivery, which closes on August 29.</p>
<p>Government officials said on Thursday diesel needs would remain high for a while despite reducing Sri Lanka's power cuts to an hour a week from an hour a day.</p>
<p>The state power monopoly Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) said it could reduce the frequency of power cuts, effective Thursday, due to rising water levels at hydropower reservoirs.  </p>
<p>Sri Lanka was forced to impose daily power cuts in March after water levels in reservoirs fell to dangerously low levels with the delay in monsoon rains. The power cuts, up to eight hours a day at one stage, led to Sri Lanka importing increased volumes of diesel to run generating sets.</p>
<p>The power cuts eased in late July after heacy rains in catchment areas.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka imported 470,000 barrels of diesel in June compared with the usual monthly 300,000 barrels.</p>
<p>CPC has said it expects to import 300,000 tonnes of diesel in 1996, up from an annual average of 200,000 tonnes.  </p>
<p>--Singapore newsroom (+65-8703084)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
