<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12240" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan urges China talks, vows to press diplomacy.</title>
<headline>Taiwan urges China talks, vows to press diplomacy.</headline>
<byline>Alice Hung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Lee Teng-hui on Friday urged China to face the reality of politically estranged Taiwan and sit down to talk, and said his island would not halt its drive for broader international ties.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a fact that both sides have been under separate rule for nearly half a century,&quot; Lee, who doubles as chairman of the ruling Nationalist Party, told a two-day party congress.</p>
<p>The Nationalists, with 2.6 million members, have ruled Taiwan since their Republic of China government was defeated by the communists in a civil war in 1949 and fled to the island.</p>
<p>&quot;Both sides should face reality, with utmost sincerity and patience, to carry out communication and dialogue...so that we can resolve the problem of national reunification,&quot; Lee said.</p>
<p>Lee nonetheless stood firm on the island's drive to seek wider &quot;international living space&quot; in the face of Beijing's efforts to isolate Taiwan diplomatically.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue to expand our friendly cooperation with countries all over the world, to participate in international organisations of all kinds,&quot; Lee said.</p>
<p>The exiled Republic of China government on Wednesday kicked off its latest bid for a United Nations seat despite the certainty of a Chinese veto.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Taipei and Beijing each called for a resumption of talks broken off more than a year ago, although China's anger over Taiwan Vice-President Lien Chan's secret mission to Ukraine cooled hopes for any breakthrough.</p>
<p>Lien said on his return to Taipei on Thursday that he had met people of all levels during his private Kiev visit, but declined to confirm Taiwan media reports he had met Ukraine's president and agreed to an exchange of representative offices.</p>
<p>Ukraine, which recognises Beijing, denied that Lien had met President Leonid Kuchma.</p>
<p>Beijing regards Taiwan as a renegade province not entitled to foreign ties and has scorned even allies whom it sees as giving political quarter to the island's leaders.</p>
<p>In a report to the party congress, Lien expressed Taipei's concern over the future of Hong Kong after its mid-1997 handover to China rule and said talks with Beijing on transition-related issues should begin as soon as possible.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has paid close attention to the status of Hong Kong after 1997,&quot; said Lien, who is also premier or cabinet chief and vice chairman of the Nationalist Party.</p>
<p>&quot;Increasing economic and trade exchanges with Hong Kong and Macau...not only will boost economic development but also promote cooperation and prosperity in the Asia-Pacific region.&quot;</p>
<p>Taiwan can adopt flexible policies to maintain and expand ties with post-1997 Hong Kong, Lien said without elaboration.</p>
<p>Nationalist delegates were scheduled to discuss reforms to boost the party's appeal, party officials said.</p>
<p>The Nationalists' once-absolute power has weakened under a liberalisation begun in the 1980s, which saw legalisation of opposition parties and a gradual adoption of popular elections for all key posts -- even the state presidency.</p>
<p>The Nationalists now hold only a razor-thin majority in the Legislative Yuan, or parliament, and have launched a major drive to make themselves more attractive to voters.</p>
<p>Taiwan's main opposition is the pro-independence Democratic Progressive Party.</p>
<p>But growing numbers of young, well-educated Taiwanese have turned to the New Party, formed in 1993 by disgruntled members of the Nationalist elite who accused the ruling party of stalling on internal reforms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
