<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12243" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo precious metals end firmer with New York.</title>
<headline>Tokyo precious metals end firmer with New York.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yen-based precious metal futures ended mostly higher on Friday in dull, rangebound trade, matching firmer levels reached overnight in New York but finding no follow-through buying, traders said.</p>
<p>The market also received no direction from the currency markets, with the yen holding steady against the dollar.</p>
<p>TOCOM most-active June 1997 gold settled four yen higher at 1,344 yen per gram, traded very narrowly from 1,345 to 1,343, while the remaining months finished one to three yen better.</p>
<p>Bullion settled at $387.50/80, fractionally above the New York closing quote of $387.20/70.  </p>
<p>Gold prices strengthened overnight following cuts in money market rates in Germany and other European centres, although resistance above $388 was seen capping the market amid quiet summer trading. Traders pegged support at $385.50 to $386.</p>
<p>&quot;If spot gold doesn't get above $389 today in New York, the outlook for near-term gains will not be very good,&quot; one trading house source said.</p>
<p>He added that overseas players appeared reluctant to take positions ahead of holidays Monday in Hong Kong and Britain.</p>
<p>Platinum and silver also ended higher in line with overnight gains.  </p>
<p>Benchmark June 1997 platinum was up five yen at 1,381 yen per gram, while June 1997 silver rose 1.1 yen to 183.7 yen per 10 grams.</p>
<p>Only palladium was lower, reflecting weakness overnight as the market struggled to form a base after sliding to 2 1/2-year lows earlier this week.</p>
<p>June 1997 palladium ended three yen lower at 437 yen per gram, while the remaining months were three lower to one firmer.</p>
<p>--Edmund Klamann, Tokyo Commodities Desk (81-3 3432 6179)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
