<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12247" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul stocks end slightly higher, prospects dim.</title>
<headline>Seoul stocks end slightly higher, prospects dim.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks closed slightly higher on Friday after a day of fluctuations on the back of selective buying on theme-backed small-sized shares, brokers said.</p>
<p>The composite stock index ened 1.79 points higher at a provisional 781.42.</p>
<p>Brokers said profit-taking emerged towards the close in the absence of fresh solid boosting news.</p>
<p>The finance ministry's plan to raise the paid-in capital of the Korea Europe Fund by 50 percent in October had little impacts on the market. &quot;The market needs stronger impetus for a rally,&quot; said Yoo Jae-kyong of Daishin Securities.  </p>
<p>Brokers said rising interest rates and jitters over an economic slump were weighing heavily on the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Economic fundamentals are not going to improve overnight,&quot; said Kim Sun-mo of Dongwon Securities.</p>
<p>Volume totalled 21.39 million shares, compared with 16.83 million on Thursday. Gainers outpaced losers 529 to 301 with 123 unchanged.</p>
<p>Trading in Kun Young Construction was suspended on talk that it had defaulted on its debts. Kun Young officials refused to comment, and SEOULBANK, Kun Young's prime creditor, was not available.  </p>
<p>SEOULBANK shares fell 50 won to 5,030.</p>
<p>Hyundai Pipe, mired in labour disputes, fell 400 won to 9,100. Workers at the company rejected a wage accord reached between union negotiators and management.</p>
<p>Union members of Hyundai Pipe have been on strike since Tuesday after wage negotiations broke down.</p>
<p>Seondo Electric rose on interest in environmental products and good earnings prospects. It gained 1,000 won to 88,800. Pharmaceutical shares also rose. They have been in the centre of takeover speculation because many of them lack dominant shareholders. --KIM MYONG-HWAN (822) 727-5645</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
