<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12255" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Sept JGBs end higher in nervous pre-tankan trade.</title>
<headline>Sept JGBs end higher in nervous pre-tankan trade.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Key September 10-year Japanese government bond futures closed higher in nervous Friday trade ahead of the Bank of Japan's &quot;tankan&quot; survey due next week.</p>
<p>Many participants were sensitive to rumours about the BOJ's monetary policy ahead of the release of the tankan and some reacted to market talk, which spread in the late afternoon, that the BOJ might not raise interest rates soon due to the economy's weak recovery, traders said.</p>
<p>The tankan is an important indicator used by the BOJ in deciding monetary policy. The September gained 0.24 to 120.90, the highest finish for any key contract since December 22.  </p>
<p>The September touched a day high of 120.91 just before the close. Its low was 120.63. Turnover was a low 29,660 contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;I heard there was a report saying the BOJ would not raise interest rates in the near future,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Traders said the rally toward the close was triggered by a foreign news report that Japan's economy may slow down in the second half of this fiscal year due to a drop in government spending.</p>
<p>The report was used as a buying factor by some operators because it implied no imminent credit tightening, although it did not include any fresh news, they said.  </p>
<p>Traders said it was becoming a consensus that the tankan may not provide a sufficient reason for the BOJ to change its current super-easy credit stance, and this had supported overall sentiment recently.</p>
<p>A Reuter poll showed private forecasts of the key diffusion index for big manufacturers ranged from minus four to plus five, against the minus three posted in the previous survey. Seven out of 15 think-tanks predicted that the index would slip into positive territory for the first time since November 1991.</p>
<p>But traders said the BOJ may not move on an improvement in only the key index because slow capital spending was likely.  </p>
<p>The key 182nd 10-year yield ended at a four-month low of 3.070 percent, down 0.045 from Thursday. It fell as low as 3.090 percent in the early morning in a vigorous mood following the Bundesbank's surprisingly large rate cut, traders said.</p>
<p>Traders said they expect the December futures contract to become the new benchmark on Monday at the earliest. Expectations of investor buying on dips would continue to underpin the market, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors, who failed to react to the recent rate falls, will review their second-half investment plan after the tankan,&quot; said a trader at a bank's securities unit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
