<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12267" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai copper ends down on panic selling.</title>
<headline>Shanghai copper ends down on panic selling.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai copper futures ended down across the board on Friday on panic selling due to rumours of new arrivals of spot copper in Shanghai, traders said.</p>
<p>The most active December 1996 contract ended down at an intra-day low of 20,100 yuan ($2,420) per tonne, losing 220 yuan. It opened at a high of 20,290.</p>
<p>September fell 80 to 20,920 yuan, October 170 to 20,510, November 220 to 20,180, the January 1997 contract fell 220 to 20,100, February 240 to 20,150, March 200 to 20,200 and March 800 to 20,200.</p>
<p>Combined volume rose to 20,655 tonnes from 16,580.  </p>
<p>Copper opened down and fell for most of the session, before most contracts closed at or near their intra-day lows.</p>
<p>Traders said that long liquidation and fresh selling emerged at higher levels, with rumours of new arrivals of spot copper continuing to depress the confidence of retail investors.</p>
<p>&quot;Panic selling was responsible for today's falls,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Technical charts show that copper will test the key support level at 20,000 yuan after falling below the range of 20,500/21,000,&quot; a second trader said. &quot;If copper cannot find support at 20,000, it will have much room to fall.&quot;  </p>
<p>Traders said poor fundamentals would not improve because of weak spot demand for copper for the rest of the year, despite a cut in interest rates as from Friday.</p>
<p>China cut deposit and lending rates by an average of 1.5 and 1.2 percentage points as from Friday, but traders said the impact would not be felt immediately in the market.</p>
<p>Traders expect copper to fall further in the next few days.</p>
<p>Aluminium ended down, following copper. The September contract fell 100 to 14,550 yuan, October 100 to 14,300 and November 110 to 14,240. Combined volume rose to 415 tonnes from 220. ($1=8.3071 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
