<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12385" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Northern Vietnam holds breath as storm passes.</title>
<headline>Northern Vietnam holds breath as storm passes.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Typhoon Niki swept across storm-battered northern Vietnam early on Friday but initial reports indicated the region had been spared further major damage.</p>
<p>Voice of Vietnam radio said coastal areas around Haiphong had borne the brunt of the storm as it swept ashore, but an official with the International Federation of the Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies said no major damage had been reported.</p>
<p>The capital, Hanoi, where hundreds of residents had to evacuate flooded homes earlier in the week, escaped relatively unscathed with only one reported death, caused by a falling tree.</p>
<p>But the IFRC official said it was too early to gauge Niki's impact and said flooding remained a danger as river levels rose.</p>
<p>Damage reports from provinces to the north and west of Hanoi were not available on Friday morning.</p>
<p>Northern Vietnam has been battered by a series of storms over the past 10 days causing some of the worst damage seen in years.</p>
<p>The IFRC official said 119 bodies had been recovered from a devastating whirlwind which ripped through fishing fleets off the coast southeast of Hanoi last week.</p>
<p>&quot;We know 119 bodies have definitely been identified. At the moment they are talking about 375 people missing, with 258 of these now believed dead,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in northern Vietnam further deaths and damage were reported and hundreds of residents in the capital Hanoi were evacuated from homes close to the Red River earlier this week.</p>
<p>Niki was heading towards the border with Laos on Friday. Forecasters said flooding remained a danger but that the storm was weakening.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
