<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12380" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan share prices finish firmer but off highs.</title>
<headline>Taiwan share prices finish firmer but off highs.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Late profit-taking erased some early-session gains but Taiwan share prices managed to close higher on Friday, with brokers expecting further consolidation.</p>
<p>Brokers noted cautious sentiment triggered by concern over Taiwan-China relations after China set rules on direct shipping links across the Taiwan Strait early in the week.</p>
<p>Taipei, saying Beijing's rules were mingled with political issues, still bans direct shipping links with China.</p>
<p>The index closed up 39.40 points or 0.64 percent at 6,200.22, compared with a mid-session high of 6,231.60. Turnover was a solid T$35.6 billion, compared with T$29 billion on Thursday.  </p>
<p>While China concerns are seen chilling sentiment, brokers said investors might turn their focus to movements of foreign institutions, noting Morgan Stanley's plans to include Taiwan's stock index in its Emerging Market Free Index on September 2.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors may gradually switch their interest to news on Morgan Stanley's index, although that does not mean foreign funds will enter Taiwan immediately,&quot; said Barry Lin of China Securities Investment.</p>
<p>Sentiment was helped on Friday by officials' recent comments that Taiwan would not change its economic policy toward China to discourage investment there, brokers said.  </p>
<p>Vice-President Lien Chan's secretive visit to Ukraine, which has riled China, cast minor worries into the market but brokers saw no major impact. Ukraine recognises Beijing, not Taipei.</p>
<p>Construction stocks were heavily traded as investors hopes for an industry recovery picked up. The government has said it would speed up public construction to boost the slow economy.</p>
<p>Prince Housing was the third most active issue, gaining 20 cents to T$25.10.</p>
<p>Brokers saw profit-taking pressure above the 6,200-point level while strong near-term support was at 6,100.</p>
<p>-- Joyce Liu (2-5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
