<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12393" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila forex deals trade hits record $254 mln.</title>
<headline>Manila forex deals trade hits record $254 mln.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turnover on the Manila foreign exchange market hit a record $254 million in intraday trading on Friday as the Philippine peso rebounded from false rumours that the national defence chief had been killed, the Bankers Association of the Philippines said.  </p>
<p>Traders said the market is now being swamped with dollars for stock market investments and from unloading banks which had bought dollars on late Thursday as the rumour injected panic.</p>
<p>The Bankers Association of the Philippines said the current volume in the foreign exchange market exceeded the $236.50 million posted in July 13, 1995 and the $232 million in Feb 14, 1996 when the market also went into a frenzy in the wake of grenade attacks in the financial district of Makati.</p>
<p>The Central Bank is now offering to buy dollars at 26.201 pesos from an earlier 26.202 pesos, traders said. They estimate the Central Bank has now gobbled up about $100 million from the market.</p>
<p>The peso is now trading at 26.205 pesos, up from its previous close of 26.225 pesos. Volume has further risen to $262 million.</p>
<p>The peso was hammered to a low of 26.235 pesos on Thursday as the rumour spread across the market.</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom (632) 841-8937</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
