<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12403" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam confirms sentencing of dissidents.</title>
<headline>Vietnam confirms sentencing of dissidents.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam confirmed on Friday that three prominent dissidents had been sentenced to prison for divulging state secrets, but diplomats and rights groups said the sentences were lighter than expected.</p>
<p>The official Vietnam News Agency said Le Hong Ha, a former senior Communist Party member, and leading academic Ha Si Phu had been jailed for two years and one year, respectively.</p>
<p>Veteran communist critic Nguyen Kien Giang also received a 15-month, suspended sentence, it said.</p>
<p>The trial was closed to foreign journalists. Court sources had indicated earlier that Phu's 12-month sentence also had been suspended.</p>
<p>Ha Si Phu has been in jail since late last year and that time will be deducted from his sentence if normal practice is followed. That would leave him behind bars for another three to four months.</p>
<p>Le Hong Ha was arrested at about the same time and would face about 15 months in prison if the sentence is not appealed.</p>
<p>Vietnam's state media also reported the sentences on Friday without comment, referring only to the sentencing of &quot;three retired state employees&quot;.</p>
<p>Newspapers said Ha Si Phu and Nguyen Kien Giang had both confessed to obtaining classified documents from Le Hong Ha.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a spokeswoman for the human rights organisation Amnesty International said by phone that it opposed jail terms for people who had expressed political views, but that the terms were not as severe as had been anticipated.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, he shouldn't be in prison,&quot; she said, referring to Le Hong Ha. &quot;But it's good that there's been a suspended sentence.&quot;</p>
<p>Diplomats and others in Hanoi, who had been looking to the trial for indications of the political mood after the recent Communist Party congress, were quietly upbeat in their reaction.</p>
<p>&quot;It's difficult to make a judgement based on just one trial (since the congress)... But it would be good if this is a sign that things are improving,&quot; said a senior Western observer.</p>
<p>Party congresses are major political events in Vietnam. The late-June congress saw a shake-up of the leadership with the appointment of several security-related personnel to prominent politburo positions.</p>
<p>However, the impact of the changes has remained unclear.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
