<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12431" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper editorials - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper editorials - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>With 312 days to go before the British colony reverts to China, the Hong Kong media focused on cross straight relations and the economies of greater China.</p>
<p>The middle of the road HONG KONG ECONOMIC JOURNAL said China's military threat had failed to get Taiwan to acknowledge allegiance to China, but Beijing had not given up, and had replaced missiles with &quot;money bullets&quot; targetted at the Taiwanese business sector.</p>
<p>It said China's decision to start direct shipping links to Taiwan was a piece of fatty pork for Taiwanese businessmen dangled before them in the hope they would persuade their government to give up seeking international recognition.</p>
<p>The paper thought Taiwan's recent high-profile diplomatic efforts were very dangerous, because they would give some Chinese leaders better reasons to start a war across the Strait.</p>
<p>The HONG KONG ECONOMIC TIMES commented said the interest rate cuts by China's central bank, the People's Bank of China, exceeded market expectations.</p>
<p>It said Beijing wanted to create a prosperous economic panorama ahead of the Hong Kong handover and the 15th general conference of the Communist Party next year.</p>
<p>It said Hong Kong's finance, trading and retail sectors would benefit from the decision.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG NEWSROOM (852) 28436441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
