<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12450" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: FEATURE - For Sakamoto, a stripped down musical journey.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - For Sakamoto, a stripped down musical journey.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Wagstaff</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>To someone known for either the rich classical film scores of 'Last Emperor' and 'Little Buddha' or his innovative work on the synthesiser, Ryuichi Sakamoto's latest incarnation has been a surprise, not least to himself.</p>
<p>Dumping orchestra, synthesisers, sequencers and computers, the bleach-haired Sakamoto fronts a stripped-down trio of piano, violin and cello for a tour and album (&quot;1996&quot;) that has brought him closer to his audience and also, he says, to himself.</p>
<p>&quot;I was a bit afraid that this tour would be a little weaker than the other ones before because we are just three, and without hi-tech equipment, but actually the result is the other way round,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;This time I have had the strongest reaction I have had in my life, because there is no wall between us so as we get the same vibe from the audience and they get the same thing from us. It's two-way communication.&quot;</p>
<p>For the striking, softly spoken Sakamoto, whose score for Bernardo Bertolucci's &quot;Last Emperor&quot; won him an Oscar, a Grammy and a Golden Globe, this is unusual territory.</p>
<p>Onstage with Everton Nelson (violin) and Jacques Morelembaum (cello) he weaves an atmosphere of intimacy despite the austere surroundings of Hong Kong's Concert Hall.</p>
<p>The pieces range from arrangements of his haunting film scores -- &quot;Merry Christmas Mr Lawrence,&quot; &quot;Sheltering Sky&quot; and &quot;Last Emperor&quot; -- to Okinawan folk songs and the minimalism and experimentation of new material from &quot;1996&quot;.</p>
<p>During an improvisatory interlude, Sakamoto leaves his stool to pluck the strings of his grand piano and strikes its wooden sides, clearly enjoying himself alongside his fellow musicians.</p>
<p>At other times he throws back his shock of yellow-black hair as he pounds the keys dramatically, or hunches during quieter moments, face disappearing under his fringe as he draws familiar but moving melodies from the upper reaches of the keyboard.</p>
<p>For Sakamoto, 44, the collaboration may be a turning point.</p>
<p>&quot;This tour has given me something more than I expected and this trio is becoming now more important than I expected, so I am thinking about using this trio in the future, maybe for the next album,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>If he does it would mark an unusual continuity in Sakamoto's eclectic musical wanderings.</p>
<p>A list of his collaborators reads like a Who's Who of great contemporary pop and jazz musicians, including David Byrne, David Sylvian, Youssou N'dour, David Bowie and Iggy Pop. He has also acted in two of the movies he wrote music for, as well as allowing his good looks to sell clothes for Barney's and Gap.</p>
<p>But for the classically trained Sakamoto, his music remains a journey of discovery that has taken him through styles as diverse as Brazilian, Indonesian, techno and the rhythms and instrumentation of traditional North Africa.</p>
<p>And, while he maintains contact with many of those he has worked with, sometimes playing alongside them later, he says this musical journey is a very personal, solitary one.</p>
<p>&quot;I am seeking my own style...one I can say 'this is Sakamoto style, this is my style... So until then I have to try many things,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Does he feel he has reached that point?</p>
<p>&quot;It's not perfect enough, no. It's maybe 80 percent. Because I have tried many things, and now I know this is good, this is bad, this is useful, this is not. But still there are many things I haven't done, so I would like to try more,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While this tour, which took in Europe, Asia, Australia, Japan and the United States, has highlighted his skills as a pianist, Sakamoto said there was little chance of him forsaking permanently the technical gadgetry of the modern keyboardist.</p>
<p>&quot;I still love it. I am a fanatic of computer technology, the Internet, digital recording systems and so on,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>Indeed, Sakamoto is true to his roots as an early dabbler in synthesiser technology, hooking himself up for this tour to the Internet to offer some of the first live concert broadcasts through the medium.</p>
<p>So where does he see music, and in particular synthesiser music, going? Is melody, composition and originality in danger of disappearing under the weight of sampled music, monotonous pulse-driven dance music and recycled songs of yesteryear?</p>
<p>Sakamoto, fresh from a concert in China, thinks not.</p>
<p>&quot;When I was in Beijing I was coming into the city from the airport and I was looking outside the bus. There was blue sky, trees, flowers and birds; cars and highways too. But nature is always there and I was convinced the future of music won't be different,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I will still be moved listening to Mozart, when I get to 60 or 70; in 10 or 20 years' time it won't be different.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
