<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12462" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: FEATURE - Kuwait sizzles in torrid summer misery.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Kuwait sizzles in torrid summer misery.</headline>
<byline>Inal Ersan</byline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;I think God will send us to paradise. He would not put us in hell twice!&quot; said el-Sharqawi Ahmad, an Egyptian labourer sweltering in Kuwait's summer sun.</p>
<p>&quot;Your excellency can fry an egg on my head,&quot; he told a reporter, pointing to a sweating, hairless spot on the top of his head normally protected by a white cloth soaked in water.</p>
<p>Sizzling Kuwait City is the hottest capital in the Gulf in midsummer, with temperatures in the shade regularly over 50 degrees Centigrade (122 Fahrenheit).</p>
<p>Kuwaiti officials say that from June to September the oven-like climate makes their city the hottest in the world and creates a lifestyle supremely dependent on the air conditioner.</p>
<p>&quot;It's like a sauna -- daily and free of charge!&quot; civil servant Najla al-Fawzan said.</p>
<p>Residents have developed precautions, many involving cars, to beat the worst effects. Newcomers learn not to touch any vehicle or anything metal left for long in the sun. Some drivers use gloves to protect against blistering steering wheels.</p>
<p>Motorists are told not to leave any living thing -- from babies to pets to potted plants -- in cars parked outdoors because they will start to bake. And going barefoot on hot sand will result in a trip to the doctor.</p>
<p>&quot;My baby looks as red as beetroot after a five-minute drive to market in the summer,&quot; said Huda, a Syrian housewife.</p>
<p>A resident who had to push his American car after it broke down badly burned his hands on the bodywork's hot metal and needed medical attention.</p>
<p>The best swimming pools in Kuwait are chilled, not heated. And doctors warn people not to swim in daylight to protect themselves from potential skin cancer and blisters.</p>
<p>Trying to take a cold shower is no solution -- the chances are that both hot and cold taps will spew out scalding water heated by the sun's onslaught on rooftop water tanks.</p>
<p>Night brings little relief to anyone outdoors. Downtown, heat stored up in the day radiates powerfully out of concrete skyscrapers directly onto sweating pedestrians. In the desert, dust and intense heat combine to form a sweaty, itchy hell.</p>
<p>&quot;The burning, fiery wind seems to scorch the very eyeballs,&quot; British diplomat Harold Dickson wrote in the desert in 1936.</p>
<p>But despite the country's annual grilling most of the 1.8 million residents manage to live comfortably thanks to round-the-clock air conditioning and the extreme aridity in summer.</p>
<p>Houses, cars, buses, shops, a pedestrian bridge -- even army tanks and battle vehicles -- are air conditioned. Car purchases are often decided on their air conditioning power.</p>
<p>Sunstroke deaths are rare as nationals wear sensible, loose white robes and headcovering to curb the sun's rays.</p>
<p>And while Kuwait's temperatures are higher, other Gulf states often endure equal discomfort because the greater humidity of their climates raises the head felt by the body.</p>
<p>Relief comes in winter when Kuwait's climate of extremes makes it the coldest Gulf capital, with temperatures below 10 degrees Centigrade (50 Faherinheit).</p>
<p>The importance of air conditioning is reinforced in very rare summer power blackouts, a disaster that happened for several days in the mid-1970s and again once in the mid-1980s.</p>
<p>The universal solution is to abandon home or office and sit in air conditioned vehicles with the engine running. In the blackouts parents had to drive heat-distressed young children around for hours in the evening to try to get them to sleep.</p>
<p>Most Kuwaitis spend the summer abroad to avoid the hottest months of July and August -- only to complain about the heat in London and Paris, where air conditioning is less common.</p>
<p>Asian and Arab outdoor labourers are not so lucky. They usually work eight hours a day, sometimes in direct sunlight.</p>
<p>&quot;We live in an oven. It's so hot it burns our face and there is no relief until late at night, and only then if there is a breeze off the water,&quot; said a Bangladeshi fisherman in a corrugated iron shanty village at Doha north of the city.</p>
<p>Some doubt official temperatures. A Canadian was shocked to see a private gauge read 58 degrees Centigrade (136 Farenheit) on a July day when the official reading was just 47.2 (117).</p>
<p>But Kuwait does not set a temperature at which businesses and state offices must shut. Labour law says work should stop only in unspecified &quot;extraordinary circumstances&quot;.</p>
<p>And to some, heat means profit. Haji Amin, an Iranian grocer who stays indoors for most of his day, chuckles: &quot;I sell more ice cream, soft drinks and mineral water in the summer.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
