<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12461" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Egyptian press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-AHRAM</p>
<p>- President Mubarak warned that it would be difficult to hold the Cairo economic summit if no progress was achieved in the Middle East peace process and if Israel does not carry out its commitments. He called on Israel to bring about progress on the ground, otherwise the conference would be pointless, in that the states of the region would stay away. He said he was surprised at demands that the Egyptian armed forces give up their missiles, saying the demand should apply to all states in the region. Egypt's missiles are within international agreements and Israel has missiles with a longer range, he said.</p>
<p>- Mubarak had telephone calls from the Emir and the Crown Prince of Kuwait. He had a telephone conversation with Palestinian President Yasser Arafat. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu called Mubarak and they discussed promoting the peace process and implementation of old agreements.</p>
<p>AL-AKHBAR</p>
<p>- President Mubarak said there was no going back on free education and the private universities do not mean a retreat from this principle. He said that work was under way on 3,556 projects with an investment of 50 billion pounds ($15 million).</p>
<p>- President Mubarak met Japanese Foreign Minister Yukihiko Ikeda and discussed promoting Japanese investment in Egypt and Japan's contribution to the bridge over the Suez Canal, 60 percent of the costs of which Japan will pay.</p>
<p>- The technical committee of the Egyptian civil aviation authority has started examining the EgyptAir plane which had an accident at Istanbul airport on Wednesday.</p>
<p>AL-GOMHURIA</p>
<p>- Mubarak's speech.</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Amr Moussa will begin an African tour on Tuesday, covering Tunisia, Mauritania and Nigeria.</p>
<p>AL-WAFD</p>
<p>- The courts have referred to the constitutional court a presidential decree requring contractors to pay sales tax.</p>
<p>- The head of the state holding company for pharmaceuticals said the state would not sell all shares in its pharmaceutical companies, but only 40 percent of them.</p>
<p>$1 = 3.40 pounds</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
