<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12464" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Iraqi Kurd group claims defeat of Iran-backed foe.</title>
<headline>Iraqi Kurd group claims defeat of Iran-backed foe.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Iraqi Kurdish guerrilla group has claimed a major victory over a rival Kurdish militia which it says is being supported militarily by Iran in fighting in the mountains of northern Iraq.</p>
<p>The Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) of Massoud Barzani said in a statement on Thursday night that its forces had halted an Iranian-backed attack by thousands of Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK) fighters.</p>
<p>&quot;The PUK force were defeated and chased all the way to the Iranian border,&quot; the statement said. KDP said the fleeing PUK fighters left a large amount of weapons and ammunition on the battlefield and suffered &quot;a major military defeat&quot;.</p>
<p>Around 400 PUK guerrillas were killed, wounded or taken prisoner, it said. The PUK, led by Jalal Talabani, was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Fresh fighting between the two groups, rivals for decades, broke out last weekend and shattered a 17-month ceasefire brokered by the United States.</p>
<p>The KDP has accused neighbour Iran of laying down artillery barrages in support Talabani's group and allowing its rivals to use Iranian territory. The PUK denies backing from Tehran.</p>
<p>The clashes are taking place in a Kurdish enclave protected from Baghdad by a U.S.-led air force based in southern Turkey since shortly after the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>Washington has urged the rival Kurdish parties to stop fighting and accept a U.S. invitation to peace talks in London.</p>
<p>Northern Iraq has been split into rival Kurdish zones since fighting broke out between the two groups in 1994. Around 3,000 people died until the ceasefire last March.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
