<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12465" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in Israeli newspapers on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>HAARETZ</p>
<p>- Security source: Arafat's distress has led to formation of Arab front against Israel.</p>
<p>- Plans for Israeli National Security Agency cancelled after Defence Minister Mordechai objects.</p>
<p>- Israeli labour and social welfare minister proposes transit camp to hold illegal foreign workers waiting for expulsion.</p>
<p>- Opposition leader Peres in Gaza: I came to advance the peace process, not to attack the Israeli government.</p>
<p>- Unilever in preliminary contacts to buy Sunfrost from Clal.</p>
<p>MAARIV</p>
<p>- Netanyahu telephoned Egyptian President Mubarak last night and promised resumption of negotiations with Arafat.</p>
<p>- Interior Ministry intends to deport 2,000 foreign workers each month.</p>
<p>- Hebron redeployment decision to be taken in a week or two.</p>
<p>YEDIOTH AHRONOTH</p>
<p>- Netanyahu telephoned Mubarak to say Israel would resume talks with Palestinians soon.</p>
<p>- Cabinet to discuss today setting up transit camps for foreign workers.</p>
<p>- Egypt announces it stopping negotiations with Israel on sale of natural gas over &quot;unrealistic&quot; prices proposed by Israel.</p>
<p>GLOBES</p>
<p>- Sheraton buys 50 percent of Koor Hotels and Leisure and will run the hotels.</p>
<p>- Israel and Jordan to open negotiations on improving trade accord.</p>
<p>- Sharp slowdown -- 35 percent drop -- in housing starts in first-half 1996.</p>
<p>JERUSALEM POST</p>
<p>- Mubarak threatens cancellation of Cairo economic summit in November.</p>
<p>- Netanyahu: Government will discuss Hebron with Palestinian Authority soon.</p>
<p>- Cabinet to examine plan to deport up to 100,000 foreign workers.</p>
<p>- Peres, Arafat meet at Erez crossing point between Israel and Gaza.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
