<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12470" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O. LICHT - Daily sugar report.</title>
<headline>F.O. LICHT - Daily sugar report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>SUGAR: World market for August 22, 1996</p>
<p>White sugar futures in London ended easier but off lows in light trade, lacking direction either from physical news or New York. October ended down $1.80 at $351.60 per tonne while December was off $0.40 at $346.40. Traders said while there was interest to deal the nearby October/December spread, actual trades looked thin. Congestion seemed to ease at Brazil's Santos Port where Lloyds shipping intelligence said nine vessels loading sugar were berthed after nearly double that number two weeks ago. Sugar futures in New York settled barely changed as the October contract failed to pierce key resistance at 11.90 cents/lb, market sources said. The contract made its high of 11.89 on early trade buying but a lack of followthrough and producer selling at the highs limited gains. The October contract closed up 0.03 cents at 11.85 cents, having ranged from 11.89 to 11.75. March eased 0.01 on the day to 11.45, while the back months went out unchanged to 0.02 lower.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>UNITED KINGDOM - Sugar imports in May 1996 amounted to 126,106 tonnes, raw value, against 128,666 tonnes in May 1995. This brought cumulative imports in the first eight months of 1995/96 (October/May) up to 893,364 tonnes compared to 947,212 tonnes. Total imports in 1994/95 reached 1.47 million tonnes compared to 1.34 million tonnes in 1993/94. Major countries of origin in October/May 1995/96 were Mauritius with 369,852 tonnes raws against 338,201 tonnes, Guyana with 124,696 tonnes compared to 118,800 tonnes and Fiji with 106,680 tonnes compared to 76,750 tonnes. Sugar exports in May 1996 reached 35,516 tonnes, down from 51,913 tonnes in May 1995. This brought cumulative exports in October/May 1995/96 up to 257,805 tonnes against 325,267 tonnes in 1994/95. Total exports in 1994/95 amounted to 560,076 tonnes compared to 537,317 tonnes in 1993/94. Major countries of destination in October/May 1995/96 were Israel with 77,060 tonnes whites compared to 88,006 tonnes, Norway with 31,678 tonnes against 25,548 tonnes and Italy with 23,030 tonnes against 20,775 tonnes.</p>
<p>NETHERLANDS - Sugar imports in May 1996 amounted to 5,657 tonnes, raw value, which brought cumulative imports in the first eight months of 1995/96 (October/May) up to 42,928 tonnes against 41,041 tonnes in 1994/95. Total imports in 1994/95 reached 64,568 tonnes against 79,854 tonnes in 1993/94. Major countries of origin in October/May 1995/96 were France with 17,748 tonnes whites against 16,163 tonnes and Belgium-Luxembourg with 12,859 tonnes compared to 11,130 tonnes. Sugar exports in May 1996 reached 5,211 tonnes, sharply down from last year's 52,242 tonnes. This brought cumulative exports in October/May 1995/96 up to 266,870 tonnes against 282,996 tonnes in 1994/95. Total exports in 1994/95 amounted to 381,586 tonnes against 654,277 tonnes in 1993/94. Major countries of destination in October/May 1995/96 were Iran with 61,802 tonnes whites against 78,697 tonnes, Libya with 25,237 tonnes compared to 6 tonnes and Turkey with 23,516 tonnes against nil.</p>
<p>IRELAND - Sugar exports in March 1996 amounted to 6,025 tonnes which brought cumulative exports in the first half of 1995/96 (October/March) up to 51,392 tonnes, sharply up on last year's 24,106 tonnes. Total exports in 1994/95 amounted to 56,773 tonnes against 31,867 tonnes in 1993/94. Major countries of destination in October/March 1995/96 were the United Kingdom with 25,253 tonnes whites against 21,216 tonnes and Turkey with 9,999 tonnes compared to nil. Sugar imports in the first half of 1995/96 reached 4,180 tonnes against 5,097 tonnes in the corresponding period the previous year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
