<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12472" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Switzerland - August 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Switzerland - August 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>NEUE ZUERCHER ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- Flavio Cotti, Swiss foreign minister and current head of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe said the OSCE should take action on election manipulations in Bosnia.</p>
<p>- Switzerland's road show to promote the country, called &quot;Treffpunkt Schweiz&quot; opened in Leipzig and will be held in nine more German cities.</p>
<p>- The Atel Group's six-month profit rose by 18.5 percent to 96 million Swiss francs compared to the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>- Galactina Group is selling its children's food, tofu product and nutrition product divisions to Wander AG, a subsidiary of Sandoz. Galactina will concentrate on its core pharmaceuticals and medical technology business.</p>
<p>TAGES ANZEIGER</p>
<p>- The Swiss Nationalbank intervened on the money market in order to offset an overvaluation of the Swiss franc. - The magazine &quot;Institutional Investor&quot; ranked Union Bank of Switzerland number ten in the world in terms of the amount of capital.</p>
<p>JOURNAL DE GENEVE</p>
<p>- The Swiss government is putting an article in the constitution on organ transplants in order to better control regulations and distribution.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
