<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12477" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Hunger strikers vow to maintain Paris protest.</title>
<headline>Hunger strikers vow to maintain Paris protest.</headline>
<byline>Irwin Arieff</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 300 Africans holed up in a Paris church since June said on Friday they planned to maintain their occupation, following Prime Minister Alain Juppe's refusal to grant them blanket permission to remain in France.</p>
<p>Spokeswoman Madjiguene Cisse, one of the 300 in the Saint-Bernard church, said the decision to keep up the protest had been urged by the 10 of them who are on the 50th day of a hunger strike to pressure the government into granting them all residence permits.</p>
<p>The decision came after Juppe announced in a television message that France's highest administrative court, the Council of State, had endorsed his government's view that the 300 Africans were not legally entitled, as a block, to residence permits.</p>
<p>But Juppe said the government still intended to review their right to remain in France on a case-by-case basis and had no intention of using deportation to break up families or expel seriously ill individuals.</p>
<p>Following Juppe's videotaped statement, protesters said they had received several calls warning that police were preparing to eject them early on Friday, although hundreds of sympathisers have surrounded the Saint-Bernard church to protect them.</p>
<p>Juppe said the Council of State fully backed his view that the group of protesting immigrants lacked the right to stay in France under 1993 laws tightening conditions for residence.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be against the law to give blanket residence permits to this or that group. We are going to continue a review of individual situations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>However he added: &quot;It never crossed our mind to expel someone who is seriously ill, separate a mother from her children, break up a couple, or expel parents of children who were born in France or are French citizens.&quot;</p>
<p>In a possible face-saving way out of their impasse, Cisse, in an interview with Reuters, hinted that the 10 hunger strikers might end their fast should the government give them a written guarantee that they were entitled to residence permits because their refusal to eat had left them seriously ill.</p>
<p>Many of the protesters say they once had residence rights and were plunged into illegality by hardline 1993 laws pushed through by then-interior minister Charles Pasqua at a time of mounting anti-immigrant sentiment.</p>
<p>Lawyers say loopholes in the laws, which also tightened conditions for citizenship, have created a legal nightmare.</p>
<p>Juppe said the law would nonetheless be enforced.</p>
<p>But the far-right National Front party, which advocates sending home all immigrants, taunted Juppe for &quot;weakness&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Words yes, but where is the action?&quot; a Front statement said.</p>
<p>Signalling their determination to force the government into what would amount to a humiliating retreat, the protesters have called a new rally for next week after a march through Paris drew 5,000 demonstrators on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The hunger strikers have been drinking sweet tea and taking vitamin pills, but two are said to be in a serious condition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
