<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12489" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Two month Paris protest ends in just 90 minutes.</title>
<headline>Two month Paris protest ends in just 90 minutes.</headline>
<byline>Thierry Chiarello</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>After a tense standoff lasting almost two months, the final act of the immigrant hunger strike drama was played out in a little over 90 minutes in Paris on Friday .</p>
<p>Hundreds of police used batons and fists to break through a crowd and storm the Saint-Bernard church in the capital's multi-ethnic Goutte d'Or neighbourhood at 7.45 a.m. (0545 GMT).</p>
<p>By 9.20 (0720 GMT), the last of the 300 African would-be immigrants who had been occupying the church since June 28 had been led or dragged from the building and whisked away in ambulances and buses.</p>
<p>Ten Africans who were on the 50th day of a hunger strike were taken to two military hospitals while other protesters were driven to a Paris detention centre.</p>
<p>The protesting Africans, who had occupied the church in the hope of convincing the government that they should be granted residence papers, had been passing sleepless nights for a week in fear of a police raid.</p>
<p>It was last weekend that government officials let it be known in a series of interviews and speeches that they had expulsions, rather than residence papers, on their minds.</p>
<p>When it finally came, the police action was impressive.</p>
<p>A huge phalanx of officers wearing riot helmets, their batons drawn, stormed the church yard and physically pushed their way through hundreds of sympathisers who had surrounded the building in the hope of protecting the protesters.</p>
<p>They appeared to go out of their way to prod the crowd with their batons rather than crack heads.</p>
<p>But when they met resistance, blows were forthcoming. In many instances, officers used their hands and even their fists to get people out of their path.</p>
<p>After only a few minutes of hand-to-hand grappling with the throngs of supporters, they reached the church gate.</p>
<p>One policeman used a heavy axe to smash the chain holding a gate shut, and then the church's heavy wooden main gate was torn down in turn.</p>
<p>But the Africans, huddled inside the church, had stacked chairs and other furniture in front of the doors -- obstacles patiently removed one by one by the police.</p>
<p>Among the first to be led from the church through the howling crowd were French film beauty Emmanuelle Beart and political activist and cancer specialist Leon Schwartzenberg.</p>
<p>The two were among numerous personalities who had flocked to the church in recent days to show their support for the protesters.</p>
<p>Then came the hunger strikers, carried out on stretchers to waiting ambulances.</p>
<p>Later, the rest of the Africans were escorted out, some willingly, others resisting all the way.</p>
<p>&quot;They took me by the arms and dragged me into a bus. Then they brought out my daughter,&quot; said Madjiguene Cisse, who had acted as a spokeswoman for the Africans during the protest's final days.</p>
<p>&quot;There, we're leaving,&quot; she told Reuters by mobile phone as the buses began pulling away from the church.</p>
<p>Another spokesman for the protesters, Aboubakar Diop, was carried out of the church by plainclothes officers as if he were a sack of potatoes. He was handcuffed before being pushed into a police van and driven away.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
