<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12492" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: PRESS DIGEST - Norway - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Norway - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in Norwegian papers this morning:</p>
<p>AFTENPOSTEN</p>
<p>- Most voters want Prime Minister Gro Harlem Brundtland to remain in office and reject the idea of her designated successor Thorbjoern Jagland taking over in the near future, an opinion poll shows.</p>
<p>- Brundtland's ruling Labour Party is losing ground in a monthly opinion poll, but the opposition Centre Party and Conservatives are gaining support more than a year before the next general election.</p>
<p>- Family Minister Grete Berget has banned staff from speaking to journalists and says all questions from the press must be handled by her chief of information. Members of the opposition in parliament accuse Berget of limiting the public's right to obtain information.</p>
<p>DAGENS NAERINGSLIV</p>
<p>- Insurance company UNI Storebrand ASA, which reported stronger-than-expected first-half profits, plans to trim the cost ratio in non-life insurance to 20 percent from about 28 percent within three to four years.</p>
<p>- Forestry company Norske Skogindustrier ASA is growing nicely. It booked a first-half pre-tax profit of 1.04 billion crowns but the outlook for the rest of the year is not as bright because of changing market conditions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
