<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12509" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights of stories in the Danish press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>BERLINGSKE TIDENDE</p>
<p>--- Economy minister Marianne Jelved thinks current Danish local authority budgets are too complicated and that making the system simpler could help them hold expenditure targets.</p>
<p>--- Denmark's opposition Conservative Party's proposals for the 1997 state budget to be unveiled next week will comprise some 10 billion crowns in cuts, party leader Hans Engell says.</p>
<p>POLITIKEN</p>
<p>--- A Finnish building worker drowned on the site of the fixed road-rail, train-car link across the Sound between Danmark and Sweden, the first death since the project, due for completion by the turn of the century, got under way.</p>
<p>JYLLANDS-POSTEN</p>
<p>--- Danish shoe manufacturer Ecco plans to penetrate the sports shoes market by launching a new series of golf shoes in Scandinavia, Germany, Ireland, Portugal and Benelux and launching test sales in the U.S.A., Britain and Japan.</p>
<p>--- Aalborg's Karup Airport in western Denmark will be able to handle foreign flights in April 1997 after the building of a new air terminal at the military base-cum-civilian airstrip.</p>
<p>BORSEN</p>
<p>--- A new welfare reform proposal from the Danish Confederation of Industry promises jobs for 200,000 unemployed, tax reductions and better training by reducing minimum wages by 20 crowns to 55 crowns per hour and raising the early retirement age from 60 to 63 years of age.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
