<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12508" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: PRESS DIGEST - Portugal -- Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Portugal -- Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are leading domestic stories in Portuguese newspapers.</p>
<p>DIARIO ECONOMICO</p>
<p>- Banco Portugues de Investimento (BPI) will be the future owner of Banco de Fomento e Exterior (BFE).</p>
<p>- The distribution of income in Portugal became more unequal in the first four years of the 1990s, according to a study by the Bank of Portugal.</p>
<p>- BPI shares rose 5.2 percent to hit a high for 1996 of 2,115 escudos after Finance Minister Antonio Sousa Franco said BPI was the only approved candidate in the privatisation of BFE.</p>
<p>PUBLICO</p>
<p>- The opposition centre-right Social Democratic Party (PSD) in the northern district of Vila do Conde voted in favour of the opening of Siemens's semi-conductor factory in the area.</p>
<p>DIARIO DE NOTICIAS</p>
<p>- The president of Portuguese retailer Jeronimo Martins, Alexandre Soares dos Santos, told the paper that he was not interested in acquiring assets in retail chain Pao de Acucar. He denied that any talks were taking place between Jeronimo Martins and French company Auchan, which recently bought Pao de Acucar, with a view to Jeronimo Martins acquiring a stake in Pao de Acucar.</p>
<p>--Lisbon bureau 3511-3538254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
