<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12513" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Leading Italian Mafia boss cooperating with police.</title>
<headline>Leading Italian Mafia boss cooperating with police.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Giovanni Brusca, considered one of the Sicilian Mafia's most brutal bosses before his arrest three months ago, has begun collaborating with the law, Italian investigators said on Friday.</p>
<p>Giancarlo Caselli, chief prosecutor in the Mafia stronghold of Palermo, confirmed to state RAI radio that Brusca had asked to talk to magistrates and had been interrogated.</p>
<p>&quot;We will see what the evaluation will be, positive, negative or neutral,&quot; he said, adding that it was premature to say whether Brusca's evidence was genuine.</p>
<p>Lawyer Luigi Li Gotti, whose clients include other well-known Mafia turncoats or &quot;pentiti&quot; such as Tommaso Buscetta, said he was now representing Brusca, who had already provided hundreds of pages of evidence.</p>
<p>&quot;He began to collaborate last July, signing the first reports with his declarations on the 26th of that month,&quot; the lawyer said, adding that Brusca had been questioned by magistrates in Sicily and the Tuscan city of Florence.</p>
<p>Italian television reports said Brusca had named the bosses behind Mafia killings and implicated politicians.</p>
<p>Brusca, publicly branded &quot;The Beast&quot; by another turncoat who accused him of strangling his 12-year-old son and disposing of the body in a vat of acid, has been charged with several high-profile crimes in Sicily and mainland Italy.</p>
<p>Investigators say it was Brusca who pushed the button detonating a bomb under anti-Mafia magistrate Giovanni Falcone's motorcade on a motorway near Palermo in 1992. Falcone, his wife and three bodyguards died in the explosion.</p>
<p>He is also accused of involvement in planning 1993 Mafia bombings against cultural monuments in Rome, Florence and Milan, one of which damaged the Uffizi art gallery in Florence.</p>
<p>Caselli said the news of Brusca's collaboration had slipped out unintentionally and investigators would have liked to continue working in secret for longer.</p>
<p>Italian newspapers, referring to fears of a deliberate Mafia plot to mislead judges with fake turncoats, said investigators were wary of being fed disinformation.</p>
<p>&quot;Brusca's revelations -- which could also link the Mafia and politics -- could throw light on an overwhelming list of crimes,&quot; the daily Corriere della Sera reported.</p>
<p>Rumours that a top Mafioso had become a &quot;pentito&quot; had been circulating for some time as police made a series of high-profile arrests in Sicily.</p>
<p>&quot;He is the first and so far the only top leader of Cosa Nostra to have decided to collaborate,&quot; Li Gotti said.</p>
<p>Pino Arlacchi, a leftist senator and an expert on the Mafia, told the Corriere della Sera that Brusca's decision marked the end for the Corleonesi clan and could lead to &quot;boss of bosses&quot; Salvatore Riina deciding to give evidence as well.</p>
<p>&quot;He is almost 70 years old, still rich and powerful but without any prospects. Or, at least, with only one prospect -- that of spending the rest of his years in a cell,&quot; Arlacchi said of Riina, who is already serving several life sentences.</p>
<p>But Arlacchi also urged caution.</p>
<p>&quot;The Mafia is not yet beaten. For the moment, only the Corleonesi who have dominated Cosa Nostra for the past 20 years have been beaten,&quot; he said, warning that the Mafia was already reorganising on a local level.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
