<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12516" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: PRESS DIGEST - Italy - Friday August 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Italy - Friday August 23.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the top headlines in leading Italian newspapers.</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP POLITICAL STORIES</p>
<p>*Giovanni Brusca, former mafia boss arrested in May, starts revealing to magistrates details of his long criminal career. Among other things, he is accused of being the man who pressed the remote control to detonate the bomb which killed anti-mafia judge Giovanni Falcone. (all)</p>
<p>*Minister for Public Works and former anti-graft magistrate Antonio Di Pietro, who was quoted as saying he wanted to lead a new centrist movement, is now seen by many as a potential challenge to the Prodi government. Green party spokesman Carlo Ripa di Meana says: &quot;We could vote against the government over Di Pietro&quot; (Corriere della Sera). Centre-right opposition Freedom Alliance is said to welcome &quot;leader&quot; Di Pietro (Repubblica).</p>
<p>*Secessionist Northern League party leader Umberto Bossi says Di Pietro wants to reconstruct the old Christian Democrat party along with Foreign Affairs Minister Lamberto Dini and former speaker of parliament and League member Irene Pivetti (all).</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>*Fiat chairman Cesare Romiti says &quot;We need measures to revive consumer expenditure. This government deserves praise for the quality of its members, but now we are waiting for the facts.&quot; (Corriere, Stampa)</p>
<p>*After 10 sample cities' CPI, the inflation rate for the month of August is now seen around 3.4 pct year-on-year. (Sole 24 Ore).</p>
<p>* Enel chairman Chicco Testa says the state electricity group should be privatised &quot;soon but sensibly&quot;. (Sole 24 Ore)</p>
<p>*Romiti says Fiat is not interested in taking a stake in state telecoms holding Stet once it has been privatised. (Corriere, Sole)</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +39266129450</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
