<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12525" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Finland - August 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Finland - August 23.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the leading stories in Finnish papers this morning.</p>
<p>HELSINGIN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Markka fell clearly on Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen's comments about a decision on linking the markka to ERM.</p>
<p>- Forestry group Enso and environmental organisations in dispute over cutting in old Carelian forests.</p>
<p>- Drugs criminals are in many ways better off than other convicts, survey shows. Many had a job and an apartment before they were jailed. @</p>
<p>- Finland would support a pact to ban infantry mines, Ministry of Foreign Affairs said.</p>
<p>- UN Human Rights observer in Bosnia Elisabeth Rehn said she will not run in European Parliament Elections, despite reconsidering earlier, and support of Swedish People's Party.</p>
<p>- Interest on student loans clearly lower than a year ago -- banks expect demand to rise this autumn.</p>
<p>- Helsinki health official warns against blue-green algae, increasing due to heat, on some beaches.</p>
<p>- Finns' self-esteem has improved despite split values and high unemployment, a study shows. @</p>
<p>- Many primary schools surrender to heat and let students go swimming during the late hours of school -- this is the hottest August since 1939.</p>
<p>- Headlice found in almost 150 school students in Western Finland.</p>
<p>KAUPPALEHTI</p>
<p>- Many sawmills have within a short period fallen into financial difficulty. Strong markka and high raw wood prices hit profitability, chief Ilkka Poyhonen from Finnish Forest Industry Federation says. @</p>
<p>- Age discrimination when applying for a job in Finland less common than was thought, survey shows.</p>
<p>DEMARI</p>
<p>- Finn Tommi Makinen favourite in the World Cup Jyvaskyla 1,000 Lakes Rally, to start today.</p>
<p>TURUN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Major cities decide to ban roller bladers from buses.</p>
<p>- Weak catch of crayfish in past few weeks -- disease suspected. @</p>
<p>AAMULEHTI</p>
<p>- Swedish Crown Princess Victoria to practice official ceremonies in her first official visit, to Finland, next week.</p>
<p>-- Paivi Mattila, Helsinki Newsroom +358 - 0 - 680 50 292</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
