<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12527" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Friday morning's Austrian newspapers.</p>
<p>DIE PRESSE</p>
<p>- Defence Minister Werner Fasslabend is launching a new pro-NATO initiative and planning to open an office for strategic studies. The office is to be led by a Freedom Party politician.</p>
<p>- The Austrian National Bank followed the Bundesbank's lead and cut the repo rate to 3.0 percent, effective September 2, establishing parity with Germany again.</p>
<p>- A telecom consortium composed of regional electricity companies, Verbund and the national railways OeBB is looking for an international operator. Global One and Unisource are under consideration.</p>
<p>DER STANDARD</p>
<p>- Media giant Mediaprint may face payments of millions of schillings after the high court ruled its newspaper street sellers were not self-employed but company employees. The company now has to pay past and future employment tax and social insurance for the street sellers.</p>
<p>- The state is looking into possible links between Austrian companies and a Libyan poison gas plant.</p>
<p>- Energieversorgung Niederoesterreich (EVN) and Hungary's MOL said they were building a joint venture power plant in Hungary.</p>
<p>- Austria's electronics industry is feeling the pinch due to competition from eastern Europe.</p>
<p>KURIER</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Viktor Klima said the budget would hold for 1996, with a deficit of about 89 billion schillings. Whether the budget for 1997 can hold depends on the economic cycle, he said.</p>
<p>- OMV said it wanted to play an active role  in the upcoming privatisation of regional electricity companies. Company head Richard Schenz said OMV was interested in a stake in the Upper Austrian OKA and Energieholding Steiermark.</p>
<p>- Austria's textile industry is worried it may lose state contracts. Some 1,000 jobs are at risk.</p>
<p>SALZBURGER NACHRICHTEN</p>
<p>- Chancellor Franz Vranitzky will travel to Israel and meet with Prime Minister Benyamin Netanyahu on September 1. He is also due to meet Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat in Gaza.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
