<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12522" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: PRESS DIGEST - France - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - France - Aug 23.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are leading stories in this morning's Paris newspapers.</p>
<p>LES ECHOS</p>
<p>-- German and French central banks cut interest rates.</p>
<p>-- Finance minister Jean Arthuis cuts 1997 GDP growth forecast to between 2.25 and 2.5 percent from 2.5 to 2.8 percent.</p>
<p>-- Promodes about to offload ailing German subsidiary Promohypermarkt to Spar AG or to Metro, Rowe and Lidl consortium.</p>
<p>-- French state-TV chairman Xavier Gouyou Beauchamps asks government to tack an extra 350 million francs onto his 1997 budget.</p>
<p>LA TRIBUNE DESFOSSES</p>
<p>-- Interest rates ease in a bid to boost the economy.</p>
<p>-- Thursday's 0.2 percent intervention rate cut is not enough to stimulate French growth but any bigger cut would have been counterproductive.</p>
<p>-- President Jacques Chirac and Prime minister Alain Juppe to discuss tax cuts for middle-income households this weekend.</p>
<p>L'AGEFI</p>
<p>-- Treasury appoints CCF to bring SNCF railways accounting principles into line with EU laws and directives.</p>
<p>	 LE FIGARO</p>
<p>-- The independent FO union head Marc Blondel says Communist-led CGT union may join September 21 nationwide demonstration.</p>
<p>LE FIGARO-ECONOMIE</p>
<p>-- Arthuis says all wage-earners will pay less income tax next year.</p>
<p>-- Total first half sales up 20 percent.</p>
<p>LIBERATION (Economic section)</p>
<p>-- George Soros predicts popular uprising in France in an article in Foreign Affairs magazine.</p>
<p>THE INTERNATIONAL HERALD TRIBUNE</p>
<p>-- Bold Bundesbank interest rate reduction prompts four EU central banks to quickly follow suit.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5381</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
