<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12532" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: PRESS DIGEST - Netherlands - August 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Netherlands - August 23.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main stories in Dutch newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>HET FINANCIEELE DAGBLAD</p>
<p>- Cabinet agrees 1997 budget, sets aside 3.25 billion guilders for employer tax relief and maintaining purchasing power.(p1)</p>
<p>- Dutch central bank DNB cuts special advances rate to all-time low of 2.5 percent from 2.7 percent, tracking big German rate cut. (p1)</p>
<p>- Trading group Internatio-Mueller books 12 percent higher H1 net of 45 million guilders, despite pressure resulting from newly-imposed ceiling on medicine prices. (p1)</p>
<p>- Bank and insurance group ING books 27.9 pct higher first half net at 151 billion guilders. (p1)</p>
<p>- Insurer Aegon raises forecast after first half net rises 15.7 pct to 711.1 million guilders. (p1)</p>
<p>- Food producer Nutricia exceeds analysts' forecasts with 51 pct profit growth to 107 million guilders in first half. (p3)</p>
<p>- Car industry supplier Polynorm expects profit recovery after net falls 43 pct in first half. (p3)</p>
<p>- Textile group Blydenstein-Willink posts first-half loss of 1.9 million guilders, as results pressured by restructuring. (p5) DE VOLKSKRANT</p>
<p>- Long-term jobless numbers fall for first time since 1992. (p1)</p>
<p>- ING puts other banks on the spot by preparing its cashomats for two rival electronic payments cards. (p1)</p>
<p>- Andy McDonald, founder of record label Go! Discs, leaves Polygram after row. (p2)</p>
<p>- Growth of temporary employment slows in Q2 according to Central Bureau of Statistics. (p3) DE TELEGRAAF</p>
<p>- Far-reaching measures to make car use more expensive circulate at ministry of transport and public works. (p1)</p>
<p>- Technical wholesaler Econosto books first half net of 5.9 million guilders, compared with 3.9 million guilders in year earlier half. (p25)</p>
<p>- ABN Amro bank to restructure its computer systems and information management unit. (p27) TROUW</p>
<p>- Broadcaster Tros leaves newspaper publisher De Telegraaf after 30 years for publisher Audax. (p7)</p>
<p>- Foundation of housing market is sound according to Rabobank economists. (p7) ALGEMEEN DAGBLAD</p>
<p>- Jeans maker G-star threatens fashion chain P&amp;C with lawsuit over copying their jeans. (p11)</p>
<p>- Unions furious about new unexpected restructuring at harbour group HES unit EBS. (p13)</p>
<p>--Amsterdam newsdesk +31-20-504-5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
