<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12535" id="root" date="1996-08-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREENLAND: FEATURE - Greenland emerges from a winter of the soul.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Greenland emerges from a winter of the soul.</headline>
<byline>Steve Weizman</byline>
<dateline>KANGERLUSSUAQ, Greenland 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The first sight of the ice cap that covers most of this vast Arctic island takes the breath away. It is nature in the raw, powerful and brooding.</p>
<p>Like a huge bulldozer it has pushed ancient mountains before it, piling rock into a heap at its edge, here just a few minutes helicopter flight from Greenland's international airport, 60 km (40 miles) above the Arctic Circle at Kangerlussuaq.</p>
<p>In the crystal-clear air, the icy desert seems to go on for ever. No people live here and no roads cross the white wastes.</p>
<p>To begin to understand Greenland it is neccessary to see and contemplate this wilderness, for it covers 80 percent of the country, divides communities and makes any project a complex and friendishly expensive undertaking.</p>
<p>Covering 2.1 million square km (810,900 square miles) Greenland is the world's largest island, but in many ways it is more like an archipelago, with pockets of population ranging from communities of less than 100, up to 13,000 in the capital, Nuuk, strung around the edge of the ice.</p>
<p>For much of the year the only link between them is by Greenland Air's heavily-subsidised plane or helicopter. There are no roads between towns and for much of the year, over much of the country, ships are icebound.</p>
<p>It is a harsh and unforgiving place in which to carve out an existence, one in which winter temperatures average -20C (-4 Fahrenheit) and -70C (-94 Fahrenheit) has been recorded in the far north.</p>
<p>The inuit (eskimo) people who make up most of Greenland's 55,000 inhabitants have had to struggle not only with the elements, but with the impact of modern society brought to them from Denmark, to which they belong, although geographically part of nearby North America.</p>
<p>&quot;It was not until the sixties that we experienced many of this century's developments which other nations had long taken for granted. Consumer goods, power tools, modern hunting weapons, navigational technology, communications,&quot; Lars Emil Johansen, Prime Minister of Greenland's home rule governement told journalists visiting Nuuk.</p>
<p>Such sudden development, and the introduction of television, heightened the aspirations of many people -- and their frustrations when they found that those aspirations could not be realised as easily as TV commercials promised.</p>
<p>&quot;Our people entered a dark time when they became confused about their identity and lost self-esteem,&quot; academic and former Johansen aide Noka Moeller told Reuters, sitting at a waterfront cafe in Nuuk, while hump-backed whales spouted nearby.</p>
<p>That dark time saw rocketing alcoholism, suicide and assault as a race of hunters and fishermen, many deprived of their livelihood by foreign environmental campaigns and shrinking fish stocks, struggled to come to terms with themselves.</p>
<p>But since Greenland achieved home rule under the Danish crown in 1979, its indigenous people -- some 10 percent of the population is Danish -- have found a new will and fresh dignity, Moeller and his country's leaders say.</p>
<p>&quot;There has definitely been a change. Social problems are easing, although they are still serious, and there is a new sense of purpose,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Suicide -- committed by almost three times as many men as women -- is decreasing, although at 11 percent of all deaths it is still worrying.</p>
<p>The chronic alcohol abuse for which Greenlanders have become stigmatised in Denmark is falling, with 23 percent of the population describing themselves as total abstainers.</p>
<p>Greenland now trains its own administrators, social workers and journalists and of the many youngsters sent to Denmark for higher eduction, most return home afterward.</p>
<p>The educated young are confident of their ability to shape their country's destiny and there is exasperation with Danish authorities, seen by many as patronising, if well-meaning.</p>
<p>The movement for full independence has no real political weight but many people would like to take more control than they have now, with defence, foreign affairs and some trade issues still decided in Copenhagen.</p>
<p>&quot;Our position is not anti-Danish but pro-Greenlandic. In general our relations are good, although we have tough talks on defence and foreign affairs,&quot; Johansen said.</p>
<p>&quot;Ultimately we need a change in the constitution, but its too early to discuss that now.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREENL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANGERLUSSUAQ, Greenland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREENLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
