<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2291" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hog prices tumble as supplies increase, cocoa gains.</title>
<headline>Hog prices tumble as supplies increase, cocoa gains.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hog prices fell Tuesday after government slaughter figures showed supplies were increasing, while cocoa futures rose on anticipation of smaller crops overseas.</p>
<p>Forecasts for shrinking deliverable supplies pulled coffee prices up. Crude oil fell after rising on Monday. Gold edged higher. The Commodity Research Bureau's index of 17 futures contracts closed down 1.32 at 250.65 points.</p>
<p>At the Chicago Mercantile Exchange, August hog and pork belly futures finished down their respective daily limits on pressure from increased hog slaughter and weakness in the cash market.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that we are seeing a few more hogs show up has people worried about the supply side but more important than this it gives the packers a little more freedom to improve their margins,&quot; said Doug Harper, Brock Associates Inc. senior livestock analyst.</p>
<p>High hog prices have pinched profits at meat-packing companies and now that hog supplies are increasing these companies will likely be quick to lower bids.</p>
<p>The Agriculture Department reported Tuesday's slaughter at 348,000 head vs. 343,000 a week ago. Also, on a weekly basis, slaughter is nearing last year's higher levels.</p>
<p>The CME August hog contract closed down the 1.50-cent-per-pound daily limit at 60.025 cents per pound.</p>
<p>Pork bellies also closed sharply lower because more hogs translates to more pork and lower pork prices. CME August pork bellies closed down the 2-cent limit at 91.375 cents per pound.</p>
<p>Cocoa futures at New York's Coffee, Sugar and Cocoa Exchange ended sharply higher on speculative buying, but the market has been buoyed by news of smaller overseas crops.</p>
<p>One analyst said until updated Ivory Coast crop estimates emerged near the end of August, the December contract was likely to range between $1,400 and $1,500.</p>
<p>December cocoa settled up $21 to $1,430 per metric ton.</p>
<p>&quot;The smaller Ivorian crop is well anticipated,&quot; the analyst said. &quot;There are other countries having problems, such as ... Ghana.&quot;</p>
<p>Preliminary forecasts, which pegged the 1996/97 Ivory Coast crop around 800,000 to 900,000 metric tons, have been largely factored into the market, he said, and barring sharp revisions, news from other cocoa producing countries could become the focus.</p>
<p>Coffee prices ended higher after a burst of late-session chart-based buying.</p>
<p>December coffee settled at 115.05 cents per pound Tuesday, up 1.75 on the day and just above the widely-watched 115 cents mark. Traders said the break through that resistance level could inspire some additional chart-driven buying Wednesday.</p>
<p>On the New York Mercantile Exchange, crude oil and refined products futures closed lower on profit-taking.</p>
<p>September unleaded gasoline closed down 1.26 cents a gallon to 64.01 cents, and September heating fell 0.91 cent a gallon to 61.67 cents.</p>
<p>September crude oil fell 40 cents to $22.86 a barrel.</p>
<p>September gold added 50 cents to close at $388.60 an ounce at New York's Commodity Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
