<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2310" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Japanese prime minister arrives in Mexico.</title>
<headline>Japanese prime minister arrives in Mexico.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto arrived in Mexico on Tuesday on the first leg of a five-nation, 10-day tour of Latin America.</p>
<p>Although Hashimoto made no comments to reporters upon his arrival at the Mexico City airport just before 11:30 a.m. EDT (1530 GMT), he was expected to announce credits to Mexico worth $940 million during his three-day trip, Mexican officials said.</p>
<p>Deputy Foreign Minister Juan Rebolledo Gout said on Monday that the credits -- aimed at ecological projects, small- and medium-sized firms and Mexican exporters -- would be signed by Mexican and Japanese officials on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The support comes as Hashimoto seeks to open a new trade front for Japanese industry in Latin America. Tokyo has already pumped nearly $60 billion in direct investment into the region over the past 14 years and its economic aid doubled between 1990 and 1995 to $1.14 billion.</p>
<p>Hashimoto will hold talks with President Ernesto Zedillo on Wednesday and will meet members of the Japanese-Mexican community during his stay.</p>
<p>Mexico was the first stop on a trip that will also take him to Chile, Brazil, Peru and Costa Rica.</p>
<p>A potential cloud over his trip was lifted on Monday when kidnappers released a top Japanese electronics executive in the Mexican-U.S. border city of Tijuana after a $2 million ransom was paid.</p>
<p>After nine days in captivity, Mamoru Konno, president of a U.S. subsidiary of Japan's Sanyo Electric Co was found in the basement of an unoccupied building after a Mexican police official contacted kidnappers with the money.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
