<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2313" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German unions split on tactics in retail pay talks.</title>
<headline>German unions split on tactics in retail pay talks.</headline>
<byline>Catherine O'Mahony</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The two main unions representing German retail workers split apart on Tuesday. The HBV union pulled out of talks in a four-month old pay dispute while the DAG opted to continue negotiations.</p>
<p>The unions have been jointly negotiating a wage and work hours deal for the 450,000 retail workers in the state of North Rhine-Westphalia, one of several regional deals being hammered out in advance of November's liberalisation of shop hours.</p>
<p>However the service sector union HBV pulled out of the talks on Tuesday after employers refused to accept its unexpected demand for extra compensation for night work.</p>
<p>Until now, unions have pressed for broad adoption of a deal struck in Rhineland-Palatinate which called for workers to get a 1.85 percent wage rise plus 20 percent extra time in lieu per hour worked after 6:30 p.m. weekdays and 2:00 p.m. Saturdays.</p>
<p>The white collar DAG, which immediately distanced itself from the HBV's demands, said it was confident it could reach an agreement with shopowners on the Rhineland-Palatinate model and would continue talks.</p>
<p>Early Tuesday evening, employers and unions said the talks were progressing well.</p>
<p>The HBV, however, is insisting that shopowners pay all workers a 55 percent bonus time in lieu for time worked between 7:30 and 8:00 p.m. The retail industry currently pays such bonuses only to truck drivers and store-room workers.</p>
<p>HBV negotiator Gerhard Keuchel said his union would try over the coming days to find fresh ground for new talks, but said the 55 percent bonus was essential.</p>
<p>Meanwhile the HDE retail industry association pleaded for a swift end to the deadlock on the talks, which has caused four months of sporadic strike action affecting shops and wholesalers throughout Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;This cannot drag on until the start of November,&quot; HDE wages expert Guenther Wassmann told German radio.</p>
<p>So far, employers, hit by weak consumer spending, have baulked at accepting the Rhineland-Palatinate deal and took particular issue with the 20 percent allowance demand.</p>
<p>However in Bavaria, DAG officials said they were confident of a positive outcome from the tenth round of their wage negotiations, which begins on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The DAG suspended token strikes ahead of the talks and said it planned to suggest a compromise on the controversial 20 percent allowance.</p>
<p>However it warned that the token strikes would resume if employers declined the offer.</p>
<p>In Berlin, wage talks resumed on Tuesday morning for the region's 87,500 retail workers. Union representatives said they planned to seek an overall pay rise of five percent, to be applicable in east German states as well, in addition to the shop hours deal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
