<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2319" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Rangebound German shares end mixed, utilities up.</title>
<headline>Rangebound German shares end mixed, utilities up.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares were rangebound in bourse trade on Tuesday, with the highlight of the day a shifting of interest from the chemical sector into utility stocks.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX ended the day down 2.50 points at 2,560.26 points after sticking in a seven-point range. The IBIS-DAX, tracking electronic trading during the day, closed slightly better at 2,562.12 points.</p>
<p>The big three chemical groups took the biggest battering, while utility shares benefited from interest partly generated by Viag AG's forthcoming six month earnings report. After the close of the electronic bourse trading Viag reported operating profit up 10 percent during the first half of this year.</p>
<p>The broader market was lacklustre, dealers said, and shrugged off a Bundesbank report showing slower July M3 growth, which is viewed as boosting the case for the central bank to cut the securities repurchase rate, or repo, on Thursday.</p>
<p>Chemicals were sold to make way for utilities. In IBIS trading Hoechst lost 31 pfennigs to 50.80 marks, Bayer declined by 5 pfennigs to 52.35 marks while utility Viag rose 6.75 to 569.75.</p>
<p>Utilities have been underperforming during the last two months, but are bottoming out now, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The upswing in utilities stocks is an answer to the recent weakness of those shares&quot;, one dealer said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the moderate M3 growth was in line with expectations and thus failed to generate momentum for the stock market.</p>
<p>However the market will continue to look for guidance on the interest rate front ahead of the Bundesbank meeting Thursday, dealers said.</p>
<p>The result of the FOMC meeting in the U.S. due early in the European evening was expected to provide further clues.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
