<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2322" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Silver hits two-month peak, gold edges higher.</title>
<headline>Silver hits two-month peak, gold edges higher.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Silver prices were at their highest levels since mid-June on Tuesday after speculative buying sent the New York market surging overnight, dealers said.</p>
<p>Gold followed only reluctantly, but market analysts said it could eventually make a go of breaking through its recent price ceiling at just under $390 an ounce.</p>
<p>Silver closed at $5.23 an ounce, up eleven cents from Monday's London close. It fixed at just over $5.20 an ounce, the highest fixing since June 19.</p>
<p>Silver eased a bit as dealers took their profits in early European business after reaching a peak of $5.26 overnight.</p>
<p>But several dealers said they saw it venturing higher later this week. &quot;It's a purely technical move, but I can see it going for $5.30 this week,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Technical analysts or chartists who follow detailed charts of past prices said that the rally needed to clear the $5.25 resistance level before pushing higher.</p>
<p>Silver have been trending lower since peaking at a fix of around $5.83 in early February.</p>
<p>&quot;Silver is not out of the woods yet,&quot; said analyst Cliff Green of Trend Analysis. &quot;But getting up past that $5.15-45.16 area is a positive step.&quot;</p>
<p>In contrast, bullion closed just $0.90 higher at $387.55 an ounce, virtually ignoring silver's newfound strength.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold has had a bit of a dismal performance. The move seems to be just in silver,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>But some chartists said gold has scope to move higher.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously much depends on gold's ability to clear the critical resistance immediately below $390,&quot; said analyst Elli Gifford of Investment Research of Cambridge.</p>
<p>&quot;But silver's recovery following what is looking to be a false breakdown earlier below $5.00 adds to the evidence this may occur,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Some analysts said gold was being cautious while waiting for the outcome of the U.S. Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting in New York in case of surprises on interest rates.</p>
<p>Another dampener was a slump in the South African rand, which was seen encouraging selling by South African producers.</p>
<p>Palladium closed at $125.60, up $0.95 and off recent 2-1/2 year lows, while platinum ended $1.40 higher at $399.80.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
