<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2324" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British money growth slows, back in monitoring range.</title>
<headline>British money growth slows, back in monitoring range.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Growth in Britain's M4 money supply slowed to 8.8 percent in the first half of the year, the Bank of England said Tuesday, while lending by banks and building societies continued to increase.</p>
<p>The slowdown in money supply growth from annual rates of 10 percent in May and June brought the figure back within the government's monitoring range of 3 percent to 9 percent for the first time since November.</p>
<p>Some economists said it could suggest a softening in future inflationary pressures.</p>
<p>However, the British Bankers' Association said a strong 539 million pound ($833 million) increase in consumer credit in July could point to a strengthening of consumer spending.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength of consumer credit and housing market activity within the lending figures will be seized upon by the Bank of England as a potential threat to the inflation target,&quot; said Andrew Cates, an economist at UBS.</p>
<p>Seasonally adjusted M4 -- a broad measure of money supply which comprises cash in circulation, personal and commercial bank deposits and certificates of deposit -- grew 0.4 percent in July from June, down from 0.7 percent in June.</p>
<p>Strong money supply growth is often seen as a pointer to future inflation and central bank Governor Eddie George has warned that interest rates might have to rise if it continued unchecked.</p>
<p>However, its reliability has been thrown into question this year because of special distorting factors, such as a rash of corporate mergers and acquisitions.</p>
<p>The slowdown will, therefore, offer little new ammunition to Chancellor of the Exchequer (Finance Minister) Kenneth Clarke if he wants to cut interest rates this fall.</p>
<p>Clarke has cut rates four times since last December to their current 5.75 percent level, overruling the Bank of England on the last occasion in June.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
