<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2327" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Thistle Hotels almost doubles profits.</title>
<headline>Thistle Hotels almost doubles profits.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thistle Hotels, Britain's second biggest hotel chain, said Tuesday its pre-tax profits almost doubled in the first half of the year.</p>
<p>The company, which plans an initial public offering of stock in September, said its net income, excluding exceptional items, expanded to 24.1 million pounds ($37.2 million).</p>
<p>However, profits were hit by a one-time charge of 87.8 million pounds ($135.5 million) to partly account for a 10 percent cut in the valuation of its hotel portfolio to 1.7 billion pounds ($2.6 billion).</p>
<p>Thistle owns some 100 hotels, including such luxury names as London's Grosvenor and Royal Horseguards hotels.</p>
<p>Market watchers say its initial public offering could value the group at between one billion and 1.5 billion pounds ($1.5 billion and $2.3 billion).</p>
<p>Thistle plans to raise 250 million pounds ($386 million) in cash through the offer. About 100 million to 150 million pounds ($155 to $232 million) would be used to reduce debt, with the remaining being invested in expanding room capacity, Chief Executive Robert Peel said.</p>
<p>&quot;We would focus the money on London -- the region where we get the best returns,&quot; he said in an interview.</p>
<p>Thistle said a price range would be announced at the time of the stock offering, which has no fixed date so far.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
