<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2328" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Fresh talks on German retail pay dispute falter.</title>
<headline>Fresh talks on German retail pay dispute falter.</headline>
<byline>Catherine O'Mahony</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Talks between German retail workers' unions and shopowners aimed at resolving a four-month old pay dispute hit a further stumbling block on Tuesday, despite union optimism that a settlement could be reached.</p>
<p>Ulrich Walter, chief negotiator for shopowners in North Rhine-Westphalia, said an unexpected union demand for night-time bonuses for the region's 450,000 retail workers had made agreement impossible in Tuesday's talks.</p>
<p>Unions and employers in several federal states are resuming talks this week to agree a wage and work hours deal to cope with the liberalisation of German shopping hours in November.</p>
<p>Until now, unions have pressed for broad adoption of a deal struck in Rhineland-Palatinate which called for workers to get a 1.85 percent wage rise plus 20 percent extra time in lieu per hour worked after 6:30 p.m. weekdays and 2:00 p.m. Saturdays.</p>
<p>However the HBV services union on Tuesday called for a 55 percent bonus time in lieu for shifts between 7:30 and 8:00 p.m. The retail industry currently pays such bonuses only to truck drivers and store-room workers.</p>
<p>The white-collar DAG union distanced itself from the demand.</p>
<p>Earlier HBV's chief negotiator for North Rhine-Westphalia, Gerhard Keuchel, said there were &quot;strong chances&quot; for agreement during Tuesday's talks, which took place in the town of Marl.</p>
<p>The HDE retail industry association also pleaded for a swift end to the deadlock on the talks, which has caused four months of sporadic strike action affecting shops and wholesalers throughout Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;This cannot drag on until the start of November,&quot; HDE wages expert Guenther Wassmann told German radio.</p>
<p>So far, employers, hit by weak consumer spending, have baulked at accepting the Rhineland-Palatinate deal and took particular issue with the 20 percent allowance demand.</p>
<p>However in Bavaria, DAG officials said they were confident of a positive outcome from the tenth round of their wage negotiations, which begins on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The DAG suspended warning strikes ahead of the talks and said it planned to suggest a compromise on the controversial 20 percent allowance.</p>
<p>However it warned that strikes would resume indefinitiely if employers declined the offer.</p>
<p>In Berlin, wage talks resumed on Tuesday morning for the region's 87,500 retail workers. Union representatives said they planned to seek an overall pay rise of five percent, to be applicable in east German states as well, in addition to the shop hours deal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
