<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2334" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed seen holding U.S. interest rates steady.</title>
<headline>Fed seen holding U.S. interest rates steady.</headline>
<byline>Caren Bohan</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Federal Reserve met on Tuesday to discuss the future course of interest rates and was widely expected to keep rates steady amid mixed signals on the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;The speeches made by various Fed governors and by bank presidents recently are not pointing toward tightening,&quot; said Preston Martin, chairman of HomeVest Financial Services Inc. in San Francisco.</p>
<p>&quot;I would think the odds are very heavily weighted toward the prospect that there will be no change at the next policy-making meeting,&quot; said Martin, a former Fed vice chairman.</p>
<p>The central bank's policy-making Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) started meeting at 9 a.m. EDT (1300 GMT). If past practice is followed, any decision should be announced around 2:15 p.m. EDT (1815 GMT).</p>
<p>Martin's forecast was shared unanimously by the 30 economists polled last week by Reuters, although some of those experts did not rule out a rate rise later this year.</p>
<p>Financial markets marked time Tuesday morning as they awaited the outcome of the central bank meeting, with bond and stock prices little changed.</p>
<p>The Fed meeting takes place at a time when questions abound about whether the economy is beginning to cool off after growing at a fast clip in the second quarter.</p>
<p>Until just a few weeks ago, many economists believed the economy was growing quickly enough to require an interest-rate rise by the Fed to slow it down and prevent inflation. However, a series of recent reports containing early signs of a slowdown changed those views.</p>
<p>The latest came on Tuesday, with news that the U.S. trade deficit fell by more than 20 percent in June as imports plunged. Analysts said the steep drop in imports pointed to slackening domestic demand and a slowing U.S. economy.</p>
<p>&quot;We had data very recently showing the housing market is starting to fade and the inflation reports were good,&quot; said Joel Prakken, chairman at the St. Louis forecasting firm Macroeconomic Advisors LLC.</p>
<p>&quot;All of that suggests we are seeing a slowdown from the second quarter and that the Fed does not need to move,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Some experts, however, said the economic signs were inconclusive and did not rule out a rate rise later this year.</p>
<p>Any rate increase would represent a reversal in the Fed's monetary policy. The previous rate change was in January, the last of a series of credit easings undertaken when the economy appeared soft. The economy has rebounded strongly since then.</p>
<p>The federal funds rate, which commercial banks charge each other for overnight cash, is now at 5.25 percent. The funds rate is controlled by the Fed and acts as a benchmark for other short-term interest rates.</p>
<p>The discount rate, which the Fed charges member banks for loans, stands at 5 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
