<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2355" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Silver fixes at two-month high, but gold lags.</title>
<headline>Silver fixes at two-month high, but gold lags.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Silver fixed at its highest level since June 19, 1996 on Tuesday morning following buying by speculators late on Monday in New York.</p>
<p>Silver fixed at $5.2025 an ounce, up 12 cents from Monday's fix and eight cents above Monday's London close.</p>
<p>It had eased a bit as dealers took their profits in early European business after reaching a peak of $5.26 overnight.</p>
<p>But several dealers said they saw it venturing higher later this week. &quot;There has seen some good hedge-fund buying of silver call options, and also the underlying (silver metal) recently,&quot; a dealer said. Silver closed in London at $5.23, up 12 cents.</p>
<p>Options are popular with market speculators as they offer a cheap way into betting on price movements.</p>
<p>An option gives its owner the right but not the obligation to buy or sell a commodity at a set price at some specified future date.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a purely technical move, but I can see it going for $5.30 this week,&quot; the dealer added.</p>
<p>Gold's reaction was half-hearted. The yellow metal closed just 90 cents firmer at $387.55.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold has had a bit of a dismal performance. The move seems to be just in silver,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The grains markets which headlined the commodities' markets on Monday turned lower on forecasts of more favourable growing wheather in the North American wheat regions.</p>
<p>&quot;The chances of frost were taken out of the forecasts for Canada,&quot; a Chicago-based trader said.</p>
<p>On the Chicago Board of Trade futures markets at 0945 CDT, wheat for September delivery was down 2-1/2 cents at $4.57.</p>
<p>September corn was down 1-1/2 cents at $3.62-1/2 and August soybeans were down 1-3/4 cents at $8.13.</p>
<p>Industrial metals were quiet with copper prices coming back $11.00 on the London Metal Exchange from $1,942 at Monday's close after stocks in the exchange's warehouses recorded a rise of 5,000 tonnes to 266,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market's stock overhang had reduced the anxiety earlier in the year of finding metal to deliver to customers. Aluminium was only $1.00 lower at $1,489.</p>
<p>White sugar futures put in a fairly robust performance, though the lack of strong fundamental news capped the market below key resistance near the $355.50 area, traders said.</p>
<p>December cocoa futures raced to a six week high, then eased below 1,040 stg in modest activity. By mid afternoon the December contract was up 12 stg at 1,037 stg.</p>
<p>The coffee price reaction modestly to a drop of 6,259 60-kg bags in the U.S. certified coffee stockpile to 34,516 bags.</p>
<p>The November contract was up only $3 at $1,660 as the fall was within forecasters' expectations.</p>
<p>Some key commodity prices at 1600 GMT</p>
<p>					     Tuesday	     Monday</p>
<p>    Gold ($/ounce)			387.55	     386.65</p>
<p>    IPE Brent ($/barrel) (Oct)	 20.69		20.54</p>
<p>(Ldn Metal Exchange)</p>
<p>    COPPER (three months/tonne)   1,931.00	   1,941.00</p>
<p>    ALUMINIUM			   1,489.00	   1,491.00</p>
<p>(Ldn futures)</p>
<p>    COFFEE ($/tonne) (Sep)	  1,675.00	   1,657.00</p>
<p>    COCOA (sterling/tonne) (Dec)  1,040.00	   1,027.00</p>
<p>    WHITE SUGAR ($/tonne) (Oct)     352.60	     350.60</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
