<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2360" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IBCA affirms Italian foreign currency ratings.</title>
<headline>IBCA affirms Italian foreign currency ratings.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>European credit rating agency IBCA said on Tuesday it affirmed its long-term foreign currency debt rating of Italy at AA minus and said the country may have finally turned the corner in its battle for fiscal reform.</p>
<p>&quot;The rating applies to $92.9 billion of senior and unsecured foreign currency debt obligations of the Republic and sets a ceiling for the foreign currency rating of all Italian entities,&quot; IBCA said in a statement.</p>
<p>IBCA also confirmed its rating of A1 plus for short-term foreign currency issues and assigned a long-term local currency rating of AAA to sovereign debt.</p>
<p>&quot;The small reduction in the public debt to GDP ratio in 1995 - the first since 1980 - signals a possible turning point in Italy's problematic fiscal policy,&quot; the agency said.</p>
<p>But IBCA said the path would not be easy.</p>
<p>&quot;A relatively small adverse shift in the macroeconomic environment will be sufficient to blow the government's public debt to gdp projections off course,&quot; it said. &quot;IBCA is projecting that the public debt to GDP ratio will rise this year, although it should fall in the more favourable macroeconomic environment expected in 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>In July, rating agency Moody's Investors Service raised its foreign currency sovereign ceiling rating on Italy to Aa3 from A1. In late April, Standard &amp; Poor's affirmed its AA foreign currency rating for Italy.</p>
<p>IBCA said Italy had considerable strengths as a sovereign credit. These were illustrated by &quot;the continued dynamism&quot; of the private sector, a current account surplus and a high savings ratio. &quot;These aspects of the economy have allowed Italy to sustain high public debt without having to draw on foreign savings,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
