<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2364" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London's Globe, an experiment in theatre history.</title>
<headline>London's Globe, an experiment in theatre history.</headline>
<byline>Helen Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>In a theatre open to London's often rainy skies, a troupe of actors begins a risky experiment on Wednesday to discover what William Shakespeare's plays were like when first peformed 400 years ago.</p>
<p>The Globe Theatre is a replica of the 20-sided wood-and-thatch arena which Shakespeare part-owned and where his finest works, including &quot;Macbeth,&quot; &quot;Hamlet&quot; and &quot;King Lear&quot;, were staged during his lifetime.</p>
<p>It is the realisation of the dream of American actor-director Sam Wanamaker, who died of cancer in 1993, just as the theatre's wooden framework was being put in place.</p>
<p>Wanamaker had waged a 40-year battle against bureacracy and commercial greed to get the new Globe built just yards (metres) from the site of the original on the south bank of the Thames, opposite St Paul's Cathedral.</p>
<p>His vision is still central to the 30 million pound ($46 million) Globe, which begins a &quot;prologue season&quot; on Wednesday with a production of &quot;Two Gentlemen of Verona.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Anyone who worked with Sam was very much influenced by what he wanted to put together,&quot; said Lennie James, who plays one of the &quot;Two Gentlemen.&quot;</p>
<p>Interviewed under grey skies in the Globe's auditorium on Tuesday, James said the place feels permeated with a sense of history.</p>
<p>&quot;When (artistic director Mark Rylance) first welcomed us onto the stage saying we were the first actors in 400 years to stand here, I got a real buzz,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wanamaker's aim was to recreate, as far as possible, the conditions that Shakespeare's actors worked under in the 16th and 17th centuries.</p>
<p>The audience, many of them standing, would have been crowded around the stage ready to heckle the actors and punish bad performances with volleys of rotten fruit.</p>
<p>The actors had little time to learn their roles and would not have seen the full script, which was kept carefully guarded for fear that it would be stolen by another theatre.</p>
<p>The Globe has been carefully recreated from historical records and what could be gleaned from excavation of the original, destroyed in 1644 by England's puritan rulers. But little is still known about the theatres of the day.</p>
<p>Rylance said he hoped that working before a live audience would help show up anything the historians got wrong.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not claim that this is it,&quot; said the boyish Rylance. &quot;This is the best we can do in 1996. There's bound to be more evidence and we look forward to it.&quot;</p>
<p>Notwithstanding his search for authenticity, Rylance's production will depart drastically from Shakespearian traditions.</p>
<p>The cast of &quot;Two Gentlemen of Verona&quot; will include women and black actors, both unheard of in Shakespeare's day, and the play is set in modern Italy.</p>
<p>Even less traditional, the Globe will be selling cushions for the hard seats and raincoats -- thunderstorms are in the weather forecast for the opening night.</p>
<p>The choice of &quot;Two Gentleman of Verona&quot;, one of Shakespeare's lesser-known plays, has raised critics' eyebrows, but Rylance says it is symbolic.</p>
<p>It was written before the original Globe was built in 1599, just as the prologue predates the scheduled official opening of its successor in June 1997, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
