<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2400" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech SPT falls back to earth, pulls PSE with it.</title>
<headline>Czech SPT falls back to earth, pulls PSE with it.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in SPT Telecom, as expected, suffered a strong downward correction on the Prague Stock Exhcange, pulling the bourse sharply lower.</p>
<p>SPT shares gained 102 crowns just before Monday's session closed, but dealers had said the move was little more than a last minute accounting procedure, and that the rise did not correspond to market reality.</p>
<p>By the end of the session, their words had been borne out with SPT shares losing 102 crowns to 3,339.</p>
<p>The fall more than offset broader issues gains, dragging the PX50 index down five points, 0.88 percent, to 564.9.</p>
<p>Overall, 201 shares gained ground on the day, while 134 fell and 65 held steady.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody is surprised by the SPT fall. This happens quite often here when someone moves the price at the end of one session, but the market knows the real price,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Banking issues fared well on the day, with Komercni Banka, Ceska Sporitelna and Zivnostenska Banka all posting modest gains.</p>
<p>Most other major issues made only minor moves.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
