<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2407" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares extend rally, may lose steam.</title>
<headline>Polish shares extend rally, may lose steam.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares rose for the fourth day running in higher turnover on Tuesday but analysts were uncertain whether slightly better July company earnings would help sustain the rally.</p>
<p>They said the day's session offered mixed signals as stronger selling after price fixing indicated a fall but higher turnover showed new investors joined the fray.</p>
<p>&quot;A fall seems more likely tomorrow but a rise is also possible because high turnover after price fixing showed there are new players,&quot; said Pawel Tarnowski, an analyst at Raiffeisen Capital &amp; Investment.</p>
<p>The main market's all-share WIG index rose 1.6 percent to 13,183.8 points and turnover rose 22 percent to 132 million zlotys ($48.2 million) on both markets. Gainers led losers by 43 to 23 with 11 stocks stable.</p>
<p>Analysts said July company earnings, which were released by Monday, looked generally better than disappointing first half results and should be well received by the market, but were unlikely to spur significant growth in the next few sessions.</p>
<p>They said said top gainer PPABank, which rose by the daily maximum 10 percent, was helped by a buy recommendation from Nomura Equity Research and strong July earnings.</p>
<p>Analysts said companies which showed the biggest earnings improvement last month were also among Tuesday's top performers but expected the impact of July results to wear off quickly.</p>
<p>No stocks traded in Warsaw bourse continuous trade.</p>
<p>Mass privatisation NFI units, which fell 1.1 percent in the main market session to 92 zlotys in seven million zloty trade, held flat at 92 zlotys in continuous trade.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
