<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2408" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak c.bank moves failing to hit target - analysts.</title>
<headline>Slovak c.bank moves failing to hit target - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Tatiana Vacova</byline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Measures by the National Bank of Slovakia to ease the country's money supply may not be working, as a mounting liquidity surplus continues to drive prices down on the money market, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said the market's burgeoning liquidity, which is seen driving rates down by some two percentage points to about 10 percent on all maturities, points to the ineffectiveness of the NBS's recent moves to take money out of circulation.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank will have to take other measures to stem the money supply, as the effect of the tool it chose to do so is partly eliminated by short-term foreign capital inflows,&quot; Jozef Bozek of Tatra Banka told Reuters.</p>
<p>Last month, the NBS drove interbank interest rates to over 14 percent when, in a move to curtail banks' short-term lending, hiked minimum reserves significantly as of August 1.</p>
<p>That, dealers said, in tandem with an earlier hike in the Lombard rate to 15 percent from a previous 13 percent, appears to be backfiring as speculative capital floods the country taking advantage of attractive real interest rates and a steady currency.</p>
<p>The Slovak key money supply measure, M2, rose 21.5 percent year-on-year, compared to a full-year target of a 11.6 percent expansion year-on-year.</p>
<p>While some dealers said that as long as the rates hang above 10 percent foreign speculators will remain interested in the crown, though Robert Hakszer of Slovenska Sporitelna noted: &quot;In the longer-term, rates could slowly ease to 10-12 percent, spoiling some of the crown's attraction.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It would be enough to bring rates to below the Czech Republic's level to cut down a bit on crown speculation,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Prague interbank offered rate (PRIBOR) for one month funds on Tuesday averaged 12.67 percent compared to 13.05 percent on the Bratislava interbank offered rate (BRIBOR).</p>
<p>The NBS also recently moved to strengthen the crown within the plus or minus five percent band of a dollar/mark basket midpoint it uses to fix the currency daily, further attracting foreign capital.</p>
<p>&quot;The revalued crown boosted the central bank foreign exchange reserves, and eventually the market liquidity,&quot; said Dalibor Cernicka, a dealer with Istrobanka.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if foreign investors pull out, their package is not so significant to have any major impact on the country, though it could temporarily toss the crown exchange rate,&quot; Bozek said.</p>
<p>The NBS hard currency reserves rose to $3.71 billion as of August 14, from $3.43 billion on July 24, pouring out onto the money market and catching analysts who were expecting a puacity of funds off guard.</p>
<p>No official figures are available yet, but analysts estimate that some six billion crowns flooded onto the market from the reserves, while the same amount entered through maturing NBS liquidity bills, another NBS sterilisation tool.</p>
<p>NBS officials were not available for comment, but the central bank has said it is still &quot;early&quot; to analyse the effect of the measures, and warned it could even resort to imposing credit limits on banks if its money supply measures would not work.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
