<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2413" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Pepsi to vanish from Venezuelan mkt soon.</title>
<headline>Pepsi to vanish from Venezuelan mkt soon.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>PepsiCo Inc products will disappear from the Venezuelan market, in which it had an 80 percent market share until Friday, by the end of the week due to a suprise move by Venezuela's main bottler and Coca-Cola Co , Pepsi officials said late Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;There are about two or three days (stock) left...Technically we are out of Venezuela,&quot; Pepsi's Latin American President Gustavo Berejam told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;People will have to go out and look for their Pepsis,&quot; said Alberto Uribe, head of Pepsi's Andean region.  </p>
<p>Pepsi's Venezuelan franchise for the last 47 years was held by the Cisneros family, a leading business group. But the Cisneros group announced Friday it had signed a joint venture with Coke to bottle Coke and Hit trademark products at its 18 plants.</p>
<p>Pepsi, which said it was caught off guard by the development, said the Cisneros are within their rights to break the contract and will incur penalties established in it.</p>
<p>But Pepsi officials have said they will challenge the cessation of the contract, which extended to 2003.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
