<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2422" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Caution culls Australia stocks gains by close.</title>
<headline>Caution culls Australia stocks gains by close.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian share market ended just firmer on Tuesday and well off its highs as cautious players cashed in gains ahead of the Federal budget, due later today at 7.30 p.m. (0930 GMT).</p>
<p>By the close, the All Ordinaries index had firmed 3.2 points to 2,264.7 while September share index futures rose seven points to 2,283, an 18.3 point premium to the underlying index.</p>
<p>Brokers said few investors were willing to hold courageous positions ahead of the budget, allowing a wave of caution to wash over the market in the afternoon session.</p>
<p>&quot;The sellers took over in the afternoon. People are getting careful before the release of the actual figures,&quot; said a Sydney broker.</p>
<p>&quot;No-one wants to be too brave so you've seen some profit taking after a strong couple of days.&quot;</p>
<p>The afternoon losses were spread around, resulting in a mixed bag of closes among the leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;It was mixed at the end but all were well off highs at the end,&quot; the broker said.</p>
<p>Turnover impressed, topping A$850 million, as investors showed a healthy interest in an active bourse.</p>
<p>Interest rate sensitive stocks like banks and insurers climbed early but fell back to with the rest of the market in the afternoon session.</p>
<p>Rises outnumbered falls by a ratio of about five to three, while about 31 percent of stocks traded remained steady.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
