<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2425" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Aust Prov News plans Asian expansion.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Aust Prov News plans Asian expansion.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Media group Australian Provincial Newspapers Ltd said on Tuesday that it had identified a number of expansion opportunities in south-east Asia.</p>
<p>The company earlier reported a 12.3 percent rise in first half net profit to A$11.56 million.  </p>
<p>Chairman Liam Healey said the group continued to seek complementary acquisitions that would enhance shareholder value, with its mobile advertising division Buspak expanding.</p>
<p>&quot;In this regard I am very pleased to announce that APN, through Buspak, has made two significant expansionary moves. In New Zealand, Buspak will establish operations later this year. In Hong Kong, Buspak has signed a long term contract with Citybus, thus launching Buspak in south-east Asia,&quot; Healey said.  </p>
<p>Healey said the move into transit and outdoor advertising through Buspak had been very successful with the division exceeding forecasts with its A$19.8 million contribution to sales and A$4.7 million contribution to earnings before interest and tax (EBIT).</p>
<p>Publishing sales revenue was reported to have increased by five percent to A$100.6 million although EBIT for regional newspapers was marginally lower than the previous year.</p>
<p>&quot;Regional newspapers continued to be affected by depressed local and classified advertising volumes due to the weak overall economy,&quot; Healey said.  </p>
<p>The chairman said the company's radio interests through its stake in the Australian Radio Network (ARN) continued to produce excellent results, producing growth in EBIT of over 30 percent.</p>
<p>Healey said over the year APN's radio interests had increased with its one third stake in the acquisition of Radio New Zealand Commercial for NZ$89 million and ARN's acquisition of two Adelaide radio stations for A$29 million.</p>
<p>The Adelaide purchase of 5AD-FM and 5DN-AM was seen making early contributions to earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;It is expected the acquisition will be earnings enhancing in the first year,&quot; Healey said.  </p>
<p>APN is about 49 percent owned by interests of Irish businessman Tony O'Reilly.</p>
<p>APN shares closed a cent higher at A$2.43 on turnover of 328,830 shares.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
