<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2433" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Korea won devaluation could cut profits - analysts.</title>
<headline>Korea won devaluation could cut profits - analysts.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea is encouraging a depreciation of its currency to try to boost flagging exports, but the move could backfire and spark inflation, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A lower won could also eat into corporate profits, they warned.</p>
<p>&quot;It does look like the Koreans are forcing the won down very sharply, not especially against the U.S. dollar but rather the yen,&quot; Graham Courtney, an economist with SBC Warburg in Hong Kong, said in an interview with Reuters Financial Television (RFTV).</p>
<p>Andrew Holland, head of research at BZW Securities in Seoul, told RFTV a weaker won was not the miracle cure South Korea was looking for to cut its rising trade deficit and boost competitiveness against Japan.</p>
<p>The two analysts also said the South Korean stock market was expected to decline further.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect more bad news. I don't think we've had all the bad news concerning the economy yet, and I think that will force the market down further,&quot; said Holland.</p>
<p>The composite stock index closed down 6.61 points to 793.91 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>While the finance ministry has officially stated that it has no intention of interfering in the currency market, foreign exchange dealers have said that, unofficially, it has encouraged a devaluation of the won.</p>
<p>The central Bank of Korea (BOK) allowed the won to fall to a six-year low of 826.10 against the dollar last week before stepping in to ease the local unit's decline, traders said.</p>
<p>The BOK has denied ever intervening in the interbank market.</p>
<p>The won closed at 819.70 against the U.S. dollar on Tuesday while the yen traded at 107.90 against the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;What they're doing at the moment is a messy intervention, and this could have implications regarding inflation later on,&quot; Holland said.</p>
<p>As the won falls against the dollar or yen, raw material imports necessary to feed growing exports would become more expensive, fuelling price increases.</p>
<p>New Finance Minister Han Seung-soo, appointed during a cabinet reshuffle on August 8, has repeatedly emphasised the government's commitment to keeping inflation in check. The central bank has forecast that inflation would remain at 4.5 percent this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Producer prices do go straight up as the won goes down, particularly against the yen, but the Koreans have a history of managing to stop producer price pressures from coming through to the consumer price index,&quot; said Courtney.</p>
<p>&quot;However, profits are likely to go out the window if the margins are squeezed even more by the fact that the pressures won't be passed on to the consumers,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
