<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2434" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Tsann Kuen reports 26 pct dip in interim.</title>
<headline>Tsann Kuen reports 26 pct dip in interim.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Appliance maker Tsann Kuen (China) Enterprise Co Ltd said on Tuesday its net earnings fell to 26.23 million yuan in the first half of this year from 35.55 million yuan in the same period of 1995.</p>
<p>Per-share earnings were 0.14 yuan, against 0.18 yuan in the first half of 1995, said the company's interim report published in the Securities Times.</p>
<p>Its main operating income hit 408.81 million yuan between January and June 1996 versus 315.47 million in 1995.</p>
<p>Tsann Kuen blamed its earnings slide on increased global competition which had forced it to cut its prices, and phasing out of its tax exempt status.</p>
<p>The firm, set up in 1993, was entitled to a three-year corporate income tax break because of its status as a Taiwan-invested enterprise, and would pay income tax at a reduced 7.5 percent rate from 1996 to 2000, a company spokesman said.</p>
<p>Tsann Kuen, which has class B shares listed in Shenzhen, saw net earnings in 1995 dive 41.6 percent from 1994.</p>
<p>The company had after-tax profits of 38.39 million yuan in 1995, compared with 65.81 million yuan in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
