<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2437" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan's economic recovery hugs the slow lane.</title>
<headline>Japan's economic recovery hugs the slow lane.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Economic data for Japan improved slightly in June, but economists said the nation's recovery does not look like it will be moving out of the slow lane anytime soon.</p>
<p>Japan's index of leading indicators, which was designed to help predict economic developments over the next six months stood at 70 in June, over the key 50 mark for the third month in a row, the Economic Planning Agency (EPA) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A figure below the so-called &quot;boom or bust&quot; mark of 50 is generally taken as suggesting the economy will contract in the coming months, while a figure above 50 suggests the economy will expand.</p>
<p>Moreover, the coincident index, which measures current economic conditions, stood at 55, up from 30 in May and above 50 for the first time since February.</p>
<p>But economists pointed out that the strength in the data, which is compiled by comparing figures from three months before, was largely relative.</p>
<p>&quot;The June figure was based on March data which was quite weak. Today's data confirm that the economic recovery is still moderate,&quot; said Satoshi Shimamoto, an economist at MMS International.</p>
<p>An EPA official said improvements in economic barometers related to industrial output were responsible for the lift in the coincident data and that continued improvement in July would also depend on how well output would do.</p>
<p>&quot;If industrial output rises 4.2 percent, then conditions will not be so severe,&quot; he said. The government has forecast a month-on-month rise of 4.2 percent in output for July after it dropped a preliminary four percent in June.</p>
<p>Industrial output data for July will be released at the end of August.</p>
<p>Analysts said the government forecast for July was not too far out of line. In general output was recovering gradually and could be expected to do so for the time being, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;It will probably rise by two percent for rest of this year,&quot; said Tod Wood, an economist at ING Baring Securities, adding that was in line with a modest economic recovery.</p>
<p>But analysts also noted there were few factors on the horizon that called for a more upbeat assessment of the economy.</p>
<p>A slow but steady comeback in consumption and healthy corporate capital spending plans have been heralded as new stimulants for recovery but an expected drop in public works spending this autumn will somewhat counter those good effects, they said.</p>
<p>Japan's economy started recovering earlier this year after recording four years of near-zero growth, propelled in part by a massive 14 trillion yen public works spending plan announced last September.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E71">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
