<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2445" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia's Maybank net meets expectations.</title>
<headline>Malaysia's Maybank net meets expectations.</headline>
<byline>Christina Pantin</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malayan Banking Bhd (Maybank) on Tuesday posted full-year results that were in line with or slightly above market expectations, belying fears they would fall below estimates, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Net profit at the nation's largest bank for the year ended June 30, 1996, rose to 1.07 billion ringgit ($428 million), or 94 cents a share, from 863.53 million ringgit, or 76 cents a share, a year earlier.</p>
<p>That was a shade above forecasts of around 1.04 billion ringgit, or 91 cents a share.</p>
<p>&quot;I think (the result) was slightly above market expectations, but it was very much in line with my estimate of 1.094 billion,&quot; said Gan Kim Khoon, an analyst at James Capel. &quot;I would say it should do some good for the share price.&quot;</p>
<p>Maybank's stock had dropped sharply on speculation results for the year would suffer from a decision to boost loan-loss provisions.</p>
<p>Its shares were suspended on Tuesday for the earnings report and last traded at 22.50 ringgit on Monday.</p>
<p>The company's latest earnings report did not contain details on its loan-loss provision, but more details may come out at a press briefing at the close of trading. Analysts will meet management on Thursday to review results.</p>
<p>Concerns about loan losses centred on troubled steel company Perwaja Steel and ailing Singapore property and trading company Amcol Holdings Ltd.</p>
<p>Analysts said on Tuesday it was difficult to tell if Maybank had boosted its loan-loss provision based on the earnings report, although several said it appeared no big increase had been made.</p>
<p>&quot;Margins did improve quite substantially,&quot; said an analyst at Vickers Ballas, adding that operating costs were &quot;quite well managed&quot;.</p>
<p>Several analysts said loan growth of 15 percent was slightly disappointing. In addition, &quot;deposit growth was tiny,&quot; said Tony Shue of Jupiter Securities.</p>
<p>Deposits from customers grew 13 percent year on year. An analyst with a foreign research house said the pace reflected &quot;a lot of competition for funds&quot; within the Malaysian banking industry.</p>
<p>Analysts said the latest results may prompt some research firms to increase next year's profit forecasts. &quot;I would expect many other houses to revise upwards their estimates for 1997 based on this,&quot; said Gan. ($1 = 2.5 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
