<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2453" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore exports surprise with 6.4 pct July rise.</title>
<headline>Singapore exports surprise with 6.4 pct July rise.</headline>
<byline>Doreen Siow</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore non-oil domestic exports, confounding most expectations, bounced back in July, surging 6.4 percent after dropping 6.1 percent in June, the Trade Development Board (TDB) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Non-oil exports expanded to Singapore $7.28 billion (US$ 5.16 billion) in nominal terms.</p>
<p>The figures were completely out of line with forecasts by leading economists. A Reuters poll of eight economists had early predicted a nominal year-on-year fall of 1.7 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Non-oil exports performed much better than expected. On the surface it looks good, but it is a volatile figure on a month-to-month basis,&quot; said Albert Tan, an economist with J.M. Sassoon.</p>
<p>The TDB said non-oil domestic exports to the United States, Singapore's largest market, and Japan continued to increase but at a more moderate rate at 7.2 percent and 13.7 percent respectively.</p>
<p>The increase in sales to the United States was mainly in disk drives, integrated circuits, and printers amongst other electronic items.</p>
<p>However, exports of computer parts and peripherals and radios declined.</p>
<p>Exports to Europe also shrank, by 2.6 percent, while exports to Malaysia and Hong Kong also remained weak, said TDB.</p>
<p>However, non-oil domestic exports to South Korea and China maintained strong growth, expanding by 24.8 percent and 17.9 percent respectively.</p>
<p>- Singapore Newsroom 65-8703080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
