<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2461" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Where in the world is Taiwan's vice-president?.</title>
<headline>Where in the world is Taiwan's vice-president?.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Parker</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Where in the world is Taiwanese Vice-President Lien Chan?</p>
<p>The question has perplexed journalists, nervous stock market investors and ordinary citizens since Lien, a dapper, U.S.-educated millionaire who doubles as premier or cabinet chief, dropped from sight in New York on Sunday.</p>
<p>Lien's whereabouts are laden with portent for Taiwan's strained ties with longtime rival China, which surely is as curious as anyone about his movements.</p>
<p>Taiwan's government knows where he is, acknowledging that Lien is making a private visit to a country where Taiwan has no diplomatic ties, apparently in Europe.</p>
<p>But officials have bent over backward to keep Lien's travels secret, knowing Beijing will savage any diplomatic friend that accords anything resembling an official welcome to a leader of what Beijing regards as Taiwan's illegitimate government.</p>
<p>A state-funded television station reported on Tuesday that Lien's journey had taken him to Ukraine, and the authoritative United Daily News said he was expected to meet the Ukrainian head of state.</p>
<p>Neither identified or described the source of its report and Taiwan officials refused to comment on it.</p>
<p>A former Soviet republic, Ukraine recognises the communist government in Beijing -- not Taiwan's exiled Republic of China government -- but has made clear its desire for better relations with Taiwan and its powerful export-driven economy.</p>
<p>In the official information void, Taiwan's media have been left to speculate about Lien's destination, variously suggesting he would visit Hungary, Poland, Switzerland, France, Austria or Belarus, not to mention Ukraine.</p>
<p>China's ire at diplomatic affronts can be dramatic and has prompted Taiwan President Lee Teng-hui in the past week to step up the rhetoric of a festering political showdown dating to the civil war that split Taiwan from China in 1949.</p>
<p>Worries over renewed acrimony on Monday sparked a three-percent slide in Taiwan's hypersensitive stock market, but share prices recouped some of the losses on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A furious Beijing downgraded its U.S. ties after Washington let Taiwan Lee make a private visit in June 1995, although the two sides recently began patching things up.</p>
<p>China showed its anger at Taipei with a nine-month spate of war games and unarmed missile tests in waters near Taiwan that peaked in the final days before the island's March 23 election, the first popular presidential poll in Chinese history.</p>
<p>France, Germany, Austria, the Netherlands and Czech Republic are among diplomatic partners of China that have paid dearly for arming Taiwan or showing other signs of political support.</p>
<p>Beijing flatly refuses to recognise any state that recognises Taiwan's exiled Republic of China government.</p>
<p>The number of those countries fell by one on Monday to just 30 as impoverished Niger, which split with Beijing to recognise Taipei in 1992, switched back to Beijing.</p>
<p>China had denounced Niger's defection to Taiwan as a result of the prosperous island's &quot;chequebook diplomacy&quot; and has made a high priority of wooing Niger and other African states back.</p>
<p>Chinese President Jiang Zemin visited six African countries in June, including Niger's neighbour Mali, prompting Taipei to claim that Beijing was the true &quot;chequebook diplomat.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
