<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2472" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli shares decline on sales by funds.</title>
<headline>Israeli shares decline on sales by funds.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli shares closed lower across the board in dull trading on Tuesday as provident funds resumed selling, traders said.</p>
<p>The benchmark Mishtanim index of the top 100 shares fell 1.08 points, or 0.62 percent, to 172.31 on an all-share turnover of 58 million shekels, unchanged from Monday.</p>
<p>The Maof 25 index fell 0.51 percent to 182.42.</p>
<p>&quot;Activity is very low and the market looks really bad. The provident funds of Israel Discount Bank were selling shares today, but there were no buyers,&quot; said Yoram Ben-Yaeir at Ahrayut Investment Management.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in the middle of a crisis and nobody knows when will it end. The tension with Syria is also bad for trading,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Israeli television reported on Monday that Syria had tested a long-range Scud missile able to hit Israeli cities. Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has also warned that problems in Lebanon would be bad for Damascus.</p>
<p>The First International Bank of Israel gained 0.50 percent to 34,652 after it reported that net profit in the second quarter of 1996 rose to 39.5 million shekels from 39.3 million shekels in the same quarter in 1995. During the first half of 1996 net profit fell to 75.3 million shekels from 82.3 million.</p>
<p>Clal Trading lost 0.5 percent to 660 after it said net profit in the second quarter of 1996 fell to 310,000 shekels from 9.4 million shekels in the same quarter of 1995. During the first half of 1996 net profit fell to 8.5 million shekels from 13 million shekels.</p>
<p>Clal Trading's parent company Clal Israel fell 2.50 percent to 6,553.</p>
<p>&quot;The bond market continues to decline and this affects trading in the stock market. The situation of the provident funds is very worrying and soon they will be forced to sell more shares to get liquidity,&quot; said Dannielle Finn at Batucha Securities and Investment.</p>
<p>Provident funds are long-term savings funds with special tax benefits. They have been forced to sell bonds and stocks to meet massive public withdrawals.</p>
<p>The most active shares were Koor Industries, which gained 1.0 percent to 27,603 on volume of 5.0 million shekels; Teva Pharmaceutical Industries, which rose 1.75 percent to 106,807 on turnover of 4.0 million shekels; and Bank Hapoalim, which rose 0.50 percent to 420 on volume of 2.8 million shekels.</p>
<p>- Dan Gerstenfeld, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
