<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2479" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Iran pins hope on Petronas deal to ease isolation.</title>
<headline>Iran pins hope on Petronas deal to ease isolation.</headline>
<byline>Michael Georgy</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tehran is banking on Malaysia's Petronas acquisition of a 30 percent stake in a project to develop two oil and gas fields in Iran to deflect intense U.S. efforts to isolate the Islamic republic.</p>
<p>&quot;This shows that unilateral moves cannot isolate the Iranian oil industry. It also indicates that the U.S. position is not shared by foreign oil companies,&quot; an Iranian oil official told Reuters by telephone from Tehran on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The official predicted the deal &quot;will have a positive impact&quot; on other foreign companies seeking business in Iran's lucrative oil and gas industries. &quot;The deal indicates that the U.S. cannot dictate its own will.&quot;</p>
<p>But the key question now is whether other companies will follow suit in the face of tough new U.S. moves to penalise non-American firms that invest in energy projects in Iran and Libya, analysts and diplomats said.</p>
<p>&quot;Iran is trying everything possible to break the sanctions and the isolation,&quot; said an oil industry executive in the Gulf.</p>
<p>&quot;But the Americans aren't joking and other companies like ours are likely to remain cautious. Iran is a risky market.&quot;</p>
<p>French oil group Total SA on Monday said Malaysia's state-owned energy company Petronas had taken a 30 percent stake in the Sirri A and E fields through its Carigali subsidiary in a deal approved by the Iranian authorities.</p>
<p>The announcement, ending a search of more than a year for partners in the $600 million project, came two weeks after U.S. President Bill Clinton signed a bill which would penalise foreign firms which invest $40 million or more annually in Iran's or Libya's energy sectors.</p>
<p>The Iranian official said Petronas sealed the deal before the new U.S. sanctions were made law. But the official and Gulf oil analysts predicted the news would still anger Washington.</p>
<p>&quot;This is outright defiance. It will be seen by Washington as open defiance of Clinton's bill,&quot; said one analyst. &quot;At the same time, companies will be taking a risk if they invest in Iran.&quot;</p>
<p>But a British diplomat underlined the rift between the United States and its European allies who were outraged at the U.S. sanctions.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be perfectly content to trade with Iran. We don't have a problem with that. There are opportunites in Iran and European companies will follow their governments' leads,&quot; the Gulf-based diplomat said. &quot;Other companies are likely to follow Petronas's lead.&quot;</p>
<p>Total, which has always said its dealings with both Iran and Libya were within French and international law, said earlier this month that the U.S. sanctions would not apply to Sirri.</p>
<p>The Sirri deal, Iran's largest with a foreign firm since its 1979 revolution, attracted fierce opposition from Washington which accuses Tehran of backing &quot;international terrorism&quot;.</p>
<p>Iran denies the charges.</p>
<p>DuPont Co unit Conoco Inc had to dissolve an earlier deal with Iran for the development of the two Sirri fields after pressure from the White House.</p>
<p>Iran said the new sanctions were doomed to fail because they lacked support from European states which have refused to adopt the U.S. hardline stand on Tehran.</p>
<p>Total signed a contract on July 13, 1995 with the National Iranian Oil Company covering all phases of the development of the two fields, including studies, delineation, development and production start-up.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
