<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2480" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Saudi king stresses agriculture's role in economy.</title>
<headline>Saudi king stresses agriculture's role in economy.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi Arabia's King Fahd said the agriculture sector played a vital role in the oil-dominated economy and the kingdom was encouraging private sector investment in agriculture, Saudi Press Agency said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This sector will continue to play a vital role in the country's economic diversification drive by expanding its links with other sectors,&quot; he told a cabinet meeting on Monday.</p>
<p>He said the private sector would continue to play a leading role in agricultural development and the government would support those efforts by providing research and facilities.</p>
<p>The king said the sector was an &quot;indivisible part&quot; of Saudi Arabia's overall security. It provides jobs and revenue.</p>
<p>The Gulf Arab state is the world's biggest oil exporter. But it has been working to diversify its oil-dominated economy to lessen reliance on its main source of revenue.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia produces wheat, potatoes and other goods.</p>
<p>Agricultural output contributes about 11 percent of the non-oil gross domestic product.</p>
<p>In the kingdom's 1995-2000 development plan, agriculture is expected to grow 3.1 percent annually, lower than previous targets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DUBAI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
