<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2481" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. tentatively approvss a new Pan AM airlines.</title>
<headline>U.S. tentatively approvss a new Pan AM airlines.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Transportation Department on Tuesday gave its tentative approval for Pan American Airlines to fly again.</p>
<p>But this will be a new airlines.</p>
<p>The old Pan Am, an aviation pioneer, was founded in 1927, but went bankrupt in 1991 after years of red ink and after a bomb brought down one of its planes in Lockerbie, Scotland in 1988, killing 270 people.</p>
<p>Transportation Department spokesman William Mosley said the new Pan Am, based in Miami, Florida, was found tentatively fit to provide aviation services, pending a comment period of 15 days.</p>
<p>The department will make a final ruling following the comment period, Mosley said.</p>
<p>Miami businessman Chuck Cobb bought the Pan Am name and its familiar blue globe logo in 1993 and with former Pan Am executive Martin Shugrue announced plans to restart the carrier as a small domestic airline.</p>
<p>Last month, the new Pan Am said it planned to start operations this summer with three planes flying routes between Miami, New York, Chicago, Los Angeles and San Francisco.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
