<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2492" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Levi Strauss launches new slacks line.</title>
<headline>Levi Strauss launches new slacks line.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Levi Strauss &amp; Co. said Tuesday it was launching a line of slacks meant to appeal to men who don't like suits, in only the third major brand introduction in the company's 140-year history.</p>
<p>The new slacks, to be called Slates, will be marketed as dressier than the company's famous jeans or its Dockers pants brand, but not as formal as suits.</p>
<p>The pants, to be aimed at men in their 30s and 40s who grew up wearing Levi's jeans and Dockers khakis, are meant to give a big boost to the San Francisco-based clothing company, though how well men accept the new line remains to be seen, industry analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to awaken a sleeping giant of a category that we think has enormous potential,&quot; Jann Westfall, president of the Slates brand, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Those men want something different to wear as the workplace gets more casual, &quot;a new look for business and social occasions that falls between casual cotton pants and suits,&quot; Westfall said.</p>
<p>The pants will come in flannel, wool gabardine and other fabrics with a suggested retail price of $50 to $90 a pair, said Lory Cogan, Levi vice president for marketing.</p>
<p>The new line will come in a broad range of styles, colours and sizes, and the pants in most cases will not require tailoring, which Levi hopes will lure men who want hassle-free shopping.</p>
<p>Cogan said research revealed that men hate to shop for dress pants and believe &quot;it's more enjoyable to go to the dentist&quot; because they can't find what they need or like.</p>
<p>Slates aims to change that when it makes its debut this fall in department stores, backed by a $20 million marketing campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;They will probably dominate the market,&quot; said retail consultant Alan Millstein. He added that slacks are a small market with very few players, such as the Haggar and Farah brands.</p>
<p>He said that Levi Strauss is trying to expand its business by going after the $1.9 billion-a-year market, but he doesn't see it as a &quot;great growth engine&quot; for the company.</p>
<p>Millstein questioned how many pairs of slacks men would buy at the prices set by Levi's.</p>
<p>A research study done last year for the company showed that 85 percent of American companies that had a traditional dress code were now allowing some form of more casual attire in the workplace.</p>
<p>In a national telephone survey of men in their 30s and 40s, almost half of men who do not work in jeans or a uniform said their office dress code is somewhere between suits and cotton pants, according to Levi Strauss.</p>
<p>Westfall believes Slates will allow men to express more individuality, youthfulness and personal style than they can in a suit. She said the pants have an &quot;accessible style.&quot;</p>
<p>The privately held company, which employs 36,000 people around the world, had global sales of $6.7 billion in 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
