<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2502" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Teamsters strike Hertz ahead of Chicago convention.</title>
<headline>Teamsters strike Hertz ahead of Chicago convention.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three hundred employees of car rental giant Hertz Corp. went out on strike just one week before the Democratic National Convention begins here.</p>
<p>More than 20,000 people are expected to descend on Chicago next week for the Aug. 26-29 convention.</p>
<p>Those wanting to rent Hertz cars will be able to do so despite the strike, said a spokesman for Hertz, the world's largest car rental firm and a unit of Ford Motor Co.</p>
<p>Hertz managers were staffing customer service counters, courtesy buses and vehicle service areas left abandoned Monday by members of Teamsters Local 781, said Hertz's Joe Russo.</p>
<p>If needed, Hertz was prepared to maintain interim staffing through the convention at the affected locations at O'Hare and Midway airports, as well as two downtown offices, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our guess is the union saw some opportunity to put some pressure on Hertz with the Democratic National Convention in town and we fully anticipated that,&quot; Russo said by telephone from Hertz headquarters in Park Ridge, N.J.</p>
<p>The 300 employees have been working without a contract since December 1995. Negotiations apparently stumbled over work rules and the two sides are not far apart, Russo said.</p>
<p>&quot;The strike came as a bit of a surprise yesterday because we thought this was an awfully attractive package,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The union could not be reached for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
