<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2512" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Federal Reserve holds interest rates steady.</title>
<headline>U.S. Federal Reserve holds interest rates steady.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Federal Reserve opted on Tuesday to hold interest rates steady amid signs that the economy is cooling off without inflation heating up.  </p>
<p>The decision by the central bank's policy-making Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) had been widely expected and left the key federal funds rate that commercial banks charge each other for overnight money unchanged at 5.25 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The Federal Open Market Committee meeting ended at 12:45 p.m (1645 GMT). There is no further announcement,&quot; central bank spokesman Joseph Coyne said in a brief statement.</p>
<p>The decision to hold rates steady keeps the independent Fed out of the line of political fire in the runup to the November 5 presidential and congressional elections.  </p>
<p>After growing at its fastest pace in two years in the second quarter, the economy looks to have slowed recently as the housing market has weakened and retail sales have stalled.</p>
<p>&quot;It's no surprise that the Federal Reserve felt justified sitting on its hands, since there have been so many mixed signals in the economy,&quot; Bill Cheney, chief economist at Boston-based John Hancock Financial Services, said.</p>
<p>Most analysts expect the economy to lose more momentum as the second half continues. But it remains an open question whether it will slow enough to keep inflation in check.</p>
<p>That means a precautionary rate rise is possible later in the year, once the Fed has more evidence in hand to help it measure how much the expansion is slowing, economists said.</p>
<p>More than half of 30 economists surveyed by Reuters last week forecast a rate increase by the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;Fed officials would prefer not to act in the last month or two before the election if they can help it,&quot; Hancock's Cheney said. But he added that he believes the next rate move could just as well be down as up.</p>
<p>Tuesday's FOMC meeting was sandwiched between the Republican Party's presidential nominating convention last week in San Diego and the Democrats' next week in Chicago.  </p>
<p>A rate rise ahead of the election would not be good news for President Clinton in his drive to win a second term, although it would likely have little immediate impact on an economy that still has considerable forward momentum.</p>
<p>The economy grew at a 4.2 percent annualized pace in the second quarter -- about twice the speed most economists reckon is sustainable on a long-term basis without fanning inflation.</p>
<p>And the jobs market has remained buoyant, putting extra money in workers' pockets and portending continued solid consumer spending.</p>
<p>The Fed holds its next policy-making FOMC meeting on September 24. Since cutting rates by one quarter of a percentage point in January, the central bank has held monetary policy steady as the economy first waned then waxed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
