<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2520" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Weaker imports shrink U.S. June trade gap.</title>
<headline>Weaker imports shrink U.S. June trade gap.</headline>
<byline>Glenn Somerville</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lower imports shrank the U.S. trade deficit dramatically in June, the Commerce Department said Tuesday, bolstering the impression of gradual waning in the economy's vigour.</p>
<p>The monthly gap between exports and imports plunged 23.1 percent to $8.11 billion from a revised $10.55 billion in May as fewer new foreign-made cars and computers poured into American markets.</p>
<p>New bilateral irritants emerged, though, as the trade shortfall with China swelled 8.8 percent to $3.33 billion to become the biggest with any country. It surpassed for the first time the $3.24 billion deficit with Japan, which was up 3.6 percent from May.</p>
<p>Commerce Secretary Mickey Kantor told a news conference that the Clinton administration was &quot;extremely resolute&quot; about trying to break down Chinese barriers to U.S.-made goods.</p>
<p>While imports of relatively cheap consumer goods from China kept rising, exports to the Asian trade giant fell for a fourth straight month during June to the lowest level since the beginning of 1995, creating a deficit that Kantor called &quot;too high.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts were surprised by the sharp 3.3 percent falloff in overall June imports to $77.82 billion, while exports held up relatively well, falling just 0.3 percent to $69.71 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;It says that exports are providing some underpinning for the U.S. economy but overall it tells us that we have sharply weakened in terms of economic vigour and activity,&quot; said Roger Shields, head of country risk management for Chase Manhattan Bank in New York.</p>
<p>Consumer goods exports in June were a record $5.95 billion, up $41 million from May. That partly offset a $138 million decline to $12.32 billion in foreign sales of industrial supplies and materials.</p>
<p>The United States typically runs a surplus on its trade with other countries in services like travel and tourism that reduces the impact of chronic merchandise trade deficits.</p>
<p>In June, the merchandise deficit fell 13.9 percent to $14.46 billion from $16.79 billion in May. Lower imports of new cars and parts, especially from Japan and Germany, as well as cheaper petroleum helped shrink the merchandise trade gap.</p>
<p>The surplus on services climbed 1.6 percent to $6.34 billion from $6.25 billion in May. Analysts said beforehand that an influx of tourists bound for the Olympic Games in Atlanta would boost the services surplus.</p>
<p>Lawrence Chimerine, executive director of the Economic Strategy Institute in Washington, said trade benefited in June as the U.S. economic expansion lost some steam and dampened consumers' ardor for imports. But he warned that it will be hard to keep exports growing.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy is slowing,&quot; Chimerine said. &quot;June marked the start of that process and the weak imports were part of it.</p>
<p>&quot;But Europe is bouncing back only slowly, Japan is still wavering and Canada is weak&quot; as a source of demand for American goods, Chimerine said. &quot;I don't think we're going to see a lot of progress on lowering the trade deficit for the rest of this year.&quot;</p>
<p>For the first six months of 1996, the cumulative goods and services deficit was down 14 percent to $52.62 billion from $61.34 billion in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>The cost and volume of all types of petroleum products fell in June after a sharp May runup. The cost of petroleum imports declined to $5.33 billion in June from $5.93 billion while the volume fell to 291,866 barrels from 305,171 in May.</p>
<p>Foreign sales of civilian aircraft declined in June by $117 million to $1.54 billion. Exports of industrial supplies and materials were off $138 million to $12.32 billion.</p>
<p>Imports of autos and parts from all sources dropped sharply, by $689 million to $10.79 billion in June. Computer imports were down $413 million to $4.24 billion and semiconductor imports decreased $291 million to $2.87 billion in June.</p>
<p>In bilateral trade, the deficit with Western Europe fell 7.1 percent to $761 million and the shortfall with Canada was down 2.2 percent to $2.42 billion.</p>
<p>The U.S. deficit with Mexico shrank 6.4 percent to $1.49 billion amid signs the Mexican economy was recovering from a deep recession and grew solidly in the second quarter.</p>
<p>The deficit with oil-producing OPEC countries dropped 26.9 percent in June to $1.40 billion from $1.91 billion in May.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
