<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2526" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Manufactured housing maker Champion to acquire Redman.</title>
<headline>Manufactured housing maker Champion to acquire Redman.</headline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Champion Enterprises Inc. has a definitive agreement to acquire Redman Industries Inc., another major manufactured housing company, in a stock deal valued at about $365.5 million, they said Tuesday.</p>
<p>The deal would combine the second- and third-largest companies in the manufactured housing business, creating an entity that would rival Fleetwood Enterprises Inc. as the industry's leader.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, Champion will offer 1.24 shares of its stock for each of Dallas-based Redman's 13.36 million shares outstanding in a tax-free pooling of interests.</p>
<p>Auburn Hills, Mich.-based Champion said it would issue about 17 million shares in the merger and would have 51 million shares outstanding after the deal.</p>
<p>Redman's stock was unchanged at $25.75 on Nasdaq, while Champion edged down 12.5 cents to $21.50 on the New York Stock Exchange at mid-morning.</p>
<p>Walter Young will remain chairman, president and chief executive of Champion. Robert Lipton, president and CEO of Redman, will head Redman, which will become a subsidiary of Champion.</p>
<p>Redman's board of directors has approved the deal and has agreed to recommend that Redman shareholders adopt the merger agreement.</p>
<p>The merger is also subject to approval by both companies' shareholders and regulators.</p>
<p>Redman said it would postpone its annual meeting, scheduled for Wednesday, and call a special shareholder meeting to vote on the deal before the end of the year.</p>
<p>Both companies said they had rescinded their stock repurchase programmes.</p>
<p>Champion, has 6,000 employees and 31 manufacturing plants, while Redman, based in Dallas, has 4,000 employees and 18 manufacturing plants.</p>
<p>The companies had combined annual sales of about $1.5 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
