<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2544" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLISH JULY EARNINGS JUST UP AFTER WEAK FIRST HALF.</title>
<headline>POLISH JULY EARNINGS JUST UP AFTER WEAK FIRST HALF.</headline>
<byline>Steven Silber</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Firms listed on the Warsaw Stock Exchange recorded slightly better July earnings after a weak first half, but analysts said it was too early to tell if there would be an earnings rebound this year.</p>
<p>In July 48 firms on the main and parallel markets showed a real net profit growth year-on-year compared with 34 firms over the first six months.</p>
<p>&quot;July earnings were average, but better than the weak results recorded in May and June, so they're returning to normal rather than worsening,&quot; said Pawel Tarnowski, an analyst at Raiffeisen Capital and Investment.</p>
<p>Analysts had attributed this year's long winter to lower profits over the year's first four months.</p>
<p>But they said unspectacular May and June earnings hastened a downward correction that followed the main market's 90- percent rise this year to a 27-month high of 14,282.2 points on July 5.</p>
<p>Analysts had expected one more growth spurt but instead a 14-percent downtrend and then stability followed until last week when investors started buying in hopes of better earnings.</p>
<p>But analysts said many players, especially foreign investors, would need preliminary third-quarter results due in October to be sure profits had taken a bullish turn.</p>
<p>Jacek Dzierwa, Polish equity analyst at Salomon Brothers in London, said better July earnings were a good sign but nothing definite, as Polish auditors were likely to find losses previously overlooked.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm taking those monthly results as an indication, but nothing tangible,&quot; Dzierwa said.</p>
<p>Firms showing good results tended to rise on the bourse on Tuesday, such as top gainer PPABank , up by the daily maximum 10 percent.</p>
<p>But analysts said the July results were not likely strong enough to maintain the WIG's recent four-session, six-percent jump to Tuesday's close at 13,183.8 points.</p>
<p>Among individual firms Swarzedz disappointed recording a loss despite improved sales, they said.</p>
<p>They said paint makers Polifarb Wroclaw and especially Polifarb Cieszyn looked particularily strong even though better earnings were expected due to a seasonal surge in sales.</p>
<p>Raiffeisen's Tarnowski said Cieszyn recorded its best monthly result in history.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
