<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2552" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Kerry says half-year profit rise 21 percent.</title>
<headline>Kerry says half-year profit rise 21 percent.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN, Ireland</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kerry Group Plc, Ireland's largest food company, said Tuesday that profits jumped 21 percent in the first half of the year despite worries over so-called mad cow disease in Europe.</p>
<p>The company, based in Tralee in County Kerry, said pretax profits rose to 20 million punts ($32.1 million) from 16.5 million punts ($26.5 million) in the first half of 1995. Sales rose 1.5 percent to 589.4 million punts ($945.4 million) from 580.7 million ($931.4 million).</p>
<p>&quot;While the bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE) scare did affect sales in some business areas at the end of the first quarter, strong advances in branded product sales in the second quarter&quot; helped boost profits margins, Kerry said in a statement.</p>
<p>In March British government scientists said they had identified a new strain of the human brain disorder Creutzfeldt-Jakob Disease that was most likely linked to eating beef infected with BSE, or mad cow disease.</p>
<p>A British coroner ruled on Monday that a 20-year-old vegetarian who died of Creutzfeldt-Jakob Disease caught it from eating hamburgers as a child, the first ruling linking a human death to mad cow disease. Some government officials and scientists cast doubt on the ruling, however.</p>
<p>After the British government's announcement in March, more than a dozen countries suspended imports of British beef.</p>
<p>Kerry said its ingredients business, bolstered by the $402 million acquisition of the U.S. food ingredients company DCA in 1994, reported a 7 percent increase in operating profits.</p>
<p>On the consumer foods side, Kerry Foods reported a 15 percent increase in operating profits while profit margins also rose.</p>
<p>The group's agribusiness division also reported a profit for the first half.</p>
<p>Chairman Michael Hanrahan said the company would focus on maximizing the potential of its fruit ingredients business across Europe after acquiring Ciprial, a fruit ingredients company with operations in France and Italy, in February.</p>
<p>But the acquisition of Ciprial has led the group to revise its end-year net debt target upward. Kerry, which had planned to cut its debt to capital ratio to 70 percent before buying Ciprial, is now aiming for 90 percent by year-end.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN, Ireland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
