<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2553" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Axa first half revenues rise 24.5 percent.</title>
<headline>Axa first half revenues rise 24.5 percent.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>French insurer Axa SA on Tuesday reported a 24.5 percent rise in first-half revenues, powered by consolidation of Australian life insurer National Mutual acquired last year.</p>
<p>Axa, one of France's Big Four insurers, said in a statement revenues rose to 81.93 billion francs ($16.10 billion) from 65.81 billion francs.</p>
<p>The increase &quot;primarily reflected the consolidation of National Mutual during the period,&quot; said the company, the most geographically diversified of France's insurers.</p>
<p>Axa acquired control of National Mutual last year for $A1.1 billion.</p>
<p>Revenues rose 8.8 percent on a constant currency and structure basis.</p>
<p>Shares rose following the figures but underperformed the CAC-40 index of 40 leading industrial shares.</p>
<p>Life insurance made the biggest contribution to revenues rising 34.9 percent to 42.68 billion francs. European life insurance revenues rose 16.1 percent to 15.14 billion.</p>
<p>Non-life insurance revenues rose 3.4 pecent to 15.43 billion francs.</p>
<p>Reinsurance revenues were up 30.5 percent to 6.34 billion francs.</p>
<p>Revenues of financial services and holding companies climbed 21.5 percent to 17.48 billion francs, helped by strong U.S. growth at Donaldson, Lufkin &amp; Jenrette and Alliance Capital Management.</p>
<p>Brokers took on board the strong special factors surrounding consolidation in Axa's figures but said the underlying picture looked sound.</p>
<p>&quot;Among the good factors is growth in life assurance,&quot; said Sami Gotrane of brokers EIFB. &quot;Much of that is NatMut but it was also up 16 percent in Europe where there was no acquisition and up 12 percent in France...,&quot; he said. ($1=5.090 French Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
