<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2556" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Viag sees 1996 net at 1995 levels despite H1 fall.</title>
<headline>Viag sees 1996 net at 1995 levels despite H1 fall.</headline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German utility group Viag AG said on Tuesday its net profit for 1996 ought at least to match year-ago levels although group pretax profit fell 21 percent to 1.178 billion marks ($790.8 million) in the first half.</p>
<p>The group said in a statement that its operating profit had &quot;clearly improved&quot; in the first half of 1996 and a sharp drop in its pre-tax profit was due purely to special income factors.</p>
<p>In 1995, around 40 percent of Viag's first-half profit was the result of one-off gains from the sale of its 43.4 percent stake in Germany's biggest paper maker PWA and other major changes in shareholdings.</p>
<p>Viag said its group sales rose to 21.803 billion marks from 21.375 billion in the first half of 1996 and that its operating profit rose 10 percent in the period.</p>
<p>Sales in its chemicals, energy and logistics divisions advanced in the period while packaging sales dropped to 5.9 billion marks from 6.3 billion marks.</p>
<p>Investment in fixed assets dropped to 792 million marks from 913 million marks and group spending on participations dropped dramatically to 178 million marks from 1.49 billion.</p>
<p>In the first half of 1995, Viag and its units bought several major companies including SBI Systems Bio-Industries, bought by Viag's chemicals division and a majority stake in Computer 2000.</p>
<p>Viag's workforce was little changed at 82,874 compared with 84,939 in the first six months of 1995. ($ = 1.489 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
