<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2558" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Holdings keep a rein on Belgian bourse gain.</title>
<headline>Holdings keep a rein on Belgian bourse gain.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian shares ended Tuesday with modest gains but still lagged other markets.</p>
<p>The Bel-20 index had to battle its way through resistance above 1,750. It ended 6.88 points or 0.39 percent higher at 1,760.15, virtually the day's high, with volume a fairly moderate 1.5 billion francs worth of Belgian shares.</p>
<p>&quot;The market started out quite dull but picked up in the afternoon. It was the holding companies which held us back,&quot; one dealer said. Societe Generale De Belgique was unchanged at 2,405 francs and Group Bruxelles Lambert lost 15 francs to 3,980.</p>
<p>Dealers could find no key reason for why holdings should have underperformed, citing just a &quot;lack of enthusiasm&quot;.</p>
<p>Kredietbank was among the most heavily traded stocks in value terms, closing unchanged at 9,350 with 13,686 shares changing hands. &quot;It remains one of the more expensive Belgian banks in terms of price-earnings. You're paying for quality, though it would have to drop 15 to 20 percent before I'd consider it a buy,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>All eyes were now turned to the U.S. where the Federal Reserve's policy-making FOMC meets on Tuesday, though it is not expected to decide on a change in U.S interest rates.</p>
<p>The prospect of Thursday's Bundesbank meeting is providing more suspense, amid growing hopes for a German repo rate cut, dealers said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
