<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2559" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France's MATIF aims to be centre of Euro trade.</title>
<headline>France's MATIF aims to be centre of Euro trade.</headline>
<byline>Penny MacRae</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's Matif, the second largest European derivatives exchange, said on Tuesday it aimed to be a main trading centre for euro-denominated interest rate contracts, following collapse of alliance attempts with Germany's stock and options body.</p>
<p>&quot;The goal for the Matif is to create in Paris benchmark interest rate products in Euros,&quot; said a spokeswoman for the Matif. &quot;That's the centrepiece of our strategy,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The Euro is the currency to be introduced under European economic and monetary union slated to start on January 1, 1999.</p>
<p>The German stock and options market exchange, Deutsche Boerse, rang down the curtain last week on cooperation efforts, saying it was &quot;not possible to develop common products right now.&quot;</p>
<p>France and Germany had been working since 1993 to integrate their financial markets to prepare for monetary union and to counter London's financial dominance. But their efforts were studded with delays and failures.</p>
<p>In April, the Matif, the French stock markets authority SBF and Deutsche Boerse abandoned plans for a joint electronic trading system for shares and derivatives when the Germans opted not to use a French-developed system for trading shares.</p>
<p>But they still planned more limited cooperation on interest rate contracts. The final blow came from German insistence that the Matif abandon &quot;open outcry&quot; for trading interest rate products. &quot;For the Germans, it had to be electronic or nothing,&quot; said the spokeswoman, saying they showed &quot;real dogmatism&quot;.</p>
<p>All other big centres which trade interest rate products use open outcry and it would have been too risky to change, she said. &quot;It's always delicate to change a system when market participants are used to it -- it might kill the contract.&quot;</p>
<p>The Matif had placed a high priority on a German link-up but played it down after difficulties emerged. Matif head Gerard Pfauwadel told L'Agefi newspaper on Tuesday that interest rate products &quot;were the real challenge for the future...Paris remains a major place for interest rate products&quot;.</p>
<p>More than 80 percent of the Matif's trading volume is in interest rate contracts. When monetary union starts, Paris would enjoy advantages giving it &quot;critical mass in euros,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The French treasury has already said it plans to start issuing its securities in euros as of 1999 and that it will convert the whole stock of existing securities into the Euro.</p>
<p>&quot;This will give the notionnel an underlying large criticial mass of securities denominated in euros,&quot; the Matif spokeswoman said. The notionnel is its flagship 10-year government bond contract, the second most heavily traded bond future in Europe after the German bund future traded on the London International Futures and Options Exchange, Europe's largest derivatives market.</p>
<p>Still, the Matif faces a struggle for dominance against LIFFE. Matif's total trading volume slid 24 percent last year and were flat in the seven months to July while LIFFE's volumes were up 20 percent.</p>
<p>The Matif has a working group developing a new strategy that will have its recommendations ready by year end.</p>
<p>&quot;It would have seemed more satisfactory from a strategic point of view to create a common platform, it would have been one less competitor if we had allied with Germany,&quot; said the Matif spokeswoman. &quot;But the risk to be taken to achieve this was was far too high.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
