<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2563" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Madrid stocks close a touch higher, eyeing Fed.</title>
<headline>Madrid stocks close a touch higher, eyeing Fed.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Madrid stocks managed a slight gain at the close on Tuesday, but trade was thin as the market kept a wary eye on the outcome of the U.S. Federal Reserve's open market committee.</p>
<p>The Fed is thought likely to leave rates unchanged. But regardless of its decision the prospect of Thursday's Bundesbank meeting should make sure volumes remain minimal for the next two days, with trading limited to a narrow range.</p>
<p>The general index rose 0.77 points, 0.22 percent, to 354.03 and the Ibex added 9.97 points, 0.25 percent, to 4,022.23.</p>
<p>Turnover totalled around 21 billion pesetas.</p>
<p>BBV climbed 70 pesetas to 5,230 after positive press reports on its Latin American investments, traders said.</p>
<p>Food retailer Pryca saw a sharp rise of 80 pesetas to 3,025 in busy trade amid talk that first half results, due to be announced in September, will be healthy dealers said.</p>
<p>Except for selected stocks trade was dull, with the extreme price swings characteristic of thin volume.</p>
<p>The tone is expected to remain similar at least until after the UK bank holiday on August 26.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
