<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2571" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Amer and Nokia help Finnish shares to 10-month high.</title>
<headline>Amer and Nokia help Finnish shares to 10-month high.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strong overseas demand for sporting goods group Amer and telecoms group Nokia's rise propelled the Finnish bourse to a 10-month high close on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The HEX all-share index rose 15 points or 0.7 percent to 2,101.2 -- the highest since October 19 last year. Turnover was a moderately lively 310 million markka with Amer grabbing a 16 percent slice and Nokia accounting for 14 percent.</p>
<p>Firm domestic government bonds also supported the stock market, brokers said.</p>
<p>The outlook was optimistic but cautious ahead of the outcome later on Tuesday of the United States Federal Reserve's (central bank) policy-setting meeting, they said.</p>
<p>Amer closed 8.70 markka higher at 108.90 after hitting a 21-month high 109.00 markka, up over eight percent, on strong overseas demand. Brokers could not give any clear reason for the advance.</p>
<p>Nokia closed 2.40 markka up at 180.10 helped by gains in its Swedish competitor Ericsson, brokers said. Paper machine maker Valmet also rose in lively trade boosted by improved third quarter profits for its competitor Harnischfeger. Valmet rose one markka to 73.20.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
