<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2574" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish shares end higher as Astra rebounds.</title>
<headline>Swedish shares end higher as Astra rebounds.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's share market closed with gains on Tuesday, getting a positive injection from the drugs sector as Astra rebounded and buoyed by overseas economic data.</p>
<p>The general index rose 0.81 percent to close at 1952.71 after shares valued at 2.9 billion crowns changed hands.</p>
<p>Brokers said the mood of the market was upbeat.</p>
<p>&quot;The reporting period has been much more positive than people expected,&quot; said one broker.</p>
<p>Market sentiment was boosted by U.S. June trade figures and Germany announcing a slowdown in M3 money supply growth.</p>
<p>Drug major Astra posted a seven crown gain, closing at 275 crowns, as it recovered some of its losses after posting a weaker-than-expected half year figure. The drug sector index rose 1.85 percent.</p>
<p>Blue chip telecoms group Ericsson was 2.5 crowns higher at 149.5 crowns.</p>
<p>Engineer Atlas Copco closed 1.5 crowns higher at 119.5 crowns after reporting a slightly higher than expected six month profit.</p>
<p>Mining and minerals company Trelleborg dropped 0.5 crowns to 85 crowns after weaker-than-hoped results.</p>
<p>The banking sector, however, slipped, ahead of a bout of half-year reports later this week with sector index losing 0.07 percent.</p>
<p>Nordbanken closed 1.5 crowns higher at 136.5 crowns, but both Handelsbanken and S-E-Banken were steady at 147.5 and 56.50 crowns respectively.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
