<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2580" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Unidanmark betters forecasts.</title>
<headline>Unidanmark betters forecasts.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN, Denmark</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unidanmark A/S, Denmark's second biggest banking group, posted better than expected first-half results Tuesday but said it foresaw slowing profits growth for the rest of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;A slightly lower rate of growth is anticipated in the Danish economy for 1996 compared with the previous year, although continuing an upward trend throughout the year,&quot; Unidanmark said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Operating profit in the second half of 1996 is projected to be lower than for the first half of the year,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Unidanmark announced a 1.275 billion crown ($221.5 million) pre-tax profit for the first half of the year, boosted by improved earnings from net interest, fees and lending. It earned 1.077 billion ($187.1 million) in the same period last year.</p>
<p>The bank attributed its advance to a 2.6 percent increase in net interest and fee income, lower losses and bad debt provisions, stable expenses and bigger extraordinary income.</p>
<p>Mortgage lending rose by nearly 30 percent and bank lending rose 7.4 percent, Unidanmark said.</p>
<p>Unidanmark was the second of Denmark's top banks to announce half-year results. On Monday BG Bank, the third biggest, posted a better-than-expected 821 million crown ($142.6 million) pre-tax profit, up from 738 million crowns ($128.2 million).</p>
<p>Denmark's biggest bank, Den Danske Bank, is to release its interim results Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN, Denmark"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
