<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2583" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: INTERVIEW-Kerry aims for 90 pct gearing at end-96.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Kerry aims for 90 pct gearing at end-96.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish food company Kerry Group Plc said on Tuesday that it had revised its end-year gearing target up to 90 percent from 70 percent following the acquisition in February of specialist fruit ingredients business Ciprial.</p>
<p>Kerry is aiming to cut its net debt to 328 million Irish pounds at end-1996 from 372 million at the half-year stage, a company spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>The group's debt-equity ratio, which soared to 120 percent following the $402 million acquisition of DCA Food Industries in late 1994, fell to 95 percent at end-1995.  </p>
<p>But it rose to 108 percent by June 30, 1996, mainly due to the 54 million punt purchase of Ciprial and the acquisition of the remaining equity in a joint venture between Solutech and DCA in Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;In the aftermath of the DCA acquisition we said we would take out 100 million Irish pound debt within a two-year period. We were well on target to do that,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Having bought Ciprial and with the Australian business, that increased our requirement by 59 million Irish pounds. So our revised target for the end of 1996 is 328 million punts,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
