<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2584" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Eridania up sharply on costs outlook.</title>
<headline>Eridania up sharply on costs outlook.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Eridania Beghin-Say rose around four percent on the Paris bourse on signs of cheaper raw material prices as well as a technical bounce, dealers said.</p>
<p>At 1334 GMT the stock was up 25 francs or 3.5 percent at 740 francs after surging as high as 749 francs.</p>
<p>U.S. corn prices have fallen by a third in the past month, putting pressure on corn (or maize) prices elsewhere and helping to reduce Eridania's key input cost for starch production.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, La Tribune Desfosses business daily highlighted a rebound in the Spanish olive oil harvest after two years of drought. It said this was likely to knock recently high prices.  </p>
<p>Several analysts called Eridania a buy for those prepared to weather what some say could be disappointing interim results.</p>
<p>&quot;The dividend is nice, the yield is attractive and the shareholders are solid. But the first-half results are going to be particularly bad which could provoke a few more share price reactions,&quot; predicted analyst Annie Bonal of Cholet Dupont.</p>
<p>Besides animal feed and olive oil, costs and margins for other branches of the agro-food group look less favourable and these are seen likely to weigh on earnings, analysts said.</p>
<p>Latest tests show French sugar yields are down this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
