<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2590" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Sweden's PLM lifts H1 profits.</title>
<headline>Sweden's PLM lifts H1 profits.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish beverage can maker PLM AB on Tuesday posted an increase in profits for the first six months of 1996, saying the improvement would be maintained for the rest of the year.</p>
<p>PLM, which was split out of investment group Industrivarden in November last year, reported an increase of just 10 million crowns ($1.5 million) in earnings after financial items to 229 million crowns.</p>
<p>However, the bottle, can and plastics maker said profits for the second quarter in isolation had risen 14 percent to 167 million crowns.</p>
<p>This improvement would last for the rest of the year, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite weaker market development in the early part of the summer, our existing forecast of a higher result after financial items for 1996 is unchanged,&quot; PLM said in its half-year report.</p>
<p>The company posted a 1995 profit after financial items of 519 million crowns.</p>
<p>In common with most Swedish exporters during the current interim report season, PLM said it had felt the effects of the stronger Swedish crown over the period.</p>
<p>Group sales, which fell slightly to 4.28 billion crowns for the first half year, would have increased by eight percent on the corresponding 1995 period at constant currency exchange rates, PLM said.</p>
<p>The weather was also partly to blame for the sales drop during the first six months, PLM said.</p>
<p>&quot;The poor early summer in Western Europea has led to weaker market development, particularly within the carbonated drink segment,&quot; PLM said, noting that the negative effect had ebbed in the second quarter. ($ = 6.611 Swedish Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
