<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2596" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Talks resume in German retail pay dispute.</title>
<headline>Talks resume in German retail pay dispute.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German retail workers' unions on Tuesday resumed regional talks with shopowners aimed at agreeing a wage and work hours deal to cope with the liberalisation of German shopping hours in November.</p>
<p>As the HDE retail industry association pleaded for a swift end to the deadlock on the talks, the HBV services union, in the second day of talks for North Rhine-Westphalia's 450,000 retail workers, said it was hopeful a deal could be struck.</p>
<p>Unions are pressing for broader adoption of a regional deal struck in Rhineland-Palatinate which called for workers to get a 1.85 percent wage rise plus 20 percent extra time in lieu per hour worked after 6:30 p.m. weekdays and 2:00 p.m. Saturdays.</p>
<p>Employers, hit by weak consumer spending, have baulked at accepting the Rhineland-Palatinate deal, and are particularly wary of the 20 percent allowance.</p>
<p>However HBV's chief negotiator for North Rhine-Westphalia, Gerhard Keuchel, said there were &quot;strong chances&quot; for agreement during Tuesday's talks taking place in the town of Marl.</p>
<p>Meanwhile HDE wages expert Guenther Wassmann urged unions to reach agreement with shopowners soon, thus ending four months of sporadic strike action which have affected shops and wholesalers throughout Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;This cannot drag on until the start of November,&quot; Wassmann said.</p>
<p>In Bavaria, the DAG white collar union suspended warning strikes ahead of the start of their tenth round of wage negotiations on Wednesday.</p>
<p>DAG representatives said they were confident of success and planned to suggest a compromise on the controversial 20 percent allowance but warned that strikes would resume indefinitiely if employers declined the offer.</p>
<p>In Berlin, wage talks resumed on Tuesday morning for the region's 87,500 retail workers. Union representatives said they planned to seek an overall pay rise of five percent, to be applicable in east German states as well, in addition to the shop hours deal</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
