<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2611" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares steady, M3 fails to provide push.</title>
<headline>German shares steady, M3 fails to provide push.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's blue-chip DAX index opened stable on Tuesday, supported by money supply data viewed as boosting the case for an interest rate cut this week.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX was up 1.53 points at 2,564.29 points at 0849 GMT and was expected to hold steady around that level through the day, with order volumes relatively thin.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not opening up any big positions,&quot; a Frankfurt trader said.</p>
<p>The market got an early boost when July M3 money supply data, released early in the morning, showed a slowdown in the monthly growth to 8.6 percent from 9.6 percent -- a figure which could support the case for a cut this week in the securities repurchase rate, or repo.</p>
<p>However the data failed to generate new momentum in the share market and dealers noted that a repo rate cut was generally already priced in.</p>
<p>&quot;What we really need is a dollar above 1.50 (marks) to give us a new impulse,&quot; said another dealer.</p>
<p>Blue chip stocks were mixed, with utility stocks the clear winners of the day while chemicals faded from popularity.</p>
<p>Dealers said investors were shifting into utilities from the chemicals sector.</p>
<p>Diversified utility Viag AG, which is expected to release six-month earnings on Tuesday, was up 3.20 marks at 568 marks and RWE AG was up 85 pfennigs at 55.35.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Bayer AG was down 67 pfennigs at 52.05 marks and BASF AG was down 25 pfennigs at 42.70 marks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
