<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2612" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German SPD calls for cut in Bundesbank rates.</title>
<headline>German SPD calls for cut in Bundesbank rates.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A cut in German interest rates is overdue, said Ingrid Matthaeus Maier, deputy parliamentary leader of the opposition Social Democrats on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;In view of the nearly four million officially registered unemployed and the anaemic recovery, a cut in interest rates by the Bundesbank is overdue,&quot; Maier said in a statement released ahead of Thursday's central bank council meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;Business and consumers are waiting for such a signal.&quot;</p>
<p>Stable prices and moderate wage agreements have eliminated any fear of reigniting inflation, and low interest rates should be the reward for wage restraint, she said.</p>
<p>A cut in interest rates would stimulate demand for capital and consumer goods, and benefit German exports as well, she said.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank last cut its discount rate on April 19, to a historic low 2.5 percent. It has kept its main money market rate, the repo rate, fixed at 3.3 percent since February.</p>
<p>Markets widely expect some cut in the repo rate at Thursday's meeting.</p>
<p>-- Terence Gallagher, Bonn newsroom, 49 228 2609750</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
