<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2617" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Analysts see uphill struggle for Volvo.</title>
<headline>Analysts see uphill struggle for Volvo.</headline>
<byline>Paul de Bendern</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The near-term fortunes of Swedish car maker AB Volvo, due to post its half-year results on Wednesday, are gloomy as the group battles with falling market share and higher costs, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The European car side is very disappointing, and Volvo has not yet achieved the volumes for the new small cars (S40/V40) that it expected, so it's going to be looking pretty grim,&quot; industry analyst Robert Barber of James Capel told Reuters.</p>
<p>Analysts polled by Reuters forecast a fall in Volvo's pre-tax earnings to 3.37 billion crowns for the first half of 1996 compared with 3.80 billion crowns for the corresponding period last year.</p>
<p>In its first quarter report, Volvo said operating income would be hit by the launch of new car and truck models as well as continuing investment in product and market development.</p>
<p>However, analysts rejected the idea that Volvo's falling profits are mainly due to a generation shift in the car and truck operations.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not all down to difficulties in the production of their new car...they're also losing some market share,&quot; Barber said.</p>
<p>Barber said Volvo's forecast that its European car sales will rise in the second half of 1996 is questionable in the light of a 20 percent slump in European new car registrations.</p>
<p>Total European car sales rose six percent over the first seven months of the year, but Volvo saw its seven-month registrations figure fall 14.6 percent to 114,894 cars.</p>
<p>The Swedish manufacturer's woes were compounded by a slump of no less than 35 percent in July sales, bringing its European market share to a modest 1.5 percent.</p>
<p>In the United States, Volvo's Truck division has been hardest hit. Intense competition and a fall in total volumes have cut Volvo sales by 31 percent in the first half of 1996 with only 9,300 trucks sold compared with 13,500 a year ago.</p>
<p>Some analysts see last week's replacement of Volvo Trucks' top management in the United States -- just a week before the half-year report -- as a sign of panic.</p>
<p>Sales have also fared badly in South America with a drop of 50 percent to 2,350 trucks, mainly due to a decline in the Brazilian market, which accounts for 70 percent of sales in the region.</p>
<p>Analysts were divided on whether Volvo Trucks' shrinking market share is wholly due to the launch of a new model range in the autumn.</p>
<p>Bjorn Germer of Sweden's Matteus stockbrokers said he did not believe the launch of a new model was the only reason for Volvo Truck's recent misfortunes.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone knows the North American market is poor right now for Volvo, we want to see (in the half-year report) how bad the sitution is there,&quot; Germer said.</p>
<p>BZW analyst Philip Ayton said the eyes of the market would be firmly on the trucks division when Volvo presents its half-year report on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;North America has been flat for cars, terrible for trucks and there's been a change of management. I don't know if that's an indication of something a lot worse in way of earnings but clearly the American truck business is in loss and has probably worsened,&quot; Ayton said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
