<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2619" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German money supply growth slows in July.</title>
<headline>German money supply growth slows in July.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German money supply growth, the German central bank's main policy guide, slowed to an annualised 8.6 percent in July from 9.6 percent in June, the Bundesbank said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Analysts polled by Reuters had predicted seasonally-adjusted, annualised July M3 growth in a range of 8.5 to 9.2 percent. Forecasts averaged 8.8 percent. The July figure remains well above a seven percent target ceiling.  </p>
<p>The German share market showed little reaction to the figure. In the bond market, where traders had become increasingly optimistic that the figure would come in below forecast, bund futures eased marginally.</p>
<p>But analysts generally warmed to the figure, saying it reinforced their expectations that the Bundesbank's main money market rate, the repo rate, could be eased soon, possibly as early as this week's Bundesbank council meeting.</p>
<p>Uwe Angenendt, economist at BHF-Bank in Frankfurt, said in an initial reaction: &quot;Monetary expansion has slowed considerably. This is a very good sign for the Bundesbank on Thursday. I expect a repo rate cut of 10 to 20 basis points.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
