<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2621" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: OMV H1 pre-tax up 4 pct, says on track to match '95.</title>
<headline>OMV H1 pre-tax up 4 pct, says on track to match '95.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austria's largest industrial group, OMV, reported on Tuesday a four percent rise in first half pre-tax profit and said it was on target to repeat 1995's record result despite expectations of a weaker second half.</p>
<p>In a statement released ahead of a news conference, the oil and chemicals group said it posted a 1.56-billion-schilling pre-tax profit in the first six months, up from 1.50 billion the previous year. Net profit was flat at 1.24 billion.</p>
<p>Earnings before interest and tax (EBIT) eased six percent to 1.51 billion schillings, in line with analysts' forecasts of 1.25 billion to 1.7 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;For the full year we expect a satisfactory group result which should match last year. The second half, like last year, will be characterised by weaker results,&quot; OMV said.</p>
<p>In 1995, the firm posted a record pre-tax profit of 2.09 billion schillings and 2.19 billion schillings EBIT.</p>
<p>Gas remained by far the biggest contributor to group earnings in the first half. EBIT was stable at 0.91 billion schillings despite a three percent decline in sales to 5.36 billion.</p>
<p>Chemicals earnings jumped 17 percent to 0.34 billion schillings, helped by stable prices and lower fertiliser costs. Sales dropped 38 percent to 2.63 billion schillings following the sale of 70 percent of OMV's Chemie Linz unit.</p>
<p>Exploration and production achieved a turnaround, posting a 0.11-billion-schilling profit after last year's 0.12-billion-schilling loss. OMV traced the upswing to higher crude oil prices and restructuring.</p>
<p>Marketing also returned to profit with an EBIT of 0.02 billion schillings after a loss of 0.06 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>In contrast, OMV's refining and plastics operations reported a poor performance.</p>
<p>Low petrochemical prices squeezed refining margins and lay behind a 76 percent drop in EBIT to 0.10 billion schillings. Plastics earnings dived 41 percent to 0.24 billion schillings, also hit by tight margins.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
