<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2624" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Wella sees 96 profit outpacing sales rise.</title>
<headline>Wella sees 96 profit outpacing sales rise.</headline>
<dateline>DARMSTADT, Germany 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German haircare products manufacturer Wella AG said on Tuesday it expected full-year 1996 sales to rise by a nominal seven to 10 percent, with earnings likely to rise at a stronger pace.</p>
<p>The company said operating profit jumped 25 percent to 61 million marks in the first six months of the year, with sales up 11.3 percent at 1.818 billion marks.  </p>
<p>Pre-tax profit totalled 61 million marks, down from 83 million marks in the year-earlier period, but Wella said the year-earlier figure contained 35 million marks of extraordinary income from the dissolution of provisions no longer required.</p>
<p>&quot;We are anticipating a continuation of the positive business develpoment in the second half of 1996,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on present foreign currency situation the nominal increase in sales should be between seven and 10 percent.&quot; Operating earnings would exceed that growth rate, Wella said.</p>
<p>First-half sales rise of 11.3 percent outstripped market growth of less than three percent. Wella said it had not included non-core business in the first-half accounts becuase of restructuring measures. On a comparable sales basis, sales would have risen 12.2 percent, the company said.</p>
<p>Wella also said it achieved an increase of 7.9 percent in sales to hairdressers despite a stagnating hairdressing market. That exceeded a planned sales increase of five percent.</p>
<p>Sales of haircare products to retailers jumped 21.3 percent, well above expectations. Sales of scents and cosmetics rose 12.4 percent in the first half due to successful product launches.</p>
<p>Domestic sales were 574 million marks versus 533 million, while sales abroad rose to 1.24 billion marks from 1.1 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DARMSTADT, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
