<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2627" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India to speed up private investment in power.</title>
<headline>India to speed up private investment in power.</headline>
<byline>Sunil Kataria</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>India would try to put 145 private sector proposals to build power plants in a &quot;fast track&quot; category for government approval, along the lines of seven units now in the pipeline, a senior official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;All the fast track projects would be cleared by September 30,&quot; Power Secretary P. Abraham, the most senior civil servant in the power department, told a meeting of U.S. and Indian representatives on the energy sector.</p>
<p>India, which wants major foreign investment to meet a huge power shortfall, had marked eight proposals it considered as practically viable for &quot;fast track&quot; approval with federal guarantees to lure billions of dollars in investment.</p>
<p>One of the companies later withdrew, saying it did not need a federal government guarantee to ensure payments for the power it produced.</p>
<p>&quot;The power sector is the story of the '90s with respect to Indo-U.S relations,&quot; said Dirk Forrister, head of the U.S. delegation said.</p>
<p>Industry estimates say that India, which has an installed capacity of 87,000 megawatts per year, would have an additional demand for 142,000 megawatts by 2007.</p>
<p>State-owned companies and the non-conventional sector are expected to contribute a total of 55,000 megawatts, and an investment of $223 billion is estimated to be necessary to make up the shortfall.</p>
<p>Indian opened up its power the sector under an economic reform programme launched in 1991. U.S. firms Enron Corp and CMS Energy Corp have been front-runners among foreign power generation firms making use of India's open-door policies.</p>
<p>&quot;The new government is very keen to streamline the programmes to speed up the process,&quot; Abraham said.</p>
<p>He added the government was also in the process of reforming unprofitable state-run electricity boards. Their financial health has raised doubts among foreign investors who would have to sell electricity to the boards.</p>
<p>&quot;Electricity boards need to become better paymasters and steps are being taken to make electricity boards more viable to foreign investment,&quot; Abraham said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
