<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2629" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Domestic funds help Bombay shares recover.</title>
<headline>Domestic funds help Bombay shares recover.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bombay shares recovered part of their losses on Tuesday helped by domestic institutional demand after the market plunged on Monday, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a combination of local fund buying and short covering,&quot; one trader said, referring to the gains. &quot;We'll have to wait till tomorrow to see where the market is headed.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the close of weekly account on the NSE halted speculative selling and forced short covering, but the undercurrent was shaky.</p>
<p>The 30-share BSE index closed 33.89 points higher at a provisional 3,315.38 after plummeting 101.26 on Monday.</p>
<p>Traders said foreign institutional investors (FIIs) continued to sell shares of SBI, the country's largest commercial bank, which has plans to issue global depositary receipts (GDRs) for up to $500 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The GDRs are priced on the basis of the underlying stock on the BSE,&quot; one trader said. &quot;The FIIs stand to benefit if they can pick up the GDRs cheaply.&quot;</p>
<p>However, SBI stock ended 2.25 rupees higher at 266.25 helped by reports it would benefit by 2.0 billion rupees in excess depreciation on government securities in 1995/96 (April-March), he said.</p>
<p>The 50-share NSE index edged up 3.71 points to a provisional 979.71.</p>
<p>Local fund buying helped TISCO gain 3.25 rupees at 183.75, TELCO 10.0 at 465 and BSES 3.50 at 180.50.</p>
<p>Bajaj Auto rallied 17.50 rupees to 990, Hindalco 12.0 to 950, Indian Hotels 9.50 to 767.50, Ranbaxy 8.50 to 608.75, Hind Lever 8.0 to 826.75, Reliance 6.0 to 201 and ITC 4.0 to 286.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
