<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2631" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka Ceramic in rapid turnaround.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka Ceramic in rapid turnaround.</headline>
<byline>Prithi Kodagoda</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lanka Ceramic, once a big player in Sri Lanka's domestic market but plagued with labour and other problems, is making a rapid turnaround, managing director Jagath Peiris said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The company suffered a crippling strike and a nine-month shutdown at its Piliyandala factory in suburban Colombo. The strike was resolved after the company pruned its workforce.</p>
<p>&quot;Piliyandala has been operating again since January 1996. We have also begun to motivate labour, and started aggressive export marketing,&quot; said Peiris, who came to Lanka Ceramic in May 1995 from Dankotuwa Porcelain, where he was managing director.</p>
<p>Lanka Ceramic has two other factories outside the capital.</p>
<p>Management structures were being changed in all factories and at Colombo's head office to make them more flexible and responsive, Peiris said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are getting on track and you will see results in 18 months to two years because there are no quick fixes.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts expect net profits of around 45 million rupees (about $818,000) for the half year to June 30, an increase from 17 million rupees (about $310,000) in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Our 12-month forecasts for the company are 73.8 million rupees ($1.34 million), but we are reviewing the figures in line with new developments,&quot; said Avanka Herath, an analyst at brokerage Jardine Fleming.</p>
<p>Lanka Ceramic's net profit in 1995 was 39.56 million rupees (about $720,000).</p>
<p>The company is working to regain its local market share. It was a state-owned monopoly venture before 1992.</p>
<p>Local market share eroded when Sri Lankans developed a taste for porcelain in preference to ceramics.</p>
<p>&quot;This happened because we also sell other people's porcelain through our network of 200 dealers and 14 shops,&quot; Peiris said. &quot;Naturally, our sales staff earned more commissions by selling pricey porcelain than our own less expensive ceramics.&quot;</p>
<p>The company now motivates sales staff by offering more incentives to sell Lanka Ceramic products.</p>
<p>Peiris said an average monthly wage of 2,700 rupees is inadequate in comparison to 7,000 rupees at Dankotuwa Porcelain, the star among Sri Lanka's five listed ceramic companies.</p>
<p>&quot;We have compiled an export marketing-linked productivity incentive for the workforce to motivate them to manufacture exportable products,&quot; said Peiris.</p>
<p>Peiris has re-established contacts with foreign buyers from his time at Dankotuwa.</p>
<p>&quot;We are doing many new self-coloured, printed and hand-painted items to fall in line with what these buyers from Italy, Spain, France, USA and Netherlands want,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The company aims to export five containers a month in November and December and fine-tune production and management systems.</p>
<p>Lanka Ceramic was privatised and listed in Colombo in 1992. The major shareholder, Uniwalkers, a local electronics firm, controls 35 percent, Noritake of Japan and the Sri Lanka government 18 percent each, and the public 29 percent.</p>
<p>The share was last traded at 25.50 a 10-rupee share.</p>
<p>(1$ = 55 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
