<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2636" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: RUGBY UNION-NEW ZEALAND BATTLE THROUGH THE DELUGE TO 31-0 WIN.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-NEW ZEALAND BATTLE THROUGH THE DELUGE TO 31-0 WIN.</headline>
<dateline>POTCHEFSTROOM, South Africa 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand's second string recorded their biggest win of the tour with a 31-0 victory over Western Transvaal (halftime 12-0) in atrocious conditions on Tuesday.</p>
<p>More than 80 percent of the pitch was covered in standing water when the teams ran out after torrential rain and hail lashed the ground for two hours before kickoff.</p>
<p>The warmup game had to be abandoned midway through the second half as the players were pelted by hail and the ground turned white.</p>
<p>Western Transvaal captain, Eugene Hare, who holds the record number of appearances for the province, said afterwards: &quot;I have never seen conditions like this.&quot;</p>
<p>The All Blacks responded superbly to the conditions and scored five tries -- all through their backs -- to put behind them the struggles they had in overcoming Boland and Western Province in their previous midweek matches.</p>
<p>However, winger Jonah Lomu looks no nearer a return to the test team. He completed his second 80 minutes of the tour but frequently limped heavily on his left knee.</p>
<p>The New Zealand tries came from Ofisa Tonu'u, Matthew Cooper, Eric Rush, Alama Ieremia and Carlos Spencer. </p>
<p>Teams (15 to 1):</p>
<p>Western Transvaal: Dewald Basson (D.P. Swart, 65th); Wynand Lourens, Fanie Heymans, Tony Lincoln, Carl Bensch; A.J. de Jager, Eugene Hare (captain); Kleinjan Tromp, Joe Beukes, Ronald Ferreira, Gerhard Laufs, Lukas Swart, Rocco Peddar (Hanro van der Merwe, 40), Leon Boshoff (Rodney Mitchell, 53), Andre Coetzer (Tenk Hendriks 40).</p>
<p>New Zealand: Matthew Cooper; Eric Rush, Tabai Matson, Alama Ieremia, Jonah Lomu; Carlos Spencer, Ofisa Tonu'u; Taine Randell (captain), Chresten Davis, Andrew Blowers (Todd Blackadder, 66), Glenn Taylor, Blair Larsen, Phil Coffin, Norman Hewitt (Anton Oliver, 64), Mark Allen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="POTCHEFSTROOM, South Africa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
