<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2641" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-CHANG WINS OPENER AT HAMLET CUP.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-CHANG WINS OPENER AT HAMLET CUP.</headline>
<dateline>COMMACK, New York 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top seed Michael Chang came off a week's rest and handily beat unseeded David Prinosil of Germany 6-1 6-3 on Monday in the opening round of the Waldbaum Hamlet Cup tennis tournament.</p>
<p>Chang, ranked third in the world, needed only 68 minutes to eliminate Prinosil, ranked 64th.</p>
<p>Chang opened a 3-0 lead and closed the match by taking the last four games.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a good match for me and it felt good playing on a Monday for a change,&quot; Chang said. &quot;My schedule was planned this way to give me a rest before the Hamlet and let me get some good matches and go right into the U.S. Open.&quot;</p>
<p>Chang said planned rests during the ATP hard court circuit had been successful. He won 14 successive matches, taking titles in Washington and Los Angeles before losing a final in Cincinnati to Andre Agassi last week.</p>
<p>A pair of players from Morocco, Younes El Aynaoui, the sixth seed, and Hicham Arazi, unseeded, posted first-round victories.</p>
<p>El Aynaoui, top-ranked in his home country for the past six years, beat Nicolas Lapentti of Ecuador 6-4 6-3.</p>
<p>Arazi, a slightly built lefthander who is playing his first year on the ATP Tour, upset eighth-seeded Magnus Larsson of Sweden, 6-3 2-6 6-4.</p>
<p>Arazi, who has steadily climbed from a ranking of 1,093rd in 1991 to a current 82nd, tenaciously fought off Larsson, who failed to convert 10 of 12 break points.</p>
<p>Larsson, who ranked 10th before suffering a fractured foot last year and was out of action five months, is now ranked 59th.</p>
<p>&quot;It takes time to work back into shape. It shakes your confidence,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Arazi, who qualified for the U.S. Open last year and lost a four-set first-rounder to Ukrainian Andrei Medvedev, said he is playing with confidence.</p>
<p>&quot;I beat Medvedev in Bologna this year,&quot; he said. &quot;It felt good. Now I'm going to get into the U.S. Open main draw with my ranking. I want to win my first match and then take it day by day.&quot;</p>
<p>In beating Larsson, Arazi overcame three doublefaults to hold service in a 14-point game and stay 2-all in the third set. He then broke Larsson and protected service from 0-30 and 30-all down the stretch.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COMMACK, New York"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
