<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2643" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-TOSHIBA RUNNER-UP LISA RAYMOND BOUNCED IN FIRST ROUND. [CORRECTED 03:25 GMT]</title>
<headline>TENNIS-TOSHIBA RUNNER-UP LISA RAYMOND BOUNCED IN FIRST ROUND. [CORRECTED 03:25 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>CARLSBAD, California 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lisa Raymond, runner-up last year at the Toshiba Tennis Classic, was bounced out in the first round this year when Sweden's Asa Carlsson dismissed her 6-4 6-0 on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;I haven't won that many matches this year, so this one feels good,&quot; said Carlsson, who improved to 10-14 this year with the 63-minute sweep.</p>
<p>Carlsson used a steady ground attack to keep the unseeded American on the run and off-balance throughout the straight-sets victory.</p>
<p>&quot;I played very relaxed, I played confident from the baseline, and she never found a rhythm,&quot; the 21-year-old Swede said. &quot;I'm happy.&quot;</p>
<p>Raymond had a career-high 17th world ranking last year but her ranking has plummeted to 49 along with her confidence.</p>
<p>&quot;I wasn't playing with much confidence out there,&quot; Raymond said. &quot;I couldn't get into a groove the whole time.&quot;</p>
<p>In other opening-round matches, Naoko Sawatsu of Japan beat Sabine Hack of Germany 7-6 (7-5) 6-3 and Shi-Ting Wang of Taiwan ousted Miriam Oremans of the Netherlands 6-1 6-4.</p>
<p>Sixteen-year-old sensation Venus Williams of the United States hammered out a 7-5 6-3 victory over German Barbara Rittner to gain entry to the main draw. She will face Katarina Studenikova of Slovakia on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Olympic silver medallist Arantxa Sanchez-Vicario and defending champion Conchita Martinez are the top seeds in the 28-player, $450,000 event, the final hardcourt tuneup for next week's U.S. Open.</p>
<p>The two Spaniards have first-round byes. Martinez plays her first match Tuesday and Sanchez-Vicario opens on Wednesday. (Corrects to reflect schedule change).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARLSBAD, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
