<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2649" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-COUNTIES REJECT MOVE TO GIVE SELECTORS GREATER CONTROL.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-COUNTIES REJECT MOVE TO GIVE SELECTORS GREATER CONTROL.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>County cricket clubs on Tuesday rejected a move to give England selectors greater control over their international players.</p>
<p>A clause in the recent Acfield Report recommended that the selection committee chairman should be able to withdraw England players from county matches in order to rest top talent.</p>
<p>But on Tuesday that was the only one of the 14 Acfield clauses to be thrown out at a Test and County Cricket Board meeting at Lords, although the board hierarchy was assured requests to rest a player would receive &quot;a sympathetic ear.&quot;</p>
<p>The seven-man Acfield committee put forward in-depth proposals earlier this year for streamlining the selection of English teams.</p>
<p>TCCB chief executive Tim Lamb said: &quot;The Acfield working party will be disappointed, but deep down in their heart of hearts they probably knew it would not get agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>Tuesday's meeting also rejected a move to have overseas players banned from English cricket in 1999 and 2000 on a trial basis and decided that in future all test matches will include Sunday play, with no rest day.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
