<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2652" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-SUSSEX PLAYER BANNED FOR COCAINE USE.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-SUSSEX PLAYER BANNED FOR COCAINE USE.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>English cricketer Ed Giddins was suspended from the first-class game until the start of the 1998 season on Tuesday after being found guilty of taking cocaine.</p>
<p>The Test and County Cricket Board (TCCB) said it had barred the 25-year-old Sussex fast bowler from playing any match under its jurisdiction until April 1, 1998.</p>
<p>The TCCB found him guilty on three charges: that he had a prohibitive substance in a urine sample, that he knowlingly used a prohibitive substance and that he behaved in a manner which may bring the game into disrepute.</p>
<p>&quot;In considering the appropriate penalty to be imposed, the committee took account of the fact that the prohibitive substance was identified as cocaine, regarding in law as a class A drug,&quot; the board said in a statement.</p>
<p>The ban takes immediate effect. Giddens has 14 days to appeal.</p>
<p>Giddens, who toured Pakistan with England A last winter, tested positive for an illegal substance after a county match against Kent in May. A second test also proved positive. His case went to a hearing which was adjourned on Monday after more than four hours.</p>
<p>On Tuesday Giddens was whisked away from the hearing after just 20 minutes, telling reporters: &quot;I've absolutely nothing to say. I wish I could.&quot;</p>
<p>The only known previous case of an English cricketer testing positive was Yorkshire bowler Richard Stemp. The TCCB accepted Stemp's explanation that his drink had been spiked.</p>
<p>But the board committee rejected Giddins's claim that he had taken the drug inadvertently, although it accepted there was no evidence Giddins had taken the drug more than once.</p>
<p>It said the use of an illegal drug &quot;was a grave breach of regulations which was not only likely to bring the game into disrepute but which had the potential to put at risk the safety of fellow players and officials.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Cricket, its players and administrators, would not tolerate in its ranks those who indulge in the use of a prohibited drug. The committee was sure the public would demand nothing less,&quot; the statement said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
