<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2655" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: TENNIS-WOODBRIDGE BEATS DOUBLES PARTNER WOODFORDE AT CANADIAN.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-WOODBRIDGE BEATS DOUBLES PARTNER WOODFORDE AT CANADIAN.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Mark Woodforde, the 15th seed, was beaten Monday by compatriot and long-time doubles partner Todd Woodbridge in the first round of the Canadian Open.</p>
<p>Woodbridge, ranked 43rd in the world, defeated Woodforde, ranked 30th, 6-3 7-5. Woodforde was one of two seeded players to lose on the opening day of the tournament.</p>
<p>Tenth-seeded Arnaud Boetsch of France was upset by unseeded Andrea Gaudenzi of Italy 3-6 7-5 6-2.</p>
<p>Alberto Berasategui of Spain, seeded 11th, needed just 50 minutes to dispatch 50th-ranked Filip Dewulf of Belgium 6-4 6-0 and another Spaniard, unseeded Alex Corretja, defeated France's Guy Forget 6-3 3-6 6-3.</p>
<p>Corretja, ranked 32nd, plays sixth-seeded American MaliVai Washington in the second round. Washington and the rest of the top eight seeds were given first-round byes.</p>
<p>Australian Patrick Rafter survived a hotly contested opening set against Spain's Carlos Costa and won 7-6 (8-6) 6-2.</p>
<p>Woodbridge has beaten Woodforde in their last four meetings and holds a 5-2 career advantage.</p>
<p>Top-seeded in the doubles at the Canadian Open and ranked first in the world, the Australian pair are Olympic gold medallists and four-time defending champions at Wimbledon.</p>
<p>&quot;We hate it when we play each other,&quot; Woodforde said of their singles matchup. &quot;We're both nervous because we respect each other and appreciate each other's games.&quot;</p>
<p>Woodbridge had a double-break point to lead 3-0 in the second set after taking the first set with a service break in the eighth game.</p>
<p>But Woodforde saved both break points and then won four games in a row, capitalising on three Woodbridge double faults in the sixth game to go ahead 4-2.</p>
<p>&quot;When Mark got up 4-2 and started to be more aggressive, I got a little tentative,&quot; Woodbridge said. &quot;I was lucky to get back to 4-4 straightaway. Mark let me back in that second set with a couple of errors.&quot;</p>
<p>The Corretja-Forget match, played on the hard-court surface at the National Tennis Centre in Toronto, featured many exciting and extended rallies.</p>
<p>&quot;He didn't play well in the first set but then he played better in the second set and I began to doubt myself,&quot; said Corretja.</p>
<p>&quot;Then I played an unbelievable game, three passing shots and a topspin lob, to break him for 5-3 in the third set.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;He hit four winners and played a perfect game to break me so I can't be too upset,&quot; said the 58th-ranked Forget, who was playing his first match in a month after a back ailment.</p>
<p>Corretja and Forget are two of a record 36 Europeans in the 56-player Canadian Open field.</p>
<p>With this year's tournament date changed from late July to a week before the U.S. Open because of the Olympics, the Europeans were more inclined to play in Toronto in order to get ready for Flushing Meadows.</p>
<p>However, the top four Americans -- Pete Sampras, Michael Chang, Andre Agassi and Jim Courier, regulars at this ATP Tour Super Nine event -- have decided to skip it this year.</p>
<p>The tournament's top seed is second-ranked Thomas Muster of Austria.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
