<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2659" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: ATHLETICS-IAAF CONSIDERS CHANGE TO DRUG BAN RULES.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-IAAF CONSIDERS CHANGE TO DRUG BAN RULES.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Amateur Athletic Federation may strip national bodies of their powers to punish drug cheats, a senior IAAF official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>IAAF general secretary Istvan Gyulai said the sport's world ruling body would consider amending its rules to centralise the process of sentencing athletes who return positive dope tests.</p>
<p>Two athletes -- Australian sprinter Dean Capobianco and Italian high jumper Antonella Bevilacqua  -- were allowed to compete at the Atlanta Olympics after failing drugs tests before the Games.</p>
<p>&quot;When we faced the Capobianco case in Atlanta we came to the conclusion our rules would probably have to be amended,&quot; Gyulai told a news conference in Sydney ahead of the world junior championships starting on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Asked if this meant the IAAF assuming the right to suspend athletes, Gyulai said: &quot;If necessary, yes&quot;.</p>
<p>Both Capobianco and Bevilacqua were freed to compete in Atlanta after lodging appeals with their respective national bodies, as allowed under current IAAF rules.</p>
<p>Capobianco tested positive for the steroid stanozolol at a meeting in the Dutch town of Hengelo in May but an Athletics Australia tribunal dismissed the charge, citing flaws in the testing process.</p>
<p>Bevilacqua was caught twice with the banned stimulant ephedrine in her body in May. An Italian athletics panel decided she had taken the drug by mistake and did not impose the usual three-month ban.</p>
<p>The IAAF said in Atlanta last month they decided not to ban the two athletes from the Olympics because they said they feared being taken to court and sued.</p>
<p>Instead, the cases were referred to the International Olympic Committee's Court of Arbitration for Sport (CAS).</p>
<p>Gyulai described the IAAF's case against Capobianco as watertight but added the federation would abide by the CAS's decision, which he said would be &quot;final and binding&quot;.</p>
<p>Athletics Australia president David Prince said the CAS hearing was likely to be held in Monte Carlo next month.</p>
<p>Bevilacqua's case is due to go to an arbitration hearing and her Atlanta result may be cancelled if it goes against her.</p>
<p>She came fourth in the high jump in Atlanta. On her return to Italy she said she would not be competing again this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
