<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2660" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: GOLF-ALLENBY SELECTED AS CAPTAIN'S CHOICE.</title>
<headline>GOLF-ALLENBY SELECTED AS CAPTAIN'S CHOICE.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE, Australia 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>President's Cup international team captain Peter Thomson on Tuesday named Australian Robert Allenby as one of his two nominated players to face the United States next month.</p>
<p>Thomson said fellow Australians Peter Senior and Wayne Riley were chasing the final spot in his 12-man team for the Ryder Cup-style team event in Washington from September 13-15.</p>
<p>But both Senior and Riley could make the team if Japan's Jumbo Ozaki decides not to take up his automatic invitation, Thomson said.</p>
<p>The international team will feature the top 10 available non-Europeans in the world rankings plus two players selected by Thomson.</p>
<p>Five-times British Open champion Thomson has yet to confirm his team after replacing fellow Australian David Graham as non-playing captain last month.</p>
<p>Thomson said Allenby would play as an automatic selection if Ozaki, ranked six in the world, did not play, freeing places for both Riley and Senior.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect to hear from Jumbo this week,&quot; Thomson said.</p>
<p>World number one Greg Norman, fellow Australian Steve Elkington, Zimbabwe's Nick Price and Ernie Els of South Africa are expected to lead the international team's challenge.</p>
<p>The Americans won the inaugural President's Cup in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
