<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2661" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-CAMINITI GRAND SLAM LEADS PADRES PAST EXPOS.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-CAMINITI GRAND SLAM LEADS PADRES PAST EXPOS.</headline>
<dateline>SAN DIEGO 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ken Caminiti hit a grand slam in the first inning and added a two-run single in the second and Scott Sanders carried a no-hitter into the seventh as the San Diego Padres coasted past the Montreal Expos 7-3 Monday.</p>
<p>Caminiti blasted a 1-1 pitch over the right-centre field wall for his career-high 27th home run and fourth career grand slam. It was his second grand slam this season.</p>
<p>Caminiti has been suffering from a case of dehydration and received treatment earlier in the day.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm trying not to do too much at the plate,&quot; Caminiti said. &quot;I'm just trying to hit the ball and stay back on the pitches. I'm actually thinking opposite field. It's great to be home, it's the first night in a while I got any sleep.&quot;</p>
<p>The Padres, playing their first true home game since August 4, have won three of four following a three-game losing streak. San Diego completed a three-game series against the Mets in Monterrey, Mexico, on Sunday.</p>
<p>Sanders (6-4) held Montreal hitless through the first six innings, allowing only a one-out walk to Darrin Fletcher in the second. But with two out in the seventh, Fletcher singled sharply to right.</p>
<p>&quot;Anytime I can get a lead that early it's great,&quot; Sanders said. &quot;I just go out there and throw strikes.</p>
<p>&quot;I honestly didn't know (about the no-hitter), it's probably better that I didn't. When everybody cheered me in the seventh after the hit by Fletcher, I was wondering what was going on. When I got back and saw the hit on the board I knew.&quot;</p>
<p>Sanders gave up two runs and three hits with one walk and eight strikeouts over eight innings.</p>
<p>Pedro Martinez (10-8) took the loss.</p>
<p>The Padres took a half-game lead over the idle Los Angeles Dodgers in the National League West with the victory.</p>
<p>Dave Silvestri hit a two-run homer for the Expos, who have dropped four of five.</p>
<p>In Chicago, Kevin Brown pitched seven scoreless innings and Gary Sheffield and Devon White each drove in a pair of runs as the Florida Marlins snapped a three-game losing streak with a 4-3 victory over the Cubs.</p>
<p>Brown (12-10) allowed four hits, struck out eight and walked none to lower his major league-leading earned run average to 1.90. Brown posted his 100th career victory.</p>
<p>Robb Nen recorded the final five outs for his 25th save.</p>
<p>Amaury Telemaco (5-7) gave up three runs and three hits before leaving with shoulder stiffness with one out in the second. Four Cubs relievers combined to allow one run and four hits thereafter.</p>
<p>Sammy Sosa blasted a two-run homer, his career-best 40th of the season. It is the 12th time a Cub has hit that many, the last being Ryne Sandberg (40) in 1990.</p>
<p>In Houston, Sean Berry's bases-loaded walk from Ramon Morel (2-1) with one out in the bottom of the 13th forced home Brian Hunter, who had led off with a double, to give the Astros a 2-1 squeaker over the Pittsburgh Pirates.</p>
<p>Alvin Morman (2-1) pitched a scoreless 13th for the Astros, who have won seven of their last 11 games.</p>
<p>Pittsburgh took a 1-0 lead in the sixth on a solo homer by Jeff King, his 24th. The Astros tied the game an inning later when third baseman Charlie Hayes' throwing error allowed Hunter to score.</p>
<p>Houston set team records by drawing 14 walks and leaving 20 runners on base.</p>
<p>In San Francisco, Marvin Benard hit a game-tying homer and Tom Lampkin singled home Barry Bonds, who had singled and stolen second, for the go-ahead run in the seventh to lift the Giants to a 5-4 victory over the New York Mets.</p>
<p>Rod Beck came on in the ninth and gave up one-out singles to Bernard Gilkey and Todd Hundley, putting them on first and third. But Beck notched his 27th save by inducing Carlos Baerga to hit into a game-ending double play.</p>
<p>Bonds hit his 35th homer, a three-run shot, in the first. It was the third straight game in which Bonds homered in the first, the second time Bonds had a three-game home run streak and the sixth time of his career.</p>
<p>Tim Scott (4-5) got the win despite allowing a run and two hits over two innings of relief. Pete Harnisch (8-9) took the loss.</p>
<p>Gilkey went 4-for-4, including three doubles, and drove in two runs for the Mets.</p>
<p>In Cincinnati, Walt Weiss hit a two-run homer and drove in three runs and Larry Walker added a solo homer and two RBI as the Colorado Rockies defeated the Reds 6-3 in the rubber game of a five-game series.</p>
<p>Colorado starter Mark Thompson (6-8) allowed two runs and six hits over 7 2/3 innings, striking out four without a walk.</p>
<p>Mark Portugal (8-9) took the loss.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN DIEGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
