<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2665" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA BASKETBALL-BARKLEY JOINS HOUSTON ROCKETS LOOKING FOR FIRST TITLE.</title>
<headline>NBA BASKETBALL-BARKLEY JOINS HOUSTON ROCKETS LOOKING FOR FIRST TITLE.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Charles Barkley finally got the trade he wanted, and now has just one thing left to accomplish in his basketball career.</p>
<p>&quot;I have no problem saying this: If we don't win the championship, I'll be crushed,&quot; the 10-time All Star said in a news conference on Monday confirming his trade from the Phoenix Suns to the Houston Rockets for forward Robert Horry, guard Sam Cassell and reserves Mark Bryant and Chucky Brown.</p>
<p>Barkley, 33, has won Olympic gold with two Dream Teams, took the Suns to the Finals four seasons ago and is a sure Hall of Fame inductee when his career ends. But he has never won an NBA title.</p>
<p>The burly power forward has a good chance to win one with the Rockets, led by the incomparable centre Hakeem Olajuwon and superstar guard Clyde Drexler.</p>
<p>The Rockets, who won the second of their back-to-back championships one season ago, also bolstered their quest for another title by signing 7-foot (2.13 metres) free agent Kevin Willis to back up Barkley and Olajuwon.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to win championships in Houston -- the coaches do, the players do, the whole team does -- and we think this furthers our effort,&quot; Rockets owner Les Alexander said.</p>
<p>Barkley used his news conference to take one last shot at Phoenix, where he said he would have played out his career if the club had not sought to trade him away.</p>
<p>&quot;The bottom line was, I originally wanted to finish my career in Phoenix, but I told them if they were going to shop me, I would never play there again,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Barkley began his NBA career with the Philadelphia 76ers in 1984 and was traded to Phoenix in 1992. He was the league's Most Valuable Player the following season, when the Suns lost in the Finals to Michael Jordan's Chicago Bulls.</p>
<p>The Rockets lost two key members of their championship team by dealing away Cassell and Horry, but could not pass up a shot at acquiring Barkley, said Drexler.</p>
<p>&quot;When you have a chance to get a Hall of Fame player, this is a once in a lifetime opportunity,&quot; Drexler said.</p>
<p>Barkley will make $4.7 million next season. Cassell, Horry, Bryant and Brown will make a combined $4.585 million, so the trade fits salary cap regulations.</p>
<p>All four players going to the Suns become free agents after the 1996-97 season. Acquiring potential free agents to clear cap room has become the newest way to quickly rebuild a franchise.</p>
<p>Since the end of the season, Barkley has been the subject of many trade rumours, the first of which had him going to Houston in a three-way deal that also involved the Denver Nuggets. But the league rejected it, alleging tampering during a period when no such dealing was allowed.</p>
<p>There were other trade offers for Barkley from the Dallas Mavericks, New York Knicks and Indiana Pacers.</p>
<p>The 6-foot-6 (1.98 metres), 252-pound (114 kg) Barkley also stage-managed his trade out of Philadelphia.</p>
<p>Barkley, who is one of just nine players in NBA history -- and the shortest -- with 20,000 points and 10,000 rebounds, averaged 23.2 points and 11.6 rebounds in 71 games for the Suns last season.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
