<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2675" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: RALLYING-MCRAE FINED $250,000 BUT ESCAPES BAN.</title>
<headline>RALLYING-MCRAE FINED $250,000 BUT ESCAPES BAN.</headline>
<byline>Rex Gowar</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>World champion Colin McRae escaped a ban on Tuesday but was fined $250,000, most of it suspended, after breaking new rules in last month's Argentine Rally and colliding with spectators. Five fans were slightly injured.</p>
<p>Motor sport's world governing body FIA decided against suspending the Scot and he will only have to pay $75,000 unless he repeats the offence.</p>
<p>&quot;This was a situation where normally there would be a one or two race suspension,&quot; FIA president Max Mosley said after a FIA world council meeting attended by McRae.</p>
<p>&quot;But he was the first person to fall foul of the new regulations and the world council has taken a lenient view and hopes it won't happen again in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;We listened to everything (McRae had to say) and he had a lot of extenuating circumstances, there were lots of spectators in the service area and he had lost a lot of time with repairs and was in a great hurry.&quot;</p>
<p>McRae exceeded the new 50 kph speed limit in a service area and also failed to follow the correct route to the next time control. </p>
<p>Mosley said McRae had apologised and admitted to driving too fast in the service area. &quot;We thought it excessive to take him out of one or more events,&quot; Mosley said.</p>
<p>He said, however, that the service area &quot;is a place for spectators to hang around&quot;, where they are allowed to wander among the cars and competitors and FIA would continue to seek strict adherence to its safety regulations.</p>
<p>McRae, looking relieved at the outcome of the meeting, said: &quot;I feel very well, very positive that the penalty was a fine and there was no suspension.</p>
<p>&quot;Security is a big, big issue and we will have to work together to ensure safety is increased as much as possible.</p>
<p>&quot;Now I can go to the 1,000 Lakes and get on with racing,&quot; the 28-year-old added.</p>
<p>The sixth round of the world championship in Finland takes place this weekend.</p>
<p>After the fifth round in Argentina, Finn Tommi Makkinen leads the championship standings with Spaniard Carlos Sainz in second place, Sweden's Kenneth Eriksson third and McRae fourth.  </p>
<p>David Richards, director of McRae's Subaru team, said: &quot;While this incident has placed considerable pressure on him, I for one share his confidence that only good can come from raising the awareness of this issue.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
