<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2677" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: MOTOR RACING-BIG FORMULA ONE CHANGES AGREED.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-BIG FORMULA ONE CHANGES AGREED.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweeping changes to the future shape and political balance of Formula One, including the abolition of Friday practice sessions, were announced by the International Automobile Federation (FIA) on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The FIA said the changes were part of a package of alterations made to the new Concorde Agreement -- a formal accord between the sport's governing body and some of the teams -- to run from 1997 to 2001.</p>
<p>Changes include an agreement by the teams to stay in Formula One until 2001, a guarantee of 20-car grids, a 17-race season and the scrapping of Friday practice.</p>
<p>The FIA also said the teams would in future accept an 80 percent majority instead of unanimous agreement for any sporting or technical changes and would agree not to test anywhere in the week before a race or between the end of the season, usually October or November, and December 1.</p>
<p>A new system of prize money allocation had been introduced to distribute evenly the vast amounts of television income generated by the sport.</p>
<p>Three teams appear to be unhappy with the new deal. McLaren and Tyrrell refused to sign the proposal and Williams withdrew from agreeing to it on August 2.</p>
<p>The lack of support of these world championship-winning teams suggested that they could cause political problems for the sport which might even lead to their non-participation in the future.</p>
<p>Even though they were not signatories they would be allowed to compete with the consent of the Formula One Commission.</p>
<p>It is believed that the three very experienced teams, with a total of 1,178 grands prix behind them in the last 30 years, objected to the loss of Friday's practice on safety grounds. They argued that it was necessary to have a day in which to set cars up correctly for both qualifying and racing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
