<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2681" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: PRESS DIGEST - RUSSIA - AUG 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - RUSSIA - AUG 20.</headline>
<text>
<p>IZVESTIA</p>
<p>- A seven-men Russian air crew has come home after more than a year in captivity in the hands of Afghan Taleban rebels.</p>
<p>- Foros, former Soviet President Mikhail Gorbachev's summer residence where he spent the four days of the foiled 1991 pro-communist coup, has been handed over to Ukrainian President Leonid Kuchma, who is currently taking his annual holidays at the superexpensive seaside resort.</p>
<p>- General Konstantin Pulikovsky, in charge of Russian forces in Chechnya, is expected to issue a statement he may launch an all-out attack on separatist rebels if they fail to leave Grozny within 48 hours.</p>
<p>- Moscow tax police have collected 10 billion roubles ($1.9 million) for the city budget in the first seven months of 1996 from selling securities seized from companies who have not paid in full their dues to the budget.</p>
<p>PRAVDA</p>
<p>-Chechen rebels are the only ones who stand to gain from bitter in-fighting between Russian generals.</p>
<p>SEVODNYA</p>
<p>- Russian pilots who escaped from Taleban captivity proved that defending life and dignity of a Russian citizen today is more of a personal matter of the citizen himself than a affair of the state.</p>
<p>- Chechen rebels have issued an ultimatum to the federal forces to clear Grozny within 72 hours or face fierce hostilities all across the separatist republic.</p>
<p>NEZAVISIMAYA GAZETA</p>
<p>- Russian security services says they had no role to play in the escape of seven Russian airmen from Kandagar, but it is hard to believe that this is true, says the paper.</p>
<p>ROSSIISKAYA GAZETA</p>
<p>- National security boss Alexander Lebed's clash with Interior Minister Anatoly Kulikov over Chechnya threatens to turn the latest attempt to resolve the crisis in the republic into another settling of personal accounts between top officials.</p>
<p>MOSKOVSKY KOMSOMOLETS</p>
<p>- President Boris Yeltsin, five years after the unsuccessful 1991 pro-communist coup remains a simbol of democracy in Russia even though he has failed to become its reincarnation, says the paper.</p>
<p>--Andrei Shukshin, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
