<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2682" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: CZECH CABINET TO PAN GRAIN PRICE HIKE DEMANDS - AIDE.</title>
<headline>CZECH CABINET TO PAN GRAIN PRICE HIKE DEMANDS - AIDE.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Czech cabinet aide said on Tuesday that the government would reject grain price increases demanded by the country's farmers by using various tools, including the possible purchase of subsidised imports.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus's chief adviser, Jiri Weigl, told reporters after a meeting of ministers that this year's harvest would be sufficient for covering domestic demand and therefore there was no reason for price hikes.</p>
<p>&quot;Considering the situation on the domestic market, there is no reason for price increase,&quot; Weigl said.</p>
<p>&quot;The state is ready to play an active role and take measures against price increases and the pressures of producers,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Czech grain prices have been several hundred crowns below the world market price per tonne, but Weigl said the governemnt would, in the short-term, resist pressures of the farmers by using the state fund for regulating food prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Measures vary from influencing the supply from sources of the state reserves... to possible imports,&quot; Waigl said.</p>
<p>He added however that keeping domestic prices low by buying more expensive government imports &quot;would obviously cost something&quot;, but he did not elaborate</p>
<p>Grain exports are subject to licencing by state authorities, and Weigl said licences would be granted only if the domestic demand is satisfied.</p>
<p>&quot;(Libelarisation of the market) would mean that the market would aim toward... world prices, which would have serious impact on the development of inflation,&quot; Weigl told reporters.</p>
<p>Farmers have demanded price hikes saying their costs have grown.</p>
<p>Speaking about long-term grain market strategy, Weigl said that &quot;most of the ministers&quot; objected to the European Union (EU) system of guaranteed grain prices.</p>
<p>The Czechs have applied to join the EU, but Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus, widely praised abroad for his universal advocacy of the free market, has often criticised the Union's Common Agriculture Policy (CAP).</p>
<p>-- Jan Lopatka, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
