<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2683" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLAND'S GOVERNMENT TO REGULATE SECURITY FIRMS.</title>
<headline>POLAND'S GOVERNMENT TO REGULATE SECURITY FIRMS.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's government on Tuesday said it planned new rules for the often-unruly private security industry following mounting public concern over violent incidents involving such firms.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz told reporters the interior ministry would present a bill to cabinet this week.</p>
<p>&quot;The law will specify conditions for granting licences... and on who firms can or cannot hire. Regulations will be passed to assure firearms are not used unacceptably,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Concern has arisen notably after a night-time fight on Saturday at Terespol station on the Belarus border over control of a lucrative business escorting traders from the former Soviet Union on trains to a vast bazaar in Warsaw.</p>
<p>Hundreds of men, some with machetes and clubs, on Saturday attacked a bus carrying members of one of the firms involved.</p>
<p>They retreated after an off-duty policeman who was on the bus fired at the ground, wounding two attackers in the legs.</p>
<p>After the clash seven policemen were suspended on suspicion of moonlighting for the firm without permission.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz said police should be banned entirely from working off-duty for private security companies.</p>
<p>Crime including robbery soared after the 1989 fall of communism, leading to a surge in private security firms.</p>
<p>According to Dorota Godlewska, deputy president of an employers' association in the industry, there may be about 4,000 to 5,000 licenced domestic firms operating in Poland, many run by former police staff, and four foreign companies.</p>
<p>These employ about 200,000 people, she estimated.</p>
<p>&quot;No-one really knows how many firms there are. There are 12,000 issued licences, but not all these firms are operating,&quot; she told Reuters.</p>
<p>She said there were also numbers of cowboy outfits, some linked to criminal groups, operating without licences.</p>
<p>Her National Association of Employers in Agencies protecting Persons, Property and Detective Services, formed partly as an industry self-regulating body, has 150 members.</p>
<p>Godlewska said the association had long sought better official regulation of the business, but had already seen several drafts fail to pass through parliament in the past.</p>
<p>The police has also attracted scandals in recent months.</p>
<p>The loudest concerned a large group of masked men who trashed a night-club in Wroclaw, western Poland, earlier this year without realising they were being filmed by television.</p>
<p>The attackers later proved to be members of an elite police squad, apparently pursuing a private vendetta.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz praised the police, who have this year halted a steady rise in some categories of crime, but added: &quot;Against this background, incidents of police acting ambiguously or clearly breaking the law are especially glaring.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the police deserved strong support, but those policemen who behaved badly needed to be dealt with.</p>
<p>-- Anthony Barker +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
