<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2692" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: MINI BULL RUN FAILS TO BOOST SLOVAK MKT SENTIMENT.</title>
<headline>MINI BULL RUN FAILS TO BOOST SLOVAK MKT SENTIMENT.</headline>
<byline>Peter Javurek</byline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sentiment on the Slovak equities market, despite its recent mini-bull run, remains bearish in the medium-term as the bourse continues to be plagued by problems of liquidity and transparency.</p>
<p>The smallest of eastern Europe's four leading bourses with capitalisation of $2.6 billion -- Prague, the region's largest, has market capitalisation of some $16 billion -- the Bratislava bourse has been setting year highs almost daily.</p>
<p>On Monday, the SAX rose 2.45 points to a new 52-week high of 225.69, putting the bourse some three percent higher in the past four sessions.</p>
<p>But analysts say the market still lacks a broad range of illiquid issues, with trading concentrated on only a few &quot;blue chips&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;This market suffers from a lack of new issues, and even if there are some, these are too small to enable higher trading activity,&quot; Peter Krutil, analyst at Creditanstalt told Reuters.</p>
<p>Equity trading in every market throughout the former East Bloc has taken time to iron out the kinks, and analysts like Krutil say Slovakia is showing the &quot;typical signs&quot; of a immaturity.</p>
<p>As an example, they point to the bourse's 12-share SAX index, which brokers complain does not adequately reflect market trends since it is held hostage by four issues -- oil refinery Slovnaft, gas storage Nafta, bank VUB and steel producer VSZ -- accounting for 80 percent of its value.</p>
<p>Dusan Sykora of ING Barings said transparency problems in the market as a whole have impeded the bourse's progress.</p>
<p>He said a recent battle for a strategic control over the country's largest investment fund, VUB Kupon, were only the latest example of such &quot;market rigging&quot; by participants.</p>
<p>In the battle, large blocks of VUB Kupon shares changed hands at prices significantly different from those trading on the bourse floor.</p>
<p>&quot;If the share price on the BSE floor was 825 crowns, but somebody matched the block of some 30,000 shares at 723, dragging the average price down to 753, I can call it nothing else but rigging the market,&quot; Sykora said.</p>
<p>He added that such unrealistic average prices, considered one of the important indicators of what a share's true current market price is, has been often spoiling trading for investors and discouraging potential new buyers.</p>
<p>After closing down the Bratislava Option Bourse (BOB) last November, Slovak finance ministry authorities allowed BSE to launch trading with derivatives, in the hopes of breathing new life into the market's development.</p>
<p>Analysts are divided on the impact the move will have when trading begins sometime around the first half of 1997, but most agree the bourse has a lot of growing up to do before it can expect to handle the increased pressures derivatives trading brings.</p>
<p>&quot;The question is wheter there will appear enough clients interested in this kind of trading,&quot; said Vladimir Kuklis, analyst at the bank CSOB.</p>
<p>&quot;However, I think traders will need it (derivatives), at least for hedging their positions, no matter if they didn't do it so far,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But, added ING's Sykora: &quot;I can't imagine the routine trading in derivatives in the near future, as it requires a lot of serious figures based on the average (price),&quot; Sykora said.</p>
<p>&quot;The SAX has been constructed in such unhappy way, that it almost doesn't have a chance to reflect the market and, for example, index-futures trading could easily turn into a farce.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
