<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2693" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: CZECHS SPLIT ON IMPETUS FOR SENATE CHOICES - POLL.</title>
<headline>CZECHS SPLIT ON IMPETUS FOR SENATE CHOICES - POLL.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A total of 45 percent of Czech voters would vote for a Senate candidate in November based on the individual's merits and regardless of which party the person represents, a poll released on Tuesday showed.</p>
<p>But 41 percent said they would vote for any candidate tied to the political party they like, the survey conducted in August by a state run Institute for Public Opinion Research (IVVM) said.</p>
<p>Altogether 65 percent of Czech citizens said they would vote in the Senate elections scheduled for November 15 and 16, in comparison with 73 percent who would vote in the lower house elections if they were to be held now.</p>
<p>Senate elections will use a first-past-the-post for candidates contesting individuals constituencies unlike the lower chamber vote, which alloted seats based proportionally on the vote the parties received nationwide.</p>
<p>A recent poll conducted by the IVVM showed the opposition Social Democrats (CSSD) have closed the gap to within two percent of Czech Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus's Civic Democratic Party (ODS).</p>
<p>The poll showed ODS with a 28 percent support level, down slightly from 30 percent in July. Meanwhile the centre-left CSSD improved its standing among the electorate, rising to 26 percent from a July IVVM poll where it stood at 23 percent.</p>
<p>-- Klara Gajduskova, Prague Newsroom 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
