<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2696" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: LDC DEBT SLIPS SLIGHTLY IN DULL TRADE AHEAD OF FED.</title>
<headline>LDC DEBT SLIPS SLIGHTLY IN DULL TRADE AHEAD OF FED.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Latin Brady bonds came under light selling from retreating U.S. Treasuries, while Russia and East European debt prices were slightly mixed.</p>
<p>Markets were closed in Argentina, Venezuela and Colombia for national holidays.</p>
<p>Adding to the torpor, emerging markets traders took to the sidelines ahead of the Federal Open Market Committee meeting on Tuesday and the Bundesbank's council meeting on Thursday, traders said.</p>
<p>While most Fed watchers expect no change in U.S. rates, Bundesbank observers have not ruled out slight easing, said a U.S. bank trader.</p>
<p>&quot;Some liquidity help from the Bundesbank could add fuel to the emerging markets,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A steady inflow into funds specializing in emerging markets has been one of the most encouraging developments this summer, he said, adding: &quot;Global liquidity consideration would have more short-term impact (on emerging market debts) than data out of any one country.&quot;</p>
<p>The most liquid Latin American issues slipped slighty, with Argentine FRBs ARFLC05=RR giving up 1/8 to 77-3/8 and Brazilian Cs BR8D14=RR giving up 1/8 to 64-3/4.</p>
<p>A strong 7.2 percent growth of Mexican gross domestic product in the second quarter year-over-year reinforced the positive sentiment about the country's recovery, but gave little boost to debt prices.</p>
<p>&quot;People were counting on seven-percent growth, &quot; said a Brady bond trader. &quot;Much of that has been priced in.&quot;</p>
<p>Expectations for above-estimate growth had risen sharply last week to spark rallies in the Mexican markets, he said.</p>
<p>Mexican Pars MX625L19=RR slipped 1/8 to 67-3/8, while discounts MXFLL19=RR edged down 1/8 to 80-1/8.</p>
<p>While the spreads of Mexican Bradies and Eurobonds over U.S. Treasuries are still in tightening trends, the pace is likely to slow down, the trader said.</p>
<p>The 30-year UMS global bond, for example, has narrowed tp around 500 basis points from 570 at its issuance in late May, and it is likely to trade in the 485-515 range in the near term, he said.</p>
<p>While Latin American Bradies faltered, dollar Vnesh RUVNUSLNS=RR ended unchanged at 61-1/2,  and still held allure on a participation basis, said the U.S. bank trader.</p>
<p>-- Nailene Chou Wiest, 212-859-1660</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
