<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2697" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US TREASURIES END LOWER BEFORE FED POLICY MEETING.</title>
<headline>US TREASURIES END LOWER BEFORE FED POLICY MEETING.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries finished lower on Monday on the eve of a Federal Reserve meeting at which policymakers are expected to leave interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>Market analysts said selling by hedge funds and central banks pushed prices lower early in the session. After that, prices stabilized at their lower levels, quietly trading in extremely narrow ranges for the remainder of the session.</p>
<p>There was no new economic data. As usual, Fed officials made no public comments immediately ahead of their Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) policy meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;The activity on the way down ... was pretty heavy for a summer Monday, particularly one with no data being released,&quot; said analysts at Stone &amp; McCarthy Research Associates.</p>
<p>But a test of further downside in the mid-morning found no followthrough and traders began to settle in from there to wait out the outcome of Tuesday's FOMC meeting, they said.</p>
<p>Prices did edge up from session lows but several factors might have hurt efforts to lift prices further, said analysts.</p>
<p>First, the Commodity Research Bureau's (CRB) index of commodity futures prices rose a sharp 2.42 points to 251.97, a noticeable event for the inflation-wary bond market.</p>
<p>&quot;Then (Republican presidential candidate Bob) Dole made a surprising gain in the (voter public opinion) polls,&quot; said Josh Stiles, senior bond strategist at I.D.E.A., an independent economic advisory firm.</p>
<p>Stiles said no doubt many people think a Dole presidency would be good for the financial markets but &quot;there are more people who find his shift in emphasis from budget-cutting to tax-cutting is not bond-friendly.&quot;</p>
<p>Also, most economic data released in the last week &quot;came in a little stronger than expected,&quot; Stiles said.</p>
<p>Stiles cited &quot;some uneasiness&quot; about how low the jobless claims trend has been. He said that wariness was appropriate.</p>
<p>The four-week moving average for new jobless claims fell to a seven-year low in the week ended August 10, the government reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;As the weeks go by, it's harder to discount the low level of new claims as aberrant,&quot; said Stiles.</p>
<p>And while analysts appear unanimous in their expectation that the Fed will leave interest rates unchanged at the FOMC meeting on Tuesday, they are more divided about the future.</p>
<p>Jim Glassman, senior economist at Chase Securities Inc, said Fed policymakers appear reluctant to signal a change in the direction of policy just yet because they assume that economic growth will slow to two percent and unemployment will remain around 5-1/2 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Even so, all roads seem to be leading to higher rates,&quot; Glassman said. &quot;Consumers have spending power and the drop in new jobless claims implies the economy is robust, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;More important for the direction of interest rates, the economy already is operating at a level of resource use that has proven in the past to be inflationary,&quot; said Glassman.</p>
<p>At the close, three- and six-month bill rates were each up one basis point to 5.05 percent and 5.12 percent, respectively. The one-year bill rate rose two basis poitns to 5.34 percent.</p>
<p>The 6-1/4 percent two-year note slipped 1/32 to 100-17/32, its yield at 5.95 percent.</p>
<p>The five-year note fell 3/32 to close at 101-8/32, yielding 6.33 percent. The 10-year note closed at 103-1/32, down 6/32 to yield 6.58 percent.</p>
<p>The benchmark 6-3/4 30-year Treasury bond closed at 99-13/32, down 12/32, its yield at 6.80 percent.</p>
<p>--N.A. Treasury desk, 212-859-1664</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
