<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2712" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: GREEK STOCKS SHOOT UP 2.30PCT ON ELECTION TALK.</title>
<headline>GREEK STOCKS SHOOT UP 2.30PCT ON ELECTION TALK.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek equities staged a rally to break resistance at 900 and close 2.30 percent higher with the market discounting political stability and a serious effort to tackle pending economic problems, fund managers said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am optimistic,&quot; said a fund manager at a private investment company. &quot;The bourse discounts the re-election of Costas Simitis, much desired political stability and economic measures to help the country join EMU.&quot;</p>
<p>Greek Prime Minister Costas Simitis will decide this week whether to call early elections next month, government spokesman Dimitris Reppas told reporters on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime minister is considering all options, he will announce his final decision very soon, most probably within the week,&quot; Reppas said during Monday's briefing.</p>
<p>Based on Greece's constitution, elections must be held within a month from the time they are announced.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Akis Tsohatzopoulos summoned the director of the state computer election centre to discuss the election schedule, a source told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Athens general share index finished 2.30 percent, or 20.37 points higher at 907.92 from Friday's 887.55 close after opening at 888.68 points. Turnover was 9.02 billion drachmas on volume of 3.64 million shares.</p>
<p>&quot;We have got at least another 100 points on the upside,&quot; the fund manager said. &quot;Investors are hesitantly coming back and turnover is up with more attention paid to large caps such as OTE, and National Bank of Greece .&quot;</p>
<p>Gainers led losers 184 to 37 with 16 issues unchanged on 237 traded. Banks gained 2.43 percent, industrials ended 1.25 percent higher with construction rising 2.47 percent. Small-caps ended with gains of 1.13 percent at 81.23 on the parallel market index.</p>
<p>The Merrill Lynch call spread warrant on OTE with a strike price of 3,800 drachmas was quoted at 511-529 at the close. Shares of OTE telecom, the underlying, ended sharply up at 3,845 drachmas.</p>
<p>The recently launched Merrill Lynch stock index call warrant based on a basket of 23 shares was quoted at 201.70-212.30 drachmas. It expires on January 9 1998 with a strike price of 1000. It was in the money at 1005.2.</p>
<p>The Morgan Stanley Hellenic Blue Chip Warrant, which has a strike price of 100 marks, was quoted higher at 3,111-3,444 drachmas at the close.</p>
<p>--Dimitris, Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
