<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2716" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREECE - AUG 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREECE - AUG 20.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek financial press:</p>
<p>FINANCIAL KATHEMERINI</p>
<p>-- Greek telecommunications organisation OTE is looking for a partner to develop the DCS 1800 mobile telephony system. The partner will have a 25 percent stake in the new company. Interested parties can apply by September 16.</p>
<p>-- The tax reduction in motor fuels will be extended by October 17</p>
<p>KERDOS</p>
<p>-- It is a matter of days before the government announces its decision about calling early elections or not. The business community wants &quot;clear solutions&quot;</p>
<p>-- Definitely, OTE enters into mobile telephony. Pre-subscriptions start January</p>
<p>-- Ukraine to export petroleum to Greece from the start of 1997</p>
<p>IMERISIA</p>
<p>-- They are looking for the date. Elections are certain and interest focuses on whether they will be in September or October. Consecutive meetings of Prime Minister Costas Simitis</p>
<p>-- Positive climate in the Athens bourse. The market reacted positively to the prospect of early elections</p>
<p>EXPRESS</p>
<p>-- &quot;Neutral reaction&quot; of the market to rumours about early elections. The business community thinks that economic policy is one way street independently of any election result</p>
<p>-- Revenues from customs are up in the first seven months. Total VAT revenues are also up 16.84 percent in the same period</p>
<p>-- The new T-bills will feature unchanged rates</p>
<p>NAFTEMBORIKI</p>
<p>-- The political-economic landscape clears up with elections. Elections are announced on Thursday and will take place excluding any unforseen event on September 29</p>
<p>-- The Greek textile industry is being modernised with 18.8 billion drachmas --Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
