<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2726" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British mortgage lending hits six-year high.</title>
<headline>British mortgage lending hits six-year high.</headline>
<byline>Michael Peacock</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>British mortgage figures on Tuesday showed that lending in July surged to a six year high, suggesting Britain's housing market recovery was gathering pace and resisting a traditional summer lull.</p>
<p>Net new mortgages worth 3.8 billion sterling ($5.9 billion) were approved last month, the highest since November 1990, despite the torpor that normally afflicts this market during the holiday season, the Building Societies Association said.</p>
<p>&quot;Approvals remained strong in July,&quot; said BSA deputy director-general Ron Armstrong. &quot;Transactions have been increasing since April and house prices have also been rising, encouraging more sellers into the market.&quot;</p>
<p>The figures from the building societies, who provide many of Britain's home loans, showed 53,000 new mortgages were approved in July, the highest monthly number since March 1994.</p>
<p>The figures will be welcome news for the beleaguered British government. Some 67 percent of the population are houseowners, most of whom felt the pain of house price falls of up to 30 percent in the 1990s.</p>
<p>City analysts say the depressed housing market has been a key factor inhibiting the so-called &quot;feelgood factor&quot;.</p>
<p>The BSA figures were not the only good news for British houseowners on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A Royal Institution of Chartered Surveyors (RICS) survey and post-results comment from the Halifax Building Society also combined to put a positive gloss on the UK housing market.</p>
<p>The RICS survey showed the housing market's pick-up, first seen in London and the South-East, was now spreading across the length and breadth of Britain. House prices in all regions of England and Wales held steady or rose in July, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a measure of the market's vigour that -- at this traditionally quiet period -- many agents reported that there were still not enough new instructions to meet demand,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>In other words, not enough houses came on to the market to match the number of potential buyers.</p>
<p>The Halifax Building Society also did its best to talk the housing market up. Reporting a six percent rise in underlying half-year profits, the Halifax said housing showed clear signs of recovery in the first six months of 1996.</p>
<p>Halifax spokesman Gary Marsh said house price inflation of five to seven percent was expected over the next year. &quot;All the signs are that the recovery is sustainable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that mortgage rates, already at their lowest level in 30 years, may not fall further even if finance minister Kenneth Clarke pushed through another cut in base rates, currently at 5.75 percent.</p>
<p>Despite all the good news on housing, analysts noted that official figures at least suggested the level of transactions remains muted at best. But here too, a pick-up is expected.</p>
<p>&quot;The official Inland Revenue figures covering transactions have been weak but anecdotal evidence suggests buying and selling has been much stronger,&quot; said Rob Thomas, building societies analyst at UBS.</p>
<p>He said transactions would pick up in the second half of the year and expected house prices to rise by at least six percent next year. &quot;The hype about a return to boom conditions is overdone but the good news is we think this recovery can continue for a good many years.&quot;</p>
<p>Marsh at the Halifax added transactions remained at low levels &quot;but are coming back quite nicely.&quot;</p>
<p>But Armstrong warned that memories of the collapse in housing prices in recent years, remained fresh in the memory.</p>
<p>&quot;Borrowers are likely to remain careful. As a result, the recovery in the housing market will remain moderate and will be slower than some commentators have suggested,&quot; he said. ($1=.6466 Stg)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
