<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2728" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Eurobourses higher as FTSE sets new record.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Eurobourses higher as FTSE sets new record.</headline>
<byline>Eric Meijer</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>London's blue-chip FTSE index hit an intra-day record on Tuesday, boosted by benign money supply data as European trading was dominated by the prospects for inflation and interest rates.</p>
<p>Positive German money supply data failed to inspire the German stock market, which traded mixed after the Bundesbank announced slower growth of key M3 money supply figures and virtually guaranteed a cut in its key money market rate.</p>
<p>French stocks opened higher and breezed quickly through the 2,000 index barrier for the first time since August 8, on strengthened hopes of a new round of rate cuts.</p>
<p>Markets were waiting for news of the U.S. Federal Reserve's open market committee meeting later in the day. It had been expected to raise interest rates but is now widely believed to be content to leave them unchanged.</p>
<p>Wall Street, also stilled by the FOMC meeting and general summer torpor had its slowest full day of trade this year on Monday, which may have been factored into Frankfurt's less than euphoric response to the money supply data.</p>
<p>The FTSE's record 3,881.5, the second record in two days, was reached when the British government announced growth in M4, the broad measure of money supply, fell to a seasonally adjusted 8.8 percent on a year-on-year basis in July from 10.1 in percent June. The figure was inside the government's 3.0 to 9.0 percent monitoring range and compared with market forecasts clustered around 9.4 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said the figures would give further ammunition to Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke if he wants to trim the 5.75 percent base interest rate again in coming months.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a good figure...most people hadn't expected the figure to come back into the monitoring range, which is about the first time for six or seven months,&quot; said economist Keith Wade of Schroders.</p>
<p>In Germany, growth in M3, the German central bank's main policy guide, slowed to an annualised 8.6 percent in July from 9.6 percent in June.</p>
<p>&quot;It is now very clear that we have a very good chance to reach the Bundesbank target zone (of four to seven percent growth for 1996). I think there is a very good chance that we will see a cut in the repo rate,&quot; said Uwe Angenendt, economist at BHF-Bank in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Frankfurt started bourse floor trading quietly, with the DAX index barely moved as traders built a fuller picture of the interest rate outlook. The electronic IBIS DAX index was up around 6.7 points.</p>
<p>Currency markets, however, marked time in early European trading. The dollar was ticking over in Europe barely changed from Monday's closing levels, with the market awaiting the outcome of the FOMC meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;It's hard to find anyone looking for a Fed tightening today,&quot; said Jeremy Hawkins, senior economic adviser at BankAmerica. &quot;There's a very small risk of a hike and the main focus now is whether the Fed has to move at all this year.&quot;</p>
<p>The outcome of the meeting is expected around 1815 GMT, too late for Europe to react.</p>
<p>Assuming no change, the next hurdle for a moribund market will be Thursday's Bundesbank council meeting. Traders are looking for the 3.30 percent repo to be pared, although opinions vary as to the size of a possible cut.</p>
<p>Some are looking for a cut of only 0.05 to 0.10 of a percentage point, while others are more bullish and reckon the central bank will go for a bigger reduction of perhaps 0.15 to 0.20 points.</p>
<p>The Ifo business sentiment index is due on Wednesday and expected to at best show a small improvement in July to around 91.0 after hitting a three-month low of 90.4 percent in June. A soft number will convince traders that the Bundesbank will ease.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES  AT 0930 GMT</p>
<p>Dollar/mark was trading at 1.4902 and dollar/yen at 107.90 versus Monday's late 1.4875 and 107.90. Mark/French franc was trading at 3.4167 against 3.4232.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 0930 GMT</p>
<p>The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares was up 18.3 points at 3,882.3.  Frankfurt's 30-share DAX index was up 0.46 at 2,563.20. Paris's CAC-40 was up 19.32 at 2005.53.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold opened firmer in quiet European trade at $387.55 London's $386.65 with next resistance at $387.50. Silver was firmer at $5.21 vs 512.00, holding overnight gains from New York, mainly due to fund buying. Dealers expect further short-term gains. Platinum was firmer at $399.500 vs $398.40.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
