<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2733" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton to sign minimum-wage increase into law.</title>
<headline>Clinton to sign minimum-wage increase into law.</headline>
<byline>Arshad Mohammed</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton on Tuesday signs into law the first rise in the minimum wage in five years, giving the lowest-paid Americans a 90-cent raise but sweetening the pill for small businesses with tax cuts.</p>
<p>The bill, boosting the wage to $5.15 per hour, was a political victory for Clinton, who called for an increase when he campaigned for president in 1992, and his fellow Democrats, who forced it through over the objections of many Republicans.</p>
<p>The fact that both of the Republican-controlled houses of Congress passed the legislation with strong majorities reflects election-year imperatives, as few legislators are willing to go to the polls on Nov. 5 having voted against it.</p>
<p>The president plans to celebrate by signing the bill in high style, arranging an elaborate outdoor ceremony on the White House south lawn.</p>
<p>The bill will boost the wage, typically paid to unskilled workers in restaurants and small businesses, by 50 cents to $4.75 on Oct. 1 and by 40 cents to $5.15 on Sept. 1, 1997.</p>
<p>Although the legislation will raise salaries of many U.S. workers, in inflation-adjusted terms it will not even restore the wage to its level in April 1991, when it was last increased.</p>
<p>One administration official said that in constant 1996 dollars the wage stood at $4.89 in April 1991 and will only be $4.85 in September 1997 after the full increase is in effect.</p>
<p>Boosting the wage was supported by roughly 80 percent of Americans but bitterly opposed by conservatives who came into office in the 1994 election that gave control of both houses of Congress to the Republican party.</p>
<p>&quot;Considering how resolutely anti-Clinton and ideological this Congress was, for one of its very few accomplishments to be a Democratic bill to increase the minimum wage is quite remarkable,&quot; said William Dickens of the Brookings Institution, a Washington-based private research organization.</p>
<p>The legislation, formally called the &quot;Small Business Jobs Protection Act,&quot; was made easier for Republicans to swallow by adding a sweeping package of tax breaks worth roughly $22 billion over ten years and aimed mostly at small businesses.</p>
<p>Conservatives argue that raising the minimum wage, which was first imposed by the federal government in 1938, would cut jobs, hurt small businesses and raise prices as companies pass on higher labor costs to consumers.</p>
<p>&quot;This needlessly destroys job opportunities and it does not do what it is supposed to do, which is help the working poor,&quot; said Mark Wilson, who specilizes in labor issues at the conservative Heritage Foundation think-tank in Washington.</p>
<p>Wilson estimates that the law would eliminate 200,000 job opportunites -- jobs either not created or jobs terminated -- because of the higher labor costs.</p>
<p>But other economists argue the negative effects of the increase will be minimal.</p>
<p>&quot;(We) expect only a small increase in inflation -- about 0.1 percent,&quot; Wharton Economic Forecasting Associates wrote in a recent study. &quot;Job losses will also be small -- the net job loss will be only about 20,000.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
