<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2734" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU readies guns for air alliance probe.</title>
<headline>EU readies guns for air alliance probe.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Chalmers</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reports on Tuesday that Britain plans to play it tough in &quot;open skies&quot; talks with the United States come as the European Commission readies its guns for a competition probe into six transatlantic aviation alliances.</p>
<p>Tuesday's Financial Times quoted British government officials as planning to wring concessions from Washington before any wider opening of access to the busy runways of London's Heathrow airport.</p>
<p>A successful outcome to the ongoing and increasingly tetchy open skies talks is crucial to the fate of British Airways' planned alliance with American Airlines. Washington says it will block the deal without increased Heathrow access for American carriers.</p>
<p>While approval for the BA/American alliance hinges principally on decisions by the U.S. Justice Department and Britain's Office of Fair Trading, the Commission has muscled in on policing a deal it sees as a threat to its competition powers within the European Union.</p>
<p>The planned alliance would capture 24 percent of the total Europe to U.S. market, British Airway's chief executive Robert Ayling said in July.</p>
<p>The sheer size of the plan made it impossible for the Commission to hold off on a move it had earlier considered but rejected for United Airlines's tie-up with Lufthansa.</p>
<p>The probe is to cover the competition effects of BA/American plans along with existing deals involving Lufthansa and United, Scandinavian Airlines Systems and United, and those between Delta Air Lines and SwissAir, Belgium's Sabena and Austrian Airlines.</p>
<p>One Brussels-based aviation expert, while convinced of the Commission's legal ground, questioned its capacity to unravel the complexities of all the different alliances, agreements for which usually run to hundreds of pages of dense legal text.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly the Commission has the legal power to act. It used exactly these instruments in 1986 when it sent competition infringement letters to 10 Community airlines,&quot; the expert told Reuters recently.</p>
<p>&quot;What I wonder at is whether the Commission has the resources to assess the competition effects of code-sharing agreements or even to calculate their market share impact,&quot; the expert said.</p>
<p>The scale of the Commission's task was evident from the conclusions of a recent report it commissioned into the impact of code-share deals, the practice by which collaborating airlines agree to use the same flight codes on respective services for a route in order to attract feeder traffic passengers to use an apparently seamless service.</p>
<p>&quot;Potential competition problems might arise (from code-shares) as the possibilities for non code-sharing carriers to compete on a global network scale are limited,&quot; said the report, a copy of which was seen by Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
