<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2739" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: REUTER EC REPORT LONG-TERM DIARY FOR AUGUST 21-DEC 31, 1996.</title>
<headline>REUTER EC REPORT LONG-TERM DIARY FOR AUGUST 21-DEC 31, 1996.</headline>
<text>
<p>****</p>
<p>HIGHLIGHTS</p>
<p>****</p>
<p>DUBLIN - EU leaders hold special European Council (October).</p>
<p>SINGAPORE - Inaugural World Trade Organisation (WTO) ministerial conference (December 9-13).</p>
<p>DUBLIN - Irish Presidency European Council of heads of state and government (December 13-14).</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, AUGUST 21</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG (NEW ITEM) - Luxembourg U.N. Association holds news conference prior to the world congress of the 50th anniversary of the world federation of U.N. associations (1700/1300 GMT). Venue: Kirchberg Centre.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, AUGUST 22</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Union cereals management committee meets for export tender.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, AUGUST 23</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG (NEW ITEM) - Luxembourg U.N. Association holds World Congress of the 50th anniversary of the World Federation of U.N. Associations (To August 26). Venue: Kirchberg Centre.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, AUGUST 27</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG (NEW ITEM) - U.N. regional European Associations hold 15th conference.</p>
<p>SUNDAY, SEPTEMBER 1</p>
<p>BERLIN - International Energy Agency (IEA) holds conference on &quot;The technologies of natural gas, power unit for market development&quot; (To September 4). Contact: IEA (33) 1 45 24 94 84.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, SEPTEMBER 3</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament Inquiry Committee into mad cow disease holds first meeting. Spanish Socialist leader Manuel Medina presents report.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - IGC Working Party of EU foreign ministers' representatives meets to continue review of EU treaties (To September 4). Topics include: citizenship, fundamental rights, subsidiarity, simplification and codification.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, SEPTEMBER 4</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commission holds first regular weekly meeting after its summer break. Provisional agenda, liable to change, includes:</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Neil Kinnock presents communication on an internal market in aviation.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament mini-session (To September 5).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (1500/1300 GMT) Statement by the Commission on urgent political matters of major importance followed by questions.</p>
<p>- (1630/1430 GMT) Statements by the Council and the Commission an public services followed by a debate.</p>
<p>- Robin Teverson report on the sixth annual report for 1994 on the structural funds COM(95)583.</p>
<p>- Joint debate:</p>
<p>- (possibly) Konstantinos Klironomos report on development issues relating to Objective I structural measures in Greece.</p>
<p>- Giles Chichester report on development issues/Objective 1 - structural measures in Portugal.</p>
<p>- Angela Siepra Gonzalez report on development problems/structural measures under Objectives 1-2 and 5b in Spain (1994-1999).</p>
<p>- Bernd Lange report on the 1995 annual report on the research and technological development activities of the European Union COM(95)443.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Karl von Wogau report on the rates of duty laid down in Council directive 92/79/EEC of 19 October 1992 on the approximation of taxes on cigarettes, Council directive 92/80/EEC of 19 October 1992, on the approximation of taxes on manufactured tobacco other than cigarettes, Council directive 92/84/EEC of 19 October 1992, on the approximation of the rates of excise duty on alcohol and alcoholic beverages and 92/82/EEC of 19 October 1992, on the approximation of the rates of excise duties on mineral oils COM(95)285.</p>
<p>- Werner Langen report on the common system of Value Added Tax (level of the standard rate) COM(95)731.</p>
<p>- Gipo Farassino report on the proposal for a Council directive amending directive 91/439/EEC on driving licences COM(96)55.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Per Stenmarck report on the proposal for a Council directive on safety rules and standards for passenger ships COM(96)61.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, SEPTEMBER 5</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament mini-session (second of two days).</p>
<p>Provisonal agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (until 0900/0700 GMT) Political group meetings.</p>
<p>- (0900/0700 GMT) Edgar Schiedermeier report on a European strategy for encouraging local development and employment initiatives COM(95)273.</p>
<p>- Michel Rocard report on the reduction of working hours.</p>
<p>- (1100/0900 GMT) Votes on reports under the cooperation, codecision and assent procedures and motions for resolutions on which the debate has closed.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Executive committee of the Bosnian Peace Implementation Council, known as the Steering Board, meets ahead of September 14 Bosnian elections to discuss post-election framework peace plan.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, SEPTEMBER 6</p>
<p>LINZ, Austria - GLOBE holds conference on &quot;Responding to climate change&quot;. Contact: GLOBE (322) 230 6589.</p>
<p>SATURDAY, SEPTEMBER 7</p>
<p>TRALEE, Ireland - Informal General Affairs Council (To September 8). Agenda includes review of IGC progress.</p>
<p>MONDAY, SEPTEMBER 9</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - (possibly) ECOFIN Council.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Euro-Mediterranean meeting on projects concerning cultural heritage (To September 10).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Newspaper Publishers Association (ENPA) holds conference on &quot;Journalists and the world of politics, publishers and politicians&quot; (1100/0900 GMT). Venue: Royal Crown Hotel. Contact: ENPA (322) 551 0190.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, SEPTEMBER 10</p>
<p>EDINBURGH - European Commission's DG XVI, Committee of the Regions and Scotland hold conference on land-use planning in the North Sea and Baltic regions.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - COURT OF JUSTICE, PLENARY COURT (0930/0730 GMT)</p>
<p>- Judgment C-61/94 Commission v/ Germany: external relations.</p>
<p>- Judgment C-222/94 Commission v/ United Kingdom: free movement of persons.</p>
<p>- Judgment C-277/94 Z. Taflan-Met and others v/ Bestuur van de Sociale Verzekeringsbank: external relations.</p>
<p>- Judgment C-11/95 Commission v/ Belgium: free movement of persons.</p>
<p>- Oral procedure C-24/95 Land Rheinland-Pfalz v/ Alcan Deutschland GmbH: state aid.</p>
<p>- (1100/0900 GMT) Oral procedure C-59/95 Francisco Bastos Moriana and others v/ Bundesanstalt fuer Arbeit: free movement of persons.</p>
<p>- (1530/1330 GMT) Oral procedure C-169/95 Spain v/ Commission: state aid.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Centre for European Policy Studies (CEPS) holds seminar on &quot;NATO enlargement&quot; (1315/1115 GMT). Speaker is Andras Simonyi, Ambassador and Head of Hungarian Liaison Mission with NATO and the Western European Union. Venue: Place du Congres 1. Contact: CEPS (322) 229 3911.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, SEPTEMBER 11</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commission holds regular weekly meeting.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda, liable to change, includes:</p>
<p>- European Commission President Jacques Santer presents communication on public services.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Christos Papoutsis presents communication on nuclear industries in the EU - indicative nuclear programme under article 40 of the Euratom treaty COM(96)339.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Martin Bangemann presents communication on the proposal for an EP and Council directive on the application to voice telephony of the principle of open network provision and universal service for telecoms in a competitive environment.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan presents communication on the second phase of the integration of textile and clothing products under GATT.</p>
<p>- European Commission President Jacques Santer and European Commissioners Yves-Thibault de Silguy and Mario Monti present communication on the legal framework for the use of the Euro.</p>
<p>- European Commission President Santer and European Commissioner de Silguy present communication on Commission proposal on a budgetary stability pact.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner de Silguy presents communication on foreign exchange in the EU.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - COURT OF FIRST INSTANCE, SECOND CHAMBER - ENLARGED (0930/0730 GMT)</p>
<p>- Oral procedure T-227/95 AssiDoman Kraft Products and others v/ Commission: competition.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, SEPTEMBER 12</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - COURT OF JUSTICE, PLENARY COURT, FIRST CHAMBER (0930/0730 GMT)</p>
<p>- Judgment joined cases C-58/95 Gallotti, C-75/95 Censi, C-112/95 Salmaggi, C-119/95 Pasquire, C-123/95 Zappone, C-135/95 Segna, C-140/95 Cervetti, C-141/95 Gasbarri, C-154/95 Narducci, C-157/95 Smaldone: environment and consumers.</p>
<p>- Oral procedure C/241/95 The Queen, ex parte: Accrington Beef Co Ltd v/ Intervention Board for Agricultural Produce: commercial policy.</p>
<p>THIRD CHAMBER (0930/0730 GMT)</p>
<p>- Oral procedure C-255/95 S. Agri and others v/ Regione Veneto: agriculture.</p>
<p>- (1030/0830 GMT) Oral procedure C-273/95 Impresa Agricola Buratti Leonardo, Pierluigi e Livio v/ Tabacchicoltori Associati Veneti Soc. coop. a.r.l. (TAV): agriculture.</p>
<p>FIFTH CHAMBER (0930/0730 GMT)</p>
<p>- Judgment C-251/94 Eduardo Lafuente Nieto v/ Instituto Nacional de Seguridad Social (INSS) and Tesoreria General de la Seguridad Social (TGSS): free movement of persons.</p>
<p>- Judgment joined cases C-254/94, C/255/94, C-269/94 Fattoria autonoma tabacchi and others v/ Ministero dell'Agricoltura et delle Foreste and others: agriculture.</p>
<p>- Judgment C-278/94 Commission v/ Belgium: free movement of persons.</p>
<p>- Judgment C-236/95 Commission v/ Greece: company law.</p>
<p>- Opinion C-340/94 E.J.M. de Jaeck v/ Staatssecretaris van Financieen: free movement of persons.</p>
<p>- Opinion joined cases C-88/95, C-102/95 and C-103/95 Bernardina Martinez Losada and others v/ Instituto Nacional de Empleo (INEM), Instituto Nacional de la Seguridad Social (INSS): free movement of persons.</p>
<p>- Opinion C-139/95 Livia Balestra v/ Istituto nazionale per la previdenza sociale (INPS): social policy.</p>
<p>- (1530/1330 GMT) Phytheron International SA v/ Jean Bourdon SA: free movement of goods.</p>
<p>SIXTH CHAMBER (0930/0730 GMT)</p>
<p>- Opinion C-221/94 Commission v/ Luxembourg: approximation of legislation.</p>
<p>- Opinion C-142/95-P Associazione agricoltori della provincia di Rovigo and others v/ Commission, Mauro Girello and Greguoldo Daniele: environment and consumers.</p>
<p>- Opinion C-262/95 Commission v/ Germany: environment and consumers.</p>
<p>- Opinion C-314/95 Commission v/ Italy: agriculture.</p>
<p>- Oral procedure C-69/95 Italy v/ Commission: agriculture.</p>
<p>COURT OF FIRST INSTANCE, FOURTH CHAMBER (0930/0730 GMT)</p>
<p>- Oral procedure joined cases T-454/93, T-455/93, T-456/93 and T-457/93 Elders Trading Ltd and Paterson Elders (Produce) Ltd. and others v/ Commission: agriculture.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Union of Industrial and Employee's Confederation of Europe (UNICE) hold press briefing on &quot;Taxation in the EU&quot; (1530/1330 GMT). Venue: UNICE, rue Joseph II. Contact: UNICE (322) 231 1445.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Friends of the Earth Europe hold conference on &quot;International biosafety&quot; (To September 13). Topics include: the EU and international biosafety actions; experiences with international legislation on the transfer of potentially hazardous substances; north-south transfer of genetically modified organisms; legal instruments to be included in an international biosafety protocol, implementation and control. Venue: Palace Hotel. Contact: Friends of the Earth Europe (322) 542 0180.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, SEPTEMBER 13</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Centre for European Policy Studies (CEPS) holds workshop on &quot;The strategic implications of the Euro for banks and corporates&quot; (1000/0800 GMT). Agenda includes: implication of the empirical findings on economies of scale and scope in European banking; mergers and acquisitions in European banking; European banking: a cross-country comparison; Euro pricing and marketing strategies in Europe; implications for corporate finance; place of business and taxation. Venue: Place du Congres 1. Contact: CEPS (322) 229 3911.</p>
<p>SUNDAY, SEPTEMBER 15</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - COPA holds conference on &quot;Women farmers: more than a job, a life&quot; (To September 17). Venue: COPA, 23-25 rue de la Science. Contact: COPA (322) 287 2711.</p>
<p>BARCELONA, Spain - Eurotextil exhibition on the textile and clothing industry takes place (To September 17). Venue: Fira de Barcelona. Contact: Eurotextil (34) 93 233 2000.</p>
<p>CRACOW, Poland - European Commission and the Polish government hold joint conference on &quot;Industrial property in European integration&quot; (1900/1700 GMT) (To September 17). Speakers include: Head of the Commission delegation in Poland Rolf Timans, Commission DG XV Director General John Mogg. Contact: Kserkop (48) 12 33 39 24.</p>
<p>MONDAY, SEPTEMBER 16</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Farm Council (To September 17).</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament plenary session (To September 20).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - IGC Working Party of EU foreign ministers' representatives meets to continue review of EU treaties (To September 17). Topics include: institutional issues, budgetary issues, national parliaments.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, SEPTEMBER 17</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Knibb, Gormezano and Partners hold conference on &quot;The automotive industry and the environment&quot; (To September 18). Venue: Renaissance Hotel. Contact: Automotive Matters International Ltd (44) 1628 526 060.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, SEPTEMBER 18</p>
<p>DUBLIN - EU trade ministers hold informal meeting (To September 19) to prepare for the first ministerial conference of the World Trade Organisation (WTO) in Singapore on December 9-13. Participants include: Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan and WTO Director General Renato Ruggiero. Venue: Dublin Castle.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Committee of the Regions holds plenary session (To September 19).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Centre for European Policy Studies (CEPS) holds seminar on &quot;Banning chemical weapons&quot; (1315/1115 GMT). Speaker is Ian R. Kenyon, Executive Secretary, Preparatory Commission for the Organisation for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons. Venue: Place du Congres 1. Contact: CEPS (322) 229 3911.</p>
<p>LONDON - AIG conferences Ltd holds &quot;The European power forum: regulatory developments and strategic opportunities&quot; (To September 20). Venue: Park Lane Hotel. Contact: AIG conferences Ltd (44) 171 2422324.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, SEPTEMBER 19</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - IBC Legal Studies and Services holds conference on &quot;Telecommunications and EC competition law&quot; (To September 20). Venue: SAS Hotel. Contact: Anna D'Alton, IBC Legal Studies and Services (44) 171 453 2043.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, SEPTEMBER 20</p>
<p>DUBLIN - Informal ECOFIN Council (To September 22).</p>
<p>SUNDAY, SEPTEMBER 22</p>
<p>KILLARNEY, Ireland - Informal Farm Council (To September 24). Provisional agenda includes beef market trends and sales promotion.</p>
<p>MONDAY, SEPTEMBER 23</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Centre for European Policy Studies (CEPS) holds seminar on &quot;World competition rules&quot; (1315/1115 GMT). Speaker is Karel Van Miert, member of the European Commission responsible for competition policy. Venue: Place du Congres 1. Contact: CEPS (322) 229 3911.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, SEPTEMBER 24</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Social Affairs Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision on the establishment of an employment and labour market policy committee.</p>
<p>- Modification of the &quot;carcinogens&quot; directive.</p>
<p>- Amendment of directive 86/378/EEC on equal treatment in occupational social security schemes.</p>
<p>- Council resolutions on equal opportunities between men and women and the European structural funds.</p>
<p>- Information and consultation of workers.</p>
<p>- Future of social dialogue.</p>
<p>- Joint report on employment.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Economic and Social Committee (ECOSOC) holds plenary session (To September 26).</p>
<p>LONDON - European Commission hosts conference on &quot;Private security industry in society: a European perspective&quot; (To September 25). Topics include: vocational training, regulation, standards of service and employment. Venue: Forte Crest Hotel. Contact: Nigel Greaves Associates, Andrew Mackay (44) 1886 833 034.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - IGC Working Party of EU foreign ministers' representatives meets to continue review of EU treaties (To September 24). Topics include: issues on which proposals become available from delegations.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Centre for European Policy Studies (CEPS) holds seminar on &quot;The inter-governmental conference&quot; (1315/1115 GMT). Speaker is Michael Patijn, State Secretary for Foreign Affairs, The Netherlands. Venue: Place du Congres 1. Contact: CEPS (322) 229 3911.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, SEPTEMBER 26</p>
<p>DUBLIN - Informal Justice and Internal Affairs Council (To September 27).</p>
<p>BERLIN - The Kangaroo Group in collaboration with the Fondation Europe et Societe host European Parliament and Commission conference on &quot;On the way to the European home market: the single currency&quot; (To September 28). Agenda includes: role of the single currency in the development of the EU; priorities of the Irish Presidency regarding the single currency; preparation for the move to the single currency; impact on the French banking system; impact on financial services and policy; impact on business; single currency and social aspects; relations between the single currency and the currencies which will join the EMU later; single currency and political union. Speakers include: MEPs Karl von Wogau, Giorgos Katiforis and Elmar Brok; Irish Finance Minister Ruairi Quinn; European Economy Commissioner Yves-Thibault de Silguy. Venue: Steigenberger Hotel. Contact: Kangaroo Group conference office (322) 284 4438.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Club de Bruxelles hold conference on &quot;The future of Biotechnologies in Europe&quot; (To September 27). Topics include: development and role of biotechnology R&amp;D in the EU; innovation in health care: novel pharmaceutical products; new crops from plant biotechnology; the &quot;greening&quot; of industry: clean products and processes; biotechnology in Europe society: public perceptions; industrial competitiveness and biotechnological innovation. Contact: Club de Bruxelles (322) 743 1520.</p>
<p>WARSAW - Euromoney Seminars holds third annual conference on &quot;The 1996 Polish investment forum&quot; (To September 27). Venue: Bristol Hotel. Contact: Euromoney Seminars (44) 171 7798793.</p>
<p>ROME - European Association of Advertising Agencies (EAAA) holds annual conference on &quot;The future of brand-building across borders&quot;. Contact: Paola di Discordia, EAAA (322) 280 1603.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, SEPTEMBER 27</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Telecoms Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for a European Parliament and Council directive on a common framework for general authorisations and individual licences in the field of telecommunications services.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a European Parliament and Council decision on action at Union level in the field of satellite personal communications services in the European Union.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Commission communication on ITU policy forum.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a European Parliament and Council directive on telecoms terminal and satellite earth station equipment.</p>
<p>- TENs: proposal for a European Parliament and Council decision on a series of guidelines for trans-European telecommunications networks.</p>
<p>- (possibly) ONP voice telephony: proposal for a European Parliament and Council directive.</p>
<p>- (possibly) proposal for a Council decision on inter-administration telematic networks for statistics relating to the trading of goods between member states (EDICOM).</p>
<p>- (possibly) Draft Council decision on promotion of multilingualism in the information society.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a European Parliament and Council directive on common rules for the development of Community postal services and the improvement of quality of service.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for a Council decision regarding the definition and implementation of Community policy in the field of telecommunications and postal services.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Health aspects of mobile phones.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Centre for European Policy Studies (CEPS) holds workshop on &quot;Completing the internal market for electricity: the meaning of the June 20th decision&quot; (1300/1100 GMT). Speakers include MEP Claude Desama. Venue: Place du Congres 1. Contact: CEPS (322) 229 3911.</p>
<p>MONDAY, SEPTEMBER 30</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - IGC Working Party of EU foreign ministers' representatives meets to continue review of EU treaties. Topics include: flexibility, follow-up of specific issues in the light of first round of discussions.</p>
<p>DUBLIN - People First holds conference on &quot;Challenges of living and working in the European information society&quot; (0830/0630 GMT) (To October 1). Topics include: employment and economic structure in the information society; the future of work in the information society; labour market and learning in the information society; living in the information society. Venue: Dublin Castle. Contact: People First (353) 1 661 8904.</p>
<p>OCTOBER</p>
<p>DUBLIN - EU leaders hold special European Council.</p>
<p>Main topics include trade, fight against drugs, EU's future, inter-governmental conference (IGC), employment and preparations for the December ministerial meeting of the World Trade Organisation (WTO) in Singapore.</p>
<p>MALTA - Ministerial meeting on drugs and organised crime.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, OCTOBER 1</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - General Affairs Council (To October 2).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Preparation for December WTO ministerial meeting.</p>
<p>- Mediterranean policy;</p>
<p>- MEDA regulation: adoption of the guidelines for the indicative programmes;</p>
<p>- Conclusion of negotiations with Jordan and Lebanon;</p>
<p>- West Bank and Gaza: Commission proposal for a negotiating mandate.</p>
<p>- Relations with Albania: approval of mandate to negotiate a new agreement.</p>
<p>- Former Yugoslavia:</p>
<p>- Follow-up to electoral process;</p>
<p>- Peace process;</p>
<p>- Medium/long-term strategy.</p>
<p>- Middle East.</p>
<p>- Mandate for negotiation of extension of steel agreements with the former USSR.</p>
<p>- Relations with central and eastern European countries; decisions of association councils.</p>
<p>- Approval to sign supplementary protocols to Baltic FTAs.</p>
<p>- India - Council conclusions on Commission communication.</p>
<p>- ASEAN - Council conclusions on Commission communication; protocol to ASEAN agreement to take account of Vietnam's accession.</p>
<p>- Preparation for SADC ministerial meeting on October 14-15.</p>
<p>- Food aid distribution regulation.</p>
<p>- Mid-term review of decisions on the association of overseas countries and territories.</p>
<p>- Draft joint action on anti-personnel landmines (possible adoption of further joint action).</p>
<p>- KEDO (Korean Peninsular Energy Development Organisation).</p>
<p>- (possibly) Preparation of the association council with Turkey.</p>
<p>- IGC ministerial session.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Touchstone exhibitions and conferences hold conference on &quot;Managing economic transition in central and eastern Europe and central Asia&quot; (To October 3). Venue: Palais des Congres. Contact: Olga Arola, Touchstone exhibitions and conferences (44) 181 332 0044.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Agra Europe holds conference on &quot;CAP reform 1996-2000 and beyond&quot; (To October 2). Venue: Sheraton Hotel. Contact: Agra Europe (44) 1892 511 807.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, OCTOBER 2</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Trade Union Confederation (ETUC) holds conference on &quot;European works councils&quot; (To October 4). Contact: ETUC (322) 224 0411.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, OCTOBER 3</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Transport Council (To October 4).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- External relations:</p>
<p>- Recommendation for a Council decision authorising the Commission to open negotiations on air transport agreements between the Community and Bulgaria, the Czech Republic, Hungary, Poland, Romania and Slovakia.</p>
<p>- Relationship with central and eastern European countries.</p>
<p>- Negotiations between the EU and Switzerland on land and air transport.</p>
<p>- Other measures:</p>
<p>- Proposal for a European Parliament and Council directive on summertime arrangements.</p>
<p>- Surface transport:</p>
<p>a) Road transport:</p>
<p>- (possibly) Access to the road haulage profession.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Taxation of goods vehicles to replace directive 93/89/EEC.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation laying down the conditions under which non-resident carriers may operate national road passenger transport services within a member state.</p>
<p>- Proposal for the modification of Council regulation (EEC) No 684/92 on common rules for the international carriage of passengers by coach and bus.</p>
<p>b) Rail transport:</p>
<p>- (possbly) White paper on the future of the railways.</p>
<p>- Air transport:</p>
<p>- (possibly) Follow-up to white paper on air traffic management.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation on air carrier liabilities in case of accidents.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation amending regulation EEC/3922/91 on the harmonisation of technical requirements and administrative procedures in the field of civil aviation.</p>
<p>- Maritime transport:</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal on the compilation of lists of passengers on roll-on roll-off ferries.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council directive setting up a harmonised safety regime for fishing vessels of 24 metres or more in length.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for a Council directive amending Council directive 93/75/EEC concerning minimum requirements for vessels bound for or leaving Community ports and carrying dangerous or polluting goods.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for a Council directive amending directive 94/58/EEC on the minimum level of training for seafarers.</p>
<p>LIEGE, Belgium - European Institute for Legal Studies &quot;Fernand Dehousse&quot; holds conference on &quot;Regional trade agreements and multilateral rules after the Uruguay Round: convergence, divergence and interaction&quot; (To October 5). Venue: Palais des Congres. Contact: Xavier Denoel, Liege University (32) 41 66 3156.</p>
<p>MONDAY, OCTOBER 7</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Research Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Financial supplement to the fourth framework programme/task forces.</p>
<p>- Follow-up to the green paper on innovation.</p>
<p>- International cooperation in the research and technological (RTD) development field:</p>
<p>- Science and technology cooperation strategy with Mediterranean countries;</p>
<p>- (possibly) Bilateral science and technology agreements with several third countries.</p>
<p>- Joint Research Centre (JRC): Commission report on progress in the implementation of Council conclusions of April 21, 1994 on the role of the JRC.</p>
<p>- Fifth RTD framework programme.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Evaluation of Community RTD activities.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, OCTOBER 8</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Industry Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Implications of the information society for EU policies.</p>
<p>- Review of the action plan &quot;Europe's way to the information society&quot;.</p>
<p>- Member state experiences.</p>
<p>- The information society and services for industry.</p>
<p>- Standardisation and the information society.</p>
<p>- Information society and the citizen.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Multilingual information society.</p>
<p>- (possibly) The information society and space.</p>
<p>- Green paper on the social aspects of the information society.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Euro-Mediterranean committee for the Barcelona process meets (To October 9).</p>
<p>GALICIA, Spain - European Commission's DG XVI, Committee of the Regions and Galicia hold seminar on land-use planning in the Atlantic Arc region.</p>
<p>LONDON - Agra Europe holds third annual European meat industry conference &quot;Meat '96&quot;. Topics include: EU policy for meat and livestock; EU policy, European meat producation and trade - perspectives from UK and Germany; market outlook for beef, sheepmeat, pigmeat and poultry; BSE and the effects on European meat consumption; rebuilding the image of meat; regaining consumer confidence. Venue: Copthorne Tara Hotel. Contact: Agra Europe (44) 1892 51 18 07.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, OCTOBER 10</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Cogen Europe holds third annual conference on &quot;Europe's cogeneration markets of the future: prospects and challenges&quot; (To October 11). Venue: Sheraton Hotel. Contact: Cogen Europe (322) 772 8290.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, OCTOBER 11</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Institute for Asian Studies (EIAS) holds conference on &quot;APEC and the EU&quot;. Main discussions focus on what APEC is, what it actually does and what it means for EU policy makers and business. Contact: EIAS, Kerstin Bergloef (322) 230 81 22.</p>
<p>SUNDAY, OCTOBER 13</p>
<p>AUSTRIA - Austria holds its first elections to the European Parliament, electing 21 deputies.</p>
<p>MONDAY, OCTOBER 14</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - ECOFIN Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- EMU third stage: preparation for Dublin European Council.</p>
<p>- European Investment Bank (EIB) loans to third countries:</p>
<p>- New guarantee system;</p>
<p>- Renewal of envelopes for eastern Europe, the Mediterranean and ALA.</p>
<p>- Protection of the Community's financial interests: regulation on on-the-spot checks and inspections (final adoption).</p>
<p>- Fight against fraud: transit sector.</p>
<p>- Taxation issues.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Fisheries Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation laying down (new) technical measures for the conservation of fishery resources.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation on logbooks and landing declarations.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Commission report on direct landing of fish.</p>
<p>- Commission report on fishing and responsible marketing.</p>
<p>- Proposal for Council regulation fixing the conditions of access to waters and resources of the Baltic Sea.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council decision on Multi-Annual Guidance Programme (MAGP) IV.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for a Council regulation on the fixing of management objectives and strategies for certain fisheries for the period 1994-1997.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for a Council regulation amending for the sixteenth time regulation (EEC) No. 3094/86 laying down certain technical measures for the conservation of fishery resources (drift-nets).</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for a Council regulation amending previous Council regulations opening and providing for the administration of autonomous Community tariff quotas for certain fishery products (1996) or for tariff suspensions (1996).</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for a Council regulation (EC) amending regulation (EEC) No. 2847/93 establishing a control system applicable to the common fisheries policy (establishment of a Community catch-reporting database).</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation (EC) laying down common marketing standards for certain fishery products.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation introducing transitional measures into regulation (EC) No 1624/94 laying down certain technical measures for the conservation of fishery resources in the Mediterranean.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for a Council regulation (EC) amending regulation (EEC) No. 2847/93 establishing a control system applicable to the common fisheries policy (satellite monitoring).</p>
<p>- Commission report on the application of the basic regulation (No. 3760/92).</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for Council regulation (EC) amending for the fourth time regulation (EEC) No 3699/93 laying down the criteria and conditions for Community structural funding in the fishing and aquaculture sector as well as the processing and marketing of their products.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Commission report on control operations in 1995.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Commission report on MAGP III.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Conclusion of new fisheries agreements with:</p>
<p>a) Estonia;</p>
<p>b) Latvia;</p>
<p>c) Lithuania.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Venice conference on marine management in the Mediterranean, November 1996 - final arrangements.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Negotiating mandate for future South Atlantic Fisheries Organisation (SAFO).</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for Council decisions on the conclusion of the agreement in the form of an exchange of letters concerning the provisional application of the protocol setting out the fishing opportunities and financial contribution provided for in the agreements between the European Economic Community and:</p>
<p>a) Angola;</p>
<p>b) Sao Tome;</p>
<p>c) Gambia;</p>
<p>d) Mauritius.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposals for the conclusion of a new fisheries agreement with Mauritania.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Conclusion of fisheries agreements with Russia on behalf of:</p>
<p>a) Sweden;</p>
<p>b) Finland.</p>
<p>- Recommendations for a Council decision authorising the Commission to negotiate fisheries agreements with certain Mediterranean countries.</p>
<p>- Commission report on third countries' activities in Community waters.</p>
<p>LILLE, France - European Commission (DG VII-transport, XI-environment, XVII-energy) and Nord-Pas de Calais Region organise congress (To October 16) on &quot;City and mobility; moving ideas around!&quot;. Venue: Alteris, avenue de la Creativite 3, 59650 Villeneuve d'Ascq. Contact: Marianne Ryckewaert (33) 20 67 08 21)</p>
<p>CYPRUS - Experts on the implementation of the multiannual rolling work programme for maritime transport in the Mediterranean hold their first meeting.</p>
<p>WINDHOEK, Namibia - EU/Southern Africa Development Council ministerial meeting (To October 15).</p>
<p>TUESDAY, OCTOBER 15</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Environment Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision of the European Parliament and of the Council on the review of the European Community programme of policy and action in relation to the environment and sustainable development &quot;Towards sustainability&quot;.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation amending Council regulation (EE</p>
<p>C) No 3254/91 prohibiting the use of leghold traps in the Community and the introduction into the Community of pelts and manufactured goods of certain wild animal species originating in countries which catch them by means of leghold traps or trapping methods which do not meet international humane trapping standards.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Follow-up of the conference on climate change and preparation of EU position for protocol negociations.</p>
<p>- Preparation for the conference on biodiversity.</p>
<p>- Preparation for the eighth meeting of the parties to the Montreal protocol on substances that deplete the ozone layer.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Commission communication on waste strategy.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council directive amending directive 90/219/EEC on the continued use of genetically modified micro-organisms.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council directive concerning the quality of water intended for human consumption.</p>
<p>- Auto oil:</p>
<p>a) Draft directive relating to the quality of petrol and diesel fuels;</p>
<p>b) Draft directive on measures against air pollution by emissions from motor vehicules - amendment of directives 70/229/EEC and 70/156/EEC.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, OCTOBER 16</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Centre for European Policy Studies (CEPS) holds seminar on &quot;Water, politics and security in the Mediterranean Region&quot; (0915/0715 GMT). Venue: Place du Congres 1. Contact: Shireen Hunter, CEPS (322) 229 3911.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, OCTOBER 17</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Executive committee of Schengen group on free movement of people meets at ministerial level under Luxembourg presidency. Venue: Kirchberg conference centre. Luxembourg is hoping to achieve admittance of Nordic countries to Schengen accord during its presidency of the group, with signature of accession protocols for Denmark, Finland and Sweden and association protocols for Iceland and Norway at December 19 meeting.</p>
<p>SUNDAY, OCTOBER 20</p>
<p>FINLAND - Finland holds municipal elections and the first elections to the European Parliament on the same day.</p>
<p>MONDAY, OCTOBER 21</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament plenary session (To October 25).</p>
<p>TUESDAY, OCTOBER 22</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - Confederation of European Paper Industries (CEPI) holds conference on &quot;Forest management and paper: growing cooperation&quot;. Contact: CEPI (322) 627 4911.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, OCTOBER 24</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Tourism Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Commission report on the evaluation of the Community's action plan to assist tourism (1993-1995).</p>
<p>- Proposal for Council decision on a first multiannual programme to assist European tourism (1997-2000) &quot;PHILOXENIA&quot;.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Report by the Commission on the situation regarding travel guides and ski instructors in the EU.</p>
<p>MADRID - European Investment Bank (EIB) holds forum on &quot;The Mediterranean: a space for partnership&quot; (1500/1300 GMT) (To October 25).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- The Mediterranean, a common destiny:</p>
<p>- The EU's Mediterranean policy: from cooperation to partnership;</p>
<p>- The sea, water and cities: preserving a common heritage.</p>
<p>- An area for joint development:</p>
<p>- The dynamic role of trans-national projects;</p>
<p>- The banking sector and north-south partnership.</p>
<p>Speakers include: EIB President Sir Brian Unwin; European Commissioner for Relations with the Mediterranean Manuel Marin; MEP Willy de Clercq; Egyptian Minister of State for Economic Affairs Youssef Boutros-Ghali; Greek Deputy Foreign Minister George Romeos; Jordanian Planning Minister Rima Khalaf; Barcelona Mayor and EU Committee of the Regions President Pasqual Maragall. Contact: Yvonne Berghorst, EIB (352) 4379 3154.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, OCTOBER 25</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Internal Market Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Operation of the internal market:</p>
<p>- Oral report of the Commission including progress report on the SLIM initiative;</p>
<p>- Administrative cooperation;</p>
<p>- Transposition.</p>
<p>- Citizens first.</p>
<p>- Preparation for structured dialogue with central and eastern European countries:</p>
<p>- White paper on approximation of the laws of central and eastern European countries in the field of the internal market.</p>
<p>- Three proposed directives concerning the free movement of persons:</p>
<p>a) elimination of controls on persons crossing internal frontiers;</p>
<p>b) abolition of restrictions on movement and residence within the Community;</p>
<p>c) (possibly) the right of third-country nationals to travel in the Community.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive on pluralism and media concentration.</p>
<p>- The &quot;Robert Schuman&quot; action.</p>
<p>- Transparency mechanism for national regulations concerning the information society.</p>
<p>SUNDAY, OCTOBER 27</p>
<p>- European summer time ends - Central European time changes from GMT +2 to GMT +1.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
