<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2742" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks close stronger with resources rally.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks close stronger with resources rally.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>CHANGE				    CHANGE</p>
<p>TSE	  5150.90    +33.33  HI  5150.90     LO	5122.60</p>
<p>DJI	  5721.26    +21.82  GOLD (LONDON)   US$387.30 +0.90</p>
<p>FTSE100    3883.20    +19.50  GOLD (NY-COMEX) US$392.30 -0.10</p>
<p>NIKKEI    21127.01    +20.60  LME CASH NICKEL US$6973   +28.0</p>
<p>CANDLR	1.3736		LME CASH ALUM   US$1447.0  -6.0</p>
<p>CAN 30-YR   103.10     +0.30  NYMEX CRUDE     US$22.86  -0.40</p>
<p>--------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>* Toronto stocks ended higher boosted by a rally in golds and base metals. * No U.S. rate hike, markets debating Canadian ease. * 87.98 million shares traded worth C$1.25 billion.  </p>
<p>Toronto stocks rallied to close higher on Tuesday, surging ahead on strength in the resource sectors.</p>
<p>&quot;Canadian gold stocks led Canadian stock prices higher,&quot; said Richardson Greenshields analyst Linda Lehman in a market report. The Toronto Stock Exchange's key 300 Composite Index jumped 33.32 points to reach 5150.89 points.</p>
<p>So far in August the key index has climbed out of its July lows to reach heights it has not hit since early June.</p>
<p>Trading reached 87.98 million shares valued at C$1.25 billion.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're not far from our highs,&quot; said P and C Holdings president Ron Meisels. Toronto's key index hit its all-time high of 5248 points on May 28, 1986.</p>
<p>At this point in the bullish economic cycle, market players are investing in resource stocks, Meisels said.</p>
<p>Markets are also now debating whether the Bank of Canada will ease short-term interest rates since the U.S. Federal Open Market Committee did not raise rates at its meeting today, analysts have said.</p>
<p>Canada's central bank can risk the rate cut without excessively widening bond spreads between the two nations.</p>
<p>Golds led all of Toronto's 14 sub-indices higher, gaining 1.38 percent. They were followed by transportation issues, base metals and media issues.</p>
<p>Advancing stocks beat out declining ones 507 to 361, while 275 traded unchanged.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Heavyweight Barrick Gold Corp jumped 0.35 to 37.90 in brisk trading while Black Swan Gold Mines Ltd was Toronto's most active stock in turnover of 2.7 million shares. The small prospector slipped 0.06 to 1.44 after recent strength as investors await drill results.</p>
<p>-- Lydia Zajc, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
