<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2750" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian bonds end firmer, outperform U.S. market.</title>
<headline>Canadian bonds end firmer, outperform U.S. market.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian bonds closed firmer and outperformed their U.S. counterparts on Tuesday on increased expectations that the Bank of Canada could soon cut interest rates, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The T-bill market got a bid and it's just extended its way up the curve,&quot; said one Toronto dealer. &quot;The money market is rallying and the Bank of Canada is not getting in the way of it.&quot;</p>
<p>Canada's 8.0 percent bond due 2023 rose C$0.32 to C$103.02 to yield 7.730 percent. The U.S. 30-year benchmark fell 2/32 to yield 6.80 percent.  </p>
<p>The spread between the benchmark bonds narrowed to 93 basis points from 96 basis points at the close of trading on Monday.</p>
<p>Both Canadian and U.S. bond markets were focused on the meeting today of the U.S. Federal Reserve's rate-setting Federal Open Market Committee. As expected, the FOMC left U.S. interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>The Fed's decision increased expectations that the Bank of Canada will lower Canadian short-term interest rates. Expectations of a rate cut were priced into the money market which provided a firm bid across the curve, analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The front end is very bullish. Traders pretty much expect another rate cut from the Bank of Canada,&quot; said Sheldon Dong, manager of fixed-income research with Midland Walwyn Capital Inc.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the Government of Canada will auction C$2.7 billion of 7.0 percent bonds due September 1, 2001.</p>
<p>In other prices, the 7.0 percent of 2006 rose C$0.29 to C$98.33 to yield 7.231 percent. The U.S. 10-year benchmark traded unchanged to yield 6.58 percent.</p>
<p>The spread between the two bonds narrowed to 65 basis points from 69 basis points at the close of trading on Monday.  </p>
<p>The three-month cash bill traded at 4.05 percent against the U.S. three-month bill at 5.17 percent.</p>
<p>-- Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
