<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2751" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Investors buzzing around Black Swan Gold.</title>
<headline>Investors buzzing around Black Swan Gold.</headline>
<byline>Heather Scoffield</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investors with &quot;exploration fever&quot; have latched onto Black Swan Gold Mines Ltd, hoping drill results expected this week will line their pockets with paper profits.</p>
<p>&quot;There certainly are rumors that the results they've got from their Brazilian exploration are going to be positive,&quot; said Fred Ketchen, senior vice-president at ScotiaMcLeod.</p>
<p>&quot;It's all part of the current phenomenon -- exploration fever.&quot;</p>
<p>Black Swan was the most active stock on the Toronto Stock Exchange on Tuesday after heavy trading on Monday and last Friday. The stock was down C$0.05 to C$1.45 on volume of 2.6 million shares Tuesday.</p>
<p>But the flurry of speculative interest in the stock is not linked to anything concrete, company spokesman Richard Simpson said from the company's headquarters in Vancouver.</p>
<p>Drilling results from Black Swan's 50 percent-owned gold project in Brazil likely will released until later this week, he said, adding that the results are very preliminary.</p>
<p>&quot;I know there'll be gold in the hole,&quot; said Simpson. &quot;As to what grade it will be, whether it will be above or below the expectations of the market, I simply don't know. They're always looking for pretty jazzy stuff.&quot;</p>
<p>The rumor in the market is that the results will be good, and investors, especially institutional investors under pressure to show robust returns, are placing their bets, analysts said.</p>
<p>Mutual funds that burnished their performances on high returns from investments in such high-flying explorations stocks as Bre-X Resources Ltd and Diamond Fields Resources are quick to pile into junior mining shares with any hint of potential.</p>
<p>Although many previously Hot junior mining stocks cooled off quickly in June and July, investors seem to have forgotten their earlier rough ride, said Barry Cooper, a mining analyst at Wood Gundy.</p>
<p>&quot;The 'once burned twice shy' saying doesn't work in junior gold stocks,&quot; he noted.</p>
<p>The attraction with Black Swan is a limited downside, since the stock has been trading around the C$1.50 mark, added ScotiaMcLeod's Ketchen.</p>
<p>&quot;Whereas the upside potential, if they come up with something, can be rather impressive.&quot;</p>
<p>Black Swan shares its Cata Preta gold project in the Brazilian State of Minas Gerais with Sul America Mineracao Ltda, a Brazilian company.</p>
<p>Black Swan is in the midst of negotiating a takeover of its partner to gain a 100 percent interest in the Cata Preta and acquire Sul America's other Brazilian properties.</p>
<p>The drill results expected this week are from hole 23, the first of a 30-hole series expected to be completed by the end of the year.</p>
<p>Black Swan plans to drill a total of 150 holes to determine how much gold lies beneath a surface deposit already explored.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
