<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2756" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - U.S. technology trade publications.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - U.S. technology trade publications.</headline>
<text>
<p>For the week of Aug. 19, here are some of the top stories reported in major U.S. technology trade publications.</p>
<p>-----------</p>
<p>PC WEEK - Three of the biggest storage managment vendors are preparing major rollouts this fall of new products and technologies to help information systems administrators centrally backup and manage growing stores of enterprise data, PC Week reported in the August 19 issue.</p>
<p>Seagate Technology will ship next week ExecView 2.01, to manage backup and storage management lines purchased by Seagate and Cheyenne Software will announce a version of its ARCserve 6 that backs up open files.</p>
<p>Microsoft Corp has made a long jump to rival that of Carl Lewis with its Internet Explorer 3.0, leaping ahead of Netscape's Navigator 3.0 in several areas, PC Week Labs reported, but Netscape still has a size and speed advantage over Internet Explorer.</p>
<p>-----------</p>
<p>INFOWORLD - Intel Corp has started developing a common data security architecture designed to integrate security software, operating systems and third party applications, into its microprocessor architecture sometime next year, Infoworld reported in the August 19 issue.</p>
<p>Microsoft and two partners will detail a strategy designed to provide high-speed access to mainframe data from a Web browser. One partner, Polaris Communications, will sell the solution and it is expected to be available in mid-September.</p>
<p>-----------</p>
<p>INFORMATION WEEK - Object-relational databases have emerged as the key battleground of the $6 billion database market, Information Week reports in its Aug. 19 cover story.</p>
<p>Oracle Corp, Informix Corp and International Business Machines Corp are vying for the lead.</p>
<p>IBM is preparing to ship the most powerful versions yet of its System/390 servers, capable of handling 44 million instructions per second, Information Week reports.</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>COMPUTER RESELLER NEWS - One year after Netscape Communications Corp's initial public offering, the company is feeling the heat from Microsoft Corp as the software giant has turned its guns on the Internet powerhouse.</p>
<p>Netscape and Microsoft are battling over Web-based multimedia messaging, the latest skirmish in the war for Internet-dominance, Computer Reseller News reported August 19.</p>
<p>Major distributors are pressing major PC vendors to shift more final assembly of PCs to the distribution channel and are moving forward with plans to manufacture their own systems in an effort to ward off chronic product shortages, CRN reported.</p>
<p>-------</p>
<p>COMPUTERWORLD - Basic problems with Microsoft Corp's new World Wide Web browser, Internet Explorer 3.0, have frustrated many early users, Computerworld reported in the August 19 issue.</p>
<p>Internet users could face a new problem, hostile Active X Web components on the World Wide Web, as Microsoft has acknowledged that it is scrambling to tighten security for its Active X technology.</p>
<p>A debate over network computer devices to access the Internet increased at the Data Warehouse WOrld conference, when a database analyst said that the Internet will push the network computers into popularity and onto desktops, Computerworld reported in the August 19 issue.</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING TIMES - New attempts to solve a conundrum of multimedia computing will headline the eighth Hot Chips conference in Palo Alto, Calif., this week. Vendors will show an array of architectures for combined audio, video, 3D and communications processing, plus the first detailed description of Microsoft's Talisman media chip architecture, EE Times reported in the August 19 issue.</p>
<p>VIScorp, a set-top box maker based in Chicago, is getting the rights to Amiga, once the property of the now-defunct PC pioneer Commodore. VISCorp is promising improved versions of the aging but still-respected platform that had one of the biggest cults in the computer industry.</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>ELECTRONIC BUYERS' NEWS -  Intel Corp will pull the plug in early 1997 of its Pentium chip-set development as part of its effort to push its low-end Pentium Pro processor into the mainstream market, Electronic Buyers News reported in the August 19 issue.</p>
<p>DRAM prices continue on their downward path as suppliers scramble to cut their losses and boost profit margins in what looks like a long-term supply glut, said EBN's Barometer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
