<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2757" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Jewell lawyer, expert say lie test clears suspect.</title>
<headline>Jewell lawyer, expert say lie test clears suspect.</headline>
<byline>Mike Cooper</byline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Olympic bomb suspect Richard Jewell passed a lie detector test in which he denied any involvement in the deadly July 27 attack, a polygraph expert hired by one of Jewell's attorneys said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Former Federal Bureau of Investigation agent Dick Rackleff said 15 hours of polygraph tests with Jewell on Aug. 4 and 15 were &quot;unquestionable and conclusive from the standpoint that he was not involved in any way with the explosive device.&quot;</p>
<p>Jewell's attorneys paid for the polygraph exam in an effort to show the security guard had nothing to do with the pipe bombing that left two people dead and more than 100 injured at downtown Atlanta's Centennial Olympic Park.</p>
<p>Jewell, 33, who was hailed as a hero in the immediate aftermath of the bombing, remains a suspect in the FBI's investigation.</p>
<p>&quot;My conclusion was that he's totally innocent of any connection with that pipe bomb that went off in the park which he discovered,&quot; said Rackleff, who administered polygraph examinations for the FBI in Atlanta from 1979 to 1990.</p>
<p>Jewell did not know a suspicious backpack contained a bomb when he pointed it out to a Georgia Bureau of Investigation agent the night of the blast, Rackleff said.</p>
<p>Jack Martin, a criminal attorney for Jewell, said the results show &quot;he didn't have anything to do with it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There's not one shred of physical evidence to connect him to the crime. He's passed a lie detector test. If there was any hard evidence he'd be arrested,&quot; Martin said.</p>
<p>Speaking to reporters in front of a federal courthouse, he said the FBI should apologise to Jewell for identifying him as a suspect. &quot;The man deserves an apology. Three weeks ago the FBI came to his residence, gave a news conference in front of his residence and named him as a suspect,&quot; Martin said. &quot;We're here on their turf and we're asking for that apology.&quot;</p>
<p>While working as a security guard at an AT&amp;T Olympic pavilion near the park, Jewell discovered the green knapsack that contained the pipe bomb and helped police clear crowds from the area before it detonated.</p>
<p>&quot;The next time somebody sees a suspicious package like that and they want to turn it over to law enforcement and do the right thing, I hope that they don't hesitate to act for fear that 'Wait a second, I'm going to be the suspect,'&quot; Martin said.</p>
<p>He said Jewell's career in law enforcement had been &quot;ruined&quot; because he was named in the case. He remains in the apartment he shared with his mother, unable to leave without being chased by hordes of reporters and FBI agents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
