<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2782" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. spot prods stable in ACCESS trade after APIs.</title>
<headline>U.S. spot prods stable in ACCESS trade after APIs.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot gasoline and heating oil prices were stable in ACCESS trade late Tuesday after release of weekly API inventory data deemed slightly bearish by traders.</p>
<p>In earlier NYMEX trade, heat futures fell 0.91 cent and gasoline futures slid 1.26 cents in a reversal of two days of sharply higher prices, traders said.</p>
<p>The API data, for the week ended August 16, showed a seasonal 1.83-million-barrel increase in distillate inventories on the heels of several weeks of drawdowns and scanty builds.</p>
<p>Total distillate stocks stand at 106 million barrels, almost 18 million lower than the comparable period last year, the report said.</p>
<p>It showed a seasonal gasoline draw of 864,000 barrels, putting stocks 1.4 million below last year's levels. But the data showed a bearish 2.2 million build in reformulated gasoline stocks in New York Harbor.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd call the numbers a little on the bearish side,&quot; one Gulf Coast trader said. &quot;Gasoline is only a million or so barrels less than last year, so it's slowly building back to normal.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
