<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2789" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IBM licenses Taligent for Sun's Java.</title>
<headline>IBM licenses Taligent for Sun's Java.</headline>
<dateline>CUPERTINO, Calif. 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>International Business Machines Corp and Sun Microsystems Inc said they had agreed to integrate IBM's Taligent technology into Sun's Java software to give Java a more international accent.</p>
<p>The Taligent enhancements would allow Java, which is a software development system written by programmers working in American English, to automatically recognize the language differences of individual countries.</p>
<p>They said the Taligent software to be utilized in Java is based on the Unicode international character set that allows computer programmers to develop software for global use.  </p>
<p>The Taligent software will allow Java software applets and full-size applications to adapt to international dating systems, non-U.S. currencies, and other numbers and characters that fit a respective countries' language format.</p>
<p>Java is a programming system that allows software designers to transform the billboard like screens of computer screens into dynamic scenes that incorporate not only text, but moving graphics, video, and sound features.</p>
<p>Scores of leading international computer, communications, and consumer electronics companies have licensed Java software for use in Internet related products they are developing.  </p>
<p>&quot;Internationalization is a critical component for Java that our developers have been asking us to provide,&quot;  said Jon Kannegaard, vice president of software products at JavaSoft, the division responsible for developing Sun's Java software.</p>
<p>Taligent was orginally formed in 1991 as a joint venture which included Apple Computer Inc and IBM and later, Hewlett-Packard Co.</p>
<p>-- Eric Auchard, New York Newsdesk, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CUPERTINO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
