<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2800" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYC Councilman urges schools to switch from coal.</title>
<headline>NYC Councilman urges schools to switch from coal.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A New York City councilman on Tuesday said he was trying to get the Board of Education to approve a faster and less costly plan to switch schools to natural gas from coal to cut pollution and save money.</p>
<p>Saying that the Board of Education had been studying the issue for 10 years, Israel Ruiz said the City Council, Mayor Rudolph Giuliani and Gov. George Pataki supported the plan to have Consolidated Edison Co convert about 120 schools.</p>
<p>The capital budget for school construction is $256 million in the 1997 fiscal year and the the utility would need about $30 million to begin the conversions, the councilman said.  </p>
<p>He explained that the rest of the program's costs would be met by a fee of $1 per therm that the schools would pay into a fund. One therm is equivalent to 100,000 British Thermal Units.</p>
<p>Ruiz said that it would cost about $750,000 to convert each of the 120 schools, about $215,000 less than under a different plan the city now is exploring.</p>
<p>He added that Brooklyn Union Gas has contacted him to see if it also would be interested in converting the schools in the area it serves under similar terms.</p>
<p>Using Con Edison to switch just over one-third of the city's 304 coal-burning schools would ensure they are converted more swiftly than having the Board of Education do another study and ask potential suppliers for their proposals, as the agency has proposed.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to make sure that they udnerstand that the mayor, city council and governor want to get this done,&quot; Ruiz added.</p>
<p>New York City now burns about 300 tons of coal at each of the schools that still use this heating method.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
