<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2840" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US corporate debt ends firm, new issues trade up.</title>
<headline>US corporate debt ends firm, new issues trade up.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. corporate bonds ended Tuesday's session mostly unchanged, except for strong new issues, as Federal Reserve policymakers left interest rates untouched, dealers said.</p>
<p>Investment-grade yield spreads remained untested in light volume as U.S. Treasuries wallowed in a narrow trading range.</p>
<p>The Fed was almost universally expected to hold monetary policy pat and market reaction to its decision was little to none, dealers said.</p>
<p>Action took place in the high-yield arena as new debt was issued and snatched up after hitting the secondary market.  </p>
<p>After reworking the deal structure and shrinking the amount of proceeds, Sprint Spectrum LP priced its long-awaited $523 million (proceeds) deal in two-tranches via lead managers Merrill Lynch &amp; Co and Lehman Brothers.</p>
<p>The first tranche of $250 million in 10-year senior notes priced at par with an 11 percent coupon. The issue gained after freed to trade, closing at a 101-1/4 bid, 102 offer.</p>
<p>The tranche is non-callable for five years and has a three-year equity call for 35 percent at 111.  </p>
<p>The $140 million in senior notes due 2004 priced at 98.095 to yield 12 percent, but gained to a 98-3/4 bid, 99-1/2 offer by the close. The paper rates a B3/B-minus and was lead managed by Merrill Lynch &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's raised the company's corporate credit rating to B-minus from CCC-plus, reflecting the fact that the refinancing will allow the company to repay its outstanding debt and avoid onerous near-term maturities.</p>
<p>In other secondary trade, troubled Stratosphere first mortgage notes hung in a 81 bid, 83 offer market, unchanged from last Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
