<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2842" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dlr/yen ends up in US, eyes trade, plays down FOMC.</title>
<headline>Dlr/yen ends up in US, eyes trade, plays down FOMC.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar finished higher versus the yen after a dramatic drop in the U.S. international trade deficit overshadowed fleeting disappointment that the Federal Reserve left interest rates unchanged, experts said.</p>
<p>The U.S. trade gap shrank overall by 23.1 percent in June to $8.11 billion, much less than the $9.4 billion shortfall forecasted by Wall Street economists.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a good trade number,&quot; said Greg Pearman, chief dealer at Credit Commerciale de France. &quot;There was definitely one huge buyer today who right after the number bought a lot of dollars for yen.&quot;  </p>
<p>The dollar ended at 108.31/36 yen, higher than 107.93/98 yen at the opening. The U.S. unit closed at 1.4891/96 marks, slightly below 1.4905 marks at the opening.</p>
<p>After the trade figures hit the market, the dollar climbed above 108 yen. The Fed's decision to hold interest rates steady only pressured the dollar temporarily because most traders expected no change in monetary policy anyway.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a fractional disappointment bascially,&quot; said Chris Turner, a currency strategist at I.D.E.A. Inc. &quot;We saw recently a survey of 37 primary dealers in the U.S. (and) not one of them were going for a Fed rate hike today.&quot;  </p>
<p>The mark also gained against the yen despite growing hopes for a cut in the 3.30 percent repo rate after news that German M3 money supply growth slowed to an annualized rate of 8.6 percent in July from 9.6 percent in June. The Bundesbank council meets to discuss monetary policy on Thursday.</p>
<p>Mark/yen traded around 72.75 near the close, up from 72.37 in early New York dealings.</p>
<p>The mark's break above key technical resistance at 72.60 yen sparked additional orders to buy the German currency and sell yen, traders said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Once it (mark/yen) broke through there, it was a technical move that pushed it up,&quot; said Frank Pusateri, a vice president of corporate foreign exchange at Mellon Bank N.A. &quot;Of course, as (the yen) got weaker againt the mark, (the yen) got weaker against the dollar.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar had also strengthened slightly versus the yen in Asia after remarks by Eisuke Sakakibara, director-general of the Japanese Finance Ministry's International Finance Bureau.</p>
<p>He told the Nikkei Finance Daily that, even if the dollar rises above 110 yen, there is only a small chance of such a rise having an adverse effect on the Japanese economy.  </p>
<p>&quot;For them to successfully be able to get out of their doldrums in their economy ... and help the banks recover, they basically need the dollar up,&quot; said Credit Commerciale's Pearman.</p>
<p>In other trade, the dollar finished at 1.2067/74 Swiss francs, down from 1.2093/98 at the open.</p>
<p>Sterling rose to US$1.5477/84 from US$1.5445/55.</p>
<p>The dollar edged lower to Canadian $1.3735/40 from C$1.3741/46.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar closed at $0.7852/57.</p>
<p>-- Donna Sells 212-859-1668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
