<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2847" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. stock index futures end mixed, Sept S&amp;P down.</title>
<headline>U.S. stock index futures end mixed, Sept S&amp;P down.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. stock index futures finished mixed and September Standard and Poor's 500 futures lower after a session of thin, quiet trading.</p>
<p>Trading was unremarkable except for a midday flurry of activity that set the session's high and low after the Fed announced it would keep interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>After the Fed announcement, September S&amp;P 500 futures rushed to the session high at 668.50, then slumped to the session low at 666.50 with weak Treasury bonds before recovering near the middle of the day's range to consolidate into the close.  </p>
<p>Traders said selling interest was heaviest at 668.00 and 668.50, with small stops noted when September dropped through 667.00.</p>
<p>&quot;The locals bid it up until they hit some stops, there was no followthrough at 668.50 and we had some good selling coming in,&quot; said an S&amp;P 500 trader. &quot;Some resting stop orders to the downside were triggered and the week low of 666.40 held,&quot; allowing September to drift higher again, he said.</p>
<p>September S&amp;P 500 futures ended down 0.25 points at 667.95, in the middle of the day's 666.50 to 668.50 range.  </p>
<p>September S&amp;Ps posted an inside trading day, indicative of a market in consolidation.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very light and roughly between 669.00 and 666.00, a range which is fairly tight for this market,&quot; an S&amp;P trader said.</p>
<p>He said a bullish bias was underpinning the market, but September needed to work through the 669.20 to 675.00 zone before any real upside progress can be made.</p>
<p>&quot;I think until we go up and trade 675.00 it's a big negative but when we can clear it, it will be a very positive sign technically,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>One S&amp;P trader noted a bit more action than usual in the Sep/Dec spread.</p>
<p>Midcap 400 fell 0.50 to end at 231.20, Value Line settled up 1.30 points to 619.90, NYSE Composite rose 0.15 to 357.45, and Nikkei 225 rose 40.0 points to 21,205.0 -Derivatives desk(312)408-8750 E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
