<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2861" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natgas futures end down sharply as longs exit.</title>
<headline>Natgas futures end down sharply as longs exit.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures ended down sharply Tuesday in a lackluster session, as longs rushed to liquidate amid perceptions a storm in the Caribbean would not threaten U.S. Gulf gas production, sources said.</p>
<p>September tumbled 13.4 cents to close near the day's low at $2.053 per million British thermal units. Oct settled 13 cents lower at $2.124. Others ended down by one to 10.5 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;People are not expecting it (Hurricane Dolly) to affect a lot of production. I think it was a bit overdone and we could rebound a little from here, but it depends on what the storm does overnight,&quot; said one Houston-based trader.  </p>
<p>But forecasters still expected Dolly to approach the Texas-Mexico border, and some traders remained concerned that a slight turn to the north could put offshore Texas platforms in jeopardy.</p>
<p>Hurricane Dolly slammed into Mexico's Yucatan peninsula Tuesday afternoon with 75 mph winds, moving west-northwest at 13 mph. At 1400 EDT, the center was located at 19.3 degrees north and 87.9 degrees west.</p>
<p>Cash prices at the U.S. Gulf Coast firmed slightly Tuesday to about the $2.10 area, still almost 20 cents below August indices. Midcon pipes scored similar gains to the low-$1.90s, about 20 cents under August 1 levels.</p>
<p>The 12-month strip tumbled 6.2 cents to $2.133. NYMEX said 33,849 Henry Hub contracts traded, up from Monday's revised tally of 24,317.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Henry Hub natgas futures expire Monday, August 26.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Permian natgas closed four cents lower at $1.82, while deferreds settled down by 3.5 cents but again were untraded. NYMEX said 30 Permian contracts traded, down from Monday's total of 85.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Permian natgas futures expire Wednesday August 28.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, September finished down by seven cents at $1.88, while deferreds ended one to six cents lower. The East/West spread narrowed by 6.4 cents to 17.3 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>KCBT September natgas futures expire Tuesday, August 27.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
