<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2862" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: LDC debts seesaw in narrow ranges, ignore Fed.</title>
<headline>LDC debts seesaw in narrow ranges, ignore Fed.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. interest rate status quo was shrugged off in the quiet trading of emerging market debts and the Brady bonds finished the day mostly flat.</p>
<p>&quot;The absence of a rate hike was already priced in,&quot; said Shafiq Islam, emerging market fixed income strategist at Credit Suisse. &quot;It is marginally positive.&quot;</p>
<p>Argentina Bradies came under light pressure as investors watched with concern how the new economy minisiter, Roque Fernandez, negotiates between raising taxes to cut deficits and appeasing the public to risk falling further behind fiscal target, traders said.  </p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund officials are in Buenos Aires to review Argentine fiscal deficits which are expected to reach $6.6 billion this year.</p>
<p>Argentina FRBs eased 1/8 to 77-1/4 and Argentina Pars slipped 3/8 to 54-3/4.</p>
<p>Brazil fared slightly better than Argentina, with Brazil C adding 3/8 to 65-1/8.</p>
<p>&quot;With or without (Brady bond) buy-back, Brazil papers may still have some room to rise,&quot; said a Brady trader.  </p>
<p>While Brazil's trade deficit of $334 million in July would not pose a problem to the currency, the stalled reform continued casting a shadow, he said.</p>
<p>Mexico papers were underpinned by the robust 7.2 percent gross domestic product growth in the second quarter, but some market participants questioned if the optimism might be overstated.</p>
<p>&quot;If the second quarter is compared to the first quarter on a seasonally adjusted basis, you get only a one-percent growth,&quot; said Shafiq at Credit Suisse.</p>
<p>Mexico Pars rose 1/8 to 67-1/2 and Discount added 1/4 to 80-3/8.</p>
<p>Among East European papers, Bulgaria was depressed by recurring concerns about its weak currency and low level of reserves, traders said.</p>
<p>Bulgaria FLRB lost 1/2 to 33-1/4.</p>
<p>Russia debt prices retreated on profit-taking.</p>
<p>&quot;We are comfortable with Russia,&quot; said a U.S. bank trader. With the IMF about to release the delayed tranche of aid and the overall low indebtedness, Russia debts were still relatively cheap, he said.</p>
<p>Russia dollar Vnesh eased 3/8 to 61.00</p>
<p>-- Nailene Chou Wiest, 212-859-1674</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
