<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2869" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. foreign crude interest wilts on NYMEX expiry.</title>
<headline>U.S. foreign crude interest wilts on NYMEX expiry.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Interest in U.S. foreign crude remained subdued amid choppy outright price activity related to the expiry on Tuesday of NYMEX September crude futures.</p>
<p>The absence of September cargoes offered into the U.S. Gulf was still blamed on narrow profit margins.</p>
<p>&quot;Apart from one or two Qua Iboes and maybe a Bonny Light, nobody's seen anything,&quot; a Houston trader said.</p>
<p>Vague rumors of Malaysian Tapis being offered for September delivery could not be immediately pinned down.</p>
<p>Overall, profit taking in crude futures kept discussion in physical markets to a minimum, traders said.  </p>
<p>September West Texas Intermediate/Cushing was pegged at $22.80-90 a barrel, down 25 cents from Monday's cash market.</p>
<p>Latin American crude differentials, meanwhile, clawed higher amid tight supplies.</p>
<p>September Cusiana was heard offered close to WTI parity, up from October minus 27 cents fob in a recent deal, with late Sept asked at a shade under November WTI.</p>
<p>Spot Cano Limon for September was pegged around WTI minus $1.65-70 a barrel fob, after Ecopetrol's tender last week went for minus $1.65 a barrel, traders said.</p>
<p>A couple of September Oriente cargoes were seen available and priced around WTI minus $1.80.</p>
<p>The upgrading of Tropical Storm Dolly to a hurricane just before making landfall on Mexico's Yucatan peninsula this afternoon, has so far not caused any crude shipping delays.</p>
<p>In the U.S. aftermarket, cash Brent traded at September Brent plus two cents fob for Aug 29-31, less than yesterday's trade at Sept plus 15 cents.</p>
<p>Brent intermonth Sep/Oct traded thrice at 50 cents, off 10 cents from morning levels.</p>
<p>--Jacqueline Wong, New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
