<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2876" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PG&amp;E sees Diablo Canyon at full output Wed..</title>
<headline>PG&amp;E sees Diablo Canyon at full output Wed..</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pacific Gas &amp; Electric Co (PG&amp;E) said its Diablo Canyon nuclear power units are expected to reach full output Wednesday after being scaled back Monday because of a wildfire in the nearby Los Padres forest.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope to be at 100 percent power tomorrow sometime,&quot; said PG&amp;E spokeswoman Arlene Morris-Versaw, adding the California Department of Forestry started backfires to contain the blaze about two hours ago (1100 PDT/1800 GMT).</p>
<p>Efforts to fight the blaze earlier today were hampered by strong winds.</p>
<p>&quot;The plan is for the backburn to continue until tonight,&quot; she said. &quot;The winds are (now) favorable.&quot;</p>
<p>If the backfires are successful, the utility will check for damage to the insulators of the transmission lines before ramping up both Diablo Canyon units to full power, she said.</p>
<p>The plant's two units, with a combined capacity of 2,160 megawatt (MW), are currentrly producing at 75 percent of capacity.</p>
<p>On Monday, PG&amp;E, as a precaution, shifted all transmission from Diablo Canyon to just one 5,000 kilovolt (KV) line after shutting the two 5,000 KV lines closest to the fire.</p>
<p>Diablo Canyon is at Avila Beach on the California coast.</p>
<p>--New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
