<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2878" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Main Street says sales still soft.</title>
<headline>Main Street says sales still soft.</headline>
<dateline>PHOENIX 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Main Street and Main Inc said sales at its restaurants continue at softer-than-expected levels with same store revenue figures since the end of the company's second quarter down roughly five percent.</p>
<p>Sales continue to remain soft, but we (are focused) on ways to increase earnings,&quot; Joe Panter, president, said in a statement along with the company's second quarter results.</p>
<p>For the quarter ended July 1, the restaurant operator lost $0.92 a share, including a $0.94 per share charge, versus a $0.09 profit one year ago. Same store sales were off two percent for the quarter and 1.7 percent for the six months.  </p>
<p>Main Street said the lower same store sales were attributable, principally, to six restaurants. The company operates a total of 43 casual dining restaurants.</p>
<p>The company noted the performance of its one &quot;Front Row Sports Grill&quot; negatively effected earnings and it is &quot;considering various alternatives&quot; about its future.</p>
<p>Main Street did not say what those alternatives were and a company official was not immediately available to comment.</p>
<p>The company said its total $7.4 million charge covered the write-off of one promissory note, some real estate, pre-opening costs of three restaurants and and other expenses.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83952">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHOENIX"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
