<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2879" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS - Fed stays put, but rate hike seen inevitable.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Fed stays put, but rate hike seen inevitable.</headline>
<byline>Chris Stetkiewicz</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>While the Federal Reserve's Federal Open Market Committee left interest rates unchanged at its meeting Tuesday, the odds of monetary tightening are likely to mount as 1996 comes to a close, analysts said.</p>
<p>Fed policy-makers astutely resisted pressures earlier this summer to raise short-term rates, but economic data over the next several weeks will almost certainly force the Fed to grudgingly tighten credit later this year, analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;My guess is (Fed tightening) is going to be right back on tap after the August data start coming out,&quot; said Salomon Brothers economist Brian Jones.</p>
<p>In a Reuters poll of 28 economists to be released later on Tuesday, a majority predicted the Fed would move to tighten credit at its November 13 meeting.</p>
<p>The Fed has held its target for the federal funds rate -- the rate banks charge each other for overnight loans -- at 5.25 percent since January 31, 1996.  </p>
<p>Despite signs of strong economic growth since then, inflation remains quite low, and the Fed has refrained from raising rates in the absence of more troubling data.</p>
<p>But upcoming U.S. employment data could change all that, analysts said.</p>
<p>Persistent job growth threatens to shatter the economy's recent low-inflation trend and the Fed will not stand idly by and watch that happen, analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The job market is still quite firm. We'll need to see jobless claims move back up pretty soon in order to confirm the economic slowdown story,&quot; said Josh Feinman, global markets economist at BT Securities Corp.</p>
<p>Jobless claims' four-week moving average reached a seven-year low last week, adding to recent warnings of pending wage inflation.</p>
<p>That also suggests the economy continues to churn out new jobs at a pace likely to drag the unemployment rate lower than July's 5.4 percent reading, analysts said.  </p>
<p>The absence of faster inflation amid such robust job creation has many analysts scratching their heads and wondering how long the Fed will hold monetary policy steady.</p>
<p>&quot;Strong job growth has persisted long enough that the Fed will certainly have to stand up and take notice,&quot; said Gary Schlossberg, senior economist at Wells Fargo Bank.</p>
<p>The Fed's inflation-fighting reputation has flourished as the board has kept rates steady with inflation holding below 3.0 percent even as the economy chugs along nicely.  </p>
<p>Critics initially blasted the Fed for failing to tighten credit at its July 2-3 FOMC meeting when a report just two days later showed that 239,000 new jobs were created in June.</p>
<p>But a month later the July report showed a decline to 193,000 in new nonfarm payrolls and, perhaps more important, a slight drop in average hourly earnings.</p>
<p>Fed officials had predicted a slowdown in real gross domestic product from the robust 4.2 percent second-quarter clip. The dip in payroll growth suddenly made that forecast look brilliant, analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;So far the Fed has done the right thing by keeping its powder dry,&quot; Schlossberg said. &quot;There is still a risk the Fed could fall behind the curve, but right now it looks like the economic slowdown is happening.&quot;</p>
<p>The August employment report due September 6 could radically alter the terrain, however.</p>
<p>Salomon's Jones predicts a whopping payrolls gain of 300,000 and an official jobless rate of 5.2 percent in the August report. If correct, that could force the Fed's hand.  </p>
<p>&quot;People tried to make the July report look weak,&quot; Jones added. &quot;But it's not like the July numbers mean we don't have to worry about tightening anymore.&quot;</p>
<p>Yet most analysts still believe the economy will decelerate in time to minimize any future inflation bubble, which may allow the Fed to keep the funds rate steady for several more months.</p>
<p>&quot;They may have gotten lucky, but the economy has validated the Fed's strategy of waiting until they see data for the second half of the year,&quot; Feinman said.</p>
<p>&quot;They did say the (inflation) risks were to the upside, but that the whole point of their strategy was to wait until they saw how the third quarter was turning out,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Analysts said Fed officials would certainly prefer to postpone any rate hikes until after the November 5 presidential election.</p>
<p>--212-859-1664</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
