<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2881" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oglethorpe solicits bids for short-term power.</title>
<headline>Oglethorpe solicits bids for short-term power.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Georgia electric power cooperative Oglethorpe Power Corp said on Tuesday it is soliciting bids from power marketers to supply power on its system through the remainder of the year.</p>
<p>The cooperative, which has peak demand of more than 5,000 megawatts, also said two bidders -- LG&amp;E Energy Corp's LG&amp;E Power and Enron Corp's Enron Power Marketing -- are actively bidding on a long-term power marketing pact with the rural Georgia cooperative.</p>
<p>The short-term deal should be in place when the Enron pact expires at the end of August, and the long-term deal should be closed by year-end, an Oglethorpe spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are currently in detailed negotiations, and will continue to work to accomplish that goal,&quot; said Robert Hosfeld, manager of system control for the cooperative.</p>
<p>The short-term power deal would replace a four-month pact with Enron, which supplied power to the cooperative in exchange for output from its generating plants.</p>
<p>Four marketers, including the LG&amp;E and Enron units and consortiums formed by Duke Power/Louis Dreyfus and Morgan Stanley/PECO had been bidding on the long-term pact with Oglethorpe, which has 39 members and serves 2.6 million people.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
