<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2906" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FDA action on Lilly's Zyprexa seen imminent.</title>
<headline>FDA action on Lilly's Zyprexa seen imminent.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Drawbaugh</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Approval of Eli Lilly &amp; Co's new anti-schizophrenia drug, Zyprexa, is expected to come soon from the U.S. Food and Drug Administration, analysts said.</p>
<p>Marketing clearance for the drug, known generically as olanzapine, would put Lilly in the front of a parade of new anti-schizophrenia medications coming on the U.S. market.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect approval yet this year ... There's been no hint of any issues&quot; from the FDA that might cause delay, said Lilly spokesman Edward West.</p>
<p>Wall Street analysts said approval could come this month.  </p>
<p>The FDA has not scheduled an advisory committee hearing for Zyprexa. West said Lilly has no indication that a committee hearing will be set. Analysts said the drug likely will be cleared without committee deliberations.</p>
<p>&quot;The big expectation would be that Zyprexa will be approved ... That's what's on everybody's radar screen,&quot; said Smith Barney pharmaceuticals analyst Christina Heuer.</p>
<p>Zyprexa received a positive opinion in June from the European Union's Committee for Proprietary Medicinal Products. European marketing approval likely will follow, analysts said.</p>
<p>Several competing products are in the pipeline.  </p>
<p>Close behind Lilly are Abbott Laboratories Inc with Serlect, Zeneca Group Plc with Seroquel and Pfizer Inc with Ziprasidone. All are expected to hit the market within the next 12 months.</p>
<p>Already on the market are Johnson &amp; Johnson's Risperdal, Sandoz AG's Clozaril and the benchmark treatment available since 1967, haloperidol, as well as a host of less frequently prescribed drugs.</p>
<p>Studies have shown that one in 100 people is schizophrenic. Estimates of the annual U.S. market for treating the disease range from $1 billion to $4.5 billion.</p>
<p>Looking at the huge success of Lilly's Prozac in treating clinical depression, drugmakers are hoping to score equally impressive wins with the new anti-schizophrenics.</p>
<p>--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
