<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2907" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY precious metals end steady, Fed makes no move.</title>
<headline>NY precious metals end steady, Fed makes no move.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX and NYMEX precious metals futures ended little changed Tuesday, after news at the close the U.S. Federal Reserve left interest rates unchanged at its latest Open Market Committee Meeting, as expected.</p>
<p>&quot;The Fed's move to keep monetary policy unchanged was expected, but most precious metals have been basing recently, after the slide earlier in the year, with most players now perhaps a bit too complacent about the lack of volatility,&quot; Paine Webber analyst Bernard Savaiko said.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. elections later this year, or signs of inflation, could still cause a breakout,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Few were expecting silver's break out from a two month range Monday, but silver held it's gains today, with a test of further resistance around $5.28 now possible,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>COMEX September silver ended unchanged at $5.21 an ounce after trading in a $5.170-5.230 range, on total estimated volume of 22,000 lots.</p>
<p>&quot;Silver was getting too cheap relative to gold with the gold/silver ratio up around 76 or 77 recently,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The jump in silver prices Monday to two month highs lowered the ratio to back to 74.2.</p>
<p>&quot;The approaching first delivery date for the September COMEX contract, which still has some 270 million ounces of open interest, may have provided some incentive to go long,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>COMEX December gold ended up $0.50 an ounce at $392.90, after trading in a narrow $392.20-393.00 range.</p>
<p>On the charts, gold's uptrend since late June still looks intact, traders said, but the rally's momentum has waned and further gains may just prompt more producer hedging.</p>
<p>Bullion was quoted $387.50/388.00 in New York near the close, from $387.10 at the London afternoon fix, and a New York close Monday at $386.90/387.40.</p>
<p>&quot;The reduced probability that the Federal Reserve will tighten monetary policy ahead of the November presidential elections should help keep gold prices steady until end user demand begins to improve again,&quot; Smith Barney analyst David Rinehimer said.</p>
<p>The next Federal Open Market Committee meeting (FOMC) is due on September 24.</p>
<p>NYMEX October platinum ended up $1.10 an ounce at $404.10, while NYMEX September palladium closed up $1.50 an ounce at $127.25.</p>
<p>&quot;Support in palladium seems to be forming at $124 and is not likely to be penetrated near term,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>Palladium slid to two and a half year lows last week.</p>
<p>&quot;The large open interest in the September NYMEX price could lead prices to push back to $130-136 in the next two weeks.&quot;</p>
<p>--Clive McKeef, New York Commodities Desk, +212-859-1641.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
