<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2910" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. West next-day power firm; back-months lower.</title>
<headline>U.S. West next-day power firm; back-months lower.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Physical electricity prices for next-day delivery in the western U.S. were firm Tuesday, but power for deferred month deliveries were traded mostly lower, brokers and marketers said.</p>
<p>Next-day prices were bolstered by Bonneville Power Administration raising its posting for 16-hour power blocks for Wednesday delivery by two dollars to $17.50 per megawatt hour (MWh), market sources said.</p>
<p>Deferred month values were weaker amid a second-day of active selling, they said. &quot;People are seeing these outer months are well overvalued,&quot; said a Houston trader.</p>
<p>A substantial decline in the natural gas market also pressured electricity prices lower, traders said.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Gulf Coast natgas futures were in the $2.060 area, off more than 12 cents per million British thermal units.</p>
<p>In the physical market, California-Oregon Border (COB) prices for firm, peak delivery were quoted at $16.00-$17.00 per MWh, up from Monday's $15.00-$16.00, market sources said.</p>
<p>September COB power for firm, peak delivery was assessed at $17.10-$17.90, up from Monday's $17.00-$17.40 range.</p>
<p>October COB, with similar delivery terms, was pegged at $15.50-$15.90, down from $15.75-$16.60 on Monday. Firm, peak COB for the 1996 fourth-quarter was valued at $16.90-$17.25, flat from Monday.</p>
<p>At the Mid-Columbia (Mid-C) point in Washington, firm, peak electricity prices for next-day delivery were quoted at $15.00-$15.50 per MWh, up from Monday's $14.50-$15.50.</p>
<p>September Mid-C electricity was pegged at $16.50-$17.10, down slightly from Monday's $16.50-$17.20.</p>
<p>Down at the Palo Verde (PV) switchyard near Phoenix, Ariz., next-day power for peak, firm delivery was valued at $21.00-$22.00 per MWh, near unchanged from Monday's range.</p>
<p>September firm, peak PV electricity was quoted at $20.75-$21.25, flat from Monday.</p>
<p>October PV electricity, with similary delivery terms, was assessed at $15.90-$16.10. Fourth-quarter PV prices was quoted at $16.30-$16.70, down from Monday's $16.90-$17.25 range.</p>
<p>Pacific Gas &amp; Electric Co continued to hold power output from its 2,160 MW Diablo Canyon nuclear power facility at 75 percent of capacity because of a nearby wildfire in the Los Padres national forest.</p>
<p>--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
