<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2912" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. debt futures finish mixed after FOMC meeting.</title>
<headline>U.S. debt futures finish mixed after FOMC meeting.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. debt futures finished mixed, with the short end settling near the day's highs, while the long end wrapped up a light, lackluster session on the defensive, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>However, both U.S. T-bond and Eurodollar futures are seen inching up slightly in the near term after the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) concluded its much-awaited meeting without raising rates.</p>
<p>U.S. Septmeber bonds set a session low of 110-23/32 in a knee-jerk reaction to the FOMC's announcement that there was no change in the U.S. monetary policy.  </p>
<p>Several traders said one firm sold 7,000 September bond contracts after the FOMC announcement, which helped pressure the contract through the day's previous low of 110-27/32.</p>
<p>&quot;They just loaded up the pit with supply,&quot; one floor source said.</p>
<p>The contract traded inside Monday's range of 111-13/32 to 110-24/32 for most of the day, and most contracts closed only 01/32 lower.</p>
<p>&quot;That doesn't exactly lead me to expect much in the way of price action on Wednesday,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Between now and then, there is not much to change things,&quot; said John Nyhoff, vice president and economist of Mitsubishi Financial Futures.</p>
<p>Nyhoff expects Eurodollars to rise slightly, with December climbing to the 94.50 area.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, July import and export prices will be released at 1000 EDT/1400 GMT and the July federal budget will be released at 1400 EDT/1800 GMT.  </p>
<p>At the end of pit trade, September T-bonds were down 01/32 to 110-28/32, 10-year notes were flat at 108-19/32, munibonds rose 05/32 to 115-09/32, December Eurodollars were up one basis point at 94.21 and March Eurodollars were also up a basis point at 94.11, while March T-bills were one point higher at 94.69. Derivatives Desk 312-408-8750;E-mail derivatives@reuter.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
