<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2918" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Mid-Atlantic spot electricity steady to lower.</title>
<headline>U.S. Mid-Atlantic spot electricity steady to lower.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Mid-Atlantic spot electricity was trading steady for short-term deals and lower in longer-term trade with below-normal temperatures expected through the region by next week, industry sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;Next week is coming off pretty good, the six-to-ten day forecast is calling for cooler weather,&quot; said one broker.</p>
<p>Prices in the Pennsylvania-New Jersey-Maryland (PJM) power pool for next day, on peak delivery were discussed relatively steady in the $29.00-31.00 range from $27.00-31.00 on Monday.</p>
<p>The next day prices were holding at levels above those seen last week.</p>
<p>&quot;The weather is probably a factor, we are seeing some pretty good loads today,&quot; said one trader, adding &quot;the prices we are seeing are still low compared to what we would see if we broke the 90s (degrees Fahrenheit).&quot;</p>
<p>Off-peak next day power was talked at $15.50-17.00.</p>
<p>PJM power for firm, peak delivery for the three remaining days of this week was talked lower in the $28.00-29.00 range from $28.50-31.00 range on Monday, the industry sources said.</p>
<p>Power for the five business days of next week was discussed lower at $24.75-25.50 from a range of $25.75-28.00 per megawatt hour on Monday, the brokers and marketers said.</p>
<p>September PJM power, also for firm, peak delivery, dipped in early trade and rebounded slightly to afternoon discussion at $22.20-22.75 with $22.50 said to have traded, although the trade was unconfirmed.</p>
<p>September PJM was talked at $23.00-23.50 on Monday.</p>
<p>October PJM electricity with similar delivery terms was quoted at $20.00-20.65 from $20.20-20.70 on Monday, while November was pegged in the $21.50-22.00 range from $21.60-21.90 on Monday.</p>
<p>December PJM was assessed at $25.00-25.75, while fourth quarter PJM was talked near $22.25-22.75, the sources said.</p>
<p>-- Chris Reese, New York Power Desk 212-859-1627</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
