<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2919" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMM currency futures end mixed after FOMC inaction.</title>
<headline>IMM currency futures end mixed after FOMC inaction.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>IMM currency futures ended pit trading mixed after edging upward when the U.S. Federal Open Market Committee, as expected, left short-term rates steady.</p>
<p>Some traders tied the firming, which briefly tugged most currencies to the day's peaks, to &quot;buy-the-rumor, sell-the-fact&quot; activities vis-a-vis the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm surprised as well...but there must have been a small amount of insurance (dollar) buying before the meeting,&quot; said Chris Turner, currency strategist, IDEA Inc.</p>
<p>He said those &quot;just-in-case&quot; long-dollar positions likely were unwound when the Fed took no action.  </p>
<p>&quot;When the FOMC was over, the dollar went offered,&quot; said a floor broker at the Chicago Mercantile Exchange. &quot;But when the Redbook hit the street, the dollar rallied.&quot;</p>
<p>Retail sales rose 1.2 percent in the first two weeks of August versus July, according to Lynch, Jones &amp; Ryan Inc Redbook retail sales index.</p>
<p>Focus shifted to Wednesday's IFO business climate survey for softness that might bolster arguments for a German cut.</p>
<p>But Turner said the currency market likely already had factored in any weakness in the German business survey during last week's dollar rally to 1.4950 from 1.4750 marks.  </p>
<p>Turner also said his firm did not look for a German ease until the Bundesbank sees more months of evidence that M3 growth has slowed to within its four-percent to seven-percent target corridor.</p>
<p>Other pundits, however, said slowing in July M3 growth to an 8.6-percent rate fueled expectations the Bundesbank will cut its 3.30-percent repo rate at Thursday's council meeting.</p>
<p>Yen fell early after Japan ministry of finance senior official Eisuke Sakakibara was quoted as saying that even a dollar rise above 110.00 yen would have only a small chance of having an adverse effect on the Japanese economy.  </p>
<p>Currencies dipped early in the session after a smaller-than-expected June U.S. trade deficit. The trade gap shrank 23.1 percent to $8.11 billion against forecasts for a $9.4-billion shortfall.</p>
<p>At settlement, September yen fell $0.000050 to $0.009261, marks eased $0.0004 to $0.6728, Swiss francs firmed $0.0009 to $0.8313, Sterling gained $0.0032 to $1.5476, Canadian dollar slipped $0.0001 to $0.7288, Australian dollar lost $0.0041 to $0.7854, and the Mexican peso rose $0.000350 to $0.131875.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
