<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2920" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed stance spells steady yield spreads, stable dlr.</title>
<headline>Fed stance spells steady yield spreads, stable dlr.</headline>
<byline>Alden Bentley</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yield differentials should play a limited roll in dollar trading in the wake of the Federal Reserve's decision to leave interest rates unchanged Tuesday, even if the Bundesbank trims its repo rate on Thursday, economists said.</p>
<p>As the Fed announced its widely expected decision, market experts said the dollar will stay in a holding pattern until Thursday.  </p>
<p>&quot;It will have very little impact on the foreign exchange market because (the market) responds more to surprises than to expected news,&quot; said Marc Chandler, senior currency analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>&quot;The market focus shifts quickly to the Bundesbank council meeting on Thursday,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Most analysts expect the Bundesbank to lop at least five or 10 basis points off its securities repurchase -- or &quot;repo&quot; -- rate when it reconvenes after a four-week summer recess.  </p>
<p>But a modest reduction in the repo's current fixed rate of 3.3 percent could be swallowed by daily variations in Euromark and U.S. dollar deposit rates, diminishing any yield advantage for the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;In the short-term, interest rate differentials will widen a little bit,&quot; said Chris Iggo, international economist at Barclay's Bank in New York. &quot;But natural fluctuations in money market rates could easily erode that again, should sentiment in Germany turn around.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, interest rate differentials are a relatively unimportant variable in determining the dollar value versus the yen, analysts said.</p>
<p>Despite offering some of the lowest short-term interest rates in the world, Japan still has one of the world's strongest currencies.</p>
<p>Expectations for a cut in the repo rate -- which German banks charge each other for overnight borrowing -- may have risen Tuesday on lower-than-expected German M-3 money supply growth, the Bundesbank's key inflation barometer.  </p>
<p>M-3 grew at an annualized rate of 8.6 percent in July, slower than June's 9.6 percent pace, but still surpassing the Buba's 4.0-to-7.0 percent target.</p>
<p>But Euromark futures barely budged after the money supply data, suggesting both M-3 and a rate cut on Thursday had already been discounted by the market, said one expert.</p>
<p>&quot;That could leave three-month Euro-rate differentials unchanged on Friday, from where they are right now, thereby denying forex traders a fresh trading incentive,&quot; Chandler said.  </p>
<p>Dollar/yen movements have a greater correlation with changes in trade relationships than interest rate spreads, analysts noted.</p>
<p>Even so, Japan is expected to ensure that yield differentials do not move in favor of the yen any time soon.</p>
<p>Many analysts think the Bank of Japan will delay hiking interest rates from record low levels until after an expected Fed tightening later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems the odds have shifted away from a discount rate hike this year in Japan,&quot; said Chandler. &quot;Instead there are some people who think Japan wants the U.S. to raise interest rates first, before they do.&quot;</p>
<p>This could mean a long wait before the BOJ moves the discount rate up from 0.5 percent, where it has stood since September.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of Fed-watchers are pushing back the time they think the Fed will raise rates, said Kevin Harris, international economist at MCM CurrencyWatch. &quot;Not only not today, but not September and maybe not this year.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;That pushes off the date of any change in differentials for another five months or more,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1667</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
