<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2924" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American Airlines hopeful on U.S.-British air pact.</title>
<headline>American Airlines hopeful on U.S.-British air pact.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>AMR Corp's American Airlines said it was optimistic that the United States and Britain would reach an &quot;open skies&quot; aviation agreement, despite a report that British officials were taking a tough line in the negotiations.</p>
<p>&quot;There's just too much benefit on both sides of the Atlantic. Open skies is just too good for all sides,&quot; said American Airlines spokesman Tim Smith said.</p>
<p>The Financial Times newspaper on Tuesday quoted British officials as complaining that U.S. negotiators were not prepared to yield any ground in the talks.  </p>
<p>The news report also said the British government would not agreed to an open skies pact modeled after a similar agreement reached between the U.S. and Germany.</p>
<p>American Airlines said its proposed transatlantic alliance with British Airways is contigent on the U.S. and Britain reaching an open skies agreement. The Fort Worth, Texas-based air carrier said such a pact would increase competition and benefit both British and U.S.-based airlines.</p>
<p>American declined to comment on whether the open skies pact now under negotiation should resemble the U.S.-German agreement.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's not our place to set criteria. Each side will come to an agreement on what they believe open skies to be,&quot; Smith said.</p>
<p>Talks are set to resume in Washington on August 28-29, but the U.S. Department of Transportation said the session would also address sides issues such as dispute procedures.</p>
<p>A later round, set for September in London, will tackle contentious issues such as access to London's Heathrow Airport and a U.S. demand to use Britain as a stop-over for flights between the United States and third countries - so-called &quot;fifth freedom&quot; rights.  </p>
<p>Industry consultants said those two issues remain the biggest stumbling blocks.</p>
<p>Edward Starkman of the Starkman Airline Report said it was too early to say how closely a final U.S.-Anglo pact would resemble the deal with Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to be a long battle, even if it is solvable, which I'm not sure it is,&quot; Starkman said.</p>
<p>He also said British negotiators may be &quot;posturing&quot; in taking a tough line, as the Financial Times reported.</p>
<p>&quot;It's all part of the negotiating process. Each side, when they get frustrated, go to the press,&quot; Starkman said.</p>
<p>British Airways said Tuesday that it was still hopefull that Britain and the United States would reach an agreement.</p>
<p>British Airways shares slipped five pence to 530p in London on Tuesday, while AMR's shares in New York rose 5/8 to 84-5/8.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
