<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2928" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. adj retail sales up 1.2 pct in Aug -- Redbook.</title>
<headline>U.S. adj retail sales up 1.2 pct in Aug -- Redbook.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. seasonally adjusted retail sales rose 1.2 percent in the first two weeks of fiscal August versus July, according to the Lynch, Jones &amp; Ryan Inc Redbook Retail Sales Index.</p>
<p>The index rose 7.1 percent when compared to the same month a year ago, the report said. Adjusted retail sales also rose 6.4 percent in the week ended August 17 compared with the same week a year ago, it said.  </p>
<p>Apparel sales, particularly of menswear, has driven retail performance so far in August, said Howard Eilenberg, retail analyst at Lynch, Jones &amp; Ryan.</p>
<p>&quot;In particular, it's the athletic apparel that (is) doing very well,&quot; Eilenberg said in an interview with Reuters financial television.</p>
<p>Menswear sales have picked up at department stores, chains and discounters, according to Eilenberg.</p>
<p>&quot;This sales pattern is well-diffused and it is taking place all over the country,&quot; Eilenberg said.</p>
<p>He said the immediate future looks promising for retail sales. &quot;With the economy holding up reasonably well, I think we're in for a good fall season,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
