<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2933" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS -- Heating oil again holding key to API report.</title>
<headline>FOCUS -- Heating oil again holding key to API report.</headline>
<byline>Oliver Ludwig</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Summer gasoline demand may be about to peak, but heating oil is still the hot topic in U.S. oil markets, with traders saying they were expecting this week's API report to show a build in distillate stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;We're at the most critical week of gasoline demand, but heating oil is the most important number,&quot; said Thomas Blakeslee, analyst at Cargill Investor Services.</p>
<p>But the fact one analyst actually predicted a draw in distillate stocks underscored the fact the report is not likely to reverse bullish views distillate stocks are too low.  </p>
<p>Distillate stocks were expected to build by just 1.13 million barrels from 104.3 million barrels in the previous report -- a level over 20 million barrels below a year-ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly everyone's concentrating on the heating oil since we had a couple of counter-seasonal draws in the last few weeks,&quot; said Tom Bentz, analyst at ING Derivatives Clearing, noting any further draws were likely to make players even more bullish on heat than they already are.</p>
<p>Bentz and others saw more balance in gasoline markets, calling for a decent draw in gasoline supplies, helped in part by a continued lull in import activity into the East Coast.  </p>
<p>Gasoline stocks will likely post a seasonal draw of 1.66 million barrels from week-ago levels of 197.6 million.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there should be good demand on gasoline. In fact it's imperative (to stronger prices) that we see good demand on gasoline,&quot; said one Texas trader.</p>
<p>&quot;A gasoline draw should be facilitated by a continued slow pace of import activity,&quot; said Jim Ritterbusch, a trader with Sweeney Oil in Chicago.</p>
<p>Ritterbusch and others also expect a lull in crude imports to come out in this week's report and bring crude stocks down by 1.16 million barrels from week-ago levels of 308.1 million.  </p>
<p>&quot;Crude supplies are expected to draw further as U.S. Gulf and Midwest refineries maintain a strong operating pace. Imports are expected to decline from a recent strong eight million barrels per day,&quot; Ritterbusch said.</p>
<p>But some said recent refinery output problems might limit the degreee to which crude supplies drew down last week</p>
<p>Indeed, analysts were split on whether refinery utilization rates would rise, with the Reuter survey arriving at a negligibly higher figure from the 94.7 percent rate recorded in API's week-ago report.</p>
<p>-- New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1633</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
