<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2940" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Arizona files suit against tobacco companies.</title>
<headline>Arizona files suit against tobacco companies.</headline>
<dateline>PHOENIX 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Arizona joined a growing list of states and municipalities seeking damages from the tobacco industry Tuesday when it filed a lawsuit against some of the world's biggest tobacco companies.</p>
<p>Arizona Attorney General Grant Woods said the state is seeking more than $300 million in damages related to costs Arizona incurred by providing health-care benefits to indigent residents with alleged tobacco-related illnesses.</p>
<p>Woods said the tobacco companies have engaged in a &quot;massive illegal conspiracy&quot; representing that smoking is not addictive.  </p>
<p>The suit also alleges the companies violated antitrust, consumer fraud and fair trade practices.</p>
<p>In addition to monetary damages, the suit asks the court to prohibit the companies from targeting children in their advertising, promotion and sales.</p>
<p>Woods alledged tobacco products kill an estimated 5,000 Arizona residents a year.</p>
<p>The suit names RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp's RJR Reynolds Tobacco Co., B.A.T. Industries Plc's Brown &amp; Williamson Tobacco Corp. and The American Tobacco Co., Phillip Morris Co, Brooke Group Ltd's Ligget Group Inc., Loews Corp's Lorillard Tobacco Co Inc., United States Tobacco Co., Hill &amp; Knowlton Inc, the Council for Tobacco Research-U.S.A., and the Tobacco Institute Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;It is time to hold the tobacco companies responsible for the misery they have caused the citizens of the state of Arizona,&quot; Woods said. &quot;It's time the tobacco industry pays for the state's health care losses and stops aiming their ads at our children.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier, Kansas filed a lawsuit against six major tobacco companies to recover Medicaid costs for smoking-related illnesses. Arizona became the 12th state to file suit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHOENIX"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
