<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2948" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natgas futures stay down late, storm hype fades.</title>
<headline>Natgas futures stay down late, storm hype fades.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures remained lower in lackluster late trade Tuesday, still undermined by long liquidation as fears faded that a hurricane in the Caribbean would trim gas output, sources said.</p>
<p>At 1420 EDT, September skidded 10.7 cents to $2.08 per million British thermal units after hitting $2.215 on ACCESS. October was 9.4 cents lower at $2.16. Others also were down.</p>
<p>&quot;We were bid up ten cents (Monday) on light speculative volume because of (Hurricane) Dolly, and now they're taking it back,&quot; said one Midwest trader, noting the storm's track likely did not pose a threat to U.S. Gulf gas production.  </p>
<p>Dolly was upgraded to a hurricane midday Tuesday just before reaching land on Mexico's Yucatan peninsula. At 1200 EDT, the center was located at 19.3 degrees north and 87.6 degrees west, or on the Yucatan coast near Punta Herrero. The storm, packing minimal hurricane winds of 75 mph, was moving west-northwest at 13 mph. Dolly was expected to approach the Texas-Mexico border on Thursday.</p>
<p>Cash prices at the U.S. Gulf Coast firmed slightly Tuesday to about the $2.10 area, with Midcon pipes scoring similar gains to the low-$1.90s.</p>
<p>NYMEX said 11,724 Henry Hub contracts traded at 1125 EDT. Open interest on August 19 rose 1,142 contracts to 142,536. NYMEX September Henry Hub natgas futures expire Monday, August 26.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Permian natgas slipped four cents to $1.82, while deferreds were still untraded at 1420 EDT.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Permian natgas futures expire Wednesday August 28.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, September was still down by three cents at $1.92, while deferreds were one to two cents lower. The East/West spread narrowed by 7.7 cents to 16 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>KCBT September natgas futures expire Tuesday, August 27.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
