<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2961" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CenCor to buy some notes, updates liquidation plan.</title>
<headline>CenCor to buy some notes, updates liquidation plan.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo. 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>CenCor Inc said Tuesday it is offering to purchase its non-interest bearing notes due July 1, 1999, at a cash price equal to 74 percent of their principal amount.</p>
<p>CenCor said it is making the offer to allow noteholders to liquidate their notes and to receive cash at a price of $0.74 per $1 of principal, prior to July 1, 1999. The offer to purchase expires on October 3, 1996.</p>
<p>The company may extend the expiration date up to an additional 45 days, although it said it will not change the price offered for the notes.  </p>
<p>CenCor also reported the value of its net assets in liquidation as of June 30, 1996. CenCor's directors had adopted a liquidation plan which will be submitted for shareholder approval on September 12, 1996.</p>
<p>If CenCor had fully liquidated and distributed its assets by June 30, 1996, the company's shareholders would have received $17,982,000 in distributions or about $12.08 a share, as compared with $18,110,000 or $12.17 at December 31, 1995.</p>
<p>The actual amount to be received from the liquidation may be reduced by several factors.  </p>
<p>These factors include claims related to the sale of the assets of a former subsidiary, Century Acceptance Corp, unexpected income tax liabilities, and the amount collected on the debt and preferred stock of Concorde Career Colleges Inc.</p>
<p>The liquidation value may also be reduced by legal matters, including class action suits pending against Century in the State of Alabama.</p>
<p>CenCor recorded a decrease to net assets in liquidation of $128,000 for the six months ended June 30, 1996. The company recognized $1,109,000 in income from liquidating activities during the six months ended June 30, 1996.  </p>
<p>The company said it recorded $1,357,000 in expenses from liquidating activities during the six months ended June 30, 1996. The company's expenses consist mainly of salaries and related benefits, interest on the company's long-term debt, professional and consulting fees, and other liquidating activities.</p>
<p>In addition, CenCor said it recorded an adjustment to net assets in liquidation of $120,000 for the six months ended June 30, 1996 as a result of its July 30, 1996 agreement to release its claim on certain assets to be sold by Concorde in consideration of Concorde's agreement to use a portion of the sales proceeds to redeem the preferred stock.</p>
<p>On August 2, 1996, CenCor received $352,495 from Concorde in exchange for the redemption of 30,975 shares of preferred stock.</p>
<p>	     Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
