<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2990" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US money managers bullish on US debt -- MCM survey.</title>
<headline>US money managers bullish on US debt -- MCM survey.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fixed-income managers grew more bullish on U.S. debt markets in the past week, according to the latest MCM MoneyWatch Inc asset allocation survey.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors (are) still finding the need to be invested,&quot; said MCM money market analyst Peter McTeague. &quot;Some reached for yield in corporate paper, while others moved out the curve into the five- to ten-year (sector).&quot;</p>
<p>The weekly survey showed durations as a percentage of benchmark rose to 106.1 in the week ended August 19 from 105.8 percent in the prior week.  </p>
<p>A duration reading above 100 percent indicates the group of investors polled is mostly long on the market. A portfolio's duration represents its average maturity and is used by portfolio managers to calculate exposure to risk.</p>
<p>In the &quot;next likely move&quot; category, portfolio managers representing 24 percent of total assets in the survey said they would &quot;buy,&quot; down from 37 percent the prior week.</p>
<p>Strategists leaning toward &quot;sell&quot; declined to nine percent, down from 10 percent in the week ended August 5.</p>
<p>Sixty-seven percent of managers said they were &quot;neutral&quot; on the market, up from 53 percent a week ago.  </p>
<p>Cash as a percentage of assets fell to 3.02 percent, against 3.05 percent registered the previous week.</p>
<p>The survey showed 39 percent of investors polled overweighted the 10-plus years duration sector, up from 34 percent in the previous week, while 36 percent underweighted it. The remaining 25 percent were &quot;neutral.&quot;</p>
<p>In the five- to 10-year duration sector, 39 percent of investors polled said they overweighted the securities and 26 percent underweighted them.</p>
<p>The survey included 38 domestic participants, who manage about $90.0 billion in fixed-income assets. The poll is conducted weekly by MCM.  </p>
<p>Results of the survey follow:</p>
<p>   Category*					    Aug 19, 1996</p>
<p>   Duration percentage of benchmark		 106.1 pct</p>
<p>   Next Likely Move-Buy(B)/Sell(S)	24 pct B-09 pct S</p>
<p>Over(O)-Under(U) Weight Benchmark</p>
<p>   Governments				  19 pct O-65 pct U</p>
<p>   Corporates				   55 pct O-20 pct U</p>
<p>   Mortgages				    65 pct O-09 pct U</p>
<p>   Cash as a percentage of assets		    3.02 pct</p>
<p>Percentage experiencing cash</p>
<p>	In (I) - Out (O)			35 pct I-11 pct O</p>
<p>Over(O)-Under(U) weight Benchmark</p>
<p>   1- to 5-year duration sector	   25 pct O-36 pct U</p>
<p>   5- to 10-year duration sector	  39 pct O-26 pct U</p>
<p>   10+     year duration sector	   39 pct O-36 pct U</p>
<p>* Table provided by MCM MoneyWatch Inc consultants.</p>
<p>Results are dollar-weighted.</p>
<p>-- Scott Gerlach, (212) 859-1868</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
