<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="2995" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. spot natgas prices extend gains with heat.</title>
<headline>U.S. spot natgas prices extend gains with heat.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot natgas prices edged a couple of cents higher Tuesday in most regions, as Tropical Storm Dolly still lurked in the Caribbean but displayed only a minor threat to Gulf facilities, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Louisiana Gulf Coast swing prices gained about one to three cents to the $2.07-2.12 per million British thermal units area as above-normal temperatures were expected in the Northeast, Midwest and Texas through Friday.</p>
<p>However, next week's forecast shows below-normal temperatures across much of the eastern U.S., with above-normal temperatures continuing in the West.  </p>
<p>In south Texas, where summer-like temperatures continue, prices rose by about one cent into the $2.04-2.09 range.</p>
<p>Similarly in the Midcontinent region, prices climbed about two cents higher into the low-$1.90s as forecasters called for temperatures about three to six degrees Fahrenheit above-normal through Thursday.</p>
<p>Permian basin prices also edged up about a cent to the high-$1.80s to $1.90.</p>
<p>Cooler weather on the West Coast pressured Topock (southern California border) prices lower to about $1.90, but the brief respite from summer heat is expected to be short-lived.</p>
<p>In the Appalachian region, traders reported closing deals in the mid-$2.20s to about $2.30. The region is anticipating slightly above-normal temperatures over the next three days.</p>
<p>--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
