<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3011" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: No major reversal in Japan trade picture -- Stiglitz.</title>
<headline>No major reversal in Japan trade picture -- Stiglitz.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>White House economic adviser Joseph Stiglitz said Tuesday he sees no major reversal in the improvement of the U.S. trade deficit with Japan.</p>
<p>Asked by a reporter if he could imagine the trade deficit returning to the $50-$60 billion levels of several years ago, Stiglitz replied, &quot;I don't see a major reversal of that kind.&quot;  </p>
<p>Stiglitz said two factors should continue to help the trade picture -- the trade agreements negotiated with Japan and that country's economic recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think that we have reached the full benefits of the trade agreements,&quot; he said. &quot;It's also the case that Japan's recovery is still in (its) early stages, and if its recovery continues, that should also be good for our exports to Japan.&quot;</p>
<p>He added, &quot;The underlying fundamentals are such that there should be -- relative to where the Japan deficit was -- continued strength.&quot;  </p>
<p>Stiglitz, chairman of the president's Council of Economic Advisers, suggested the U.S. trade deficit with China could worsen this year.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be surprising if it were lower than last year's,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>The Commerce Department reported on Tuesday that the overall U.S. trade deficit shrank dramatically in June, dropping 23.1 percent to $8.11 billion from a revised $10.55 billion in May.</p>
<p>The trade shortfall with China swelled 8.8 percent to $3.33 billion. It surpassed for the first time the $3.24 billion U.S. trade deficit with Japan, which was up 3.6 percent from May.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
