<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3046" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Eurobourses close at highs in cautious trade.</title>
<headline>Eurobourses close at highs in cautious trade.</headline>
<byline>Eric Meijer</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>European bourses moved cautiously to close around their highs on Tuesday, slightly constrained by nerves over over U.S. and German interest rate policy.</p>
<p>No change in U.S. interest rates is expected from the U.S. Federal Reserve's Open Market Committee meeting on Tuesday but market players are still tending to hold back until news emerges.</p>
<p>In Germany, growth in M3, the central bank's main policy guide, slowed to an annualised 8.6 percent in July from 9.6 percent in June, virtually guaranteeing a cut in interest rates at Thursday's meeting of the Bundesbank council, analysts said.</p>
<p>French shares extended earlier gains to close over one percent higher, outshining most other European centres, as fresh talk of rate cuts allowed the market to claw back some of its recent underperformance.</p>
<p>The Paris bourse gained more than 30 points, quickly pushing the CAC-40 share index through the 2,000 barrier for the first time since August 8. The index closed at its highest level since August 2, before recent attacks on the franc.</p>
<p>London shares climbed to another record high, led by renewed strength in retailing and oil stocks and following reassuring money supply data from both Britain and Germany. The market closed only slightly below its high.</p>
<p>The blue-chip FTSE 100 index peaked at 3,884.8, nearly seven points up on its previous record set on Monday, after British M4, the broad measure of money supply, showed money growth remained subdued through July.</p>
<p>Analysts said the figures could give further ammunition to Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke if he wants to trim the 5.75 percent base interest rate again in coming months.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a good figure...most people hadn't expected the figure to come back into the monitoring range, which is about the first time for six or seven months,&quot; said economist Keith Wade of Schroders.</p>
<p>Germany's positive data failed to set a cautious bourse alight and it traded mixed, with the floor traded bourse index down 2.5 and the electronically traded IBIS DAX up 5.87 points.</p>
<p>The dollar was edging below earlier levels in late European business that was cautious ahead of the outcome of today's Federal Reserve meeting.</p>
<p>Wariness ahead of the meeting has taken the shine off the dollar's earlier dash to session highs on news that the U.S. trade deficit for June had narrowed 23 percent from the previous month.</p>
<p>&quot;OK, so the Fed probably won't move and the Bundesbank probably will, particularly after that good M3 number. But in this market you will get killed if you're wrong and have a big position,&quot; said one trader. &quot;I'm not taking the risk.&quot;</p>
<p>CURRENCIES  AT 1515 GMT</p>
<p>Dollar/mark was trading at 1.4880 and dollar/yen at 108.32 versus Monday's late 1.4875 and 107.90. Mark/French franc was trading at 3.4159 against 3.4232.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS CLOSES</p>
<p>The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares ended up 19.5 points at 3,883.2. Frankfurt's 30-share DAX index closed down 2.5 at 2,563.20. The electronic IBIS DAX was up 5.87. Paris's CAC-40 finished up 33.05 at 2,019.347.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold closed a little firmer at $387.55 an ounce vs Monday's $386.65, awaiting the outcome of the Federal Reserve meeting. Silver ended up 11 cents at $5.23, consolidating at current levels following its sharp move higher overnight. Platinum finished up $1.40 at $399.80.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
