<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3057" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Brent ends at low as Sept NYMEX expires.</title>
<headline>IPE Brent ends at low as Sept NYMEX expires.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE Brent crude closed lower on Tuesday in a partial retracement of recent sharp gains and under pressure from the expiring Sept NYMEX crude contract, dealers said.</p>
<p>Oct Brent closed down 42 cents at the session low of $20.54 a barrel posted in the last few minutes of trading.</p>
<p>The expiring Sept NYMEX crude contract shed 46 cents to end at $22.80 a barrel, trimming by nine cents the backwardation which has helped underpin Brent crude in recent weeks.</p>
<p>The Oct Brent-WTI spread, under pressure earlier, recovered to close seven cents firmer at $1.69 a barrel.  </p>
<p>Traders said expectations of a build in U.S. inventories when the American Petroleum Institute (API) reports later on Tuesday were adding to the pressure on crude and products.</p>
<p>Low stocks, particularly of heating oil, have helped fuel the recent rally across the complex.</p>
<p>Traders and analysts surveyed by Reuters expected middle distillate stocks -- mainly heating oil and diesel -- to have risen by just over one million barrels last week.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was fairly quiet this afternoon. People were waiting for September to expire and the API figures before resuming normal business tomorrow,&quot; said a broker.  </p>
<p>Earlier, prompt IPE gas oil futures closed narrowly lower after a quiet session with most activity concentrated on the Sep/Oct spread, dealers said.</p>
<p>September gas oil settled at $188.25 a tonne, down 25 cents but towards the middle of the session's range of $186.50-$189.00 a tonne.</p>
<p>The prompt intermonth spread shed 75 cents a tonne to stand at $1.25.</p>
<p>-- Mark Thompson, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7930</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
