<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3067" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Mideast tanker chartering picks up, rates steady.</title>
<headline>Mideast tanker chartering picks up, rates steady.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Middle Eastern crude tanker rates were steady again on Tuesday with an upwards bias in a busier market, shipbrokers said.</p>
<p>ULCCs and VLCCs found employment both east and west. Mobil was seen taking a ULCC to the Red Sea, two VLCCs were fixed to Asia, Kuwait Petroleum took a VLCC to the US Gulf and two VLCCs were chartered by Engen and Shell to South Africa.</p>
<p>VLCC rates to Asia remained around W65, while trips to the U.S and Europe were put close to W59-60. VLCC trips to Japan were assessed between W65-72.5, though there were no charters seen on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Brokers noted several fixtures done into South Africa. Shell chartered the Golden Fountain to carry 260,000 tonnes and Engen fixed 290,000 tonnes on the New Victory.</p>
<p>&quot;We've also seen today an enquiry by BP South Africa to take a VLCC from the Middle East to Durban,&quot; said one broker.</p>
<p>In the inter-UKC sector, rates rose marginally with 80,000 tonners taking W102.5-105. Dow chartered a Lundqvist tanker at W105.</p>
<p>There were a couple of transatlantic trips seen. Statoil and Irving fixed a VLCC apiece from the North Sea to East coast Canada. Rates across the Atlantic were put around W65-67.5.  </p>
<p>For the second consecutive day, fixing in the Mediterranean was poor. Brokers continued to cite the tail end of the public holidays in the region last week.</p>
<p>By mid-afternoon, Trafigura's fixing of a 120,000 tonner on the Greek Fighter travelling from Novorossisk to Cuba was the only charter seen.</p>
<p>&quot;Although there is almost no activity in the Med, rates remain firm with 80,000 tonners steady at W100-104,&quot; an Italian broker said.</p>
<p>The Caribbean market was steady with 70,000 tonners heading up the U.S. Coast, commanding around W130-135.  </p>
<p>Hurricane Dolly, approaching Mexico, was not affecting rates and all the key Mexican crude export ports were open.</p>
<p>-- Mike Blouki, London Newsroom +44 171 542 4088</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
