<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3068" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Doctor agrees mum will try to deliver eight babies.</title>
<headline>Doctor agrees mum will try to deliver eight babies.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The doctor treating a British woman pregnant with eight foetuses said on Tuesday he had given up trying to persuade her to have a partial abortion in order to give one or two of them a better chance of survival.</p>
<p>Consultant gynaecologist Kypros Nicolaides said his patient Mandy Allwood would now probably miscarry. &quot;But I cannot abandon all hope that we will have at least some survivors,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Allwood, who has sold her story to the News of the World Sunday newspaper, has said she is determined to have all the babies. She has been backed by her boyfriend Paul Hudson.</p>
<p>Nicolaides had told Allwood, who is now 15 weeks pregnant, that her that her best chance of having some healthy babies would be to abort most of the foetuses by a process known as foetal reduction.</p>
<p>But he told Sky television: &quot;The issue of foetal reduction is now resolved. Mandy and Paul have decided to continue the whole pregnancy. I respect that view.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The most likely outcome of this pregnancy is an expiry before 24 weeks or deliveries after 24 weeks with a high chance that all the babies will die, or if they survive there is a high chance that they will all be handicapped,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nicolaides examined Allwood on Saturday and found both her and her eight foetuses &quot;very well&quot;. She was very confident about the pregnancy, but he said he had tried to make her realise that her chances of having healthy children were slim.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
