<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3072" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dated Brent confusion stifles North Sea trade.</title>
<headline>Dated Brent confusion stifles North Sea trade.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Uncertainty about the value of benchmark Dated Brent on Tuesday stifled activity on most North Sea spot crude markets, traders said.</p>
<p>The only Brent cargo nominated into the forward paper chains, loading Sept 4-6, was kept by U.S. major Texaco who then sold it on -- but on a private and confidential basis.</p>
<p>Only one physical Brent -- an August 29-31 loader -- was on offer at Sept Brent +8 cents, but some felt the market for September barrels was three or four cents firmer.</p>
<p>Oct Brent lost 17 cents to $20.68 a barrel by 1730 GMT. Intermonth paper spreads were also weaker, traders said.  </p>
<p>The prompt SepT/Oct paper spread traded as low as +56 cents, down about nine cents from early talk. Oct/Nov was valued at +48 cents, about four cents weaker than on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a broad feeling in the market that Brent was overheated and had to come down,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Brent CFDs slid with the balance of this week talked at Oct +60/+68 cents from +80/+85 cents late on Monday. Next week's dates, which fetched Oct Brent +47 cents early on Tuesday, traded later at +42 cents.</p>
<p>Other North Sea markets were quiet as buyers waited for premiums to weaken in line with the shallower Brent curve.  </p>
<p>&quot;The other grades should come down but there hasn't been a trade today,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Mediterranean refiners found little to tempt them from the few cargoes on offer as they weighed up options in the face of appalling margins although there was no sign any had cut runs.</p>
<p>Syria's Sytrol was under pressure from buyers to keep prices down in current price talks for September cargoes.</p>
<p>One trader said Sytrol had come down from an offer of Dated Brent -30 cents to -38 cents while lifters were holding out for Dated -45 cents. &quot;I think the talks will last all week,&quot; an oil company trader said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
