<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3076" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Mideast clean product tanker rates touch softer.</title>
<headline>Mideast clean product tanker rates touch softer.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Clean tanker rates in the Middle East dropped slightly on Tuesday while other chartering sectors saw rates settle around last done levels, shipping brokers said.</p>
<p>Middle East activity was relatively lacklustre with rates on 55,000 tonners to Japan slipping to W165 from W170.</p>
<p>Brokers said the the market was slow and they expected rates to remain steady until the end of the week.</p>
<p>GSSK was seen taking a 70,000 tonne cargo on the Pacific Ruby to Japan at W145.</p>
<p>Mediterranean activity was hampered by a lack of suitable tonnage, particularly for naphtha carriers.</p>
<p>Gas oil carriers were seeing rates around W210 to carry 30,000 tonnes. Rates were placed at W230 about a week and a half ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The rates for 30,000 tonne gas oil carriers are relatively elastic and erratic at the moment,&quot; said one broker.</p>
<p>UK/Continent chartering was slow on Tuesday with 20,000 tonners in particuarly finding employment hard to come by.</p>
<p>&quot;We've seen some transatlantic fixing and some fixing on the 30,000 tonners, but its been quiet on the smaller ships,&quot; said one London broker.</p>
<p>Rates remained on a level of W200, but brokers said there was underlying strength in the market given a perceived lack of tonnage.</p>
<p>Rates in the Caribbean up U.S. coast market have steadily strengthened, supported by recent active fixing and thinning tonnage. A 30,000 tonne cargo fixed by Vitol Caribs up coast on the Petrobulk Cougar was placed at W215 was seen to reflect the market.</p>
<p>-- Mike Blouki, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7630</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
