<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3084" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GDR REPORT - India squeezed higher, premiums expand.</title>
<headline>GDR REPORT - India squeezed higher, premiums expand.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian global depositary receipts (GDRs) rose in the wake of gains on the local market and premiums expanded from five percent, but market makers are not optimistic gains will carry through.</p>
<p>&quot;A few buyers came in in the morning and this forced the market makers to cover, which attracted in more buyers and so on,&quot; said one market maker.</p>
<p>The HSBC James Capel Indian GDR index  JCEAI rose 2.60 points, 3.90 percent, to 69.28 points, with the premium over the locals at 9.32 percent compared with yesterday's 5.36 percent.</p>
<p>The Bombay Stock Exchange 30-share index rose 34.57 points, or 1.05 percent, to 3,316.06 points.</p>
<p>&quot;The market may go up 100 points, but it is a classic bear squeeze, no one is bullish on India at the moment,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Indian Hotels gained $1.40 at 23.87/24.87.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no big trades, just deals in 10s and 20s,&quot; said a trader. &quot;There are lots of frustrated market makers out there,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Capel Korea GDR Index ended down 1.26 points, 1.83 percent, at 73.01 points, a premium of 19.36 percent over the local market, compared with yesterday's 19.85 percent.</p>
<p>The Korea Composite Index fell 6.61 points to a provisional 793.91, its lowest level for 33 months.</p>
<p>The Capel Taiwan GDR Index ended up 1.84 points, 2.15 percent, at 87.65 points, a premium of 7.79 percent after 5.64 percent yesterday.</p>
<p>The Taiwan Weighted Index rose 9.93 points or 0.16 percent at 6,057.44. -- David Chance, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5887</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
