<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3092" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Rugby Union-Fatialofa to retire.</title>
<headline>Rugby Union-Fatialofa to retire.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peter Fatialofa, who after despairing of winning an All Black jersey won acclaim as captain of Western Samoa, has retired from rugby at all levels.</p>
<p>The burly prop confirmed on Monday that his brief appearance as a replacement for Counties in Sunday's national championship match against Canterbury was his last in any game.</p>
<p>Fatialofa said that at 37 he now no longer had the motivation to put in the hard training needed to stay at a top level.  </p>
<p>&quot;My body's starting to talk to me now big time,&quot; he said. &quot;I can now start to hear the bells ringing. But I've got absolutely no regrets and I'm happy to be bowing out, not sad, because it's the right time to go.&quot;</p>
<p>After missing the All Black tour of Australia in 1988, Fatialofa took up an offer to join Western Samoa who were then trying to win a place in the 1991 World Cup.</p>
<p>He has now played more than 100 games for Western Samoa, including an estimated 37 tests. By 1990, he was Western Samoa's captain and he reached his peak when the side was one of the sensations of the 1991 World Cup with wins over Wales and Argentina to become a quarterfinalist.</p>
<p>&quot;Playing in that World Cup when Manu Samoa became an international force was the  highlight for me,&quot; Fatialofa said.</p>
<p>&quot;Actually not becoming an All Black may have been a blessing in disguise: if I had been an All Black I may have only been a midweek player and I wouldn't have got the same feeling as I got playing for Manu Samoa.&quot;</p>
<p>Fatialofa said he now hopes to spend more time in Western Samoa concentrating on coaching and promotional work. Fatialofa has played for Counties in recent seasons,  but between 1984 and 1992 he played 72 games for Auckland.  </p>
<p>Several of Fatialofa's Auckland and All Black team mates will play in his farewell match in Apia in November.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WSOMOA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
