<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3102" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian mother killed saving son from cougar.</title>
<headline>Canadian mother killed saving son from cougar.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER, British Columbia 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A cougar mauled a Canadian woman to death after she intervened to save her 6-year-old son who was being attacked, police said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Cindy Parolin, 36, was horseback-riding with her three children in the southern British Columbia interior on Monday night when a cougar sprang from the bush at her young son.</p>
<p>The boy was thrown from his horse and the cougar began mauling the child. Parolin tried to beat the beast with a stick and the cougar then turned on her, the Royal Canadian Mounted Police said.</p>
<p>Parolin shouted to her 11-year-old daughter and 13-year-old son to carry the injured boy to safety.</p>
<p>They made it back to the family car about a mile (two km) away and the older son returned with several people who were camping nearby to help his mother.</p>
<p>One man located Parolin by following her cries for help. &quot;The cougar was still on top of the mother nearly an hour after the attack. The man managed to scare the cougar off after shooting it,&quot; the police said.</p>
<p>Parolin was pronounced dead on arrival at the hospital in Princeton, British Columbia, about 120 miles (200 km) east of Vancouver. The injured 6-year-old, whose name was not released, was in stable condition with severe lacerations to his head and puncture wounds on his back.</p>
<p>The cougar, wounded by gunshots, was later tracked and killed by wildlife officials.</p>
<p>Parolin and her three children had been heading to a camp about a mile (two km) away where her husband and fourth child were waiting.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER, British Columbia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
