<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3106" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TOGO: Togo names economist as prime minister.</title>
<headline>Togo names economist as prime minister.</headline>
<byline>Apedo Amah</byline>
<dateline>LOME 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Togo's President Gnassingbe Eyadema on Tuesday named a technocrat prime minister from among his supporters after his party won three more parliament seats in by-elections earlier this month.</p>
<p>A presidential decree announced the appointment of Kwassi Klutse, minister of planning and regional development in the outgoing government.</p>
<p>Edem Kodjo, leader of the Togolese Union for Democracy (UTD), resigned from the prime minister's post on Monday, saying he had to take account of the change in the balance of power.</p>
<p>His party had governed in an increasingly uneasy alliance with Eyadema's Togolese People's Rally (RPT) since parliamentary elections in 1994.</p>
<p>An economist by training, Klutse, 51, was director-general of the planning ministry from 1988 until his appointment as minister in November 1995.</p>
<p>According to the constitution, the prime minister must come from within the parliamentary majority. The RPT, in coalition with allied parties, now has an absolute majority after winning three seats in the 81-seat parliament in by-elections this month.</p>
<p>Eyadema's party won two seats outright on August 4 and one in a runoff on Sunday. The main opposition Action Committee for Renewal (CAR) boycotted all three by-elections.</p>
<p>Before the by-elections Eyadema's RPT had 35 seats of its own, plus two from its allies in the Union for Justice and Democracy. It also had the support of former premier Joseph Kokou Koffigoh and two independents who had quit the UTD and CAR.</p>
<p>If confirmed by the supreme court, Sunday's result will leave the RPT with 38 seats of its own, plus its five allies, giving Eyadema a comfortable majority.</p>
<p>Eyadema, an army general, seized power in 1967 and was elected in 1993 in polls boycotted by the UTD and CAR.</p>
<p>The two parties formed an opposition alliance to contest the 1994 parliamentary elections and had won a majority until the Supreme Court annulled three seats citing irregularities.</p>
<p>That alliance collapsed after Kodjo accepted the post of prime minister.</p>
<p>Relations between Eyadema and Kodjo had been strained in recent months. Kodjo spoke publicly of differences and Eyadema's supporters openly criticised the prime minister.</p>
<p>Kodjo told reporters on Tuesday the CAR's refusal to cooperate with parliament had made it difficult to govern. The party boycotted parliament for several months in 1994 and 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TOGO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TOGO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
