<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3107" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe civil servants strike declared illegal.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe civil servants strike declared illegal.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Zimbabwean government said a civil servants strike that began on Tuesday was illegal and ordered workers back to their jobs.</p>
<p>Public Service, Labour and Social Welfare Minister Florence Chitauro said her government would only negotiate with the Public Service Association (PSA) once it ended the strike that hurt the southern Africa state's social services.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as we are concerned, this strike is illegal and we are ordering all those workers who did not go to work today to report for duty tomorrow,&quot; she told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;If they do not take heed to this call the heads of ministries are required to take the necessary disciplinary action according to the public service regulations,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Earlier, PSA executive secretary John Makoni told reporters &quot;a lot&quot; of the country's 180,000 civil servants had heeded his PSA union's call &quot;to go to work and walk out&quot;.</p>
<p>The chairman of the Public Service Commission (PSC), Mariyawanda Nzuwah, described the strike as irresponsible and unacceptable, saying negotiation channels had not been exhausted.</p>
<p>But Makoni said the government had left the union with no option because it was not prepared to look at workers's demands for increases of around 25-30 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not go back to work until the PSC and the Ministry of Public Service, Labour and Social Welfare reviews the situation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Only senior officials were in Zimbabwean government offices on Tuesday while many other civil servants milled around or marched their work locations demonstrating.</p>
<p>Nurses at state hospitals around the country also joined the strike, but the government filled some of the gaps with personnel from the army and the local Red Cross medical division.</p>
<p>---Cris Chinaka, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9.---</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
