<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3108" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: Rwanda refugees flee Burundi despite assurances.</title>
<headline>Rwanda refugees flee Burundi despite assurances.</headline>
<byline>Christian Jennings</byline>
<dateline>BUTARE, Rwanda 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of Rwandan Hutu refugees fled Burundi on Tuesday for their equally troubled homeland despite assurances from Burundi's new Tutsi strongman Major Pierre Buyoya that he was opposed to any expulsions.</p>
<p>U.N. refugee agency officials said a total of 3,313 Rwandans had crossed the border into Rwanda by Tuesday afternoon and had reached Musange transit camp outside Butare.</p>
<p>A convoy of trucks with 1,480 refugees would cross the border within the next 30 minutes, they said.</p>
<p>They said heavy rains had prevented further movements and the exercise was being suspended until Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The rains have prevented further movements from Magara camp in Burundi. These refugees will be the last movements for the day,&quot; an official with the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) told Reuters in Butare.</p>
<p>Magara is the biggest Rwandan refugee camp in north Burundi and once held over 45,000 people. After earlier expulsions, and the flight of some 7,000 refugees on Monday -- 24 hours after soldiers killed three refugees -- about 24,000 remain.</p>
<p>&quot;The largest concentration of refugees will arrive this afternoon and evening,&quot; said Stephano Severe, head of UNHCR in Butare.</p>
<p>The refugees accuse the Tutsi-dominated Burundian army of harassment and say they fear for their lives. To help them return to Rwanda, the International Organisation for Migration (IOM) has organised 91 trucks and buses.</p>
<p>Butare governor Atanase Samuhungu told Reuters he expected some refugees, accused of taking part in Rwanda's 1994 genocide, to face problems once they reached their original villages.</p>
<p>&quot;The problems will be in the countryside when they try to reintegrate,&quot; Samuhungu said without elaborating.</p>
<p>Around two million Rwandan Hutus fled their homeland to Zaire, Tanzania and Burundi in 1994 after Tutsi rebels defeated the Hutu army and ousted the government, blamed for the genocide of up to one million Tutsis and moderate Hutus.</p>
<p>Burundi's new leader Buyoya pledged on Tuesday to protect the refugees after they complained of harassment and beatings from his army. Buyoya's spokesman said a team of investigators had been sent to northern Burundi. The spokesman also said Buyoya had sacked the country's three most powerful military officers.</p>
<p>Buyoya's spokesman Jean-Luc Ndizeye told Reuters by telephone that the new president of Burundi remained committed to international conventions on the protection of refugees.</p>
<p>Shortly after the July 25 coup that brought him to power, Buyoya ordered an end to expulsions of Rwandan Hutu refugees.</p>
<p>Ndizeye said the latest exodus from the north was caused by panic after troops entered Magara on Sunday to search for arms.</p>
<p>He said Burundian army positions near Magara had come under fire on Saturday and Sunday forcing soldiers to move into the camp to search for weapons and ammunition.</p>
<p>He said anyone found guilty of inciting refugees to leave against their will would be punished. &quot;The president is not going back on his word to protect refugees,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The exodus of Rwandan refugees picked up after troops killed three refugees at Magara camp. Army spokesman Lieutenant-Colonel Jean Minani confirmed on Tuesday that soldiers killed them but said they fired only after one refugee shot at them.</p>
<p>Besides the 24,000 refugees remaining at Magara, another 13,000 are at Rukuramigabo Camp in neighbouring Kirundo province, Paul Stromberg, UNHCR regional spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Burundian authorities accuse the refugees of supporting Hutu rebels in a war against the Burundian army in which 150,000 people have died since 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUTARE, Rwanda"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
