<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3109" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: OPINION - Zimbabwe's inflation - By Tony Hawkins.</title>
<headline>OPINION - Zimbabwe's inflation - By Tony Hawkins.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Tony Hawkins, Professor of Business Studies, University of Zimbabwe</p>
<p>With consumer inflation slowing half a point in July to 22 percent - its lowest level in a year - market analysts seem satisfied that, at last, Zimbabwe's inflation cycle has turned.</p>
<p>Since breaking through the 20-percent barrier in 1991, inflation in Zimbabwe has averaged 27 percent and has been stuck around 22 percent for the last three years.</p>
<p>But not everyone shares the market's &quot;conventional wisdom&quot; of markedly lower inflation in the latter half of 1996 and into next year. Indeed, it is increasingly difficult to understand why market analysts are so upbeat in their inflation forecasts.</p>
<p>The slowdown from recent peaks of 28 percent in January to July's 22 percent is explained chiefly by the excellent harvest and the fall in some food prices, the increasingly overvalued Zimbabwe dollar exchange rate, which has kept the lid on import prices, and high levels of competition in the domestic market, which have prevented firms from passing on cost increases as liberally as they would have liked.</p>
<p>Until last year, too, average real wages were falling, also contributing to greater price stability.</p>
<p>With the favourable food price effect beginning to lose momentum, the Zimbabwe dollar set for a substantial downward adjustment and the government seemingly committed to inflationary import tarrif hikes - to counter what Zimbabwean industrialists call South African dumping - the three main influences making for lower inflation are likely to be reversed over the next six to nine months.</p>
<p>Add to that, the spate of wage awards well above the inflation rate and continued excessive money supply growth in the first half of 1996, and the inflation outlook looks increasingly bleak.</p>
<p>The July budget adopted a benign neglect stance towards inflation and the country's worsening debt-trap situation. No corrective measures were taken to curb money supply growth, and the projected budget deficit of 8.5 percent of GDP in 1996/97 will maintain upward pressures on prices over the next year.</p>
<p>The latest money supply numbers make depressing reading too. In the first half of the year, the monetary aggregates grew at annual rates ranging from 25 percent to 48 percent, well above the official target of 18 percent to 22 percent.</p>
<p>However, that is only part of the story. This excessive monetary expansion occurred despite a huge - and increasingly unsustainable - sterilization campaign by the central bank.</p>
<p>By July, the Reserve Bank of Zimbabwe's Treasury bill issue had grown to over Z$22 billion (US$220 million) from Z$6.5 billion a year earlier.</p>
<p>Indeed, government's floating debt of &quot;ordinary&quot; and &quot;special&quot; Treasury bills now approximates 35 percent of GDP, costing the taxpayer some Z$5.3 billion a year (about eight percent of GDP) in interest charges. Some of the more thoughtful analysts are asking how much longer this balancing act of mopping up Z$1 billion and more in special Treasury bills each month can continue.</p>
<p>When he delivers his half-yearly monetary policy statement in the next few weeks, RBZ governor Leonard Tsumba may give some clues, unlike his boss, Finance Minister Herbert Murerwa, who sidestepped the whole problem in his budget speech last month.</p>
<p>Not that Dr Tsumba has any great room to manoeuvre. He is locked into a policy cul-de-sac from which there is no easy escape. If he listens to the increasingly shrill demands of the industrial lobby to cut interest rates, credit growth will take off thereby ensuring that the downturn in inflation is shortlived. If he continues to expand the Treasury bill mountain at the current rate of Z$1 billion a month, he may delay the inevitable monetary explosion for a while yet, but only at an enormously heavy cost to the taxpayer.</p>
<p>To compound his problems the Zimbabwe dollar continues to appreciate in the foreign exchange market. In the first seven months of 1996, the Zimbabwe currency has appreciated some 15 percent against that of its main trading partner, the South African rand. With a gap of some 15 percent between Zimbabwe's 22 percent and South Africa's seven percent inflation rates, the real appreciation of Zimbabew's dollar - against an admittedly weak and probably undervalued rand - is running close to 30 percent. Against all currencies, the Zimbabwe unit is up some 10 percent to 12 percent in real terms over the past year.</p>
<p>With agricultural exports, especiallly tobacco, in boom mode and some of the main mineral exports also doing well, there is no great pressure on the balance of payments, especially since high real interest rates have constrained import and investment demand. But tourism is beginning to hurt, while mining companies are reporting unit cost increases of between 17 and 22 percent that are squeezing their margins.</p>
<p>Industrialists continue to clamour for anti-dumping measures against South Africa, seemingly unperturbed by the much more potent threat of low-cost competition from the Asian Rim and the need to reduce their dependence on domestic market sales. Indeed, the contrast between their vehement demands for tariff restructuring (a euphemism for greater protection) and their silence on exchange rate overvaluation is striking. It confirms that Zimbabwe has some way to go before the culture of export-led growth takes root amongst its industrial community.</p>
<p>Sooner rather than later the problems of the Treasury bill mountain, the monetary bubble, the liquidity overhang and the overvalued exchange rate will have to be resolved. It's hard to avoid the conclusion that the resolution is going to be both painful and inflationary.</p>
<p>The more protracted the strategy of  benign neglect the nastier the eventual monetary crunch will be when it comes.</p>
<p>				  / / / / / / /</p>
<p>(The opinions expressed in this article represent those of the author only. They should not be seen to represent the views of Reuters.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
