<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3110" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>Burundi: Burundi's new leader sacks senior military men.</title>
<headline>Burundi's new leader sacks senior military men.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bigg</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burundi's new Tutsi military strongman Major Pierre Buyoya on Tuesday sacked the three most powerful military officers in his ethnically-divided country, his spokesman said.</p>
<p>Buyoya sacked the powerful army chief-of-staff and previous de facto head of state, Colonel Jean Bikomagu, and also fired the head of the gendarmerie, Colonel Pascal Simbanduko, and Colonel Gedeon Fyiroko, head of the military at the presidential palace.</p>
<p>All three officers were Tutsis and were replaced by Tutsis.</p>
<p>The army, dominated by the minority Tutsi tribe, is locked in a guerrilla war with Hutu rebels, in which aid workers say around 1,000 people are dying each month.</p>
<p>Presidential spokesman Jean-Luc Ndizeye said Buyoya, who seized power in a bloodless coup on July 25, appointed equally senior but little-known officers to the three powerful posts.</p>
<p>Lieutenant-Colonel Vincent Niyungeko was named as new chief-of-staff, Lieutenant-Colonel Georges Muhorako as chief-of-staff of the gendarmerie and Lieutenant-Colonel Alfred Ngurunziza as head of military at the presidential palace.</p>
<p>&quot;With the new changes the president has the right to choose who he works with. It's not a question of competence or incompetence. It's just to show that President Buyoya has a free hand,&quot; Ndizeye added.</p>
<p>Analysts said the dismissals of the hardline officers may also have been designed to placate regional anger over the coup that ousted civilian Hutu President Sylvestre Ntibantunganya.</p>
<p>Burundi's neighbours have imposed an embargo on the country.</p>
<p>Ntibantunganya remains holed in the U.S. ambassador's residence in Bujumbura and his wife said last week that Buyoya had prevented him from leaving the country.</p>
<p>Regional countries, led by Tanzania, and including Rwanda, Kenya and Zaire, have cut air, land and water links with Burundi to try to force Buyoya to restore &quot;constitutional order and legality&quot; in the tea and coffee-growing nation.</p>
<p>They also want Buyoya, who first ruled Burundi between 1987 and 1983, to open talks with Hutu rebels led by former minister Leonard Nyangoma's National Council for the Defence of Democracy (CNDD).</p>
<p>Nyangoma, whose guerrillas are waging an increasingly successful war, has in recent weeks poured scorn on talks with Buyoya.</p>
<p>Buyoya has also said he would only talk to rebels who first laid down their arms.</p>
<p>Bikomagu and other unnamed senior military commanders were implicated in a U.N. report on an attempted coup in Burundi in October 1993 in which Burundi's first freely-elected president, Melchior Ndadaye, a Hutu, was murdered by Tutsi soldiers.</p>
<p>Western diplomats said Bikomagu played a central role not only in the 1993 failed coup attempt but also in the coup that brought Buyoya to power.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
