<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3113" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: Buyoya wants refugees protected, arrivals expected.</title>
<headline>Buyoya wants refugees protected, arrivals expected.</headline>
<byline>Christian Jennings</byline>
<dateline>BUTARE, Rwanda 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burundi's new Tutsi strongman Pierre Buyoya is opposed to any expulsions of Rwandan Hutu refugees from northern Burundi and has sent a team to investigate the reasons behind their movement, his spokesman said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But in Rwanda, aid agencies prepared to receive thousands more Rwandan Hutus, who say they are fleeing Magara camp in northern Burundi because of intimidation and beatings by Buyoya's Tutsi-dominated army.</p>
<p>In Brussels, the European Union called on the ethnically divided Central African country to seek peace.</p>
<p>The EU statement issued by Ireland -- which holds the rotating presidency of the 15-nation bloc -- said that the EU was deeply concerned about the situation in Burundi.</p>
<p>Buyoya's spokesman Jean-Luc Ndizeye told Reuters by telephone that the new president of Burundi remained committed to international conventions on the protection of refugees.</p>
<p>&quot;The president expects refugees to stay where they are. He does not expect any movements at all today,&quot; Ndizeye said.</p>
<p>In Butare, aid agencies prepared to receive some 4,500 refugees on Tuesday. &quot;We are expecting some 4,500 refugees today (Tuesday),&quot; Stephano Severe, head of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) in Butare, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Shortly after the July 25 coup that brought him to power, Buyoya ordered an end to expulsions of Rwandan Hutu refugees.</p>
<p>Ndizeye said the latest movements by thousands of refugees from the north were not part of official policy but were caused by panic on the part of the refugees after the army entered Magara on Sunday to search for arms.</p>
<p>He said Burundian army position near Magara had come under fire on Saturday and Sunday forcing soldiers to move into the camp to search for weapons and ammunition.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not the position of our government to send them (refugees) back. They have decided to leave on their own, many panicked when the army searched the camp. They are welcome to stay for as long as they want,&quot; Ndizeye said.</p>
<p>He said any one found guilty of inciting refugees to leave against their will would be punished. &quot;The president is not going back on his word to protect refugees,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The exodus of Rwandan refugees back to Rwanda picked up after troops killed three refugees at Magara camp. Refugees accused the army of killing them as part of a campaign of intimidation.</p>
<p>Army spokesman Lieutenant-Colonel Jean Minani confirmed on Tuesday that soldiers killed the three but said they fired only after one refugee pulled out a revolver and shot at them.</p>
<p>UNHCR's Severe said he expected Magara, the biggest of Rwandan refugee camps in Burundi with an initial population of more than 45,000 people, to be emptied within two to three days.</p>
<p>&quot;We have got 65 trucks at the ready today (Tuesday) and if the returns continue like this, it will only be a matter of two to three days before we finish the repatriations from Magara,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some 7,000 refugees returned to Rwanda on Monday leaving around 24,000 at Magara and 13,000 at Rukuramigabo Camp in neighbouring Kirundo province, Paul Stromberg, regional spokesman for the UNHCR, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Around two million Rwandan Hutus fled their homeland to Zaire, Tanzania and Burundi in 1994 after Tutsi rebels defeated the Hutu army and ousted the government, blamed for the genocide of up to one million Tutsis and moderate Hutus.</p>
<p>Burundian authorities accuse the refugees of supporting Hutu rebels waging a guerrilla war against the Burundian army in which 150,000 people have died since 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUTARE, Rwanda"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
