<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3114" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria denies reported Ogoni arrests.</title>
<headline>Nigeria denies reported Ogoni arrests.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Tostevin</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigerian authorities on Tuesday described as &quot;crazy&quot; reports that 16 activists from the Ogoni region had been arrested in the run-up to an anticipated Commonwealth visit.</p>
<p>&quot;It is crazy to say Ogonis have been arrested for being MOSOP (Movement for the Survival of Ogoni People) members, any time an Ogoni is arrested for anything they have to say it is political. I am not aware of these arrests at all,&quot; Fidelis Agbiki, press secretary to the local military administrator told Reuters by telephone from Port Harcourt.</p>
<p>MOSOP on Monday said a total of 16 Ogoni activists had been arrested in the past month.</p>
<p>&quot;Less than three weeks before the scheduled visit of the Commonwealth Ministerial Action Group to Nigeria, a new wave of arrests of MOSOP activists has begun,&quot; the group said in a statement issued in London.</p>
<p>Africa's most populous nation became an international pariah after MOSOP leader Ken Saro-Wiwa and eight other Ogoni activists were executed for murder last November, provoking international protests and Nigeria's suspension from the Commonwealth.</p>
<p>MOSOP said that the first of the new wave of arrests was Akina Deesor, producer of a radio station in Ogoni. Deesor was detained on July 31 for broadcasting an Ogoni song.</p>
<p>Fifteen more people were arrested on August 13 and accused of planning to seek meetings with the Commonwealth mission, it added.</p>
<p>&quot;Victims of the latest arrests are detained at unknown destinations and MOSOP believes they must have been tortured and kept in terrible conditions,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Nigeria refused to allow a Commonwealth fact-finding mission into the country, allowing instead a team from the United Nations.</p>
<p>But this month Nigeria offered to host talks on its suspension from the club of Britain and its former colonies in the capital Abuja on August 29-30.</p>
<p>The eight-nation Commonwealth Ministerial Action Committee on Nigeria has yet to respond to the invitation.</p>
<p>The two sides met in London in June and Commonwealth ministers decided not to impose agreed sanctions on Nigeria pending further talks.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not guilty of 'Ogoniphobia',&quot; said Agbiki. &quot;As we don't even know if the Commonwealth will visit here how can we arrest people for trying to meet them?&quot;</p>
<p>The U.N. team called for reform of some laws, including those under which Saro-Wiwa and the other activists were hanged, but backed military ruler General Sani Abacha's plan for restoring democracy by 1988, which the Commonwealth group had called &quot;inadequate&quot;.</p>
<p>Hundreds of people demonstrating against alleged repression met the U.N. group on its visit to Ogoniland.</p>
<p>&quot;The visit of the UN fact-finding team to Nigeria last April occasioned similar repression in Ogoni and the reprisal actions that followed that visit cost the Ogonis two lives and several detentions,&quot; MOSOP said.</p>
<p>The 500,000 Ogonis live on oil-rich land, which MOSOP says has been ruined by the activities of producing companies.</p>
<p>Shell, which pumps nearly half on Nigeria's two million barrels a day of crude oil, halted production in Ogoniland in 1993 after acts of sabotage by activists.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
