<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3116" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Party propaganda dominates S.Africa's truth body.</title>
<headline>Party propaganda dominates S.Africa's truth body.</headline>
<byline>Anton Ferreira</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former white president F.W. de Klerk appears before South Africa's &quot;truth commission&quot; on Wednesday as political parties strive to extract what propaganda value they can from the country's history of race war.</p>
<p>De Klerk, who will speak for the National Party that introduced apartheid in 1948, has said party leaders will accept overall responsibility for &quot;the many things that went wrong&quot; with the policy.</p>
<p>But he is likely to shift most of the blame onto his predecessors and cite the fact that barely a year after he took office he began in 1990 to dismantle apartheid -- freeing African National Congress leader Nelson Mandela as one of his first steps.</p>
<p>He plans to start his presentation in 1652, the year the first white settlers arrived in the Cape, giving him an opportunity to comment that British colonialists were among the first to enforce racial discrimination in South Africa.</p>
<p>The Truth and Reconciliation Commission is devoting all week to hearing from political parties how they saw the context of their actions during the apartheid era.</p>
<p>The commission, chaired by Archbishop Desmond Tutu, is charged with establishing as full a picture as possible of South Africa's decades of racial hostility during which millions of blacks were forced to move to &quot;homelands&quot;, hundreds of people were killed by police or guerrillas and countless more were tortured or jailed for their beliefs.</p>
<p>Political parties which have made submissions so far include the right-wing Freedom Front and the radical black Pan Africanist Congress (PAC), both of which tried to score political points.</p>
<p>The PAC, which won less than two percent of the vote in South Africa's first all-race election in 1994, sought to portray itself on Tuesday as a more important player in the liberation struggle than the ANC.</p>
<p>Freedom Front leader General Constand Viljoen, a former defence force chief, acknowledged on Monday that Afrikaners had &quot;invited&quot; violent revolution by their actions but said their brutality in trying to crush it was provoked in part by their opposition to communism.</p>
<p>ANC sources said Mandela's party, due to make its submission on Thursday, would object to any attempt to equate the morality of enforcing apartheid with that of resisting it.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
