<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3117" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Burundi's Buyoya asserts control in army shakeup.</title>
<headline>Burundi's Buyoya asserts control in army shakeup.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bigg</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burundi's new Tutsi strongman Pierre Buyoya has shocked the Tutsi-dominated army by sacking its powerful chief-of-staff in an apparent first step to tighten control over the unruly military.</p>
<p>Analysts said top officers were still stunned on Wednesday over this and two other dismissals seen as ending army impunity in the violent, ethnically-divided nation.</p>
<p>The army, dominated by the minority Tutsi tribe, is locked in a guerrilla war with Hutu rebels, in which aid workers say around 1,000 people are dying each month.</p>
<p>The decision to replace army chief-of-staff Col Jean Bikomagu with little-known Lt-Col Vincent Niyungeko reinforced Buyoya's credentials as a moderate determined to bring the army under control.</p>
<p>Bikomagu was heavily implicated in a recent U.N. report on an attempted army coup in October 1993, in which the country's first Hutu president was assassinated. The coup attempt sparked an ethnic civil war in Burundi in which around 150,000 people have died.</p>
<p>&quot;No sooner had the president been murdered than the officers regained control of their troops and Bikomagu retook supreme control of the army,&quot; said the U.N. report, a copy of which was seen by Reuters though it is yet to be published.</p>
<p>As part of the changes Lt-Col Georges Muhorako takes over from Col Pascal Simbanduko as chief of staff of the gendarmerie, while Lt-Col Alfred Ngurunziza replaces Gedeon Fyiroko as head of the military at State House (presidential palace).</p>
<p>&quot;People were saying that Buyoya was a prisoner of certain individuals but these changes show that he is free to choose whom he wants,&quot; presidential spokesman Jean-Luc Ndizeye told Reuters in a telephone interview. Army spokesmen declined to comment on the shakeup.</p>
<p>East African states including Tanzania, Kenya, Uganda and Rwanda imposed sanctions on Burundi following a coup d'etat on July 25 that brought Buyoya to power and deposed Hutu president Sylvestre Ntibantunganya.</p>
<p>Ntibantunganya remained holed-up at the American embassy residence in the capital on Tuesday, where he has been for almost a month.</p>
<p>Burundi's prime minister Pascal Firmin Ndimira on Tuesday said sanctions could lead to famine in Burundi and urged the states to lift the embargo, according to state radio.</p>
<p>&quot;Ndimira warned that sanctions imposed on his country may cause famine,&quot; the radio said, adding that internally displaced Burundians would be particularly hard hit.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, almost 5,000 Rwandan Hutu refugees returned to Rwanda from a camp in Ngozi province in north Burundi on Tuesday under pressure from the Burundian army, according to the United Nations High Commission for Refugees (UNHCR).</p>
<p>Refugees at Magara camp charged the army maintained a campaign of intimidation on Monday night, burning huts and warning the refugees they had to go home.</p>
<p>&quot;They came at night, burned huts and yelled at us that we had to go home,&quot; one refugee, who declined to be identified, told Reuters. Up to a dozen huts on the outskirts of the camp were still burning on Tuesday.</p>
<p>UNHCR officials instructed army guards at the camp to deny access to Reuters photographer Corinne Dufka, arguing that journalists had reported lies about events at Magara.</p>
<p>Aid workers are divided over whether army tactics at Magara add up to the forced expulsion of refugees, illegal under international law.</p>
<p>&quot;The rain prevented further movements of refugees from Magara Camp in Burundi,&quot; a UNHCR official told Reuters in Butare.</p>
<p>Butare governor Anatase Samuhungu told Reuters some of the refugees, accused of participation in Rwanda's 1994 genocide, could expect to find problems in their home villages.</p>
<p>Around two million Rwandan Hutus fled their homes for Zaire, Tanzania and Burundi after Tutsi rebels defeated the Hutu army and ousted the government, blamed for a genocide against up to a million Tutsis and moderate Hutus.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
