<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3124" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Gold Fields yr profit helped by base metals.</title>
<headline>Gold Fields yr profit helped by base metals.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold Fields of South Africa Ltd said on Tuesday that strong performances in its base metal and non-mining investments helped to offset reduced earnings from gold mining investments in the year ended June 30.</p>
<p>&quot;Chief executive Alan Wright acknowledges that lower dividend receipts from the gold mining investments nevertheless contributed to a five percent decline in earnings,&quot; the group said in a statement released late Tuesday.</p>
<p>Mining operations had resumed in the areas affected by underground fires at Driefontein Consolidated Ltd's east and west gold mines, &quot;which should start making a valuable contribution to production&quot;, Wright said.</p>
<p>Widespread labour unrest across the industry did not leave operations unscathed and continued to impact on productivity at Gold Fields operations, he said.</p>
<p>Turning to Northam Platinum Ltd, Wright said that considerable progress had been made in introducing new mining methods and he said he expected a positive cash flow from Northam in the coming financial year.</p>
<p>A feasibility study at Gold Fields Ghana's Tarkwa concession had confirmed its viability with gold output from the first phase of the operation estimated at 230,000 ounces a year.</p>
<p>The group's earnings were supported by outstanding contributions from Gold Fields Coal, Zinc Corp of South Africa Ltd and Black Mountain.</p>
<p>Gold Fields posted earnings per share for the year of 393 cents compared to 417 cents in the previous year.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
