<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3128" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: More Cuban doctors arrive to work in S.Africa.</title>
<headline>More Cuban doctors arrive to work in S.Africa.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of 110 Cuban doctors arrived in South Africa on Tuesday, joining their 96 compatriots who have been working in impoverished areas since February.</p>
<p>The latest group, which includes surgeons, paediatricians and gynaecologists, will stay for three years to help in rural and township hospitals which are under severe pressure with the departure of many young South African doctors not prepared to put up with long hours, poor pay and spiralling crime.</p>
<p>Under a health cooperation accord, a third group of 250 Cuban specialists is due in South Africa in November, followed by a fourth group, which will take the eventual number to 600.</p>
<p>South Africa's Deputy Foreign Minister Aziz Pahad told a news conference on a visit to Cuba recently the South African press had initially been sceptical about the Cuban doctors.</p>
<p>&quot;But they have done so well in their professional work and in their relations with our people that they have become excellent ambassadors,&quot; Pahad said.</p>
<p>Surveys show up to half of South Africa's English-speaking medical graduates emigrate soon after qualifying. Only 22,000 doctors serve the population of about 43 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
