<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3135" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa budgeting within its means - Marcus.</title>
<headline>S.Africa budgeting within its means - Marcus.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa is budgeting according to its means, with tighter control on rollovers and policy-making increasingly restricted by affordability, Deputy Minister of Finance Gill Marcus said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Marcus, former chairwoman of parliament's influential finance committee, outlined several mechanisms introduced since the transition to democracy in 1994 to control expenditure and to ensure efficient use of state funds.</p>
<p>&quot;The Budget Council as well as the national Budget Committee, which has just completed two weeks of presentations, have agreed to and are preparing budgets in accordance with the four percent deficit target,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday, Finance Minister Trevor Manuel told a news conference the government was on track to meet both its 5.1 percent deficit target for fiscal 1996/97 and its four percent target for fiscal 1997/98.</p>
<p>Marcus said the government was trying to extend its budget horizon from one year at present to at least three years, adding: &quot;This approach will also enable departments and provinces to plan ahead with confidence.&quot;</p>
<p>She cautioned planning ministries to ensure that their long-term strategies were mapped in accordance with revenue projections in the government's macro-economic framework published in June.</p>
<p>&quot;The constitution has created various bodies, commissions and obligations, all of which require additional expenditure. We urgently recommend that this be costed and an approach taken that fits with what we can afford,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She urged that policy white papers should be &quot;accompanied by actuarial evaluation of the expenditure required&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Spending allocations should be outlined for a three to five-year horizon, enabling multi-year planning to achieve objectives. This needs to be done so as to reflect objectives, time frames, costs and what is actually going to be delivered in return for the resources allocated,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Marcus confirmed a report earlier this week that the projected rollover of budgeted funds from fiscal 1995/96 to the current financial year could total 10.5 billion rand.</p>
<p>&quot;This requires urgent attention. It clearly indicates that the question is not simply one of allocating more resources, but paying attention to capacity, reprioritisation, efficiency and the effectiveness of spending within all departments and provincs.</p>
<p>&quot;Ongoing discussions are taking place with the departments reflecting large rollovers, as to both the cause and the solutions,&quot; Marcus said.</p>
<p>-- Brendan Boyle, Parliamentary newsroom, +27 21 403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
