<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3139" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa central bank yet to draw on credit lines.</title>
<headline>S.Africa central bank yet to draw on credit lines.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's central Reserve Bank has yet to draw on foreign credit lines in its defence of the rand, Bank Governor Chris Stals said on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>&quot;Obviously we won't run down our reserves completely. But the moment you use your credit facilities you pay interest on them, so we are trying to avoid paying interest on the facilities for as long as possible,&quot; he said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>The Bank has some 15 billion in foreign credit lines it can draw on to bolster official reserves which stood at just over one month's import cover at end-July.</p>
<p>The central bank's gold and foreign exchange reserves fell 883 million rand to 10.37 billion rand in July.  </p>
<p>Stals confirmed the Bank had been active in the foreign exchange market in recent days providing liquidity by selling dollars following renewed pressure on the rand which hit an all-time low of 4.59 against the dollar late on Monday.</p>
<p>There had been considerable speculative transactions in recent days, he said, with markets rattled by last week's murder by car hijackers of Erich Ellmer, the German financial director of the AEG electronics group in South Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets were influenced by the murder of the German businessman. That certainly justified some intervention by us,&quot; Stals said.</p>
<p>That intervention, which some dealers described as &quot;aggressive&quot;, particularly last Friday, had prompted speculation that the Bank may have dipped into its credit facilities.  </p>
<p>Asked about the possibility of an increase in interest rates in the face of pressure on the currency and a tight money market, Stals said the Bank was monitoring the situation daily.</p>
<p>&quot;We must be very flexible about it (moving rates)...we watch the situation develop from day to day and every day. It looks like it is getting a little bit more stable.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Ben Hirschler, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
