<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3141" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Burundi's Buyoya sacks top chiefs in shake-up.</title>
<headline>Burundi's Buyoya sacks top chiefs in shake-up.</headline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burundi's new Tutsi military strongman on Tuesday sacked the ethnically-divided country's three most powerful military officers, his spokesman announced.</p>
<p>Jean-Luc Ndizeye told Reuters that Pierre Buyoya, who seized power in a bloodless coup on July 25, had dismissed powerful chief-of-staff Colonel Jean Bikomagu, head of the gendarmerie Colonel Pascal Simbanduko and Colonel Gedeon Fyiroko, head of the military at the presidential palace.  </p>
<p>Ndizeye said Buyoya had appointed Lieutenant-Colonel Vincent Niyungeko as new chief-of-staff, Lieutenant-Colonel Georges Muhorako as chief-of-staff of the gendarmerie and Lieutenant-Colonel Alfred Ngurunziza as head of military at the presidential palace. All are Tutsi officers.</p>
<p>&quot;With the new changes the president has the right to choose who he works with. It's not a question of competence or incompetence. It's just to show that President Buyoya has a free hand,&quot; Ndizeye added.</p>
<p>Analysts said the dismissals of the hardline and powerful officers may be a move by Buyoya to placate regional anger over the coup that ousted civilian Hutu President Sylvestre Ntibantunganya. Neighbours have imposed an embargo on Burundi.</p>
<p>Bikomagu and other unnamed senior military commanders were implicated in a U.N. report on an attempted coup in Burundi in October 1993 in which Burundi's first freely-elected president, Melchior Ndadaye, a Hutu, was murdered by Tutsi soldiers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
