<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3142" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa sees illegal immigrants as big problem.</title>
<headline>S.Africa sees illegal immigrants as big problem.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Home Affairs Minister Mangosuthu Buthelezi expressed concern on Tuesday at a flood of illegal immigrants into South Africa, saying they placed an unacceptable burden on already stretched services like health and housing.</p>
<p>&quot;The position is very serious. They pose a serious threat to South Africans as far as services are concerned,&quot; Buthelezi told a briefing for parliamentary correspondents.</p>
<p>He said his department estimated there were between two million and five million illegal immigrants, compared with South Africa's total population of about 40 million.</p>
<p>About 70 percent of the illegal immigrants are from neighbouring Mozambique, the rest mostly being split among South Africa's other neighbours like Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>According to figures from his department, 150,000 illegal immigrants were deported last year at a cost of 12 million rand ($2.6 million).</p>
<p>Buthelezi said the issue would be discussed at the annual meeting of the Southern African Development Community (SADC) in Lesotho this week but he ruled out any steps towards allowing free movement within SADC on the European Union model.</p>
<p>He said police were unable to give full attention to illegal immigration because of South Africa's crime wave. ($1=4.6 rand)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
