<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3143" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ETHIOPIA: Private Ethiopia firms see rise in coffee exports.</title>
<headline>Private Ethiopia firms see rise in coffee exports.</headline>
<byline>Tsegaye Tadesse</byline>
<dateline>ADDIS ABABA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Private Ethiopian coffee firms, responsible for 50 percent of the country's record exports of 102,000 tonnes in the current year to end-September, expect exports to rise even further on the back of government reforms.</p>
<p>Senior coffee industry officials also confirmed earlier forecasts of a rise in production because of favourable weather and a renewed enthusiasm among farmers, who now receive their earnings from the crop in a timely fashion.</p>
<p>&quot;Our success this time could be attributed to the favourable policy measures taken by the government to help us expand our business,&quot; Aschenaki G. Hiwot, secretary-general of the private Ethiopian Coffee Exporters Association, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Reform undertaken in the financial sector and the task force established by the government to seek swift solutions whenever we have problems have also helped in the improvement of our business,&quot; Aschenaki said in an interview.</p>
<p>Aschenaki said that as a result of &quot;encouraging government support&quot; enjoyed by private exporters, many of the 47 exporters were now in the process of improving their facilities.</p>
<p>He said private exporters were building modern stores (warehouses) and installing high-technology coffee-cleaning machines so as to be able to export better quality coffee.</p>
<p>Ethiopia exported 102,00 tonnes of coffee during the 1995-96 period, the highest volume in its trade history. But it earned $279.5 million -- much less compared to $330.9 million it received for exporting 78,420 tonnes of coffee in 1994/95.</p>
<p>The government and private exporters have blamed poor global prices for the decline in export earnings. Aschenaki would not say what percentage rise he saw in 1996/97.</p>
<p>Ethiopia's annual coffee production, which has ranged between 200,000 and 250,000 tonnes in recent years, is expected to top 300,000 tonnes, government agriculturalists said.</p>
<p>Private exporters sold 48,640 tonnes of the 1995/96 crop for $141.8 million while the state-owned Ethiopian Coffee Export Enterprise exported 53,183 tonnes for $137.72 million.</p>
<p>Ethiopian private coffee exporters were branded as economic saboteurs and their businesses were closed during the rule of the dictator Mengistu Haile Mariam who was ousted in 1991.</p>
<p>Under the liberal economic policy declared by the government of Prime Minister Meles Zenawi in 1992, licences for private exporters were restored and they were allowed to participate in the industry previously crippled under a state monopoly.</p>
<p>Ethiopia is Africa's third largest producer of coffee after Uganda and Ivory Coast.</p>
<p>Coffee is Ethiopia's main export commodity and accounts for more than 60 percent of all foreign exchange revenues, according to government figures.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ETHPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADDIS ABABA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ETHIOPIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
