<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3144" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TOGO: Togo's president names new prime minister.</title>
<headline>Togo's president names new prime minister.</headline>
<byline>Apedo Amah</byline>
<dateline>LOME 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Togo's President Gnassingbe Eyadema named one of his supporters prime minister on Tuesday, after accepting the resignation of opposition politician Edem Kodjo who had held the post since 1994.</p>
<p>Officials said Eyadema, West Africa's longest serving leader, named Kwassi Klutse as prime minister in a decree. Klutse was minister of planning and regional development in the outgoing government.</p>
<p>Kodjo, a former Organisation of African Unity secretary general who accepted the post after elections in 1994, resigned on Monday, ending months of friction with Eyadema.</p>
<p>He said that three by-election wins by Eyadema's Togolese People's Rally (RPT), the latest on Sunday, had changed the balance of power in the 81-seat parliament.</p>
<p>Under the constitution, approved by referendum early in Togo's democratic transition in 1992, the prime minister must come from within the parliamentary majority.</p>
<p>Eyadema, an army general, was elected president in 1993 during Togo's turbulent transition to democracy in polls boycotted by the main opposition.</p>
<p>Kodjo and his Togolese Union for Democracy (UTD) were part of an opposition alliance that won a majority in the 1994 parliamentary elections until the Supreme Court annulled three of its seats citing irregularities.</p>
<p>Kodjo broke ranks with his allies in the main opposition party, the Action Committee for Renewal (CAR), and accepted the post of prime minister, citing the interests of national unity.</p>
<p>But relations between Kodjo and Eyadema had been strained in recent months. Kodjo spoke publicly of differences and Eyadema's supporters openly criticised the prime minister.</p>
<p>Eyadema's party won the three vacant seats -- two outright on August 4 and one in a runoff on Sunday.</p>
<p>If confirmed by the supreme court Sunday's result will leave Eyadema's party with 40 of parliament's 81 seats, but the support of a minor party and two independents following earlier defections gives him a comfortable majority.</p>
<p>The CAR boycotted all three by-elections. Some commentators had speculated the new prime minister would come from its ranks.</p>
<p>Sunday's by-election formally brought the first phase of Togo's democratic transition to an end.</p>
<p>A string of Francophone countries in West and Central Africa embraced democracy in the early 1990s after the collapse of Communist rule in Eastern Europe. Ivory Coast and Benin have already held their second wave of multi-party elections.</p>
<p>Presidential and parliamentary elections in Togo are not due until 1998 and 1999 respectively.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TOGO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TOGO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
