<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3148" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Peace on track despite clash in S.African Zulu area.</title>
<headline>Peace on track despite clash in S.African Zulu area.</headline>
<byline>Ellis Mnyandu</byline>
<dateline>DURBAN, South Africa 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African President Nelson Mandela's ANC and their Inkatha rivals reaffirmed their quest for peace on Tuesday after five people were wounded in a shoot-out between their supporters.</p>
<p>Monday's shooting, after a row between Inkatha and African National Congress supporters at a court hearing over the killing of four policemen in an Inkatha stronghold last year, raised fears of a new flare-up of violence in KwaZulu-Natal province.</p>
<p>But a joint statement by the province's premier and Inkatha Freedom Party (IFP) national chairman, Frank Mdlalose, and provincial ANC chief Jacob Zuma condemned the clash and said it should not be allowed to derail the fragile peace.</p>
<p>&quot;The leadership of both the ANC and IFP appreciate the achievement of peace that has taken root in this province,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;We remain committed to peace and all efforts towards bringing about peace in our province. We encourage everyone who has gone out of his way to make (peace) happen, to continue to do so.&quot;</p>
<p>Political violence in the province, dominated by its nine million Zulus, subsided dramatically after peaceful local elections in June which gave Inkatha clear control of rural areas while the ANC swept the cities.</p>
<p>A joint peace drive between the two parties whose supporters had fought a low-level civil war for a decade before has stemmed the fighting in which more than 14,000 people had died.</p>
<p>But the truce, brokered just days before the vote, has been under constant fire. Local warlords from both sides still refuse to accede that the time to end the bloodshed has come, violence monitors say.</p>
<p>&quot;Senior politicians talk peace in public, but on the other hand they are turning a blind eye to what their supporters are doing on the ground. People need firm police action and stricter gun control here,&quot; said one such monitor, Mary de Haas.</p>
<p>The IFP had said in a separate statement that unless incidents like Monday's shoot-out were prevented, the peace pact could turn out to be just a &quot;cruel hoax&quot;.</p>
<p>Three adults and two children were shot and burnt to death last weekend in a suspected political attack, police said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DURBAN, South Africa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
