<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3152" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Plantations, pull Nairobi index further down.</title>
<headline>Plantations, pull Nairobi index further down.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Nairobi Stock Exchange 20-share index continued its downward trend on Tuesday with less demand for stocks, and share prices for most leading stocks lost value, brokers and bourse officials said.</p>
<p>The index fell 14.56 points to 3106.71. Turnover was 9.136 million shillings on 394,742 shares from 30.049 million shillings on 1,402,019 shares on Monday.</p>
<p>A bourse official said there was little demand for shares as most investors found the prices not right to deal in. He said stocks would only attract buyers if prices eased.</p>
<p>A floor dealer said the stocks that fell were mostly in the agricultural, commercial and industrial sectors.</p>
<p>Plantation company Brooke Bond lost 4.0 shillings to close at 173, Kakuzi eased to 91 from 91.50 but Rea Vipingo rose to 11.45 from 11.40 on 17,900 shares.</p>
<p>In commercials, CMC Holdings shed 4.0 shillings to close at 61, Express Kenya Ltd eased to 81.50 from 83 while Kenya Airways traded 55,636 shares at 10 shillings, eased to 9.50 but corrected to close at 9.95.</p>
<p>Among financials, National Bank of Kenya continued to dominate the market's trading with a total of 236,255 shares being dealt at 18.50, 17.50 and a close of 17.95 from Monday's close of 18 shillings.</p>
<p>Brokers said there was a lot of demand for the National Bank with local investors showing interest, but the state pension agency National Social Security Fund (NSSF) continued to be the main buyer for its shares.</p>
<p>NSSF already owns around 42 percent of National Bank. Economists say the pension agency is looking to obtain a majority stake in the bank ahead of plans that will make it totally independent of government by end of the year.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in industrials, British American Tobacco fell 1.0 to 69, Bamburi Cement Ltd eased to 29 from 29.25 while Total Kenya remained unchanged at 78 shillings.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
