<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3163" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: South Africa prepares for transport privatisation.</title>
<headline>South Africa prepares for transport privatisation.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The South African government has earmarked transport as the second sector to be assessed for privatisation with air transport on the agenda for a meeting on Friday, Trade and Industry Minister Alec Erwin said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Erwin, standing in for Public Enterprises Minister Stella Sigcau, who is ill, told a news conference that the search for a foreign equity partner for state-owned telecommunications group Telkom remained on track for completion by early next year.</p>
<p>&quot;The next sector will be transportation, but there is no overall timetable, it doesn't make sense to do that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Erwin said the government would not publish its proposals for the full or partial privatisation of transportation services until they had been discussed with labour unions in line with a National Framework Agreement (NFA) on privatisation.</p>
<p>Government privatisation adviser Kennedy Memani said officials were in the process of identifying separate entities within the transportation sector, ranging from the road transportation company to the South African Airways, and drafting a range of options for each.</p>
<p>He said options for the air transportation industry would be discussed with unions at an NFA meeting on Friday.</p>
<p>President Nelson Mandela has declared privatisation to be the official policy of his African National Congress government and the commitment was reiterated in the macro-economic framework for growth and development released by Finance Minister Trevor anuel in June.</p>
<p>The first sales of government-owned enterprises are likely to be radio stations owned by the South African Broadcasting Corporation with foreign minority shareholder for the giant Telkom telephone and telecommunications company next.</p>
<p>But Erwin confirmed that agreement in principle had been reached with labour unions on an outside equity partner for the state-owned Airports Company, which reported a 223.3 million rand ($52.4 million) profit on Monday.</p>
<p>The Business Day newspaper reported on Tuesday that the government was considering a three to five-year limit on the South African Rail Commuter Corporation's monopoly on commuter rail services before allowing private competitors into the market.</p>
<p>Erwin said there was no logjam in the privatisation process, but stressed that it would be handled cautiously.</p>
<p>&quot;The National Framework Agreement sets up the ability to deal with each and every case. This is not going to be an easy process...but what's accepted is an agreement to manage the process,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
