<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3165" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Burundi's Buyoya says he wants refugees protected.</title>
<headline>Burundi's Buyoya says he wants refugees protected.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burundi's new Tutsi military strongman is opposed to any expulsions of Rwandan Hutu refugees from northern Burundi and has sent a team to investigate the reasons behind their movement, his spokesman said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Boyoya's spokesman Jean-Luc Ndizeye told Reuters by telephone that the new president of Burundi remained committed to international conventions on the protection of refugees.</p>
<p>&quot;The president expects refugees to stay where they are. He does not expect any movements at all today,&quot; Ndizeye said.</p>
<p>U.N. officials expect thousands of refugees on Tuesday to leave northern Burundi and return to Rwanda. They say they fear for their security following an army coup in Burundi on July 25.</p>
<p>Shortly after the coup by the Tutsi-dominated army, Buyoya ordered an end to forced expulsions of Rwandan Hutu refugees.</p>
<p>Ndizeye said movements by thousands of refugees from the north since Sunday were not part of official policy and any one found guilty of inciting them would be punished. &quot;The president is not going back on his word to protect refugees,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The exodus of Rwandan refugees back to Rwanda picked up after troops killed three refugees at Magara camp. Refugees accused the army of killing them as part of a campaign of intimidation.</p>
<p>Lieutenant-Colonel Jean Minani, a Burundian army spokesman, confirmed on Tuesday troops killed the three but said they fired only after one refugee pulled out a revolver and shot at them.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
