<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3166" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African finance ministry working on 14 bills.</title>
<headline>S.African finance ministry working on 14 bills.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The finance ministry had 14 bills either before parliament or awaiting certification by state law advisers, Finance Minister Trevor Manuel said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>He told a media briefing at parliament that the department was also working on a white paper on financial management and expenditure budget reform.</p>
<p>The bills before parliament included the Special Pensions Bill to provide so-called &quot;struggle pensions&quot; to those who fought against apartheid and were not able to provide for their own pensions.</p>
<p>The Customs and Excise Amendment Bill provided for some technical customs and excise duty adjustments while the Borrowing Powers of Provincial Governments Bill aimed at allowing provinces to raise loans for capital expenditure.</p>
<p>The Banks Amendment Bill aimed to amend the 1990 Banks Act to regulate investments by banks in joint ventures with or outside South Africa and further regulate the amalgamation of two or more banks.</p>
<p>The state expenditure department had the Supplementary Estimates and Appropriation Bill and the Finance Bill before parliament.</p>
<p>Bills awaiting certification included the Development Bank of Southern Africa Bill aimed to accommodate the bank's new role in the financing of domestic infrastructure.</p>
<p>The Unit Trusts Control Amendment Bill would allow for the establishment of money market unit portfolios by unit trust schemes.</p>
<p>&quot;This will provide the public with an alternative savings mechanism in the short-term money market and will make it more difficult for 'grey market operators' such as money brokers, pyramid schemes, to take savings from unsophisticated small savers,&quot; said a memorandum handed out at the briefing.</p>
<p>The Stock Exchanges Control Amendment Bill would correct minor errors in existing legislation.</p>
<p>The Financial Markets Control Amendment Bill would correct minor errors in the Financial Markets Control Act and introduce &quot;interdealer brokers&quot;.</p>
<p>The Insurance Amendment Bill would provide for the underwriting of registered medical scheme business, prescribe the valuation of assets, further allow foreign investments by insurers, prohibit the publication of misleading material and further restrict the use of certain names by unregistered insurers.</p>
<p>The Safe Deposit of Securities Amendment Bill would clarify certain interpretations and the Revenue Laws Amendment Bill would legislate recently announced tax incentives for investors.</p>
<p>The South African Reserve Bank Second Amendment Bill would synchronise the election of board members and make several other technical changes.</p>
<p>-- Lynda Loxton, Cape Town newsroom, +27 21 252-238</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
