<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3167" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa money market shortage surges 831 mln rand.</title>
<headline>S.Africa money market shortage surges 831 mln rand.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's money market shortage surged 831 million rand on Monday to 8.847 billion rand, Reserve Bank figures show.</p>
<p>Money market traders had varying reasons for the rise, ranging from Reserve Bank manipulation to Standard Bank's repayment of its three billion rand foreign loan which it drew in May.</p>
<p>&quot;Our view is that the Reserve Bank is trying to keep the shortage at these levels via the tax and loan accounts or by the forex accounts,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;By doing so the Bank keeps short-term rates where they are and keeps the squeeze on (commercial) banks without having to hike Bank rate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But John Cruickshank, Standard Bank domestic treasury director, said that argument was counterproductive.</p>
<p>&quot;If the (central) Bank keeps the squeeze on the banks then the implication is that rates have to be hiked,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Three-month NCDs were static at between 16.65 to 16.85 percent while the 90-day BA rate was also unchanged at between 16.05 and 16.25 percent.</p>
<p>Another dealer said the higher shortage was a result of Standard Bank repaying part of the three billion rand offshore loan it drew in May.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that in the course of this month, Standard Bank has been repaying part of its offshore loans,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>Cruickshank had no comment on the speculation.</p>
<p>He said that the differing explanations offered for the higher shortage highlighted the fact &quot;that we are all working in a market which is to some extent rather confusing&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that the shortage can gyrate to the extent that it has is disquieting at the best of times,&quot; Cruickshank said.</p>
<p>-- Paul Richardson, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
