<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3169" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: New figures underline ailing S.African tourism.</title>
<headline>New figures underline ailing S.African tourism.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hotel bednights sold to foreign tourists slumped by 29.3 percent in June 1996 compared to the year ago period, new figures from South Africa's Central Statistical Service show.</p>
<p>The decline reflects, in part, a high comparative month since a large number of visitors came to South Africa a year ago for the World Cup Rugby tournament.</p>
<p>But a fall in foreign bednights sold, to 137,141 in June 1996 from 193,881 in June 1995, underscores the sharp slowdown in South Africa's tourist industry.</p>
<p>According to the South African Tourist Board, visitor arrivals in the first five months of the year grew just 0.2 percent, down from 30 percent a year ago.</p>
<p>Much of the stagnation is blamed on violent crime which officials say is scaring off foreign visitors.</p>
<p>&quot;The decline can be put down to perceptions about personal safety and the negative publicity which South Africa has received as a result of its crime problem,&quot; Satour research head James Seymour told Reuters last week.</p>
<p>While most holidaymakers have no trouble, police figures show South Africa is one of the world's most crime-ridden societies. A total of 1.98 million serious crimes were reported last year, with only half solved, including 36,888 rapes, 18,983 murders and 66,838 armed robberies.</p>
<p>Satour believes South Africa has the potential to increase tourism over 10 percent a year into the next century, after the market was kick-started by the country's first all-race elections in 1994. But this target is out of reach for 1996.</p>
<p>Last year nearly 1.1 million foreign tourists visited South Africa. That was 50 percent up on 1994, but still a pinprick compared with the 40 million who flock to Spain each year.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27-11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
