<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3173" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Kenyan press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY NATION</p>
<p>- Opposition FORD-Kenya (Forum for the Restoration of Democracy) will institute private criminal prosecutions against 30 individuals and firms named in the Public Investment Committee report in connection with irregular financial deals.</p>
<p>- A report by USAID's Regional Economic Development Service says Wajir, Mandera and Isiolo districts in the North Eastern Province of Kenya face a serious food shortage because of the failure of long rains between march and July.</p>
<p>EAST AFRICAN STANDARD</p>
<p>- The new Kenneth Matiba and Raila Odinga alliance comes under heavy criticim from FORD-Kenya chairman Kijana Wamalwa's group, which terms it as just another plot to ruin the National Opposition Alliance.</p>
<p>- The chairman of the Kenya Dairy Board Andrew Kiptoon says the proposed Kenya Dairy Development Policy is not meant to dismember the giant Kenya Cooperative Creameries.</p>
<p>- Kikuyu opposition member of parliament Paul Muite has challenged ruling Kenya African National Union leaders to tell the public why they are opposed to consitutional reforms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
