<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3176" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: South African budget targets on track - Manuel.</title>
<headline>South African budget targets on track - Manuel.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African Finance Minister Trevor Manuel said on Tuesday he was confident the government remained on track to meet its budget deficit target of 5.1 percent of GDP this financial year (April-March) and four percent next.  </p>
<p>Manuel, addressing reporters, added that growth this year was set to reach three percent, little changed from 1995's 3.3 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are confident of attaining a 5.1 percent deficit despite the currency problems and we're on target to move to the next level, namely the four percent target next year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Latest figures showed expenditure levels were in line with predictions and revenue was better than expected, he said.  </p>
<p>Economic fundamentals were looking sound, he added:</p>
<p>&quot;Indications are that we remain on target for three percent growth. Even though there is a slowdown in manufacturing we have a very buoyant agricultural sector and non-gold mining (sector).&quot;</p>
<p>Inflation remained fairly well under control, despite the weakness of the rand, he said.</p>
<p>The one area of difficulty was the current account of the balance of payments. &quot;That is a structural problem that will take a long time to correct,&quot; Manuel said.</p>
<p>South Africa was still experiencing positive inflows, but this was not sufficient to cover the current account which is running at around one billion rand a month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
