<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3187" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin takes short break, stays out of sight.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin takes short break, stays out of sight.</headline>
<byline>Brian Killen</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The presidential press service, denying new rumours that President Boris Yeltsin was ill, said on Tuesday that the Kremlin leader had started a two-day break in the picturesque lakeland of northwestern Russia.</p>
<p>A spokesman said Yeltsin would size up prospects for a longer vacation in Valdai, which is some 350 km (220 miles) northwest of Moscow.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, 65, has made only one brief public appearance since late June, at his inauguration ceremony on August 9, where he read the oath from an autocue in a flat, emotionless voice.</p>
<p>Rumours have circulated in Russia and in the West that he is ill, but the presidential press office has denied them all, saying Yeltsin has been working every day.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's press secretary Sergei Yastrzhembsky said on Tuesday that the president had flown by helicopter to a residence in Valdai, a lakeland region northwest of Moscow.</p>
<p>The flight took two hours and 20 minutes, testifying to Yeltsin's solid health, Yastrzhembsky said on NTV commercial television. He said there was no special medical equipment in the building where Yeltsin was staying.</p>
<p>Itar-Tass news agency earlier quoted him as saying that a statement on Yeltsin's trip had been prompted by &quot;usual guesses and suppositions about the president's whereabouts&quot;.</p>
<p>He dismissed as &quot;complete rubbish&quot; a report by Ekho Moskvy radio that Yeltsin, who suffered two heart attacks last year, had been in a specialist cardiological centre since August 15.</p>
<p>Ekho Moskvy quoted informed sources as saying that doctors at the centre, named after heart specialist Yevgeny Chazov, had diagnosed the president's condition as of average seriousness.</p>
<p>&quot;In the coming hours the question of carrying out a surgical operation may be decided,&quot; the radio said.</p>
<p>But it also quoted the acting head doctor at the centre as saying Yeltsin was not there. &quot;You can come and see for yourself,&quot; the doctor said.</p>
<p>Yastrzhembsky on Monday denied a report by the U.S. magazine Time which said Yeltsin had suffered new heart problems in the second half of June.</p>
<p>Time said that, according to an official Kremlin medical advisory it had obtained, the president needed round-the-clock monitoring and the Kremlin was considering transferring him to a Swiss clinic for a bypass operation.</p>
<p>&quot;This information is part of a series of rumours and conjectures concerning the state of the president's health,&quot; Yastrzhembsky told a news briefing.</p>
<p>In a move likely to trigger more speculation about Yeltsin's health, Russia's Security Council, which groups top officials and is managed by newly appointed Alexander Lebed, issued a statement doubting the authenticity of recent presidential orders on rebel Chechnya.</p>
<p>&quot;The contents of the documents give solid grounds to doubt that the president of Russia took a direct part in finalising the text of the order,&quot; said the statement.</p>
<p>Yeltsin on Sunday ordered Lebed, whom he had put in charge of handling the 20-month conflict in Chechnya, to restore Russian control over the capital Grozny from separatists who seized large parts of it on August 6.</p>
<p>But the statement said Yeltsin's orders were issued with a facsimile of the president's signature rather than signed by the president in person. It has also said Lebed was unaware of the preparation of the orders -- which violated normal procedure.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
