<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3189" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak VUB share gains push SAX index to yr-high.</title>
<headline>Slovak VUB share gains push SAX index to yr-high.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovak top shares were mostly quiet in thin trading on the Bratislava Stock Exchange (BSE) on Tuesday, with gains to shares of VUB bank helping push the SAX index up 0.65 points to new year-high of 226.34.</p>
<p>The country's largest commercial bank VUB closed up 200 crowns at 2,300 crowns, on a volume of 498 traded shares. Brokers said one unidentified investor has been apparently building up a position in VUB.</p>
<p>&quot;If it's really so, this investor must be in hurry, as I see the price in VUB as being a bit artificially and too quickly pushed up,&quot; Patrik Granec of Slovenska Sporitelna said.</p>
<p>Slovak parliament effectively postponed further privatisation of shares in the country's banks until at least the end of March next year, but analysts said the investor could be building a position anticipating the state selloff.</p>
<p>Investment fund VUB Kupon dominated the listless trading on the BSE floor, with closing price at 760 crowns, down 40, on a volume of 14,491 traded shares.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect further decline in VUB Kupon issue, as the price is likely pulled down by one of the investors struggling for a strategic stake in the fund,&quot; Granec said.</p>
<p>Among the few shares traded on the bourse floor, steel maker VSZ closed unchanged at 651 crowns, with 822 traded shares, and oil refinery Slovnaft traded 64 shares, closing up 10 crowns at 1,010.</p>
<p>Overall volume edged up to 91,312 shares, from 82,891 shares traded on Monday, on turnover of 71.89 million crowns, after 63.84 million crowns. -- Peter Javurek, Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
