<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3190" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Civilians flee Grozny saying bombing begun.</title>
<headline>Civilians flee Grozny saying bombing begun.</headline>
<byline>Lawrence Sheets</byline>
<dateline>GROZNY, Russia 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Terrified civilians flooded out of the Chechen capital on Tuesday after a top Russian military official threatened to use planes and heavy artillery to drive separatist forces from the city.</p>
<p>The refugees, many of them with little more than the clothes in which they stood, said Russian planes had started bombing the town, much of it already in ruins after attacks at the start of Russia's campaign to crush Chechnya's independence bid.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole city is on its way out,&quot; said Nina Madayeva, who said 12 planes had bombed Grozny's southwestern Chernorechye district overnight. &quot;We've been in a basement for 14 or 15 days and couldn't stand it any more.&quot;</p>
<p>Konstantin Pulikovsky, Russia's acting commander in Chechnya, said his forces had begun artillery attacks on rebels in Grozny and would bomb the city if needed to drive them out. But he denied that bombing had already started.</p>
<p>With the region on the brink of all-out war and President Boris Yeltsin reported to have gone on holiday, arguments broke out in Moscow over who was running policy on Chechnya.</p>
<p>Russia's influential Security Council, whose secretary, Alexander Lebed was put in charge of resolving the conflict last week by Yeltsin, cast doubt over the authenticity of the president's latest orders on the region.</p>
<p>A Security Council statement said Yeltsin did not appear to have been involved in drawing up the order to retake Grozny from the rebels, which carried a facsimile of his signature.</p>
<p>It said carrying the order out would ruin peace efforts undertaken by Lebed and wreck a ceasefire deal he agreed with the separatist leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;This would mean in fact the beginning of a large-scale military operation involving aviation and artillery, which would naturally lead to heavy losses among federal troops, massive deaths among the civilian population...and a justified burst of resentment in the country,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The presidential press office said Yeltsin had left for Valdai, some 350 km (220 miles) northwest of Moscow. But an official in the Novgorod region where Valdai is located said they knew nothing about the visit.</p>
<p>Lebed and rebel leaders agreed last week to arrange a truce to allow peace negotiations to resume in a region racked by conflict which has cost tens of thousands of lives in 20 months.</p>
<p>Pulikovsky, who signed the ceasefire order on Saturday, accused the guerrillas of using the truce to dig in in the regional capital, much of which they seized two weeks ago.</p>
<p>&quot;I see force as the only way out of the situation in Grozny,&quot; he told Interfax news agency.</p>
<p>Rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov appealed to Kremlin security chief Alexander Lebed, who has held talks with the rebels and opposed the use of aircraft, to rein in Pulikovsky.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's special envoy to Chechnya should &quot;use all of his influence to stop the approaching madness&quot;, Interfax quoted Maskhadov as saying.</p>
<p>Itar-Tass news agency said Lebed would travel to Chechnya on Wednesday -- his third visit to the region in just over a week. Tass said Lebed remained committed to a peaceful solution to the Chechen conflict.</p>
<p>The rebels swept into Grozny on August 6, seizing key buildings and trapping Russian soldiers in their checkpoints and in the central government complex.</p>
<p>Pulikovsky, who on Monday gave civilians 48 hours to leave before he unleashes an all-out bombardment, said on Tuesday he was determined to drive the rebels out.</p>
<p>He said he was sure of the backing of Russia's leaders and was acting &quot;in the interests of the state&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GROZNY, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
