<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3191" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin, out of sight for days, takes short break.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin, out of sight for days, takes short break.</headline>
<byline>Brian Killen</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The presidential press service, denying new rumours that President Boris Yeltsin was ill, said on Tuesday that the Kremlin leader had started a two-day break in the picturesque lakeland of northwestern Russia.</p>
<p>A spokesman said Yeltsin would size up prospects for a longer vacation in Valdai, which is some 350 km (220 miles) northwest of Moscow. But an official in the Novgorod region where Valdai is located said they knew nothing about the visit.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no information about a visit from the president,&quot; the local official said.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, 65, has not been seen in public since he was inaugurated for a second term in office on August 9.</p>
<p>Rumours have circulated in Russia and in the West that he is ill, but the presidential press office has denied them all, saying Yeltsin has been working every day on decrees.</p>
<p>But the Russian Security Council, which groups top officials and is managed by newly appointed Alexander Lebed, issued a statement doubting the authenticity of Yeltsin's recent orders on Chechnya, where fighters want independence from Russia.</p>
<p>&quot;The contents of the documents give solid grounds to doubt that the president of Russia took a direct part in finalising the text of the order,&quot; said the statement.</p>
<p>Yeltsin on Sunday ordered Lebed, whom he had put in charge of handling the 20-month conflict in Chechnya, to restore Russian control over the capital Grozny from separatists who seized large parts of it on August 6.</p>
<p>But the statement said Yeltsin's orders were issued with a facsimile of the president's signature rather than signed by the president in person. It has also said Lebed was unaware of the preparation of the orders -- which violated normal procedure.</p>
<p>Itar-Tass news agency quoted presidential press secretary Sergei Yastrzhembsky as saying the statement on Yeltsin's trip to Valdai had been issued &quot;in connection with the usual guesses and suppositions about the president's whereabouts&quot;.</p>
<p>He dismissed as &quot;complete rubbish&quot; a report by Ekho Moskvy radio that Yeltsin had been in a specialist cardiological centre since August 15.</p>
<p>Ekho Moskvy quoted informed sources as saying that doctors at the centre, named after heart specialist Yevgeny Chazov, had diagnosed the president's condition as of average seriousness.</p>
<p>&quot;In the coming hours the question of carrying out a surgical operation may be decided,&quot; the radio said.</p>
<p>However, it also quoted the acting head doctor at the centre as saying Yeltsin was not there. &quot;You can come and see for yourself,&quot; the doctor said.</p>
<p>Yastrzhembsky said Yeltsin and Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin were continuing to work on the formation of the new Russian government, most of which was announced last week.</p>
<p>Yeltsin suffered two heart attacks last year and his disappearance from the public eye in late June triggered fresh rumours about his health.</p>
<p>Yastrzhembsky on Monday denied a report by the U.S. magazine Time which said Yeltsin had suffered from heart problems again in the second half of June.</p>
<p>Time said that, according to an official Kremlin medical advisory it had obtained, the president needed round-the-clock monitoring and the Kremlin was considering transferring him to a Swiss clinic for a bypass operation.</p>
<p>&quot;This information is part of a series of rumours and conjectures concerning the state of the president's health,&quot; Yastrzhembsky told a news briefing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
