<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3193" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin takes break in Russian lake district.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin takes break in Russian lake district.</headline>
<byline>Brian Killen</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin started a two-day break in the picturesque lakeland of Valdai in northwestern Russia on Tuesday, the presidential press service said, denying rumours that the Kremlin leader was ill.</p>
<p>A spokesman said Yeltsin would size up prospects for a longer vacation in Valdai. &quot;It is expected that Boris Yeltsin will return to Moscow this week where he will hold a series of meetings with members of the government,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Valdai, in the Novgorod region about 350 km (220 miles) northwest of Moscow, has been mentioned by Kremlin aides as a possible holiday destination for the 65-year-old leader.</p>
<p>Itar-Tass news agency quoted presidential press secretary Sergei Yastrzhembsky as saying the statement on Yeltsin's departure had been issued &quot;in connection with the usual guesses and suppositions about the president's whereabouts&quot;.</p>
<p>He dismissed as &quot;complete rubbish&quot; a report by Ekho Moskvy radio that Yeltsin had been in a specialist cardiological centre since August 15.</p>
<p>Ekho Moskvy quoted informed sources as saying that doctors at the centre, named after heart specialist Yevgeny Chazov, had diagnosed the president's condition as of average seriousness.</p>
<p>&quot;In the coming hours the question of carrying out a surgical operation may be decided,&quot; the radio said.</p>
<p>However, it also quoted the acting head doctor at the centre as saying Yeltsin was not there. &quot;You can come and see for yourself,&quot; the doctor said.</p>
<p>Yastrzhembsky said Yeltsin and Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin were continuing to work on the formation of the new Russian government, most of which was announced last week.</p>
<p>Yeltsin suffered two heart attacks last year and his disappearance from the public eye in late June triggered rumours about his health.</p>
<p>Yeltsin has made only one public appearance since June 26, briefly turning up at his inauguration ceremony on August 9.</p>
<p>Aides say he suffered &quot;colossal weariness&quot; after his reelection campaign, but they deny he has suffered new heart trouble.</p>
<p>Yastrzhembsky on Monday denied a report by the U.S. magazine Time which said Yeltsin had suffered from heart problems again in the second half of June.</p>
<p>Time said that, according to an official Kremlin medical advisory it had obtained, the president needed round-the-clock monitoring and the Kremlin was considering transferring him to a Swiss clinic for a bypass operation.</p>
<p>&quot;This information is part of a series of rumours and conjectures concerning the state of the president's health,&quot; Yastrzhembsky told a news briefing.</p>
<p>He said the president, whom he had met recently, had been doing paperwork every day at a residence near Moscow.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, who frequently spends vacations at the Black Sea resort of Sochi, had been expected to start a holiday outside Moscow after his inauguration.</p>
<p>The Valdai area, a mixture of thick woods and hundreds of lakes where Russia's River Volga originates, is a long-time resort area popular for its mild climate and beautiful nature.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
