<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3196" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Poland - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Poland - Aug 20.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- According to a poll by the PBS institute, only 48 percent of Poles said they had any savings. Of the rest, only just more than one half said they would invest in financial instruments including bank accounts or in real estate if they came into money.</p>
<p>- Poland's unemployment rate fell in July by 1.7 percent (42,400) to 14.1 percent in July, Labour Minister Andrzej Baczkowski said.</p>
<p>- The government has prepared a proposal for a 300,000 tonne tax-free fuel import quota which will be discussed soon, cabinet spokeswoman Aleksandra Jakubowska said.</p>
<p>- The Dutch Makro Cash and Carry network heads the list of Poland's 50 biggest wholesalers, with 1995 turnover of 450 million zlotys. By the end of next year Makro will operate 17 stores around the country.</p>
<p>- A Poland-China Economic Chamber has been registered in Warsaw to promote trade, financial and technological cooperation between the two countries and to support small and medium sized businesses. In the first half of 1996, trade turnover between China and Poland totalled $283.5 million.</p>
<p>- Tarnobrzeg province's governor will produce a draft this month for a Special Economic Zone to be set up there. The zone is to embrace the Tarnobrzeg, Stalowa Wola and Nowa Deba municipalities, the governor's aide Kazimierz Blasiak said.</p>
<p>- Industrial output in July this year grew by 13.1 percent compared with the same period last year, mostly due to a 16.5 percent growth in processing industries, according to Central Statistical Office (GUS) data.</p>
<p>NOWA EUROPA</p>
<p>- Three out of the four banks which will form the new Pekao SA banking group have agreed on the founding concepts, staffing policies and the group's consolidation goals. &quot;We've agreed on the legal framework of our contract&quot;, Pekao SA deputy president Andrzej Dorosz said.</p>
<p>- Reve, Germany's major food sector corporation, has bought a controlling stake in Austria's Billa company and gained major influence on operations of the Billa-Polen supermarket chain.</p>
<p>- Food prices in the first 10 days of August were 0.2 percent up compared with the last 10 days in July, according to the GUS office data.</p>
<p>- Around 80 producers of healthy foods and ecological articles will participate in an international fair in Tarnow, southern Poland, on September 5-7 this year.</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>- The Czech Tatra tram maker will supply five fast trams to the city of Poznan. Another five will be provided by the local Zaklady Cegielskiego plant.</p>
<p>- A new government programme envisages creating huge bonded warehouses to serve agricultural commodity exchanges. Germany firms Bosch and Siemens are likely investors in the &quot;Zachod&quot; warehouse planned in western Poland, Zielona Gora agricultural commodity exchange head Wladyslaw Pawelczyk said.</p>
<p>ZYCIE WARSZAWY</p>
<p>- The opposition centrist Union for Freedom (UW) will support proposals extending consumers' rights in the government's consumer protection bill, UW deputy Anna Skowronska-Luczynska said.</p>
<p>- Poland's oldest airport, Lawica in Poznan, will be privatised by the end of this year and the new airport company will operate from the start of 1997. Foreign investors have been invited to participate in the privatisation but the treasury will keep a controlling 51 percent stake.</p>
<p>PARKIET</p>
<p>- The Warsaw Stock Exchange (WSE) board has suspended trading in shares of Lodz-based printing firm LDA as its report was submitted late and equal information access to all traders could not be guaranteed, WSE president Wieslaw Rozlucki said.</p>
<p>- Poland's Warta insurance company wants the tax office to pay it 27.6 million zlotys in interest accrued on excess income tax payments in 1990, 1991 and 1992, Warta officials said.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
