<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3198" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine denies Taiwan vice-president visiting.</title>
<headline>Ukraine denies Taiwan vice-president visiting.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Ukrainian Foreign Ministry denied on Tuesday a report by Taiwanese television that Vice-President Lien Chan's secretive journey was taking him to the former Soviet republic.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no information at all on this visit. There is no visit,&quot; Valentyn Adomaitis, head of the ministry's Asia-Pacific department, told Reuters. &quot;Our policy towards Taiwan is clear -- it's part of China. We have no official ties with Taipei and we have always strongly followed this line.&quot;</p>
<p>Taiwan Television had reported that after ending a visit to the United States Lien Chan made a brief stopover in Vienna and then flew to the Ukrainian capital.</p>
<p>The broadcast, which gave no source for the information, followed a flurry of rumours that Lien had arrived in various European nations.</p>
<p>China regards Nationalist-ruled Taiwan as a rebel province ineligible for foreign ties and has sought to isolate it diplomatically since a civil war separated them in 1949.</p>
<p>Adomaitis said Ukraine maintains only economic relations with Taiwan with no political or diplomatic ties. Ukrainian and Chinese leaders signed a joint declaration two years ago stressing that Kiev recognises &quot;a single China&quot; policy.</p>
<p>&quot;I cannot exclude that Taiwan's leader might make a brief transit stopover in Ukraine but we also have no information on that,&quot; Adomaitis said by telephone. &quot;We do not follow the leaders of states with whom we have no relations.&quot;</p>
<p>Ukraine views China as one of its most important trading partners, with annual bilateral trade volume of almost $1 billion.</p>
<p>Several Ukrainian politicians have visited Taiwan since Kiev gained independence from Moscow five years ago but Ukraine has only recently started considering allowing the presence of a Taiwanese trade mission, a move tolerated by China.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
