<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3199" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Aug 20.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>PARI</p>
<p>-- An International Monetary Fund mission is expected to arrive in Bulgaria this week to review the progress of its reform programme within a funding agreement approved in July, the IMF Sofia representative Franek Rozwadowski said.</p>
<p>--  Fuel prices are expected to rise by some 15-20 percent from September 1 due to a fall of the national currency, the lev, on the local forex market, the National Price Commission said.</p>
<p>24 CHASA</p>
<p>-- The State Fund for Reconstruction and Development will cover credits to the cash-strapped National Electricity Company to secure sorely needed funding, finance minister Dimitar Kostov said after a closed-door cabinet meeting.</p>
<p>-- Some 40 percent of Bulgarian hotels are expected to be privatised by the end of this year, Tourism Commitee chairman Vassil Velev said.</p>
<p>-- The State Savings Bank (SSB), the second largest credit institution in the country, which holds most of citizens' lev deposits, posted a 4.733 billion levs profit for the first half of the year, SSB chairman Bistra Dimitrova said.</p>
<p>STANDART</p>
<p>-- Germany's tourist operator Neckerman is expected to invest in Bulgaria some five million marks by the end of next year for reconstruction of hotels along the Black Sea coast, a visiting company official said.</p>
<p>-- The government postponed the planned closure of the Pleven-based Plama oil refinery for four months in the hope of finding a buyer for the indebted facility. The liquidation procedure is to be reopened if no buyer appears, the cabinet decided at an extraordinary meeting.</p>
<p>KONTINENT</p>
<p>-- Sofia airport ground engineers threatened a strike if the airport management raises only the salaries of air traffic controllers, trade unions said.</p>
<p>The air controllers' demand for a $1,000 monthly wage is to be discussed today, Transport Ministry said. -- Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 981 8569</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
