<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3200" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovakia - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovakia - Aug 20.</headline>
<text>
<p>NARODNA OBRODA - The government holds its regular session today. The preliminary agenda includes the long-term programme of Slovakia's foreign trade policy and transformation of four state-owned energy utilities to 100-percent state joint-stock companies.</p>
<p>- The British-Slovak telecom equipment producer, Telspec Slovakia, plans to expand its commercial activities to markets in Ukraine, Russia and countries of the former Yugoslavia. The joint-venture posted turnover 205 million crowns in the first seven months of this year.</p>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - Slovakia's production of beef significantly exceeds country's consumption and the agriculture ministry said it would seek the ways for exports of the commodity.</p>
<p>- Chinesse ambassador to Slovakia Tao Miaofa and Jan Gabriel, President of Slovakia's largest commercial bank VUB, on Monday discussed ways of possible cooperation in the field of banking.</p>
<p>- Polnobanka, the fourth largest Slovak commerial bank, said it would manage funds of the state fund for support of agriculture and food industry, effective this September.</p>
<p>SME - The opposition Democratic Union (DU) has accused the NPF of violating the law according to which the fund is obliged to inform parliament about the privatisation process.</p>
<p>- Slovakia and its Visegrad Four partners intend to ask NATO to &quot;review&quot; Slovakia's position in the process of integration into the alliance.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
