<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3201" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Aug 20.</headline>
<text>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - The Czech National Bank's baance sheet totalled 612.5 billion crowns as of August 10.  Compared to the most recent figures from the end of July, this is an increase of 9 billion crowns.</p>
<p>- The Ministry of Agriculture wants to considerably change the current regulation of the grain market.  The new system should bring price stabilisation not only for farmers, but also for customers.  Ministers are to discuss the new system in parliament today.</p>
<p>- A group led by Motoinvest has been gathering shares of Ceska Sporitelna for several months with the intention of taking a substantial stake in the institution which manages the majority of personal deposits in the Czech Republic.  According to well-informed sources, the group may already control 15 percent of the shares representing 18 percent of the voting rights.</p>
<p>- Sales of the Skoda Felicia automobile have increased by 116 percent in Austria in the first half of 1996, making it the second-most successful make of automobile after the Opel Vectra. Some 6,258 Felicias were sold by the end of July in Austria.</p>
<p>- Rail fares will increase by a maximum of 40 percent from March or April next year, the Minister of Transportation, Martin Riman, confirmed yesterday, adding that this marks the first fare increase in two years.</p>
<p>- Dental a.s., which controls 70 percent of the Czech and Slovak market for dental materials, decided at its shareholders meeting not to pay any dividends on last year's net profit of 2.5 million crowns.</p>
<p>MLADA FRONTA DNES - Czech senatorial candidates can recieve pre-election donations from anyone and do not have to publicize these sources to the public.  Even the parties they are representing do not have access to their sources of income.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
