<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3204" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Karadzic posters removed in Zvornik - Bildt.</title>
<headline>Karadzic posters removed in Zvornik - Bildt.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bosnian Serb nationalist SDS party in Zvornik has heeded a warning to remove campaign posters featuring Radovan Karadzic or risk disqualification from upcoming elections, international mediator Carl Bildt said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;European Community monitors surveyed the town and reported back to me that they found only one Karadzic poster in a public place on a garage wall near the local hospital,&quot; Bildt told Reuters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Bildt met the mayor and local SDS party chief in Zvornik on Saturday and threatened election penalties if posters he saw along the main street were not removed by Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks as if the warning has had an effect, which is good. Let's hope that it lasts,&quot; Bildt said.</p>
<p>&quot;I have also written to the SDS leadership indicating that I have yet to see an SDS poster anywhere without Karadzic's face on it.&quot;</p>
<p>Radovan Karadzic, twice indicted for war crimes, served as president of both Bosnia's Serb Republic and the SDS until international political pressure forced him from both offices last month.</p>
<p>The Dayton peace accord which ended Bosnia's 43-month conflict prohibits people indicted for war crimes from holding public office or playing any role in the elections scheduled for September 14.</p>
<p>But in the run-up to the poll, posters with Karadzic's name and face have been appearing in public, much to the consternation of the international community, for whom Bildt is High Representative in Bosnia.</p>
<p>Zvornik, 80 km (50 miles) northeast of Sarajevo, once had a majority Moslem population but is inhabited by Serbs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
