<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3208" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: Latvia wants energy sale applications by October.</title>
<headline>Latvia wants energy sale applications by October.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Latvian Privatisation Agency (LPA) on Tuesday said that it wanted expressions of interest in the sale of its Latvenergo energy company by October 15.</p>
<p>&quot;The agency wants to attract funds from energy related companies, who will be interested in playing a strategic role in the future of the enterprise,&quot; the LPA said in a statement.</p>
<p>The sale of Latvenergo is expected to be one of the biggest privatisations in Latvia since it regained independence from the former Soviet Union in 1991.</p>
<p>The LPA said privatisation of the company would be carried out via a capital increase and sale of new shares to investors.</p>
<p>It said that it would offer at least 25 percent but not more than 35 percent of the company at first.</p>
<p>&quot;The agency has already received expressions of interest from major energy companies,&quot; the LPA added.</p>
<p>Sweden's  Vatenfall and German  Preussen have already presented their ideas to the LPA on how the privatisation should be carried out.</p>
<p>&quot;The main goal of privatisation is to find a strategic partner and raise new capital for the company,&quot; the LPA added.</p>
<p>The agency recently sold a stake in the state-owned Latvian Gas company to a consortium of Preussen and  Ruhrgas and Russia's  Gazprom.</p>
<p>-- Patrick Lannin, Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
