<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3212" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Grain trade at a standstill in Ukraine -dealers.</title>
<headline>Grain trade at a standstill in Ukraine -dealers.</headline>
<byline>Irene Marushko</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain trading in Ukraine has ground to a halt as the government has locked dealers out of state-controlled elevators in order to fill its own contracts, traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Industry sources say the government has quietly ordered the provinces to hold on to this season's limited supply of grain, much of which has already been purchased through forward contracts signed in May and June but which now might not be released until November.</p>
<p>&quot;They just closed the doors to the (grain) elevators, so brokers can't take the grain,&quot; said a spokesman from the Ukrainian Mercantile Agrarian Exchange (UMAE), which handles more than half Ukraine's grain trade.</p>
<p>The spokesman said trading on Ukraine's 22 exchanges stopped earlier this month.</p>
<p>&quot;Since August 7, there have been no deals,&quot; he said. &quot;Why should traders buy if they can't move what they buy?&quot;</p>
<p>The UAME spokesman said dozens of forward contracts of up to 10,000 tonnes had been sold but the ban might not be lifted until mid-November, when the most forward state contracts mature.</p>
<p>The government needs to buy about five or six million tonnes of grain, traders say.</p>
<p>But agriculture ministry food resources department head Mykola Solodky, also president of the Ukrainian National Exchange Association, said there was no official government ban.</p>
<p>&quot;If anyone has complaints they can come to the ministry and we will address it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But brokers say the government has not made any overt moves.</p>
<p>&quot;There's nothing to stop them from calling the oblasts, who call the elevators and say, 'Don't move any grain,'&quot; said Bohdan Chomiak, a representative of the Washington-based Chemonics commodities research group in Kiev.</p>
<p>&quot;They call it restrictions, but the farms are now dealing grain to the state,&quot; said a Western trader whose company does not hold forward contracts but believed a ban is in place.</p>
<p>Ukraine has forecast the 1996 grain harvest at 28 million tonnes -- the lowest since the late 1940s. It also hopes to export one million tonnes of grain this year.</p>
<p>Only about eight percent of Ukraine's grain is bought and sold on the relatively new exchange system -- the majority is bartered for fuel and machinery or used directly as animal feed or sold straight to the government.</p>
<p>Without a written government order as evidence of force majeure, brokers are liable for breach of contract.</p>
<p>&quot;What's critical, and what's destructive, is people have forward contracts maturing in August, and they have put down money in advance,&quot; Chomiak said.</p>
<p>--Irene Marushko, Kiev Newsroom +380 44 229 2264 REUTER IMM</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
