<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3213" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>LITHUANIA: Lithuanian energy minister defends oil merger plan.</title>
<headline>Lithuanian energy minister defends oil merger plan.</headline>
<dateline>VILNIUS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lithuanian Energy Minister Saulius Kutas on Tuesday defended plans to merge key state-owned oil sector companies into one large holding company ahead of a key parliamentary vote on the project later this week.</p>
<p>The Lietuvos Nafta firm is to be formed from the Mazheikiu refinery, the Naftotiekis pipeline company, Butinge oil terminal and the Lietuvos Kuras chain of petrol stations.</p>
<p>Parliament is due to vote on the plan on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The main reason behind the forming of the national oil concern is not to privatise Lietuvos Nafta but to provide capital for the energy sector,&quot; Kutas told parliament.</p>
<p>The state has to hold 51 percent of Lietuvos Nafta for three years but can then bring its share down to 34 percent.</p>
<p>The capital of the company is valued at around 790 million litas. If the company is successful, an emission of around 300 million litas of stock would be made.</p>
<p>Opposition politicians are worried Russian giant Lukoil will become a dominant player in the Lithuanian market and want the pipeline company to be kept in state hands.</p>
<p>But the government has decided that no single investor can hold more than 34 percent of the new company.</p>
<p>&quot;It makes no sense to create a national company which does not have its own pipeline,&quot; Kutas told parliament.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VILNIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LITHUANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
