<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3219" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Kremlin jousts on Chechnya, manoeuvres familiar.</title>
<headline>Kremlin jousts on Chechnya, manoeuvres familiar.</headline>
<byline>Alastair Macdonald</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kremlin infighting over a plan to bomb Grozny spilled into the open on Tuesday, close on the heels of new media speculation that President Boris Yeltsin was ill.</p>
<p>It raised doubts about the 65-year-old president's grip on power as his army threatened to launch a massive air and artillery bombardment of the Chechen capital on Thursday.</p>
<p>Russian analysts said, however, that Yeltsin was still in command and they saw the show of discord as a new twist to familiar Moscow manoeuvring over managing the fallout from the Chechen debacle.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's absence -- aides said he left for a short holiday and denied reports he had had a recurrence of heart trouble -- was by no means the first time he has dropped out of sight when trouble has boiled over in Chechnya.</p>
<p>Analysts said it could be a simple tactic to avoid blame for unpopular policies.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone is dodging responsibility, including Yeltsin,&quot; said Pavel Felgenhauer, a commentator at Sevodnya newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;I think his absence is political.&quot;</p>
<p>Alexander Lebed, Yeltsin's outspoken new Security Council secretary and his personal envoy to Chechnya, appeared to allege the president had been sidelined by officials intent on sabotaging Lebed's peace talks with the separatists.</p>
<p>The Security Council issued a statement questioning the authenticity of an order published by Yeltsin's spokesman on Monday that instructed Lebed to restore order in Grozny, seized by the rebels in a bloody battle that began on August 6.</p>
<p>The order bore only a facsimile signature and sanctioned the army's bombing plan, which would mean heavy casualites, it said.</p>
<p>Lebed himself, a tough-talking general who in two months has earned a reputation as something of a loose cannon in the Kremlin, did not sign the statement. Felgenhauer said he might even disown it later if it backfired.</p>
<p>That leaves the question of why it was issued.</p>
<p>Viktor Kremenyuk, a political analyst at Moscow's USA and Canada Institute, said he had no doubt Yeltsin did approve Monday's order and, despite health problems, was in control of major policy decisions, including those on Chechnya.</p>
<p>He saw the Security Council statement as an attempt by Lebed to regain the initiative from his Kremlin opponents in settling the Chechen crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;Lebed is trying to recover ground,&quot; Kremenyuk said.</p>
<p>Lebed, who won praise from the separatists after two visits to the region last week, has staked his brief political career on making peace -- although the two sides seem as far apart as ever on the Chechens' basic demand to secede.</p>
<p>Some commentators say Lebed is opposed by a &quot;party of war&quot; in the Kremlin which has blocked talks in order to prolong the war and the profits which powerful Russians have made from it.</p>
<p>Felgenhauer, however, warned against making too much of faction-fighting in the Kremlin.</p>
<p>He said Yeltsin was seeking a way to limit the political damage from the war without granting Chechen independence, and to save face after the army was humiliated in Grozny this month.</p>
<p>Felgenhauer said Yeltsin had given his subordinates a free hand to achieve that and the threat of force was as much a part of that process as negotiations.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a high-stakes poker game and Lebed knows that,&quot; he said, comparing the army's plan to bomb Grozny and Lebed's talks to the tactic of interrogators adopting &quot;Mr Nice and Mr Nasty&quot; tactics to break a prisoner's resistance.</p>
<p>Lebed, with a gravel voice and a permanent scowl, may seem miscast as Mr Nice. But he has thrown himself into the role.</p>
<p>Tuesday's statement may simply be his way to avoid being upstaged by a fellow general, Konstantin Pulikovsky, currently commanding the army in Chechnya and playing Russia's Mr Nasty.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
