<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3221" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: Nordic ministers back Baltics for NATO.</title>
<headline>Nordic ministers back Baltics for NATO.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign ministers from the Nordic countries said on Tuesday they supported efforts by the Baltic states to get into NATO.</p>
<p>Latvia, Lithuania and Estonia quit the former Soviet Union in 1991 and have all applied for membership of the alliance as they remain fearful of huge neighbour Russia.</p>
<p>Ruled by Moscow for most of the last 200 years, they want strong security guarantees against any resurgence of Russian expansionism.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt about our support for the Baltic states' membership of NATO,&quot; Norwegian Foreign Minister Bjoern Tore Godal, whose country is a member of the military alliance, told a news conference.</p>
<p>He was speaking after talks between foreign ministers from Norway, Sweden, Iceland, Finland and Denmark and their Baltic counterparts. Denmark and Iceland are also NATO members.</p>
<p>Russia has been angered by Baltic efforts to join NATO as it remains sensitive to any expansion of its former Cold War foe.</p>
<p>The Baltic states also had huge strategic importance in the Soviet defence system and were packed with military bases.</p>
<p>But Western diplomats say the Balts have little chance of joining NATO in a first round of enlargement.</p>
<p>&quot;No matter what happens it is the job of all of us to keep the Baltic security issue on the international agenda,&quot; Danish Foreign Minister Nils Helveg Petersen said.</p>
<p>Swedish Foreign Minister Lena Hjelm-Wallen, whose country maintains a policy of neutrality, said she respected the wish of the Baltic states to join NATO.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BALTST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
