<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3222" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Top Romania party hits rival's pro-monarchy stand.</title>
<headline>Top Romania party hits rival's pro-monarchy stand.</headline>
<byline>Sean Maguire</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's ruling leftist party on Tuesday attacked a leading presidential hopeful's support for the return of the country's exiled king, giving a taste of the bitter campaigning ahead for national elections in November.</p>
<p>Adrian Nastase, executive president of the Party of Social Democracy (PDSR), said remarks made by Emil Constantinescu in the United States showed that if elected he would be  prepared to breach the constitution by handing power to King Michael.</p>
<p>&quot;Constantinescu declares that during his mandate he wants to hand over power to the &quot;real' leader of Romania, former King Michael,&quot; Nastase told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Constantinescu recognises his incompetence for the function he wishes to occupy, realising he will never produce a programme for Romania and looking from the very beginning for a replacement,&quot; Nastase added.</p>
<p>Romanians go to the polls on November 3 to elect a 341-seat Chamber of Deputies (lower house) and 143-seat Senate (upper house) and a president for a new four-year term.</p>
<p>The monarchy was abolished in Romania in 1947 and young King Michael was exiled to Switzerland. He made one triumphant return in the post-communist era, in 1992, but worried authorities have barred him from coming back ever since.</p>
<p>Constantinescu is presidential candidate of the Democratic Convention (CDR), an alliance of centrist parties and civic groups, and leading rival to incumbent Ion Iliescu.</p>
<p>Iliescu's PDSR, its reputation tarnished by corruption allegations and charges of economic mismanagement, has been looking for an opportunity to tackle the CDR and retake the initiative before formal campaigning begins on September 4.</p>
<p>It seized on the comments to a small U.S. magazine, reprinted in a Romanian daily newspaper, and pushed the CDR and Constantinescu, an academic who lost the 1992 presidential battle, on to the defensive.</p>
<p>&quot;My position has been consistent since 1992,&quot; said Constantinescu, who complained the PDSR had misrepresented his acknowledged support for Michael's return and for a referendum on the future role of the monarch.</p>
<p>&quot;To start again with diversions like attacking the opposition with issues like the monarchy and capitalism...is to turn away from Romania's essential problems - the economy, poverty and corruption,&quot; Constantinescu said in a statement.</p>
<p>CDR officials insisted Constantinescu was battling to win a whole term in office and he himself said less than 10 percent of Romanians would currently support a return of the monarchy.</p>
<p>Opinion polls suggest Iliescu will win the presidential election with Constantinescu and former premier Petre Roman, another centrist politician, battling for second place.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
