<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3223" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Bucharest bourse offers free listing to firms.</title>
<headline>Bucharest bourse offers free listing to firms.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bucharest's stock exchange, in the doldrums all summer, on Tuesday offered free listing for the first 10 companies privatised under a mass selloff and ready to join in bourse trading by end-October.</p>
<p>Commissions on listing will be waived for the first 10 companies to seek a bourse quotation before October 30, a bourse statement said.</p>
<p>The Bursa de Valori Bucuresti has seen sluggish business for the past two months, with turnover seldom exceeding 100 million lei against peaks of around 1.5 billion earlier this year, when its per-session average was 500 million.</p>
<p>Tuesday's statement invited recently privatised companies to participate, promising them safe and efficient services.</p>
<p>The exchange, Romania's first in 50 years, opened last November with six stocks. It now trades shares in 13 companies, of which only one -- syringe maker Sanevit SA  SNVT.BX -- is owned privately.</p>
<p>Under a mass privatisation programme begun last October stakes of up to 60 percent in around 4,000 state companies were offered in exchange for coupons and vouchers doled out to some 17 million adult Romanians.</p>
<p>Subscription level at the end of the process this spring was about 90 percent.</p>
<p>Brokers say the main reason for the bourse's recent poor performance is the absence of big institutional investors, who have stayed on the sidelines till more attractive private companies get a listing.</p>
<p>Tuesday's invitation and plans to attract another 50 stocks to trading before end-1996 seems a bid to end the recent torpor on the bourse, which will soon face tough competition from an over-the-counter (OTC) market now in the making.</p>
<p>The OTC market, developed under a $20 million capital market project run by the U.S. Agency for International Development is scheduled to go on line later this year, offering a means to trade the large number of mass privatisation shares.</p>
<p>Some say its size and volume will brush the stock exchange aside, while others say the bourse will be able to attract companies which stand out from the 4,000 privatisation stocks on the OTC.</p>
<p>&quot;At present, Bursa de Valori Bucuresti is the only organised market trading securities, authorised by (regulator) the National Securities Commission,&quot; the bourse statement said. -- Luli Popescu, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
