<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3224" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania sugar industry hit by multiple woes.</title>
<headline>Romania sugar industry hit by multiple woes.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Dascalu</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>An acute shortage of funds and low beet output have pushed Romania's sugar industry almost to the brink of collapse and the country will import some 300,000 tonnes in 1996 to meet domestic demand, an official said.</p>
<p>&quot;I see the sugar sector heading to bankruptcy,&quot; Vasile Stancu, vice-president of Patronatul Zaharului, the sugar sector employers' association, told Reuters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>He said crop on 23,000 hectares from the 161,950 sown to sugar beet had been lost due to a harsh winter and late snows.</p>
<p>The remaining 138,680 hectares were expected to yield some 2,774,000 tonnes of beet, he said, adding that latest tests showed beet sugar content amounted to 11,8 percent &quot;which is not bad at all at this stage&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Taking into account losses due to handling and impurities, we count on a white sugar output of some 230,000 tonnes, this against an annual consumption of 450,000 tonnes,&quot; Stancu said.</p>
<p>Sugar beet harvesting usually starts in Romania by October.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the present circumstances I think Romania will have to import up to 300,000 tonnes of raw sugar to meet demand.&quot;</p>
<p>Romania's 1995 sugar production was 300,000 tonnes. Data show the Balkan country imported 246,489 tonnes of sugar last year and 90,230 tonnes over January-May 1996.</p>
<p>A continuing drop in beet output over the past years, caused by bad management of cropland and lack of funds, have created a crisis situation in the sector, Stancu said.</p>
<p>He cited the sugar factory in the southern town of Giurgiu which saw the 12,000 sugar beet hectares alloted to it by the state in 1995 cut to 500 hectares this year.</p>
<p>Stancu said he did not rule out further losses from the 1996 beet crop due to lack of proper machinery, inadequate storage as well as delays in transport and poor fertilisation.</p>
<p>Fund squeezes had forced farmers to use only 100 kilograms of fertilisers per hectare, compared with a recommended 160 kg, he added.</p>
<p>Many farmers had given up growing sugar beet after sugar factories had failed to pay them in time for the 1995 crop, Stancu said, ading that ageing farm labour was also responsible for the scant crop expected this year.</p>
<p>Only 24 of 33 sugar factories are operational with a total capacity of 62,000 tonnes of beet a day.</p>
<p>Sugar factories have debts worth 73 billion lei, the bulk of which is the heavy cost of credits taken in 1992 to finance a government programme to upgrade the plants and increase productivity in the sector, Stancu said.</p>
<p>&quot;The programme boosted output in some areas but on the other hand it ruined the sector financially,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100128">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
