<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3225" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Still a chance for free Bosnia elections - Cotti.</title>
<headline>Still a chance for free Bosnia elections - Cotti.</headline>
<byline>Sabina Cosic</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bosnia could still create the minimal conditions necessary for free and fair elections on September 14 if its formerly warring factions guarantee freedom of movement, OSCE Chairman Flavio Cotti said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe if this freedom of movement for citizens would be guaranteed, the main condition for minimal, correct elections would be given,&quot; Cotti said in Sarajevo after meeting Bosnia's Moslem-Croat federation president, Kresimir Zubak.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope this will be the case elsewhere, specifically in the (Bosnian) Serb republic, because -- as I repeat -- this is certainly the most important condition for elections.&quot;</p>
<p>The OSCE (Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe) is supervising the Bosnian elections with a mandate provided under the Dayton peace agreement.</p>
<p>Zubak said federation officials would guarantee freedom of movement on their 51 per cent of Bosnia. Similar commitments in the past have not been realised even among Moslems and Croats.</p>
<p>Bosnian Serbs control the other 49 per cent of Bosnia, and what is supposed to be an administrative boundary between their republic and the federation has become something closer to a formal border.</p>
<p>Thus the more than 1.5 million Bosnian refugees and displaced persons have been effectively denied the opportunity to cross de facto ethnic boundary lines to return to their homes.</p>
<p>The OSCE's head of mission in Bosnia, Robert Frowick, has acknowledged that the September 14 election is unlikely to be free or fair when measured by Western democratic standards.</p>
<p>Both he and Cotti insist, however, that the balloting must go forward despite what independent observers say are crippling limitations.</p>
<p>In addition to restrictions on freedom of movement there is virtually no freedom of the press in Serb or Croat-held territory in Bosnia.</p>
<p>The OSCE's own election-monitoring unit reported recently that the voter registration process among Serb refugees and displaced persons had been manipulated for territorial advantage to a degree that constituted fraud.</p>
<p>Ruling Bosnian Moslem and Serb nationalist parties have been harassing and intimidating opposition candidates in some of the areas they control.</p>
<p>Asked on Tuesday if conditions for elections existed at present, Cotti said only that there had been some progress since his June decision to go ahead with the elections.</p>
<p>But in a small sign that progress was still possible, the Bosnian Serb nationalist SDS party in Zvornik heeded a warning to remove campaign posters featuring former president Radovan Karadzic or risk disqualification from upcoming elections.</p>
<p>&quot;European Community monitors surveyed the town and reported back to me that they found only one Karadzic poster in a public place on a garage wall near the local hospital,&quot; international mediator Carl Bildt told Reuters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks as if the warning has had an effect, which is good. Let's hope that it lasts. I have also written to the SDS leadership indicating that I have yet to see an SDS poster anywhere without Karadzic's face on it.&quot;</p>
<p>Intense Western pressure forced Karadzic to quit the Bosnian Serb presidency last month, under Dayton clauses which prohibit people indicted for war crimes -- such as Karadzic -- from holding public office or playing any part in September's poll.</p>
<p>&quot;Our deep wish is that these elections will really be able to present, as provided in the Dayton agreement, the first step on the long road to reconstruction -- not only reconstruction of democracy but also of economic welfare,&quot; Cotti said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
