<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3236" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian stocks mixed, market seen as stronger.</title>
<headline>Croatian stocks mixed, market seen as stronger.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks traded mixed on Tuesday with blue chips again hitting higher levels and market appeared to be consolidating, in line with reawakened activity on international markets.</p>
<p>&quot;New rise for drugs firm Pliva is the best indicator that many investors are back from holiday,&quot; said Velimir Zelimorski of Fima brokerage.</p>
<p>He added he expected livelier trade in the coming week, with fully listed Pliva and Zagrebacka Banka following their London prices.</p>
<p>&quot;But main events are not expected before mid-September,&quot; Zelimorski said.</p>
<p>* Of seven issues that traded, two rose, one fell and four were flat.</p>
<p>* Drugs firm Pliva jumped 1,500 kuna from last Thursday, closing at 11,000 on volume of 932 shares. Its GDRs on London Stock Exchange rose to $47 from last Friday's $42.125.</p>
<p>* Most actively traded Zagrebacka gained 38 kuna to close the day at 650, selling 4,000 shares. Its GDRs  ZBB.L traded at SEAQ International at $14.25, unchanged from last week.</p>
<p>* Food processor Podravka lost 15 kuna to 195, with 1,062 units changing hands.</p>
<p>* All four hoteliers that traded remained unchanged:</p>
<p>- Jadranturist was flat at 160 kuna, with 214 shares sold.</p>
<p>- Laguna traded at 800 kuna on volume of 82 shares.</p>
<p>- Riviera and Arenaturist both traded at 100 kuna, with 467 and 385 shares sold, respectively.</p>
<p>* Daily volume up at 7,141 shares, turnover slightly lower at 13 million kuna.</p>
<p>* Central bank's exchange rate: 5.2803 kuna = $1. -- Laura Lui, Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
