<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3238" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian shares close mixed in unclear trend.</title>
<headline>Russian shares close mixed in unclear trend.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading Russian shares slipped on Tuesday with traders saying the trend was still unclear.</p>
<p>The Russian Trade System index of 21 leading issues fell by 0.72 percent to 182.02.</p>
<p>&quot;This week really feels like a holiday week -- a lot of clients in London are on holiday and on the continent and in New York,&quot; said Martin Diggle from Brunswick Brokerage.</p>
<p>&quot;Shares aren't really doing anything, because there aren't many clients who really want to do anything at the moment. Most of the market is trading in a vacuum.&quot;</p>
<p>The Russian Security Council, whose secretary is General Alexander Lebed, said on Tuesday that it doubted the authenticity of President Boris Yeltsin's latest orders on Chechnya.</p>
<p>But the news had very little impact on share prices, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's a story that people will be watching to see if it develops any further,&quot; Diggle said. &quot;It's a little bit worrying, that headline.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders were uncertain about the possible course the market may take in the next few days.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no flows to really shape the market,&quot; Diggle said. &quot;I would not be surprised if we drifted around these levels in very, very thin volume.&quot;</p>
<p>Bobby Meshoyrer, director of sales and trading at IK Aton, agreed, saying prices were most likely to stick to current levels.</p>
<p>&quot;I think in the near future everything will keep to current levels -- no one wants to sell cheap and to buy dear,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At 1430 GMT Mosenergo was at $0.960 after $0.952 at Monday's close, LUKoil fell to $9.670 from $10.125, UES edged down to $0.0815 from $0.0829 and Norilsk Nickel slipped to $7.70 from $7.90.</p>
<p>--Julie Tolkacheva, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
