<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3244" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Zloty rises on late gains, NBP cuts drainage rate.</title>
<headline>Zloty rises on late gains, NBP cuts drainage rate.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish zloty recouped early intraday losses and closed slightly stronger against the basket of currencies against Monday but trade remained light.</p>
<p>Dealers said zloty swings resulted from domestic client orders and from closing long currency positions after a recent zloty weakening against the basket.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar- and mark-selling trend may continue during the next few days, as there were signs that clients were keen on gradually shortening currency positions,&quot; said Pawel Gajewski from Creditanstalt in Warsaw.  </p>
<p>The zloty was at 2.7395/00 to the dollar, flat from opening at 2.7375/00 and Monday's close of 2.7385/95 and at 1.8384/89 to the mark, up from opening and Monday's 1.8390/00.</p>
<p>It was at 1.77/1.75 percent from the trading band centre, a touch firmer than Monday's close at 1.70/1.66 percent.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Poland lowered the maximum accepted rate at its 14-day reverse repo by 0.13 point to 19.12 percent, after banks placed bids for 619 million zlotys at the 300 million zloty auction.  </p>
<p>The move followed July's reserve money figures, which showed the average daily level falling to 31.86 billion zlotys from June's 32.1 billion, the first fall this year.</p>
<p>Some traders said the NBP limited the scope of today's operation to make it apparent that it did not need to drain the market heavily in order to achieve its August average reserve money level target between 31.93 and 32.63 billion zlotys.</p>
<p>&quot;If the NBP knew the demand for today's reverse repo would exceed 600 million zlotys, the dwindling offer was a signal that it would stick to its reserve money policy,&quot; said Malgorzata Sikora from ING Bank in Warsaw.  </p>
<p>On the money market one-day rates were not moved by either the reverse repo rate cut or July's reserve money result as overnight rates closed at 16.5/17.5 percent just down from opening at 16.8/17.8 percent and Monday's 16.0/17.5 percent.</p>
<p>Tomorrow/next rates were at 17.7/18.7 percent against opening's 17.5/18.5 percent and Monday's 17.0/18.0.</p>
<p>-- Krzysztof Wojcik +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
