<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3245" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian MinFins correct down, Yeltsin not worrisome.</title>
<headline>Russian MinFins correct down, Yeltsin not worrisome.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prices of Russian MinFin bonds eased on Tuesday in a correction after last week's rise and dealers said uncertainty about President Boris Yeltsin's health had little impact on the market.</p>
<p>The Russian Security Council of top officials, whose secretary is Alexander Lebed, issued a statement casting doubt on the authenticity of Yeltsin's recent orders on Chechnya, where fighters want independence from Russia.</p>
<p>The presidential press service said the Kremlin leader had started a two-day break in northwestern Russia.</p>
<p>		 tranche  Aug 20		  Aug 19</p>
<p> 1999 maturity (3)    76.15-76.45	   76.35-76.65</p>
<p> 2003 maturity (4)    49.30-49.60	   49.90-50.20</p>
<p> 2008 maturity (5)    32.35-33.65	   32.90-33.20</p>
<p> 2006 maturity (6)    37.80-38.10	   38.10-38.40</p>
<p> 2011 maturity (7)    28.40-28.70	   28.60-28.90</p>
<p>&quot;The market is not especially concerned about Yeltsin's health. The fall is not rapid. It is just a correction after the rise as the market, known to be volatile, cannot grow two points every day,&quot; Eurobank dealer Olivier Coursault said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no negative news around. Everybody is still awaiting (Russia's) Eurobonds, and there should be a confirmation the International Monetary Fund is giving its July tranche of the ($10 billion) loan,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Other dealers said some buying interest was still evident on the market, mainly from abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is going both ways. Russian banks are generally selling, with foreigners buying immediately, but then prices are going down without trading,&quot; a Russian bank dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some impact of Yeltsin news is possible as prices were too high (after last week's rise),&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Dealers said the MinFin bond market was showing little concern about the U.S. Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting, which began at 1300 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;Russian operators are not looking straight at the meeting, those in the West may do,&quot; the Russian bank dealer said.</p>
<p>Coursault said most of the market was not concerned about the FOMC meeting, and traders did not believe interest rates would be raised.</p>
<p>--Artyom Danielyan, Moscow newsroom (095) 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
