<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3249" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian lending rate rises to 9.3 from 8.9 pct.</title>
<headline>Croatian lending rate rises to 9.3 from 8.9 pct.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Croatian average lending rate rose 40 basis points to 9.3 percent on Tuesday boosted by higher rates on some of the interbank kuna loans.</p>
<p>Zagreb's Money Market total settlements rose to 84.6 million kuna against the supply of 130 million, most of which were previous placements rolled over at new rates.</p>
<p>Call money moved up to 9.3 from 9 percent, and insurance firms' five-10 day rate also rose to 8.7 from 8 percent.</p>
<p>Dealers said state investment bank HBOR rolled over 45 million kuna at a lower rate of 9.5 percent, down from 10 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>Overnight trade left a surplus of 335.4 million on the supply side after six commercial banks with shortfalls squared their positions. One bank bought funds for maintaining its reserve payments.</p>
<p>National Bank of Croatia said it stayed out of the foreign exchange market on Tuesday. Its kuna midrates for Wednesday were slightly weaker at 5.2918  against the dollar and at at 3.5518 against the German mark. -- Laura Lui, Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
