<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3252" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Salomon sees debt deal for former Comecon banks.</title>
<headline>Salomon sees debt deal for former Comecon banks.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Expectations of a rescheduling deal between the London Club of commercial bank creditors and two banks of former Soviet-bloc trade group Comecon could drive prices of the banks' debt higher, Salomon Brothers said.</p>
<p>It said in a report that a rescheduling agreement with the International Investment bank (IIB) and International Bank for Economic Co-operation (IBEC) could follow soon after a London Club deal with Russia.</p>
<p>The London Club agreement with Russia is likely to be formally completed by the end of this year.</p>
<p>Prices of the two banks' debt are likely to rise in the sovereign debt market as attention focuses on a possible deal, Salomon's report said.</p>
<p>The IIB has already achieved agreement in principle with its London Club creditors, and heads of terms could be announced before the bank's next council meeting in Vietnam in October, with completion in first-quarter 1997, it said.</p>
<p>The IBEC has negotiated less actively with its creditors but could use elements of the IIB agreement as a basis for its own London Club negotiations, Salomon said.</p>
<p>The two Moscow banks are the last surviving institutions of Comecon, which united the Soviet Union, Eastern Europe and three developing country Soviet satellites until 1989.</p>
<p>Trading in the unrestructured defaulted loans of the two banks has been rare and mainly linked to debt buyback activity through which indebted shareholding countries have sought to settle their obligations to Comecon multilaterals, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;However, as the contours of a London Club deal with IIB begin to emerge, interest in the two banks is rising,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result of this interest and our expectation of further progress in talks with external creditors, we anticipate further price appreciation, primarily of IBEC debt,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>IIB debt has already strengthened in anticipation of an early settlement following Russia's own deal. It is currently trading around 39, it said in the August-dated report, and is close to fair value on the basis of the deal being discussed.</p>
<p>Under current proposals, IIB would retain 25 percent of repayments. If a lower percentage is agreed upon, the value of the debt would be significantly higher, Salomon said.</p>
<p>IBEC's outstanding debt to external creditors is substantially below what it is owed by shareholders, and IBEC debt is trading at a deeper discount to Russian Vnesh loans than IIB debt is.</p>
<p>If agreement is reached with IBEC on the lines of the IIB deal, IBEC paper would be undervalued, as it should at least be in the same range as IIB debt, Salomon said.</p>
<p>The two banks sought a standstill agreement from creditors in 1993 while Russia, their biggest shareholder, was negotiating its own rescheduling. At that time IIB owed external creditors $1.78 billion and IBEC $662 million.</p>
<p>&quot;With the completion of Russia's London Club deal expected by December, we expect $1.6 billion of outstanding IIB debt and $554 million of outstanding IBEC to trade in sympathy with Vnesh, with IBEC strengthening relative to IIB,&quot; Salomon said.</p>
<p>The two banks, which as international organisations have diplomatic status, intend to seek repayment from their debtor countries, normalise relations with external creditors and resume operations, it said. Shareholders including the biggest, Russia, want the banks to resume normal operations, it said.</p>
<p>The main feature of the agreement IIB hopes to complete with the London Club by 1997 will be a multi-tranche Special-Purpose Vehicle through which repayments of debts from the bank's own debtor member countries will pass to the bank's creditors, Salomon said.</p>
<p>--Jonathan Lynn, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
