<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3258" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Small zloty withdrawals cut Polish reserve money.</title>
<headline>Small zloty withdrawals cut Polish reserve money.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Smaller-than-expected summer cash withdrawals from banks pushed the central bank's reserve money aggregate below its target in July, a senior National Bank of Poland (NBP) official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Earlier today, the NBP said July's average daily reserve money level, the bank's operational monetary policy target, was at 31.861 billion zlotys, against the 32.4-33.1 billion target.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand for cash in circulation fell in July due to seasonal factors and did not correspond with estimates done on 1995 basis,&quot; Jacek Osinski, deputy head of monetary policy and credit department, told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said cash in circulation, which makes up about 70 percent of reserve money, failed to grow as quickly as forecasted because cold and rainy weather in July kept many would-be holiday makers at home and curbed demand for cash.</p>
<p>Cash in circulation inched up by 0.6 percent in July to 22.49 billion zlotys after growing by 2.3 percent in June.</p>
<p>However, for a large part of the month cash in circulation was actually declining and, because reserve money is calculated using a daily average, July's average level fell, Osinski said.</p>
<p>The central bank has missed its monthly reserve money target only twice since the start of the year by exceeding it in March and falling below the set goal in July.</p>
<p>The NBP sets the monthly reserve money level as its operational goal for this year through which it wants to control money supply and, consequently, price growth.</p>
<p>Reserve money, also referred as high-powered money or monetary base, comprises cash in circulation, cash in vaults and bank's obligatory reserves.</p>
<p>-- Krzysztof Wojcik +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
