<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3263" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish coalition to start reshuffle talks.</title>
<headline>Polish coalition to start reshuffle talks.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's ruling left-wing coalition will begin talks this week on a cabinet reshuffle to accompany an approaching reorganisation of ministries, Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The leadership of the coalition will meet on Wednesday to discuss...the line-up in the newly-created ministries,&quot; Cimoszewicz told reporters before a cabinet session.</p>
<p>The cabinet reform, scrapping seven ministries and creating four new ones, has again divided the uneasy coalition of the ex-communist Democratic Left Alliance (SLD) and the smaller Polish Peasant Party (PSL), in power since 1993.</p>
<p>The Peasants, who analysts believe want to strengthen their role in government, say the reform should be linked to the dismissal of the current cabinet and appointment of a new one.</p>
<p>The SLD's Cimoszewicz aims to replace ministers gradually as of October, when the months long process of liquidating current ministries and creating new ones is due to begin.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz said on Tuesday that decisions on cabinet appointments could not be expected soon.</p>
<p>The hottest argument is widely expected to concern the two new, powerful ministries of the economy and of the treasury as well as the finance ministry, which will remain important despite a diminished role.</p>
<p>Newspapers have quoted coalition sources as saying that Finance Minister Grzegorz Kolodko, the author of the government's economic programme, is likely to be dismissed.</p>
<p>Last week Cimoszewicz, asked about Kolodko's prospects, said no minister could be sure of keeping a cabinet job.</p>
<p>Kolodko, a non-party technocrat linked to the more reform-oriented SLD, has won praise from international institutions for maintaining financial discipline that helped Poland sustain economic growth over the past three years.</p>
<p>Peasant leaders, cautious about privatisation and trade liberalisation, have also suggested they will try to oust the SLD's liberal Privatisation Minister Wieslaw Kaczmarek.</p>
<p>The Peasant party's parliamentary speaker Jozef Zych has said rifts over the cabinet reshuffle could cause a break-up of the coalition and bring about early general elections, otherwise not scheduled until late next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
