<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3272" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Security Council doubts if Yeltsin orders genuine.</title>
<headline>Security Council doubts if Yeltsin orders genuine.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Russian Security Council said on Tuesday that it doubted the authenticity of President Bolris Yeltsin's latest orders on Chechnya.</p>
<p>&quot;The contents of the documents gives solid ground to doubt that the president of Russia took a direct part in finalising the text of the order,&quot; said a statement by the policy-making Security Council, of which new security chief Alexander Lebed is the secretary.</p>
<p>Yeltsin on Sunday ordered Lebed, whom he had put in charge of handling the 20-monthold conflict in Chechnya, to regain Russian control over the capital Grozny from rebels who seized large parts of it on August 6.</p>
<p>The Security Council statement said an attempt to carry out this order would ruin peace efforts undertaken by Lebed and wreck a ceasefire deal he agreed with the separatist leaders.</p>
<p>The statement said Yeltsin's orders were issued with a facsimile of the president's signature rather than signed by the president in person. It has also said Lebed was not aware of the preparation of the orders -- which violated normal rules.</p>
<p>The Russian military commander in the Chechen capital Grozny on Monday gave the rebels 48 hours to leave the city or face an all-out bombardment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
