<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3285" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak money rates seen easing toward 10 pct.</title>
<headline>Slovak money rates seen easing toward 10 pct.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovak short-term money market rates were seen easing toward 10 percent from current 12-13.2 percent, potentially taking the shine off crown securities and deposits, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The (stronger) crown boosted the central bank foreign exchange reserves, and eventually market liquidity. High deposit rates are unjustified and we expect their decline,&quot; said Dalibor Cernicka, a Istrobanka dealer.</p>
<p>Added Robert Hakszer, a head of dealing at Slovenska Sporitelna: &quot;In the longer-term, rates could slowly ease to 10-12 percent, spoiling some of the crown's attraction.&quot;</p>
<p>Slovak interbank money market rates eased to a bid range of 12.0-13.2 percent on Tuesday amid a liquidity surplus, with the market eyeing the results of a state bond auction, as well as a possible central bank repo rate cut.</p>
<p>In July, the National Bank of Slovakia (NBS) boosted the interbank interest rates to about 14 percent, in a move to curtail banks short-term lending.</p>
<p>The NBS liquidity bill repurchase (repo) and reverse repo rates, which, since then, are the key price determining factor on the market, now stand at 8.2 and 7.4 percent respectively.</p>
<p>&quot;Both the repo and reverse repo rate could ease slightly even if the state bond auction on Tuesday is successful,&quot; Hakszer said.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
