<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3289" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MACEDONIA: PRESS DIGEST  - Macedonia - August 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST  - Macedonia - August 20.</headline>
<dateline>SKOPJE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Skopje press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DNEVNIK</p>
<p>- Leading opposition parties negotiating possible coalition for the forthcoming elections, warning there are too many unknown elements due to government's slowness in reforming the electoral system.</p>
<p>- Government interference has made a mockery of the Macedonian Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>NOVA MAKEDONIJA</p>
<p>- Inter-ethnic tensions growing in Tetovo with the approach of the local elections. Opposition Albanian Party for Democratic Prosperity (PPDA) plans to take over the local government and create a crisis to destabilise the country and force the government to legalise the Albanian language and other ethnic Albanian institutions.</p>
<p>- The Macedonian government opts for proportional election system for councillors and majority model for the election of mayors. The long overdue local elections will be held at least 45 days after parliament adopts the new election law.</p>
<p>VECER</p>
<p>- Drug abuse in Macedonia is alarmingly high, even ten-year old children are recruited as future addicts.</p>
<p>- Skopje overrun by rats due to lack of city regulations for pest extermination.</p>
<p>-- Skopje newsroom +389 91 201196</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MCDNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SKOPJE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MACEDONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
