<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3296" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria may close Plama refinery in December.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria may close Plama refinery in December.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's cabinet decided late on Monday to close the debt-ridden Plama oil refinery if an investor does not buy it by December, Industry Minister Lyubomir Dachev said.</p>
<p>&quot;The refinery will be liquidated if the attempt for its privatisation fails,&quot; Dachev told reporters at the end of the extraordinary cabinet meeting.</p>
<p>Last week the cabinet decided to sell a stake in Plama, which is among 64 state firms scheduled for closure as part of the government's economic reform programme agreed with international financial institutions.</p>
<p>The cabinet has authorised the opening of Plama's privatisation procedure and to decide the size of the stake to be offered.</p>
<p>Dachev said Bulgaria's Euroenergy was among the most serious candidates to buy a stake in Plama, Bulgaria's second biggest refinery located in the northern town of Pleven.</p>
<p>However, any future buyer should service Plama's debts, which totalled some nine billion levs last month, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;Plama will be sold by the end of this month,&quot; said a Privatisation Agency official, who declined to be named.</p>
<p>The refinery stopped production last November due to a lack of cash to buy crude. Earlier this year Bulgaria's Biohim Bank blocked credits of $40 million that it had granted the refinery against its assets.</p>
<p>Plama produces mainly lubricating oils and meets some 80 percent of the country's needs.</p>
<p>The 25-year-old refinery signed an agreement in 1993 with France's Elf Aquitaine to sell lubricating oils for ships.</p>
<p>The government had come under heavy pressure from trade unions, politicians and businessmen to remove Plama from its list of firms marked for closure.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's two biggest trade unions offered to buy Plama for a token $1 in order to keep it running.</p>
<p>Foreign oil firms are known to have expressed interest in buying Plama.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, +359 2 84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
