<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3298" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the reports carried by Estonia's newspapers on Aug 20. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- STATOIL raised its motor fuel price; other fuel companies do not rule out price rises in the near future.</p>
<p>- The first Estonian produced mortar-bomb launcher was demonstrated to Defence Minister Andrus Oovel last Friday; the production of shells is also planned.</p>
<p>SONUMILEHT</p>
<p>- The security police deny leading a campaign against Russian activist Pyotr Rozhok or controlling a Russian-language daily in Estonia.</p>
<p>- Former defence forces officer Juri Kadak accuses political lobbies of having engineered the removal of General Aleksander Einseln from his post as defence forces chief and covering up an arms smuggling scandal.</p>
<p>- Estonia and China plan to conclude an agreement on avoiding double taxation, it was announced during Premier Tiit Vaehi's meeting with Chinese minister of state Li Tieying.</p>
<p>EESTI PAEVALEHT</p>
<p>- Police are investigating the actions of a sentry who shot and killed a conscript who was under arrest.</p>
<p>- President Lennart Meri is ready to meet the Development Party, which demanded that a meeting is needed to learn about his position concerning the presidential elections.</p>
<p>- Police chief Ain Seppik promised to dismiss two police officers, who fired their pistol in a public place in Saaremaa and endangered passers-by.</p>
<p>POSTIMEES</p>
<p>- The daily published a interview with Centre party leader Edgar Savisaar, who claims that he was the victim of a plot by powerful business and political circles when he was dismissed last year.</p>
<p>- The rotation of Estonian ambassadors may begin soon after written agreements have been received.</p>
<p>- Vaehi left for a three-day visit to Finland on Tuesday; he is to meet his Finnish counterpart Paavo Lipponen.</p>
<p>ARIPAEV</p>
<p>- The quarrel concerning the transition of government communications to the privately-owned Eesti Telefon has lasted several months but no solution is expected.</p>
<p>- Deputy state prosecutor Alar Kirs claims that the article on corruption in the penal code is so inefficient as to make the pressing of charges virtually impossible.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
