<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3301" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Over August 12-19 leu's reference rate depreciated 0.28 percent against dollar and 0.42 percent against mark. Depreciation was higher on interbank market.</p>
<p>- IMF June report on Romania, made available to newspaper, says unflexible exchange rate threatens macroecomic stability achieved in 1994.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Monthly inflation jumped to 7.5 percent in July and price stability till autumn seems utopia.</p>
<p>- Foreign investment is low in Romania and existing red tape cannot encourage foreign investors to come to this country and stay.</p>
<p>- Oil refinery  RAFO SA in Onesti has not been supplied crude for two weeks and management was compelled to halt processing equipment.</p>
<p>TINERETUL LIBER</p>
<p>- Chemical pollution affects some 400,000 hectares in Romania and amount of waste is now 300 million tonnes, growing by annual 75 million tonnes.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- Milk price is expected to go up after recent energy and fuel price hikes.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- First reactor of Romania's first nuclear power plant at Cernavoda, which will start operating at end-1996, will supply 8.0 percent of Romania's energy output.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Former premier Theodor Stolojan, present World Bank executive to arrive in Bucharest on August 23 to attend official campaign launch of President Ion Iliescu for a new presidential mandate ahead of the Nvember 3 polls.</p>
<p>- Beggar in western town of Arad, at border with Hungary says he earns minimum 200 marks a day when the Germans come to Romania for holidays, otherwise some 100,000 lei a day ($32).</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- None of the 50,000 people detained in Romania's jails is HIV infected, said the jails department.</p>
<p>- Gheorghe Funar, head of National Unity Party (PUNR) invites President Iliescu to a televised debate on the Romanian-Hungarian treaty which is likely to be signed in September.</p>
<p>CRONICA ROMANA</p>
<p>- National Liberal Alliance (ANL) is only centre right group, opposition Democratic Convention (CDR) and ruling Party of Social Democracy (PDSR) are centre left, says Nicolae Manolescu, ANL candidate for the November 3 presidential polls.</p>
<p>- Number of street children is on rise in Bucharest, said sources in the organisation &quot;Save the Children&quot;. Some 800 are estimated to be now in the capital, while across Romania there number is estimated at 5,000.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- National Broadcasting Council (CNA) to set broadcast time for parties and candidates in the November 3 parliamentary and presidential elections on Thursday.</p>
<p>ZIUA</p>
<p>- State television remains major promotion agent for ruling PDSR and President Iliescu, says report by independent centre for social studies on Romania's main televisions broadcasting from the capital city of Bucharest. ($=3,156 lei) -- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
