<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3303" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in Latvian newspapers on Tuesday. Prepared for Reuters by the Co-operation  Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- A representative of the Latvian foreign ministry met the Lithuanian charge d'affaires Arunas Vinciunas to explain Latvia's position on the construction of the oil terminal in Butinge. Latvia wants a joint study of the environmental affects of the project on the Baltic sea region.</p>
<p>- 29 cars crashed on the road between Riga and the seaside region of Jurmala due to fog. The accident is believed to be the second largest in Latvia's recent history.</p>
<p>- A majority of deputies in parliament voted against replacing deputy speaker Andris Ameriks (Democratic Party 'Saeimnieks') by Aivars Jirgens (Fatherland &amp; Freedom). Deputies also rejected the dismissal of Defence Minister Andrej Krastinsh and did not take a no-confidence vote against the head of the central bank Einar Repshe.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Andris Shkele took part in a meeting of Latvian teachers, which focussed on plans to reform the system of paying salaries to teachers by transferring it to local governments. Shkele wants the reform to be enforced from September 1.</p>
<p>DIENA</p>
<p>- Nine parliamentary deputies from the Chechnya support group called on parliament to recognise the independence of the break-away republic de jure and de facto.</p>
<p>NEATKARIGA RITA AVIZE</p>
<p>- After paying off a part of its debt, Latvia has recovered the right to vote in the U.N.</p>
<p>BIZNESS &amp; BALTIYA</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Valdis Birkavs speaks about priorities of the Latvian foreign policy, which includes more work on getting the support of Western countries for Latvia's EU and NATO entry.</p>
<p>- Shkele will pay an official visit to Russia at the beggining of September. On return from Moscow, he has scheduled a visit to Iceland.</p>
<p>- Igor Tsonde, representative of the Singapore company Interlorg BTE in Latvia, was shot on August 18 while training in a sports hall in Jurmala. The company he represented is one of the founders of the huge Europe Center supermarket, recently built in Riga.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
