<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3304" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Croatian newspapers on Tuesday.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- Judging by the current state of affairs we (Croatia and Yugoslavia) will be signing an agreement on mutual recognition on Friday, claims foreign minister Mate Granic.</p>
<p>- Bosnian diplomat Mirsad Catic apprehended by Croatian authorities, based on an arrest warrant issued by the Zadar and Knin police authorities in 1991.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- The price of bread has to go down, said at a regular government press conference, agriculture minister Matej Jankovic.</p>
<p>- The Croat-Yugoslav agreement has not been initialed, said the deputy foreign minister, Ivan Simonovic during a break in Croat-Yugoslav talks held on Monday in Belgrade.</p>
<p>- First post-war Croatia airlines flight to Sarajevo cancelled on Monday due to inclement weather.</p>
<p>- The cost of living of a Zagreb family for August down by nealy 100 kuna compared to July due to lower prices of food stuffs.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- The production of oil at the Djeletovci oilfield in Eastern Slavonia to restart on Thursday, announced the INA oil company.</p>
<p>- The Bosnia elections can only be stopped by a fresh eruption of war, says the OSCE (Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe) head of mission in Bosnia, Robert Frowick. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
