<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3313" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Hurricane Dolly slams into southern Mexico.</title>
<headline>Hurricane Dolly slams into southern Mexico.</headline>
<byline>Marie Rivero</byline>
<dateline>CANCUN, Mexico 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hurricane Dolly slammed into Mexico's Yucatan Peninsula on Tuesday, dumping heavy rains and whipping up rough seas although causing no reported loss of life, authorities said.</p>
<p>Dolly touched land 12.5 miles (20 km) south of the port of Felipe Carrillo Puerto on the Caribbean coast of Quintana Roo state, the National Meterological Service said.</p>
<p>National radio network Radio Red reported that around 800 people had been evacuated from Punta Allen and Solidaridad, two sparsely populated communities close to where Dolly came ashore.</p>
<p>Dolly, the fourth weather system of this Atlantic season, packed sustained winds of 75 mph (120 kmh) and gusts of 94 mph (150 kmh) and kicked up waves of up to 13 feet (4 metres) as it rolled into flat, mainly agricultural farmland close to the border with Belize.</p>
<p>Officials from the Quintana Roo Civil Protection Agency said the hurricane dumped heavy rains across the region, but they had received no reports of deaths.</p>
<p>Quintana Roo Gov. Mario Villanueva told reporters that state emergency brigades had been sent to where Dolly touched land to ascertain damage to crops, mostly corn and beans, that are crucial to the livelihood of local residents.</p>
<p>Tourists at the resort here and in nearby Cozumel and Isla Mujeres appeared little troubled by the hurricane, although some complained of the overcast skies and rain.</p>
<p>But 29 ports in four states were closed across southern Mexico to small shipping because of the rough seas created by Dolly, the Communications and Transport Ministry said.</p>
<p>In Miami, the National Hurricane Centre said the storm had been downgraded again to a tropical storm by 5 p.m. EDT (2100 GMT), and gave its location as latitude 19.5 north, longitude 88.6 west, about 120 miles (192 km) southeast of Merida, Mexico.</p>
<p>The storm was moving to the west-northwest at 14 mph (22 kph), the centre said.</p>
<p>Maximum sustained winds had dropped to 60 mph (96 kph) as the storm moved over land and some further weakening was expected during the next 12 hours, forecasters said.</p>
<p>It was expected to move over Gulf waters early on Wednesday and to approach the Texas-Mexico border on Thursday.</p>
<p>Forecasters said Dolly was likely to strengthen again once it reached the warm waters of the Gulf of Mexico.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANCUN, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
