<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3323" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru set to let Fujimori run for president again.</title>
<headline>Peru set to let Fujimori run for president again.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The constitutional committee of Peru's congress approved Tuesday a proposal that opens the way for President Alberto Fujimori to stand for a third consecutive term in office in the country's presidential elections in 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;With this project we are making it possible for the best candidate, whether that is Fujimori or not, to have the option of entering a future electoral process,&quot; said Jorge Trelles, who sits on the constitutional committe and forms part of the government's alliance in congress.  </p>
<p>Under Peruvian law, a president, who has been elected for two consecutive terms in office, cannot run in the following election.</p>
<p>But the congressional committee, where the government has a majority, voted Tuesday 9-6 in favor of a interpretation that means Fujimori's first term in office will not be taken into account should he wish to stand for re-election.</p>
<p>Fujimori was elected president in 1990 and again in 1995. But after he dissolved parliament in 1992, a new constitution was written the following year by a reformulated congress.  </p>
<p>The congressional committee upheld Tuesday that only elections under the new constitution had validity when an incumbent president wished to put himself forward as a candidate for the next term.</p>
<p>The government proposal will now be put on Thursday to a vote of congress' full chamber, where the government's comfortable majority is expected to approve the constitutional committee's interpretation.</p>
<p>-- Saul Hudson, Lima newsroom, 511 221-2134 REUTER SH</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
