<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3346" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks close at record high on rates.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks close at record high on rates.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican stocks closed with record gains on Tuesday as dwindling interest rates fueled a long winning streak that began at mid-month when major U.S. brokerage houses upped their ratings of Mexico, dealers said.</p>
<p>The IPC index of blue-chip stocks rose 77.12 points or 2.32 percent to 3,401.79 points, an all-time record.The closing figure also surpasses any previous intraday record.</p>
<p>Dealers and analysts said Wall Street started upping its rating of Mexico just as other emerging markets were slumping a little bit and U.S. investors, confident of non-inflationary growth at home, are seeking higher yields abroad.  </p>
<p>&quot;I just think investors are starting to rerate Mexico, which is over the worst of the crisis, certainly,&quot; one analyst said. &quot;But I'm a little concerned that this is running way ahead of itself, really.&quot;</p>
<p>Others said Mexico is at a breakthrough moment in the eyes of foreign investors.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a change in the perception of the risk of the country,&quot; said Roberto Solano, an analyst with the Estrategia Burstil brokerage firm. &quot;There's a lot of optimism over the economic variables, and that was confirmed by the interest rates this afternoon.&quot;  </p>
<p>Same-day Cetes rates closed at 23.90 percent on the secondary money market, the lowest close since January 25, 1995.</p>
<p>All the markets were expecting primary Cetes rates to fall sharply in today's primary auction. Rates on the benchmark 28-day paper are seen falling by 158 basis points to 25.05 percent, according to a Reuters survey of nine Cetes dealers.</p>
<p>The expected lower rates and rising stock prices fed off each other. Peso traders at one point were predicting a rate drop of up to 300 basis points in the primary auction.  </p>
<p>But despite a flock of foreign investors rushing in to buy pesos, the Mexican currency posted only slight gains because local banks began to square positions out of concern that yields from the Cetes auction might be too low.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, volume on the bolsa was frenzied with 159.89 million shares traded. Of 121 stocks, 77 gained and 24 lost ground.</p>
<p>Benchmark stocks led the rally in the bolsa. Tribasa was up 13.95 percent or 2.02 pesos to 16.50 pesos on what one construction analyst called short covering of its ADRs, which were up 5/8 to 4-3/8.  </p>
<p>Telmex L shares, accounting for nearly 30 percent of the value of the bolsa index, were up 3.85 percent or 46 centavos to 12.42 pesos. Meanwhile, Telmex ADRs climbed 1-1/4 to 33-3/8.</p>
<p>-- Dan Trotta, Mexico City newsroom, (525) 728-9507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
