<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3348" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuela to meet all debt arrears by year end.</title>
<headline>Venezuela to meet all debt arrears by year end.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Venezuela will meet all its outstanding arrears on internal and external unrestructured debts by the end of the year, high-ranking Finance Ministry officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;Paying off these arrears will be an important first step towards increasing our credibility... which in turn will lead to lower interest rates (on future debt),&quot; Roy Ellis, Public Finance assistant director at the Finance Ministry, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Venezuela had some $500 million in arrears at the end of 1995, Ellis said, and the Finance Ministry is currently preparing a schedule of how to best meet them.</p>
<p>Once paid off, &quot;the Republic will then honor all of its future debts, as they mature,&quot; Ellis said.</p>
<p>&quot;But first we have to clear the decks of old debt&quot;.</p>
<p>A $900 million debt re-financing law, published August 16 in the National Gazette, paves the way for the government to take on fresh debt to meet delayed payments on debts that matured in 1994 and 1995.</p>
<p>Debt payments delayed in 1996 will be paid down &quot;basically via the budget,&quot; Ellis added.</p>
<p>-- Omar Lugo, Caracas newsroom, 582 834405</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
