<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3353" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil shares end up in listless, razor-thin trade.</title>
<headline>Brazil shares end up in listless, razor-thin trade.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian stocks ended higher in listless, razor-thin trade as a spate of afternoon buying wiped out early losses that had spilled over from Monday's options expiry, broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;The day was mostly trendless, moving sideways, with some buying at the end,&quot; one broker said. &quot;Volume was very thin, lower than normal.&quot;</p>
<p>The Sao Paulo bourse's Bovespa index of 52 most traded shares rose 450 points to close at 63,371 points, up 0.71 percent from Monday.  </p>
<p>Turnover reached a meager 288 million reais, with benchmark Telebras shares and options accounting for 63 percent of total trade.</p>
<p>Brokers said the bolsa was hung-over from Monday's options settlements during most of Tuesday's session, but erased early declines as large local investors swooped in late in the day, snapping up major blue chips.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was at a standstill. To me, it was hung-over from exercising options yesterday,&quot; one dealer said. &quot;There was no foreign or local news.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
