<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3354" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine stocks skid lower at close, seen erratic.</title>
<headline>Argentine stocks skid lower at close, seen erratic.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine stocks bucked the trend on Wall Street and Latin America to close lower Tuesday, weighed down by a fresh bout of technical selling.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is very hesitant and mindful of technical factors -- today it just shrugged off the good news from the Fed,&quot; said Jorge Bonanno of Interfin brokers, referring to the U.S. Federal Reserve's decision to keep interest rates steady.</p>
<p>The blue-chip MerVal index resumed its rollercoaster ride after Monday's holiday, losing 2.0 percent to 514.40. It had gained 4.0 percent between Thursday and Friday but shed 2.0 percent on the week.  </p>
<p>Traders said uncertainty generated by a recent package of tax bills was keeping investors at bay.</p>
<p>&quot;Congress seems to be warming to the measures and we expect it to pass them fairly soon, but you can never know for sure. Then you have some bad news, like media speculation on alleged government plans to tax fixed-term deposits, which is hurting the banking sector,&quot; said Bonanno.</p>
<p>Traders said the rumor especially knocked Banco Frances, whose ADRs are more heavily traded than Banco de Galicia's. Banco Frances dropped 4.4 percent on the bolsa, while Banco de Galicia fell 1.9 percent and Banco del Sud fell 1.1 percent.  </p>
<p>Technical analysts forecast the MerVal would remain volatile Wednesday but would head back up towards resistance at 533 points later in the week.</p>
<p>The broad market index slipped 1.4 percent in the session, with losing issues pounding winners 29 to seven and 13 stocks closing flat.</p>
<p>Floor volume recovered to 20.1 million pesos from 14.6 million pesos Friday, when the market was deserted by holiday-makers. Over-the-counter volume, however, remained extremely weak Tuesday at 39.1 million pesos compared to 56.4 million Friday.  </p>
<p>The only main-tier gainers were utilities Capex and Transportadora de Gas del Sur, which tacked on 2.1 percent and 0.4 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>Heaviest MerVal losses were in oil concern Sol Petroleo, holding company Comercial del Plata and construction stock Polledo, which tumbled 6.5 percent, 6.0 percent and 5.3 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>-- Carmen Pignotti, Buenos Aires Newsroom 541 318-0657</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
