<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3356" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Lima shares end down, but electric sector buoyant.</title>
<headline>Lima shares end down, but electric sector buoyant.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares on the Lima stock exchange closed down Tuesday, but investors maintained their enthusaism for electric companies, brokers said.</p>
<p>Wednesday could see further drops, however, as brokers said they expect a technical correction in electricity stocks because investors hope to take profits on their recent buys.</p>
<p>Tuesday, the General Index, fell 1.07 percent to 1399.12 points, while the blue-chip Selective Index slipped 0.71 percent to 1,913.53 points, according to preliminary stock figures.  </p>
<p>Volume remained low at 35.7 million soles ($14.5 million) due to the continued absence of foreign investors, who have been discouraged from entering the market by recent investment bank reports, brokers said.</p>
<p>In sluggish action, there were 2,374 trades, where 17 stocks rose, 31 fell and 37 were stable.</p>
<p>Electric companies, which have dominated the market this month, again attracted the greatest interest Tuesday due to the sector's growth potential and the utilities' positive results in the first half of the year, brokers said.  </p>
<p>Electricity generator Edegel rose 2.42 percent to 5.51 soles in volume of 6.6 million soles, while distributor Edelnor rose 3.89 percent to 3.47 soles in volume of 3.0 million soles.</p>
<p>Accounting for 26 percent of the day's volume, Luz del Sur was the most heavily traded stock as it dipped 0.01 sol to 3.77 soles.</p>
<p>The absence of foreign investors resulted in another session of lethargic trade for Telefonica del Peru. The benchmark closed down 0.18 percent at 5.48 soles on 907,000 shares.  </p>
<p>Despite recent apathy on the exchange, brokers said prospects for the equities market were still positive in the medium- and long-term as prices are likely to gradually rise to reflect the country's steadily improving economy.</p>
<p>Particularly in the mining sector, prices could move up as &quot;there are various stocks that are close to reaching their floor,&quot; said Luis Cueva of Argos brokerage.</p>
<p>-- Claudia Guilln, Lima newsroom, 511 221-2134</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
