<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3369" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Coca growers agree to halt protest in Colombia.</title>
<headline>Coca growers agree to halt protest in Colombia.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA, Colombia 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coca growers in Colombia's Putumayo province agreed on Tuesday to stop protesting the government's drug crop eradication programme after officials promised increased aid for crop substitution and other benefits.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands of peasants have staged mass protests in three southern provinces since mid-July, blocking roads and clashing with security forces to protest the eradication of what they say is their only viable source of income.</p>
<p>At least six people have been killed in outbreaks of violence stemming from the protests so far and the situation in Putumayo was aggravated by a wave of crippling attacks by leftist guerrillas against government oil installations there.</p>
<p>Eduardo Diaz Uribe, head of a government commission sent to Putumayo to negotiate a peace accord, said Tuesday's agreement included a pledge of stepped-up aid for crop substitution in the area. The government also promised to increase spending on public works projects in the impoverished province and to guarantee the protection of human rights there, Diaz told reporters.</p>
<p>Details of the agreement were not immediately available but the emphasis on human rights was seen as signalling that no action would be taken against leaders of the protest.</p>
<p>Government and military officials say the demonstrations in Putumayo and neighbouring Caqueta and Guaviare provinces have been orchestrated by leftist rebels who make millions of dollars a year protecting drug farms and laboratories in the jungle-covered south.</p>
<p>As proof of the alleged guerrilla role in the protests, officials said one of the lead negotiators for coca leaf growers in Putumayo was a local commander of the country's top rebel group, the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia.</p>
<p>Military officials said rebels also instigated a clash on Monday in Caqueta in which one person was killed and more than 30 injured in a pitched battle between protesters and security forces outside the provincial capital of Florencia.</p>
<p>Protesters in Caqueta demanded the presence on Tuesday of Interior Minister Horacio Serpa to help negotiate peace there but there was no immediate response from the government.</p>
<p>The government, under heavy pressure from the United States to wipe out tens of thousands of acres (hectares) of illegal coca and opium poppy crops this year, has vowed that it will continue spraying illicit drug fields from the air with the herbicide glyphosate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA, Colombia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
