<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3378" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine unions reset strike vote after gunfight.</title>
<headline>Argentine unions reset strike vote after gunfight.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's main CGT trade union federation said Tuesday it had rescheduled for August 23 a vote on whether to stage a general strike after postponing the ballot because of a gunfight among members of rival unions.</p>
<p>CGT chief Gerardo Martinez, speaking at a news conference, declined to say who he believed was responsible for the violence in which five people were injured. But he promised to resign if the instigators were not found and brought to justice.  </p>
<p>Martnez had called the meeting of the Central Confederal Committee of unions Tuesday for a vote on a proposed 36-hour general strike next month to protest the Peronist government's austerity moves, following up a 24-hour strike on Aug. 8.</p>
<p>The dissident MTA union, which accused Martnez of being too close to the Peronist government, wants a 48-hour strike.</p>
<p>The gunfire erupted when MTA members, including truck drivers, were blocked from entering a union leisure center outside Buenos Aires where the vote was due to take place. MTA officials were among those inside, making up 27 of the 270 union officials scheduled to vote.  </p>
<p>Television footage showed men in white MTA caps shooting with handguns and firing flares from a sports field near the building where unions leaders were set to debate.</p>
<p>CGT and MTA officials swapped accusations of blame for the shoot-out. CGT official Ral Amn said truckers' leader Hugo Moyano provoked the violence by taking hundreds of followers to the meeting, while MTA leader Juan Palacios told reporters the CGT &quot;orchestrated everything from inside...to get the strike called off as ordered by President Carlos Menem.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are not delinquents; we are workers,&quot; said Palacios. &quot;It was the CGT that called the Confederal Committee, so it should guarantee the safety of everyone there.&quot;</p>
<p>The CGT's Martnez started the news conference by &quot;asking publicly for the forgiveness of all the workers of our country for these incidents.&quot; He blamed the violence on &quot;tiny sectors trying to spoil the image we all want for Argentine unions.&quot;</p>
<p>But he promised he and the CGT leadership would step down if it were proved that the CGT had any role in the violence: &quot;If the courts cannot clear up the facts, I don't want to bear the responsibility for single drop of my brothers' blood.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Stephen Brown, Buenos Aires Newsroom, +541 318-0695</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
