<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3381" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuelan inflation sends results topsy-turvy.</title>
<headline>Venezuelan inflation sends results topsy-turvy.</headline>
<byline>John Paul Rathbone</byline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>As if to foil recent foreign interest in Caracas stocks, Venezuelan corporate results are suffering a bout of inflation-adjusted accounting -- and its effects have sent company results through Alice's looking-glass.</p>
<p>What does it mean, for example, when a near-bankrupt company suddenly reports a forty-six fold increase in profits?</p>
<p>&quot;You stop looking at earnings,&quot; said InvestAnalysis consultant Alex Dalmady who advises stock market analysts to leave their number-crunching and financial ratios to one side, at least for the moment.  </p>
<p>&quot;Don't forget, Rembrandt, Picasso and Van Gogh didn't create their masterpieces by painting by numbers,&quot; Dalmady cautioned in a recent market commentary.</p>
<p>Accountants bounce the numbers, writing-up and writing-down. Debt-holders report bulging profits: the past 12 months of 100 percent inflation reduces the real value of debt, allowing a &quot;monetary gain&quot; to pass from the balance sheet to the profit and loss statement.</p>
<p>The opposite is true for cash rich companies that are penalized as that same inflation eats into the real value of their cash.  </p>
<p>&quot;There's no really good way to view the stats,&quot; said Frank Amador of CNI financial consultants who notes that inflation- adjusted accounting has its uses when inflation, interest rates and foreign exchange rates are moving in the same direction.</p>
<p>But over the past year in Venezuela the three components uncoupled as real interest rates turned negative while inflation soared and currency controls left the exchange rate fixed.</p>
<p>IMF-inspired economic reforms launched mid-April have since brought a degree of rationality to the economy. But residual macroeconomic static still sends company results in a thousand different directions.  </p>
<p>&quot;Until inflation comes down, the numbers are going to remain fairly unenlightening,&quot; said a New York-based investor. Monthly inflation is decelerating, but still running at a five percent monthly clip.</p>
<p>Troubled paints company Corimon, suspended from the New York and Caracas stock exchange earlier this year, reported a year end loss of 60 billion bolivars in mid-July. Two weeks later, however, it reported first quarter profits of 12 million bolivars.  </p>
<p>&quot;The inflation and devaluation that impacted so negatively at the close of our fiscal year... have now produced favorable results,&quot; explained the company in a press release.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, market-leading stock Electricidad de Caracas -- currently locked in battle with the Ministry of Energy and Mines over delayed increases in electricity rates -- posted a non-adjusted one billion bolivar first half loss at the beginning of August.</p>
<p>Later in the same day, however, it reported an inflation- adjusted 17 billion bolivar first half profit.  </p>
<p>&quot;It does look strange,&quot; admitted an Electricidad spokesperson. &quot;But we do have a serious cash flow problem,&quot; she added, noting that the company made an inflation-adjusted ten billion bolivar operating loss.</p>
<p>And if company results are not what they seem, that's doubly true for Banks, analysts say. &quot;Their recent results have had little to do with core businesses,&quot; said Dalmady.</p>
<p>Most notably, profits have bulged among those that went long on dollars before the bolivar was devalued forty percent on April 22.</p>
<p>Two state-owned banks, Consolidado and Venezuela, both slated for re-privatization before the end of the year, owed 93 percent and 68 percent of their profits to extraordinary exchange gains, according to Dalmady.</p>
<p>The majority of remaining profits have derived from investments in Central Bank paper, called TEMs, rather than lending or project finance.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there'll be some very surprised investors when monthly inflation falls to one or two percent,&quot; said Dalmady who currently favors only one benchmark ratios, price to sales, as an indicator of a business's market capitalization compared to its size.</p>
<p>&quot;When the dust settles you're going to hear people exclaim: My God, that company's making money! And of course the flipside: that one's losing!&quot;</p>
<p>-- Caracas newsroom, 582 834405</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
