<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3382" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile plans curbs on 1997 government spending.</title>
<headline>Chile plans curbs on 1997 government spending.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chilean Finance Minister Eduardo Aninat said the government's spending increase next year will be less than the economic growth rate, and vowed to place a high priority on social programs.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an implicit commitment that this (lower government spending growth) will occur,&quot; Aninat told reporters after a meeting with President Frei to discuss the 1997 budget.</p>
<p>&quot;We aim to reaffirm and justly give priority to social programs within a framework which clearly must respect the development of economic conditions.&quot;  </p>
<p>Analysts have forecast the central bank's credit-squeeze, which has been in force for nearly a year, will slow economic growth to around five percent in 1997 from over seven percent this year.</p>
<p>The finance ministry has asked the Chilean Copper Commission, a government studies center, and state copper producer Codelco to send three estimates of average copper prices next year, said Aninat.</p>
<p>Copper sales are a key budget item. They account for for 40 percent of the country's exports.  </p>
<p>The government must by law send the budget to Congress before the end of September.</p>
<p>Aninat said Monday's increase in kerosene and diesel prices would not pose a threat to the government's target of cutting inflation to 6.5 percent this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate (the threat) to be very minimal as the effect will be reflected in two months,&quot; said Aninat.</p>
<p>&quot;Our preliminary estimates point to the impact on comsumer prices of less than 0.1 percent in cumulative terms.&quot;</p>
<p>The government jacked up kerosene prices 10 pesos a liter and diesel by five pesos as the result of a rise in international oil prices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
