<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3391" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexican church paper says govt behind Colosio death.</title>
<headline>Mexican church paper says govt behind Colosio death.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Roman Catholic church newspaper alleged on Tuesday that the &quot;highest circles of power&quot; in Mexico were behind the 1994 murder of ruling party presidential candidate Luis Donaldo Colosio.</p>
<p>The bimonthly newspaper Nuevo Criterio, an official publication of the Archdiocese of Mexico, said in an unusually outspoken editorial that the Colosio slaying was clearly a plot and not the work of a lone gunman.</p>
<p>&quot;The resources used to carry out the crime, but especially the way it was handled afterwards, make it clear that ... the mastermind was in the highest circles of power,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>It added, without directly accusing Mexico's former president: &quot;There is much evidence of the violent and vengeful way in which ex-president (Carlos) Salinas de Gortari resolved his difficulties with other people.&quot;</p>
<p>Salinas denied any involvement in the killing. Authorities last year said he was not being investigated in relation to the crime but might be called to testify.</p>
<p>Salinas left Mexico in disgrace last year following the arrest of his brother on murder charges and lives in Ireland.</p>
<p>The newspaper alleged the March 23, 1994 slaying of Colosio -- Salinas' hand-picked successor, who had been widely expected to win August 1994 presidential elections -- was the work of &quot;someone who had more than enough reasons to get rid of an uncomfortable and independent candidate.&quot;</p>
<p>The Roman Catholic church in Mexico is not generally known for such pronouncements on public affairs.</p>
<p>Many Mexicans sazid they believe Salinas was involved in the Colosio slaying, the most serious political assassination in Mexico in half a century, because Colosio was not obeying instructions from the man who gave him the candidacy.</p>
<p>But sceptics pointed out that the killing undermined Salinas' presidency, caused massive capital outflows and damaged his international image, making his involvement unlikely.</p>
<p>The newspaper praised Attorney General Antonio Lozano of the opposition National Action Party, sectors of which have ties to the church, for his efforts to solve the crime.</p>
<p>An alleged second gunman in the case was acquitted last week for lack of evidence, leaving just one man -- Mario Aburto Martinez -- in prison for the killing.</p>
<p>In a telephone conversation from prison with his father, broadcast on Tuesday by radio station Radio Red, Aburto said he feared for his life and accused authorities of torture to make him confess to shooting Colosio.</p>
<p>&quot;They want to make people think I am mad and that I killed myself,&quot; Aburto told his father, who lives in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>There was no immediate official comment on his charges.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
