<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3392" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil coffee exporters, gov't to meet August 23.</title>
<headline>Brazil coffee exporters, gov't to meet August 23.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian coffee exporters are to hold their monthly meeting with top government coffee officials on August 23 to discuss the progress of overseas sales, coffee export officials said.</p>
<p>The meeting, to be held at 1100 local/1400 GMT, is the second in what are to be regular discussions between the government and exporters to ensure Brazil keeps to an export limit agreed with other producing countries.  </p>
<p>Under the plan, Brazil should ship nine million 60-kg bags between July and December this year. In July, exports totalled 1.12 million bags, the first time shipments had exceeded the one million bag level since September 1995.</p>
<p>August figures are already expected to be higher than July, said Oswaldo Aranha, president of the Brazilian Federation of Coffee Exporters (FEBEC).</p>
<p>According to the daily bulletin released by the Rio de Janeiro Coffee Business Center, exports as registered by bills of lading totalled 482,538 bags by August 16 while certificates of origin reached 765,383 bags.  </p>
<p>Both FEBEC's Aranha and Jorge Esteve, president of the Brazilian Association of Coffee Exporters (Abecafe) welcomed a proposal to scrap the ICMS export tax which currently stands at 13 percent for coffee.</p>
<p>&quot;This is very much what FEBEC has been suggesting for some time. It means Brazilian coffee will be more competitive and there will be a better return for the producer,&quot; Aranha said.</p>
<p>Last week Brazil's Planning Minister Antonio Kandir reached an agreement with state governments to eliminate the tax.</p>
<p>Today the Lower House will vote on a motion that the bill be given priority treatment which could mean it be put to the vote as early as tomorrow.</p>
<p>But even if passed by the Lower House and the Senate, it still would not take effect until the begininng of next year, traders said.</p>
<p>-- Caroline Bulloch, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 5074151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
