<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3395" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ECUADOR: Ecuador Emetel phone co readies for privatization.</title>
<headline>Ecuador Emetel phone co readies for privatization.</headline>
<dateline>QUITO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ecuador's state telephone company Emetel may privatized early next year, the firm's new president Manuel Zhindon said.</p>
<p>International consultants have priced the company's assets at $800 million, &quot;but that doesn't mean it will be sold for that amount. In the auction we'll accept the best offer, which may be five or six times higher,&quot; Zhindon told reporters.</p>
<p>He said the sale could be completed within five or six months and preliminary screening of bidders begins in October.  </p>
<p>Emetel will be split up into two companies for privatization and each will offer a 35 percent stake to private operators, according to official sources.</p>
<p>Workers will have a right to purchase up to 10 percent of the shares and the government will keep a 55 percent stake.</p>
<p>Ecuador has 800,000 telephone lines or seven per 100 people, one of the lowest line densities in Latin America.</p>
<p>Zhindn said Emetel and the National Telecommunications Council (Conatel) will discuss a new rate system over the next few days to improve efficiency. They will jointly award the tender and proceeds will go to a solidarity fund.  </p>
<p>&quot;Even right now with apparently very low rates it is great business in telecommunications. There are significant gains to be made with the current rate system,&quot; Zhindn said.</p>
<p>He admitted that international rates, averaging $2.80 per minute, are steep but subsidize the domestic rate of $0.10.</p>
<p>Business sources said Telefnica de Espaa has shown interest in the privatization. Telefnica already operates in Argentina, Chile, Colombia, Puerto Rico, Per and Venezuela.</p>
<p>-- Gustavo Oviedo, Quito Newsroom 5932 258433</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="QUITO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ECUADOR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
