<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3398" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian finance chief refers to high cost of war.</title>
<headline>Colombian finance chief refers to high cost of war.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA, Colombia 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Minister Jose Antonio Ocampo was quoted on Tuesday as saying more than two-thirds of government spending in Colombia was absorbed by the country's military and judicial system.</p>
<p>&quot;To give you an idea of how things stand, let it suffice to say that 70 percent of the (government&quot;s) operating costs go to defence and justice,&quot; Ocampo said in an interview with Bogota's El Espectador newspaper.</p>
<p>He did not detail the costs, but said much of the military spending was associated with maintaining what he described as a &quot;very expensive&quot; pension system for the armed forces.</p>
<p>President Ernesto Samper proposed a &quot;war tax&quot; to Congress to help shore up the military in its fight against leftist guerrillas, drug lords and organised crime.</p>
<p>The tax, which Samper referred to as a &quot;public security contribution&quot; in a speech earlier this month, would involve a one-time levy of 0.5 percent against the liquid assets of anyone worth more than $88,000.</p>
<p>The government hoped to raise $500 million through the tax for military expenditures, including the purchase of helicopter gunships.</p>
<p>Ocampo did not refer to the tax in his interview with El Espectador. But he hinted the government was eyeing other possible formulas to increase private sector support of the armed forces.</p>
<p>&quot;This matter shouldn't be handled exclusively by the government,&quot; he said. &quot;We need to hold a public debate on the amount of money that is assigned to the armed forces.&quot;</p>
<p>Despite the high level of government spending, Ocampo said the military was poorly equipped to deal with guerrillas.</p>
<p>Armed Forces commander Adm. Holdan Delgado and Army chief Gen. Harold Bedoya said in interviews published over the weekend that Colombia's guerrilla war could be won militarily, despite what Western military experts described as mounting evidence to the contrary.</p>
<p>But Delgado said the military had 35 helicopters for operational troop lifts -- the same number the U.S. military uses to support a single brigade. And Bedoya complained the country &quot;ought to have at least 360,000 soldiers, and it has less than a third of that.&quot;</p>
<p>Western military experts said the Colombia army, which is primarily foot-driven, has about 120,000 troops in its five divisions across the country. No more than 100,000 are in a forward combat capacity.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA, Colombia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
