<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3405" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine unionists hurt in gunfire at strike vote.</title>
<headline>Argentine unionists hurt in gunfire at strike vote.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Several Argentine trade unionists were injured in a gunfight on Tuesday outside a meeting due to vote on whether to hold a general strike next month, local media reported.</p>
<p>The state-run news agency Telam said seven were injured in two outbursts of gunfire at a union leisure center outside Buenos Aires. Truck drivers' union leader Hugo Moyano said at least four of his colleagues were injured and were taken to a hospital.</p>
<p>Television reporters at the scene said security guards refused entry to the meeting to about 300 members of the truck drivers' union, then opened fire on them. They said unionists appeared to have fired back.</p>
<p>The Central Confederal Committee of unions was scheduled to vote at the meeting near Ezeiza international airport on proposals for a second general strike against the Peronist government's austerity measures. It would follow a 24-hour stoppage that took place on Aug. 8.</p>
<p>The main CGT labor federation, which is normally close to President Carlos Menem's government but led the first strike, wants a 36-hour strike in September while other, more hardline unions want a 48-hour stoppage.</p>
<p>CGT chief Gerardo Martinez, speaking to local radio, blamed the gunfight on &quot;outside groups who want to damage the image of the unions.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES, Argentina"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
