<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3406" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Senseless killings shock middle-class Brazilians.</title>
<headline>Senseless killings shock middle-class Brazilians.</headline>
<byline>John Miller</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO, Brazil 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A rash of senseless killings and other violent criminal acts has shaken Sao Paulo's middle classes, which are increasingly being struck by drug-related crimes spilling out of city slums.</p>
<p>&quot;CRIME - No one is safe,&quot; screamed this week's cover of Brazil's leading news magazine Veja. The warning was printed over a photo of 23-year-old college student Adriana Ciola, killed last week when assailants stopped outside a bar they had just robbed and fired randomly through a window.</p>
<p>Police in South America's largest city blame much of the violence on roaming bands of &quot;crack&quot; addicts who find students and the elderly an easier target than armed rivals inside Sao Paulo's sprawling shantytowns.</p>
<p>Poverty and the city's 16 percent unemployment rate also contribute to the problem. But authorities are at a loss to explain the degree of cruelty in much of the recent violence.</p>
<p>A 73-year-old attorney was critically injured this month when two men set him on fire for refusing to disclose the location of a safe. The assailants also played Russian roulette with his wife and burned her arms with a hot poker.</p>
<p>Two weeks ago, four men broke into a 61-year-old woman's house, locked her in the bathroom, searched for valuables and then set the house ablaze. The woman managed to escape serious injury.</p>
<p>Long accustomed to distancing themselves from rival city Rio de Janeiro's violent reputation, Sao Paulo residents are mobilising against a crime wave whose vicious nature is uncommon even by Rio standards.</p>
<p>&quot;Violence is hitting the middle class and we want to mobilise residents and the authorities (to stop it),&quot; said Carlos Eduardo Lima, an organiser of &quot;Sao Paulo Reacts,&quot; a community drive begun on Monday to curb crime. Taking its name from an anti-crime drive in Rio last year, the Sao Paulo effort seeks to unite businesses, workers, schools and community groups to make streets safer.</p>
<p>Brazilians are not strangers to crime. Murder is the leading cause of death among men aged 20-29 and it accounts for about 38 percent of deaths among teens aged 14-19.</p>
<p>The Justice Ministry says 31 of every 100,000 Brazilians is murdered, compared to 20 per 100,000 in Mexico and 10 per 100,000 in the United States. Most of the violence takes place in slums at a safe distance from middle-income communities, but because it is striking more vocal groups crime is becoming a leading issue in the city's upcoming municipal elections.</p>
<p>The gruesome news accounts of torture and cold-blooded killings have renewed calls for stiffer sentencing of minors, who up to the age of 21 cannot be tried for murder. Some residents have even called for implementing the death penalty, a punishment frowned upon in most Latin American nations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO, Brazil"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
