<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3416" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Tropical Storm Dolly picks up steam off Mexico.</title>
<headline>Tropical Storm Dolly picks up steam off Mexico.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tropical Storm Dolly, the fourth big weather front of the Atlantic season, is picking up steam off Mexico's Caribbean coast, National Meterological Service said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Centered 160 km (100 miles) east of El Ubero in the southern state of Quintana Roo, Dolly currently is moving west-northwest at 22 km/h (14 mph).</p>
<p>&quot;It is expected that Tropical Storm Dolly becomes steadily stronger in the next six hours and that it will hit land between Felipe Carrillo Puerto and Punta Allen in the state of Quintana Roo in the next six to 10 hours,&quot; the service said.  </p>
<p>Estimations are that Dolly will touch land with maximum sustained winds of 100 km/h (63 mph) and gusts of 120 km/h (75 mph) and waves up to four meters along the coasts of Quintana Roo and Yucatan states.</p>
<p>Heavy rains of more than seven cm (two inches) are expected to be dumped in the states of Oaxaca, Chiapas, Tabasco, Yucatan, Quintana Roo and Campeche with landslides in Tabasco and Chiapas, the service said in an update.</p>
<p>States of alert were declared to shipping and inhabitants along the coast between Chetumal in Quintana Roo to Puerto Progreso in Yucatan state. Weather forecasters also said alerts were posted along the northern coast of Belize.</p>
<p>Weathermen from the Mexican TV network Televisa said Dolly was likely to cleave through the Yucatan peninsula and emerge in the Gulf of Mexico.</p>
<p>From there, Dolly could pave its way westward toward Mexico's Veracruz and Tamaulipas coasts or veer more northerly toward southern Texas, they predicted.</p>
<p>--Chris Aspin, Mexico City newsroom (525) 7289530</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
