<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3423" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Medieval marriage laws under fire in Nicaragua.</title>
<headline>Medieval marriage laws under fire in Nicaragua.</headline>
<byline>David Koop</byline>
<dateline>MANAGUA, Nicaragua 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Under Nicaragua's archaic penal code, a woman who cheats on her spouse can be jailed for two years, the same sentence that a jealous husband could face if he killed his wife.</p>
<p>Nicaraguan lawmakers recently took the first steps to overhaul the country's outdated penal code, although legal experts said there is still a long way to go in placing women's rights alongside a man's honour.</p>
<p>&quot;The penal code is totally sexist. In its defence of the father's honour it sacrifices the rights of women and children,&quot; said Angela Rosa Acevedo of the private Centre for Constitutional Rights.</p>
<p>Legislators last week voted to modernise family violence laws and scrap adultery as a crime for women. The bill still must be signed by President Violeta Chamorro before it becomes law, but lawyers praised the move as a good first step.</p>
<p>&quot;(That) was the first step in the separation of law and morality in our society,&quot; said Sergio Cuaresma, a penal expert.</p>
<p>Currently, a woman can be sentenced to two years in prison for adultery, while a man can have as many lovers as he wants, punishable only when &quot;he keeps a mistress within the marital home or in a public fashion that causes a scandal,&quot; the law says.</p>
<p>If a man murders his wife and/or her lover in the heat of passion after catching them &quot;in the act,&quot; he can face two to five years in prison. He faces a similar term if he kills a man he catches in bed with his daughter, if she is under 21 years old.</p>
<p>Dueling among men is still legal.</p>
<p>&quot;The penal code needs to be changed because it collides head on with constitutional principles and has no relevance to the problems now facing Nicaraguan society,&quot; Cuaresma said.</p>
<p>The code even requires a man's approval if a woman is to have an abortion to protect her health, the only kind of abortion legal in Nicaragua, according to Acevedo.</p>
<p>While more outdated parts of the law are not adhered to, some cases are successfully brought to court based on the code, legal experts said.</p>
<p>Nicaragua's Supreme Court is currently demanding an &quot;urgent&quot; reform of this &quot;legal museum piece&quot; to bring the country into the modern era, Acevedo said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA, Nicaragua"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
