<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3427" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: FEATURE-Luxury tortillas herald Mexican food revolution.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Luxury tortillas herald Mexican food revolution.</headline>
<byline>Chris Aspin</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forget the Zapatistas and other gun-toting Mexican guerrillas. The real revolution is taking place in the tortilla.</p>
<p>Luxury tortilla stores might not sound like the breeding grounds of revolution, but for many they mark a first step to dismantling a food subsidy system that has helped quell hunger and unrest.</p>
<p>For decades, Mexico has paid subsidies now totalling at least $1 billion per year to keep the price of the cherished corn pancake within the means of even the dirt-poor. But now upscale stores in swanky suburbs of Mexico City are allowed to sell machine-made-to-measure tortillas fit for bourgeois bellies -- at uncontrolled prices.</p>
<p>&quot;They are tortillas par excellence,&quot; says Deputy Trade Minister Eugenio Carrion Rodriguez, explaining why price controls have been lifted for the gourmet pancakes. He said stores wanting to sell them without price controls have to pass 30 quality control tests including the use of purified water, stainless steel machinery, special packaging and staff uniforms.</p>
<p>Traditional tortillas, ground from corn often in ways unchanged from pre-Colombian times, are pegged rigidly at 1.40 peso (18 cents) per kilo. The new premium tortillas cost up to 3 pesos (40 cents), well over double the controlled price.</p>
<p>&quot;They have a cleaner, more uniform taste,&quot; said Claudia Fernandez, a housewife who calls herself middle-class and who has started to buy luxury tortilla.</p>
<p>Mexican families devour hundreds of millions of tortillas a day. The industry is said to be worth $3 billion a year.</p>
<p>Since the 1910-1917 civil war, the government has sought to make tortillas available to all Mexicans. Food shortages linked to land battles were at the heart of fighting in which more than a million people lost their lives.</p>
<p>But the inequity of a general subsidy system, under which billionaires and unemployed peasants pay pennies for the same product, is forcing a reappraisal of Mexico's tortilla system.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is analysing ways to rationalise those subsidies so they are not generalized and so they reach those people who really need them,&quot; Social Development Minister Carlos Rojas told reporters recently.</p>
<p>Aside from luxury tortillas, one idea is to give free tortillas to the poor via coupons, nicknamed tortibonos. State governments already provide free tortillas to the poorest citizens and officials are looking at lifting the threshold to include more low-income families. At the same time, they want to force more wealthy Mexicans to pay free market prices.</p>
<p>Despite fears of possible corruption and a shifting official definition of poverty, the government is slowly working up to a fundamental tortilla policy change. Officials reiterate they will not lift the current price, but Mexicans have an adage: &quot;The more the government says something will not happen, the quicker and more certain it is that it will.&quot;</p>
<p>Francisco Sanchez Armas, head of a credit bank serving the tortilla industry, said the luxury tortilla stores pave the way for price controls to disappear as early as next year.</p>
<p>Mexican media have pounced on the luxury tortilla story, which rivals news of Zapatista rebels in the southern state of Chiapas and a guerrilla group called the Popular Revolutionary Army (EPR) that appeared six weeks ago in Guerrero state.</p>
<p>&quot;Tortillas are an important factor in the socio-political history, both past and present,&quot; Mexican anthropologist Breen Murray said. Refering to one of Mexico's most advanced pre-Aztec indigenous peoples, the Toltecs, Murray added: &quot;Mexicans are Toltecs made from tortillas.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
