<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3432" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: FEATURE - Debt deals tie Peru to lofty payments.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Debt deals tie Peru to lofty payments.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Once the scourge of international financial markets for its refusal to pay foreign debt, Peru has virtually completed a return to favour with its latest restructuring deals.</p>
<p>Yet the government may have bought back approval abroad at too a high price, with an ambitious repayment schedule likely to squeeze state coffers and prejudice social spending in coming years, analysts and critics warn.</p>
<p>&quot;On the books, these restructuring agreements look great, but you have to remember that they commit Peru to paying far more than it ever has before,&quot; said a senior Latin American analyst on Wall Street, who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;The cost of paying is going to be very tough on the people of Peru.&quot;</p>
<p>Peru now owes a total $32.445 billion foreign debt -- or about $1,350 per head in this country of 24 million people -- according to latest figures from the Central Reserve Bank.</p>
<p>Ten years ago, populist president Alan Garcia effectively suspended all foreign debt payments, hastening the Latin American debt crisis and guaranteeing Peru's pariah status in the international financial community.</p>
<p>But now President Alberto Fujimori's government is promising to pay on nearly all fronts.</p>
<p>&quot;No one can say that Peru is not serious now about paying its debt,&quot; said Fujimori after his triumphant announcement in July of a rescheduling deal with the Paris Club of creditors.</p>
<p>This year, Fujimori's debt negotiating team has hardly stopped for breath, renegotiating terms on $7.4 billion debt in Paris, and is soon to close a complicated Brady Plan to restructure up to $10 billion commercial debt.</p>
<p>These deals followed the priority given to multilateral loan organisations, with whom Fujimori restarted payments in his first years of office after taking power in 1990.</p>
<p>With the exception of a few loose ends, such as its disputed debt to Russia, the completion of the Brady Plan will bring Peru full circle from its militant position of the 1980s.</p>
<p>The deals also remove obstacles to fresh credits and will enable Peru at the end of this year to issue new bonds on foreign markets for the first time in a decade.</p>
<p>While few now doubt Fujimori's good intentions to pay the debt, many do, however, recognise it will be far from easy to make good these commitments on a long-term basis.</p>
<p>Economists estimate combined debt payments will cost a total of more than $1.2 billion next year, rising steeply to between $2 billion and $3 billion by early next century.</p>
<p>This compares to an annual budget in 1996 of 22 billion soles ($9 billion), and a total gross domestic product of 149 billion soles ($61 billion), according to the Economy Ministry.</p>
<p>The Paris Club debt alone will cost Peru $496 million this year, rising to $1 billion by 2001, a peak of $1.07 billion in 2004, then gradually falling until the debt is paid off by 2015.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is betting on being able to pay its foreign debt, but it was the only sensible bet the country could make. There was no other solution,&quot; said Oscar Jasaui, head of the Lima college of economists and president of Duff &amp; Phelps del Peru.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no magic formula. It depends on the performance of the economy, and it will be a day-by-day process.&quot;</p>
<p>Jasaui said the ability to pay would depend principally on boosting internal productivity and exports, and deepening the structural reforms underway since 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;Chile managed to reduce its debt. Why not us? Peru has the potential to export as much as Chile. It is possible,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Peru ran up a trade deficit of $2.115 billion in 1995, more than double the 1994 figure. But a nine percent rise in exports in the first five months of 1996 has helped bring the January-May deficit down 13 percent on the same period of last year to $786 million.</p>
<p>Despite Fujimori's slick and upbeat public presentations of his debt restructuring accords, not all are convinced they were as successful as he makes out.</p>
<p>The government &quot;wanted better terms than they got with the Paris Club, undoubtedly,&quot; said one Peruvian analyst.</p>
<p>The analyst, who asked not to be named, added that Peru suffered in the July talks in Paris due, ironically, to the success of its economic reforms and its own self-projection as an emerging Latin American &quot;tiger&quot;.</p>
<p>Former Central Reserve Bank president Manuel Moreyra said Peru set out in Paris to achieve a flat annual payment rate over 25 years rather than the increasing scale over 20 years finally agreed.</p>
<p>Foreign analysts added that Peru has exaggerated its success in the Brady Plan by inflating the total amount owed. While the government is talking of an approximately $5 billion reduction on $10.56 billion owned, market and other independent sources put the total Brady debt at nearer $8 billion, of which they estimate a 40 to 50 percent reduction.</p>
<p>At home, the most serious concern is how the debt schedule will affect efforts to tackle poverty and unemployment.</p>
<p>Despite the macroeconomic advances of the last six years, at least 60 percent of Peru's population still live in poverty, with some estimates as high as 80 percent, and around 55 percent are either unemployed or underemployed.</p>
<p>&quot;To what extent are the annual quotas (for debt payment) compatible with still-unsatisfied social needs?&quot; asked opposition legislator Manuel Lajo.</p>
<p>He is among those leading calls for the government to provide detailed projected income statements to show how it will cover both its debt obligations and the social spending programmes promised in last year's election campaign.</p>
<p>On the streets, few Peruvians are informed about the intricacies of the rescheduling agreements, but they give Fujimori credit for sorting out the perceived &quot;mess&quot; that his predecessor Garcia left the country in.</p>
<p>They are under no illusion, however, as to the enormous burden represented by the foreign debt bill.</p>
<p>&quot;It's like a noose round the whole country's neck,&quot; said fruit-seller Marco Hermoza. &quot;But who will be hung? Who suffers most? Not (Economy Minister Jorge) Camet, or Fujimori, but the poor, who have no chance of a future thanks to this damned debt.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
