<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3435" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian General News - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian General News - Aug 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Disgraced Australian tycoon Alan Bond was sentenced to three years' jail on fraud charges by Judge Antoinette Kennedy in the Perth District Court yesterday. However, he will be eligible for parole in 12 months. After hearing the sentence, Bond, 58, instructed his solicitor to appeal. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Some colleagues of Senator Malcolm Colston, who altered the balance of power in the Senate yesterday by resigning from the Australian Labor Party, said yesterday they believed he had quit because the party did not select him as its candidate for Senate Deputy President. Page 2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The federal government's chances of securing passage of its Workplace Relations Bill through Parliament reached another hurdle yesterday when Tasmanian independent Brian Harradine told ABC Radio National he opposed the proposed legislation because it undermined trade union unity and would leave people in the work force in a defenceless position. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The chair of the Senate committee inquiring into the Howard Government's proposed A$8 billion sale of one third of the national telecommunications carrier, Telstra, Senator Meg Lees, has revealed the committee is requesting a three-week extension because it has received insufficient information to complete its final report. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>The Federal Government last night embarked on a high-risk strategy with a budget that pays for the delivery of its election commitments to &quot;mainstream Australia&quot;, which it defines as families, children and small business, by hitting the aged, the sick, students and the unemployed. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Canberra experienced its second day of violent political rioting yesterday when 150 Aboriginal protesters tried to storm Old Parliament House. Two protesters and four police officers were injured when more than 100 police in full riot gear were attacked wth bricks, bottles and stakes. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Howard Government yesterday outlined a budget strategy which promised fundamental medium-term improvements to the economy's performance. However, this will come at a significant short-term cost with economic growth seeing a sharply reduced pace during 1996/97 and the Treasury predicting a jobless rate of 8.25 percent in mid-1997. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Only hours after Queensland Labor Senator Mal Colston resigned from the Australian Labor Party after it failed to endorse him for the position of Senate deputy president, Colston was elected to the position, with most of the votes in the secret ballot appearing to come from the Liberals and Nationals who nominated him for the position over endorsed Labor candidate Senator Sue West. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Treasurer Peter Costello's first Budget slashes outlays by A$19 billion in net terms, reducing government spending to its second lowest level since the early 1970s. The Coalition has halved the underlying deficit to A$5.6 billion, relying on spending cut, tax rises and user-pays charges to help finance election pledges. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Although Australian Federal Police have vowed to track down those involved in criminal behaviour at Monday's Canberra riot, the ACT Trades and Labor Council blamed the police for a last minute change to a rally plan agreed to by the TLC which allowed protesters to enter the Parliament House forecourt. Page 2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Although New South Wales Liberal leader Peter Collins suggested yesterday that the party might withdraw its Port Macquarie by-election candidate in an attempt to make peace with the Nationals, the National Party is almost certain to quit the 13-year Coaliion today over the Liberals' decision to pit their candidate against a National nominee. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Westmead Hospital is considering a plan to privatise up to one quarter of the hospital, amalgamating closed wards and other hospital infrastructure and leasing them to a private hospital operator. Under the plan, the private operator would have to build perating theatres and the outpatients department would be relocated. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Federal Treasurer Peter Costello said last night his first budget would deliver a &quot;historic turnaround in Commonwealth finances&quot;. It appears the unemployed will bear the brunt of the Howard Government's cost-cutting budget, designed to deliver its coreelection commitments to mainstream Australia. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Canberra saw its second successive day of violent protests yesterday, with Aboriginal demonstrators at Old Parliament House protesting against the A$400 million cuts to Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Commission funding, sparking a 20-minute outbrea in which bricks, bottles and pieces of timber were thrown. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Although U.S. Forces Japan has denied the incident posed any danger to the Qantas jumbo, Japanese Defence Minister Hideo Usui has announced an investigation into a Qantas pilot's complaint over an affair which saw two F-18 Hornets fly within 1,200 feet of the plane, forcing the pilot to pull into a steep climb to avoid a collision. Page A3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Disgraced businessman Alan Bond will appeal against the severity of a three-year jail term for corporate fraud and deception, which was handed down yesterday by Western Australian District Court Judge Toni Kennedy despite strong pleas by Bond's defence counsel that the experience could be fatal for the sick businessman. Page A3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
