<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3436" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Business News - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Business News - Aug 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>In a move which will deal another blow to pay-TV arch rivals Rupert Murdoch and Telstra, Kerry Packer and Optus Vision have pulled struggling pay-TV operator Australis Media from the brink of collapse with a US$250 million refinancing scheme which was accepted by the Australis board yesterday. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After losing A$18 million in the August 1990 transaction, Coles Myer and parties involved in the controversial Yannon transaction are finalising a financial settlement, amid suggestions the company may accept as little as A$10 million to resolve the matter. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Qantas Airways Ltd managing director James Strong is expected to meet union negotiators tomorrow after the airline and unions reached a make-or-break stage in their long-running negotiations for a new enterprise agreement, with unions pushing the company to guarantee that all employees be entitled to a total of A$1,500 of shares over the next two years. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian Refineries Operatives Committee, a national committee of oil refinery union delegates, issued a statement yesterday threatening to escalate an industrial dispute that has halted production at Shell Australia's large Geelong oil refinery. The statement offered &quot;unqualified support&quot; to the striking unionists at the plant. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After profit for the six months to June lifted by 12 percent to A$11.56 million, the chief executive of sprawling regional media group Australian Provincial Newspapers Ltd, Cameron O'Reilly, says he is optimistic the group will continue its unbroken record of yealy profit growth intact. Page 15.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a bid to cut its high-gearing and cement footings for its next stage of growth, contract miner Macmahon Holdings Ltd is expected to release details of a A$30-plus million equity raising next week. Details of a convertible preference share placement and a rights issue are expected next Monday when the company releases its audited 1995/96 results. Page 15.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Business will lose A$2.8 billion in taxpayer assistance over the next four years after the Howard government reduced the top rate for research and development tax concessions from 150 percent to 125 percent for R&amp;D expenditure incurred after 7.30 p.m. yesterday, axed 38 industry and export schemes and abolished manufacturers' bounty payments in the budget. Page 45.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Business representatives endorsed the 1996/97 federal budget yesterday, saying it had laid the groundwork for an improvement in confidence. However, professional investors voiced their disappointment that the budget was not as fiscally stringent as had been expected - staging a selloff of bond and share futures and the dollar last night. Page 45.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Satellite pay-TV operator Australis Media defied the liquidators yesterday when it entered a A$367 million recapitalisation plan led by Kerry Packer's Publishing &amp; Broadcasting Ltd. The deal sees Packer emerging as the driving force behind an &quot;infrastrucure sharing&quot; alliance between Australis and Optus Vision. Page 45.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Federal Treasurer Peter Costello told Parliament yesterday the fiscal rigour of the budget would see business investment grow - forecasts say by as much as A$7 billion, or 14 percent - and improve the interest rate environment. He also predicted the long awaited rebound in housing would begin this year. Page 45.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Amid widespread pessimism in the business community about its future prospects as the main profit reporting season gets underway, Treasurer Peter Costello is counting on a A$7 billion business investment surge this financial year to help alleviate his A$8 billion deficit black hole. Page 47.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The decision to introduce retirement savings accounts without trustee banking as part of yesterday's budget superannuation measures will mean fund managers and trustee companies face stiff competition from banks, credit unions and life ofices in the battle for superannuation savings. Page 47.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>While the announced decision to cut the budget deficit by A$4 billion in the 1996/97 financial year was welcomed by many in the financial sector, concerns still exist about the deficit, stronger than expected growth in the first half of the year and the predicted jump in wages by five percent. The Australian dollar, bonds and the sharemarket futures fell last night after the budget postponed a second interest cut in 1996. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Simsmetal managing director John Crabb and others like David Buckingham, executive director of the Minerals Council of Australia, have voiced their concerns on the budget, stating that it lacked strategic direction and was still spending and taxing beyond Australia's ability. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Satellite pay TV group Australis Media yesterday struck a last minute survival deal with a consortium of investors that included Optus Vision and Kerry Packer's Publishing and Broadcasting. The proposal now has to go before Australis' U.S. junk bond holder to secure its recovery. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian Provincial Newspapers lifted its net profit from A$10.3 million to A$11.6 million in the June half year. APN still found the going tough in the bush, provincial Queensland and in specialist publishing, but was boasting sales with it radio network and Buspak advertising schemes. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A fatal accident at Northparkes mine has called into question the mine's ongoing financial viability and its uphill battle to get the mine to a sustainable level of operations. Stephen Shorrock, 43, who was killed in a rock slide was an experienced contract miner. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>ANZ Bank will be Australia's first dual user of the international automated teller machines operated by Visa and MasterCard International. An announcement will come next week confirming ANZ's adoption of the Visa Plus system. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Views were mixed today in the financial world on how the markets would react to the new budget, with ANZ Securities' chief economist Phil Graham, stating the outlook for the sharemarket was &quot;pretty neutral&quot;. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The business community is standing firm behind the budget saying it will provide stimulus to consumer spending and will provide a good environment for increased business investment with hope for relaxed interest rates in months ahead. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Concerns were voiced by small business over cuts to business assistance programmes in last night's budget. However, the overall view from small business was that the budget outcomes were generally positive, especially in relation to the two specific reforms to capital gains tax law. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In the early hours of yesterday Australis Media accepted a rescue package from a consortium of investors that included rival pay TV operator Optus Vision. With the A$134 million of fresh equity injected into the debt-laden Australis it is hoped a strong resurgence will follow. Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Woolworths intends to put added emphasis on its specialty stores, such as Dick Smith Electronics, in an attempt to further strengthen its non-food operational base. Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Visa International will have confirmation next week of securing ANZ as Australia's first bank to be a dual user of the international teller machine brands operated by Visa and MasterCard International. Page C3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
