<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3440" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-No hurry for election - Australia's Howard.</title>
<headline>RTRS-No hurry for election - Australia's Howard.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John Howard said on Wednesday he was in no hurry for a fresh election.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm in no hurry to have an election,&quot; Howard told radio 2GB.</p>
<p>Some political analysts believe Howard, elected in March for a three-year term, may be forced to call an early election because of parliamentary obstruction of key reforms.  </p>
<p>Australia's constitution allows a government to call an election if parliament blocks legislation twice within three months.</p>
<p>Howard's Liberal-National government does not have a majority in the 76-seat upper house, the Senate, and needs the support of at least two non-government senators to pass legislation.</p>
<p>But the Labor opposition and minor parties have pledged to block key reforms, including the partial sale of government telecoms giant Telstra Corp.  </p>
<p>An election called because of blocked legislation allows a joint sitting of both houses after the polls.</p>
<p>Political analysts believe Howard would win an early election with a lower-house majority big enough to guarantee passage of his reforms through a joint sitting.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
