<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3457" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Howard hopes for further Australia rate cut.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Howard hopes for further Australia rate cut.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John Howard said on Wednesday that he hoped there would be another cut in official interest rates, but that the Reserve Bank was directly responsible for monetary policy.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope we get some further cut in interest rates,&quot; Howard told Australian Broadcasting Corp radio.  </p>
<p>&quot;But I don't, nor does the Treasurer, direct these things, that's a matter for the monetary authority,&quot; Howard said.</p>
<p>&quot;The budget last night did far more to set up an interest rate cut than the budget that was urged on us by (Labor Opposition Leader) Kim Beazley and (Labor Treasury spokesman) Gareth Evans,&quot; Howard said.  </p>
<p>The government announced on Tuesday it would make A$3.9 billon of budget cuts to produce an underlying budget deficit in the year to June 30, 1997 of A$5.65 billion.</p>
<p>Howard said he was hopeful the resignation of Labor senator Mal Colston and his subsequent election as an independent Senate deputy president with the support of the government would help the budget get through the Senate.</p>
<p>&quot;He's become an independent and we certainly hope he'll support us on some things,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't expect he'll support us on everything.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
