<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3480" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian farmers support basis of budget.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian farmers support basis of budget.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's National Farmers' Federation (NFF) was encouraged by the Federal government's commitment to achieve a balance in the underlying budget over the economic cycle, NFF president Donald McGauchie said.</p>
<p>The benefits to agriculture and to the economic community generally from tough budget measures were already apparent in recent reductions in short and long-term interest rates, he said in a statement.</p>
<p>Treasurer Peter Costello earlier handed down a budget with a A$5.65 billion underlying deficit for fiscal 1996/97 to June 30.  </p>
<p>The NFF welcomed retention of the diesel fuel rebate and of matching funding for research and development corporations, increased funding for the Commonwealth Scientific and Industrial Research Organisation and the A$3.4 million commitment to the &quot;Supermarket to Asia&quot; food export strategy, he said.</p>
<p>NFF was also pleased that core funding for landcare programmes would be increased.</p>
<p>However, it was disappointed most of the funds earmarked for the National Vegetation Initiative and the Murray Darling Basin initiative would be delayed pending the partial privatisation of state-owned telecommunications group, Telstra Corp, he said.  </p>
<p>NFF also regretted the decision to reduce funding for the Rural Industries Research and Development Corp by A$5 million and the Land and Water Resources Research and Development Corp by A$1 million.</p>
<p>A A$25.6 million cut from the Australian Quarantine Inspection Service between 1996/97 and 1999/2000 for community service obligations while quarantine was under review and the ten percent a year cut in the Citrus Market Diversification Programme would not help the rural sector, he said.  </p>
<p>Graham Dalton, executive director of the Queensland Farmers' Federation (QFF), told Reuters the Australian national budget on balance was good for the farm sector because a hard-nosed budget was necessary for the wider economy,</p>
<p>&quot;A good budget for the farm sector is one that gets the Australian economy moving,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although there's no real handouts for farmers in this budget, it was a necessary budget,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>It had the appearance of a tough budget which spread the burden of fiscal reform across much of the community, he said.  </p>
<p>The farm sector welcomed confirmation that the diesel fuel rebate was largely unchanged, he said.</p>
<p>Some of the important farm measures would be dependent on the sale of one-third of Telstra Corp. QFF would want to work through the fine print, he said.</p>
<p>The disposal of Telstra, cuts to universities and Aboriginal expenditure were hard messages for Australia, but the government did not have many options, he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
