<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3481" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Budget little impact on Australian metals.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Budget little impact on Australian metals.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austalia's mining and metals commodities markets are unlikely to react much to Australia's 1996/1997 budget, unveiled on Tuesday, analyst and traders said.</p>
<p>The key component of the budget relevant to miners, the retention of a diesel fuel tax rebate, was already made known to the industry a week ago.</p>
<p>&quot;From a commodities standpoint, the budget is deadpan, super-slugged,&quot; said an analyst for an international bank.</p>
<p>Leading Australian mining company stocks showed only minor fluctuations in the run-up to the release of the budget.  </p>
<p>The Broken Hill Pty Co ltd, Australia's largest company and the world's number two copper producer, closed four cents down at at A$17.50.</p>
<p>The budget put some pressure on the Australian dollar, which some think could push up Australian dollar-denominated gold.</p>
<p>Australia's new conservative government on Tuesday unveiled a 1996/97 budget making sweeping spending cuts.</p>
<p>Treasurer Peter Costello, announcing a A$5.6 billion underlying deficit for the fiscal year to June 30, 1997, said tough decisions were taken to turn Australia away from &quot;a path to deficit and debt.&quot;  </p>
<p>The executive director of the Minerals Council of Australia said the council supported the government's medium-term fiscal strategy of a return to an underlying budget surplus.</p>
<p>&quot;The Coalition government's action will cause some adjustments and pain but as a country australia cannot continue to spend and tax beyond the capacity of the economy to deliver,&quot; the council's executive director, David Buckingham, said.</p>
<p>&quot;This budget helps create a sound basis for sustainable long-term economic growth,&quot; Buckingham said in a statement.</p>
<p>He said the minerals industry &quot;particularly appreciated&quot; the government's decision to retain the diesel rebate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
