<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3488" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Australia set for solid growth, low inflation.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Australia set for solid growth, low inflation.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's economic outlook is for another year of strong growth and subdued inflation, the Australian Treasury said in the 1996/97 Budget papers.</p>
<p>Business investment, particularly construction, was again set to lead the growth charge, reinforced by robust private and public consumption and a turnaround in the housing market.</p>
<p>That was expected to deliver growth of 3.5 percent in the average measure of gross domestic product (GDP-A) in 1996/97, off slightly from the 4.1 pace reached in 1995/96.</p>
<p>The expansion, now in its fifth year, would be long-lived with growth of 3.25-3.5 percent pencilled in to the year 2000.  </p>
<p>This measure is targetted by the Reserve Bank which aims to set monetary policy to keep it within a 2-3 percent range over the course of a business cycle.</p>
<p>Headline inflation would fall further, averaging 2.0 percent for the year from 4.2 percent in 1995/96, thanks to recent cuts in mortgage rates, Treasury said.</p>
<p>Business investment would be the engine of growth, with the Treasury forecasting a 14 percent rise in 1996/97 following a 9.7 percent gain the year before. Capacity utilisation remained high, business confidence was positive and corporate profits were see expanding as productivity outstripped wages growth.  </p>
<p>A near-boom was seen in non-dwelling construction courtesy of major engineering projects for the Sydney Olympics in 2000, mining infrastrucutre and general road building.</p>
<p>Over the year, Treasury expected construction to rise by 15 percent, while spending on plant and equipment would only be a shade behind at 14 percent.</p>
<p>Since capital equipment was an import-intensive sector, robust business investment would also result in higher imports, with Treasury forecasting 1996/97 growth of 11 percent, almost twice the rate of 1995/96.  </p>
<p>Export growth was seen slowing somewhat to an annual 8.0 percent from 10.3 percent in 1996/97 as transitory effects, such as the breaking of the drought, fade away.</p>
<p>Overall, net exports were expected to detract about 0.75 point from GDP-A in the year ahead.</p>
<p>The current account deficit, however, was seen remaining relatively steady at A$20 billion, or 4.0 percent of GDP, thanks to an improvement in Australia's terms of trade.</p>
<p>Treasury expected employment growth to accelerate through 1996/97, although a sluggish first half looked like restraining the average rise to 1.5 percent after 2.6 percent in 1995/96.  </p>
<p>That would not be fast enough to make inroads into the unemployment rate which was seen steady at 8.5 percent.</p>
<p>A slow recovery in the housing market was expected to begin during the course of 1996/97, spurred by falling mortgage rates and rising household income. However, the stock of excess housing was so great the Treasury expected dwelling investment would still fall 3.0 percent over the year.</p>
<p>Public final demand was set to strengthen despite the contractionary impact of the budget, largely reflecting the large investment programme of state telecommunications carrier Telstra. -- Canberra newsroom 61-6 273 2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
