<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3489" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Australia hits wealthy with retirement tax.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Australia hits wealthy with retirement tax.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian government announced on Tuesday a 15 percent tax surcharge on the retirement savings of wealthy people to raise about A$500 million annually as part of an overhaul of the superannuation (pension) system.</p>
<p>The measure, outlined in the 1996/97 (July/June) budget announced on Tuesday, accounts for the bulk of net savings to be achieved under the overhaul, which also changes the tax treatment of employer contributions to retirement funds.  </p>
<p>The budget papers list the effect from all the changes would be an increase in revenue of A$523 million in 1997/98 -- the first full year of the new arrangements -- rising to A$582 million in 1999/2000.</p>
<p>The surcharge, to be phased in for annual incomes between A$70,000 and A$85,000 and to apply in full for people earning above that, will raise A$480 million in 1997/98, rising to A$530 in 1999/2000.</p>
<p>The government estimates it will affect 355,000 tax-payers and will apply to the superannuation contributions made by, or on behalf of, high-income earners.  </p>
<p>&quot;The measures I am announcing tonight are designed to make superannuation (retirement savings) fairer,&quot; Treasurer Peter Costello said in his budget speech.</p>
<p>He also confirmed in his budget speech the government would honour the previous administration's pledge to make public contributions to workers' retirement savings.</p>
<p>These contributions, originally meant to have been delivered by way of tax cuts by the former Labor government, were costed in the 1995/96 budget at A$1.1 billion in 1998/99.  </p>
<p>Costello also said the government would raise the age limit for retirement contributions to 70 from 65 years and allow people on low incomes to take a wage rise in lieu of employers paying mandatory contributions into their retirement funds.</p>
<p>The government will also allow a tax rebate for contributions made on behalf of a low-income spouse.</p>
<p>The standard contribution limit, which enables employers to claim tax relief on their contributions to a worker's retirement savings, has been dropped, Costello said.</p>
<p>This change in the tax treatment of employer contributions will raise about A$40 million annually, the budget papers show.  </p>
<p>He also confirmed that financial institutions would be able to create retirement savings accounts as a simple, low-cost superannuation product.</p>
<p>-- Canberra bureau 616-273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
