<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3506" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia govt targets corporate tax avoiders.</title>
<headline>Australia govt targets corporate tax avoiders.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian government announced on Tuesday a range of measures aimed at what is said was tax avoidance by companies and wealthy individuals.</p>
<p>Changes were also announced to industry assistance schemes and import duty schemes and costs that would affect companies.</p>
<p>The government also announced changes to capital gains and other taxes that it said would help small businesses and poor pensioners.</p>
<p>TAX AVOIDANCE MEASURES  </p>
<p>* Amendments to the tax rules over lease arrangements on luxury cars so they are treated as loan transactions, with the lessee now treated as the owner instead of the lessor.</p>
<p>* Moves to stop wholesale sales tax fraud in the computer industry, including a review of the exemption for on-sellers.</p>
<p>* Australian Taxation Office to spend extra A$19.2 million over next two years to investigate the tax minimisation practices of some high wealth individuals. The government sees the crackdown raising an extra A$100 million in 1997/98.  </p>
<p>* Changes to the non-resident witholding tax arrangements, including the application of the Income Tax Assessment Act to non-resident interest, dividend and royalty taxes.</p>
<p>* Measures to ensure companies that are dual residents will be treated as non-residents for tax purposes.</p>
<p>* the removal of the income tax exemption granted to &quot;bona fide&quot; minerals prospectors.</p>
<p>* amendments to the capital gains tax rules over transfer of capital losses and the liquidation of groups.</p>
<p>INDUSTRY ASSISTANCE SCHEME CHANGES  </p>
<p>* The premium rate for tax deduction on Research and Development spending will be cut to a maximum of 125 percent from the current 150 percent.</p>
<p>* Confirmation of announced changes to the R&amp;D tax regime including the abolition of concessions for R&amp;D partnerships and syndicates.</p>
<p>* The creation of a new assistance programme for R&amp;D called Start to replace the syndication scheme. It includes A$520 million of funding over the next four years to provide targetted grants and loans.  </p>
<p>* Changes to the Export Market Development Grants Scheme (EMDG) which caps spending at A$150 million a year from 1996/97 onwards and makes it more accesible for small business. The eligibility threshold will be lowered to A$20,000 from A$30,000 and firms with a turnover of more than A$50 million will be excluded. Joint venture applications from the tourism industry will now be considered.</p>
<p>* Confirmation of changes to the tariff concession system which raise expected tariff revenues by A$1.026 billion over the next four years.  </p>
<p>* New user charges for Customs' service activities associated with imports, which are expected to raise A$161 million over the next four years.</p>
<p>SMALL BUSINESS TAX AND OTHER CHANGES</p>
<p>* The reduction of the provisional tax uplift factor to six percent from eight percent, which would deliver, the government said, A$180 million back to provisional taxpayers in 1996/97.  </p>
<p>* Relief from Capital Gains Tax (CGT) for small businesses selling one business and buying a new one. The rollover relief applies to businesses with assets of less than A$5 million and the new business must be bought within 12 months and be similar to the one sold previously.</p>
<p>* CGT exemption of up to A$550,000 for those selling a business and using the proceeds in their retirement.</p>
<p>* The extension of the qualifying period for capital gains tax exemption to 24 months from 12 months for the sale of an inherited house.  </p>
<p>* Tax law amendments to bring equity investments in small to medium sized enterprises by lending institutions into the Capital Gains Tax regime. The government said this would give an incentive to institutions to invest long term in small business.</p>
<p>* Fringe Benefits Tax exemption for housing provided by farmers for workers in remote areas.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
