<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3507" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia to enact 'Charter of Budget Honesty'.</title>
<headline>Australia to enact 'Charter of Budget Honesty'.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Treasurer Peter Costello said the government plans to introduce legislation requiring semi-annual updates of the economic and fiscal outlook.</p>
<p>As part of the government's 1996/97 (July-June) budget, the government said the 'Charter of Budget Honesty' will also require an updated economic and fiscal outlook to be released when an election is called, and an intergenerational report every five years.  </p>
<p>The proposed legislation would introduce principles for the sound management of fiscal policy and a formal requirement that each government clearly outlined its fiscal strategy.</p>
<p>&quot;The principles will require governments to give consideration to the impact of policy on: government debt and managing fiscal risks; national saving; the stability and integrity of the tax base; and equity between generations,&quot; the Treasurer said in a statement.</p>
<p>Part of the proposed principles included a requirement that the government outlined the process to reverse discretionary stimulatory measures introduced when the economy is in downturn.  </p>
<p>As part of the proposed Charter, a new detailed system of reporting would be introduced, and these are tabled below.</p>
<p>    Report			 Required Frequency  Responsibility</p>
<p>Fiscal Strategy Statement	  Annual		 Government</p>
<p>Budget Economic and Fiscal	 Annual		 Government</p>
<p>Outlook  </p>
<p>Mid-year Economic and Fiscal     Annual		 Government</p>
<p>Outlook</p>
<p>Pre-election Economic and     Election run-up   Treasury/Finance</p>
<p>Fiscal Outlook</p>
<p>Intergenerational report	  Five yearly	   Government</p>
<p>Final Budget Outcome		 Annual		 Government</p>
<p>The Fiscal Strategy statement was intended to increase public awareness of fiscal policy objectives and establish a benchmark for evaluating the conduct of fiscal policy.</p>
<p>Costello said the statement should outline the longer term objectives for fiscal policy within which shorter term policies would be framed, and explain the broad strategic priorities on which the budget was based.</p>
<p>The Budget and mid-year outlooks would provide fiscal projections for the three years after the budget year, together with the economic and other assumptions on which they were based.  </p>
<p>It was proposed that the Budget report would be presented each year with the annual appropriations, while the mid-year report was to be published by the end of December.</p>
<p>The pre-election report was to be released within 10 days of an election's announcement to ensure the availability of updated information prior to the election.</p>
<p>Each five years an intergenerational report, assessing the long-term sustainability of current polices, would be issued to help ensure fiscal policy addresses both short and long-term policy issues, Costello said.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
