<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3510" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia govt borrowing programme A$7.0 bln.</title>
<headline>Australia govt borrowing programme A$7.0 bln.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian government's total borrowing programme for 1996/97 is expected to be around A$7.0 billion in the year to end-June 1997, the Australian Treasury said in 1996/97 Budget papers.</p>
<p>This was A$1.0 billion above the mimimum needed to meet the financing task, which was estimated at A$6.0 billion in the year to end-June 1997 down from A$13.8 billion in 1995/96.</p>
<p>Treasury said a borrowing programme of that size offered flexibility to repurchase Treasury Bonds scheduled for maturity in out-years if this is judged desirable.  </p>
<p>The financing task comprised an estimated headline budget surplus of A$500 million in 1996/97 offsetting scheduled bond maturities of around A$4.6 billion, foreign currency debt repayments of A$700 million and A$1.2 billion in payments associated with Commonwealth public trading enterprises.</p>
<p>Aggregate Treasury bond issuance was expected to be around A$6.0 to A$7.0 billion in 1995/96, down from A$7.8 billion in 1995/96, providing scope to introduce a new benchmark line.</p>
<p>At this stage, the intention is that the new Treasury Bond will be a long-end stock, possibly a 2009 maturity, Treasury said.  </p>
<p>However, market feedback will be an important determinant in the final decision, it added.</p>
<p>A Treasury indexed bond issuance programme of around A$500 million to A$1.0 billion is envisaged for 1996/97, with the final amopunt subject to market conditions.</p>
<p>Subject to market demand, consideration will be given to the introduction of a new benchmark capital-indexed bond, probably with a maturity beyond those of existing lines, perhaps a 2020 line, Treasury said.  </p>
<p>Issuance of Treasury adjustable rate bonds is expected to be around A$1.0 billion. Again, the focus will be on a programme that will best support and contribute to the long-term development of this market, Treasury said.</p>
<p>The possible extension of the Commonwealth floating-rate curve beyond the present October 2000 line will be considered, it added.</p>
<p>Treasury said it expected a large within-year funding requirement in 1996/97 which will require regular Treasury Note issuance.  </p>
<p>However, current intentions are for a reduction in the volume of Treasury notes outstanding at end-June 1997 to below A$15 billion, compared to end-June 1996 levels of A$15.3 billion.</p>
<p>As in previous years, it was the intention to maintain a small, core holding of U.S. dollar exposure in the government's debt portfolio, Treasury said.</p>
<p>This will involve the acquisition of new foreign currency exposure of around A$3.0 billion in the year ahead, including allowance for scheduled maturities.  </p>
<p>Treasury said the most effective way of obtaining US$ exposure had been to issue domestically and swap the A$ proceeds into US$. Although not currently planned, a return to direct issuance offshore by the Commonwealth remains an option should it become advantageous, Treasury said.</p>
<p>Should that happen, there would be a corresponding reduction in the domestic borrowing programme.</p>
<p>The current practice of holding Treasury Bond tenders every four to six weeks would continue, as would the practice of weighting Bond issue towards the first half of the financial year, Treasury said.</p>
<p>-- Canberra newsroom 61-6 273 2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
