<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3515" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: INTERVIEW - QNI says nickel mines must hit cost.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - QNI says nickel mines must hit cost.</headline>
<byline>James Regan</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>With demand for nickel wavering and stocks building, producers have little choice but to attack costs, nickel producer QNI Ltd said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Nickel prices are down about 25 percent in the last 12 months, reflecting a slow-down in consumption by the all-important stainless steel sector, Wyn Davies, managing director of QNI said in an interview.</p>
<p>To maintain margins, producers must therefore hit at costs, Davies said. Davies declined to forecast future nickel prices but said the metal was likely to stay on a roller-coaster.  </p>
<p>&quot;The markets will continue to be volatile and that's something one learns to accept,&quot; Davies said.</p>
<p>Davies said he did not fully understand the reason why an abundance of potential new players wanted to get into nickel.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday, QNI reported a 20 percent fall in net profit to A$85.89 million in the 1996/97 year ended June 30 versus the previous year.</p>
<p>The decline was linked in part to a weaker nickel price.</p>
<p>&quot;For the first time since the 1970s, there is a very strong interest in getting into the nickel or cobalt business,&quot; Davies said.  </p>
<p>&quot;At just over US$3.00 a pound, a considerable number of existing nickel producers are not making much money,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But it doesn't seem to have dented the interest of a lot of would-be players.&quot;</p>
<p>More than half-dozen new nickel projects are proposed in Australia and an international group is aiming to restart the long-idled Nonoc refining and mining complex in the Philippines.</p>
<p>In Canada, the giant Voisey's Bay discovery is gearing for start-up in a few years, potentially supplying up to 16 percent of the world market.  </p>
<p>A bright spot in the market for those already in the market has been soaring demand in parts of Asia, where regional growth of as much as 15 percent far-outruns historical overall growth rates of closer to three percent, Davies said.</p>
<p>However, some 35,000 tonnes of nickel sitting in London Metal Exchange warehouses and possibly a further 30,00 tonnes stockpiled off-LME warrant is weighing on the market, he said.</p>
<p>Also, &quot;There's pretty much in the hands of consumers,&quot; he said.  &quot;We're not carrying much stock.&quot;</p>
<p>Davies said it wouldn't take much too firm up the market, although currently &quot;people are pretty much supplied.&quot;  </p>
<p>Smart producers of nickel were looking to knock down their operating costs, Davies said.</p>
<p>It's certainly something we're putting alot of effort into.&quot; Still, market conditions aren't as bad as they were in 1992 and 1993, when Russian-produced nickel was flooding into western markets, Davies said. Better transparency of the Russian industry now exists, he said. &quot;I think we all know a lot better what's going on in Russia these days, Davies said.</p>
<p>While metal continues to leak out Russia, most comes out from new prodcution and not stockpiles, Davies said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 93-73-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22471">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
