<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3518" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Aug 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>NIHON KEIZAI SHIMBUN</p>
<p>Mitsubishi Motors Corp, a Malaysian government-affiliated investment company and two munition makers owned by the Chinese government are to set up a joint company to manufacture car engines in China. They are expected to receive permission to set up the venture from the Chinese government by the end of this month. They hope to start making 150,000 engines annually by 1998. The joint company will be capitalised at about 40 billion yen.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Osaka prosecutors plan to raid pharmaceuticals maker Green Cross Corp today in connection with the company's sale of blood products which may have been contaminated with HIV.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Matsushita-Kotobuki Electronics Industries Ltd expects its parent current profit in the half-year to September to increase by 3.1 times from the same period a year earlier to 9.8 billion yen, compared with its former forecast of 6.2 billion yen.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Mycal Corp expects its parent current profit in the six months ending August 31 to increase by 44 percent from the same period a year earlier to six billion yen, against its previous forecast of five billion yen.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Major computer modem maker U.S. Robotics Inc plans to set up a Japanese unit in Tokyo within a few months to manufacture computer modems. The new unit will be employ about 50 people.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Japan's Showa Shell Sekiyu KK and a Chinese subsidiary of the Royal Dutch Shell group are considering selling gasoline and lubricating oil in Asia, mainly in China.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Hitachi Metals Ltd plans to set up a new company in the United States to make steel components for use in power steering pumps. It will invest $5.3 million in the new plant and start operations from February 1997.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Kirin Beverage Corp plans to boost output of yeast extracts, which are in increasing demand as food seasonings. It also plans to start producing extracts from the beginning of 1997 at its own brewery in Shiga prefecture, central Japan, as it had contracted out production to another company in Tokyo.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Fuji Zerox Co Ltd plans to market colour laser printers in Japan from the second half of the business year starting April 1997.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
