<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3520" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan leader emerges in Ukraine, may meet Kuchma.</title>
<headline>Taiwan leader emerges in Ukraine, may meet Kuchma.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Parker</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan Vice President Lien Chan emerged in Kiev on Tuesday, two days after vanishing on a mysterious European mission, raising the prospect of diplomatic sparks between Ukraine and communist China.</p>
<p>Taiwan Television showed Lien with his wife and other Taiwan and Ukraine officials posing at the University of Kiev, where the announcer said Lien had received an honorary degree.</p>
<p>State-funded television said Lien's secretive visit had been arranged by the university, indicating it was unofficial, but said Lien had met Ukraine officials and was awaiting a meeting with President Leonid Kuchma.</p>
<p>A former Soviet republic, Ukraine recognises the communist government in Beijing -- not Taiwan's exiled Republic of China -- but has made clear its desire for improved relations with Taiwan and its powerful &quot;Asian dragon&quot; export economy.</p>
<p>Ukraine nonetheless views China as a key trading partner, with annual two-way trade of almost $1 billion.</p>
<p>China regards nationalist-ruled Taiwan as a rebel province ineligible for foreign ties and has sought to isolate it diplomatically since a civil war separated them in 1949.</p>
<p>Lien's presence in Ukraine virtually guarantees an angry response from Beijing, which spurns states that recognise Taipei and fumes even at diplomatic partners that entertain Taiwan's leaders.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Ukraine's foreign ministry, interviewed by Taiwan Television, said a Lien-Kuchma meeting was possible.</p>
<p>&quot;So far there is no such meeting in the plan, but it may take place absolutely unexpectedly,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Ukraine Foreign Minister Hennady Udovenko said Kiev considered Taiwan an &quot;integral part of continental China&quot; and had no information on Lien's visit.</p>
<p>Officials of Ukraine's Crimean peninsula said Lien's &quot;unofficial stopover&quot; included a trip to the picturesque Black Sea resort of Yalta, contradicting earlier assertions from Kiev officials that Lien was not in the country.</p>
<p>Kuchma was due back in Kiev on Tuesday after a holiday in Crimea, but officials said he did not meet Lien, a millionaire who doubles as Taiwan's premier or cabinet chief.</p>
<p>Crimean spokesman Oleg Khomenok told reporters in Simferopol that Lien had met the deputy prime minister, the vice-speaker of the local parliament and a parliamentary faction leader in the pro-Russian peninsula.</p>
<p>The nature of Lien's talks was not disclosed.</p>
<p>In mid-1995, a furious China downgraded its U.S. ties after Washington let Taiwan President Lee Teng-hui make a private visit and assailed Austria and the Czech Republic for allowing a similar visit by Lien.</p>
<p>Taiwan Foreign Minister John Chang maintained Taipei's pall of official silence, saying to disclose Lien's travels could compromise further activities still being planned but vowing to press ahead with Taiwan's drive to win diplomatic allies.</p>
<p>&quot;We can only confirm vice-president Lien is currently in Europe for a private visit...,&quot; Chang told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to realise our difficult situation in the international community. We will not give up any effort to expand our international living space,&quot; Chang said.</p>
<p>The number of states recognising Taiwan fell by one on Monday to 30 as impoverished Niger, which split with Beijing to recognise Taipei in 1992, switched back to Beijing.</p>
<p>In the past week, President Lee has warned that Taiwan was becoming too dependent on China's economy and assailed what he called Beijing's irrational drive to isolate the island.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
