<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3523" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Police assault ends South Korean campus siege.</title>
<headline>Police assault ends South Korean campus siege.</headline>
<byline>Shim Sung-won</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean riot police backed by helicopters and assault troops stormed a Seoul campus on Tuesday to end a seven-day occupation by students demanding reunification with North Korea.</p>
<p>They smashed through a bonfire of wooden desks and chairs engulfing the main entrance of a teaching block and flushed out about 1,000 mostly female students after a pitched battle.</p>
<p>Hours later, a further 1,000 or so terrified students holed up in a nearby science block fled into alleys and hills surrounding the Yonsei University campus where they were hunted down. They had earlier threatened to explode gas canisters and dangerous chemicals seized from laboratories.</p>
<p>In all 3,225 students were arrested, bringing the total held in a week of pro-Pyongyang agitation at Yonsei to around 5,500.</p>
<p>Dozens of students were injured in the assault by denim-clad riot police trained in martial arts and many had blood streaming from head wounds as they were dragged away.</p>
<p>A South Korean news photographer was in critical condition in hospital after being struck on the head by a rock.</p>
<p>The raid started just before dawn when police helicopters skimmed low over the classroom complex and dropped liquid teargas on students packed on the roof.</p>
<p>Thousands of riot police rushed the building, occupied by undergraduates calling for unity with North Korea on Pyongyang's terms that would leave the governments of both North and South intact.</p>
<p>The students also demanded the withdrawal of U.S. troops stationed in the South, which is still technically at war with the North since the 1950-53 Korean War.</p>
<p>Police held aloft metal shields as students rained down rocks, desks, chairs and petrol bombs.</p>
<p>After leaping across flames at the entrance and clambering through smashed windows, they were briefly beaten back by a raging fire in the lobby.</p>
<p>Firefighters successfully brought the blaze under control.</p>
<p>By then, some students on the roof were waving white flags to signal surrender.</p>
<p>On the rooftop of an adjacent building, assault troops dropped by helicopter and wearing black balaclavas trained automatic weapons on student occupiers.</p>
<p>One male student clung by his fingertips from the roof and threatened to let go in a suicide bid before changing his mind.</p>
<p>Police grabbed and pummelled him with their fists.</p>
<p>Large parts of the classroom building were gutted by fire and equipment was smashed beyond repair.</p>
<p>&quot;This place is beyond recognition,&quot; said university administrator Yoo Young-choon, surveying the scene.</p>
<p>Authorities have branded the student leaders as Communist stooges and more than 100 have been formally charged, some under national security laws.</p>
<p>Outside the main campus gate, about 50 mothers and other relatives of the students wailed and pleaded for mercy for the youths. &quot;My son is not a communist,&quot; one mother screamed.</p>
<p>Students fleeing from the science block scrambled over alleyway rooftops in their desperation to avoid club-wielding police. Some resisted arrest by hurling rocks and brandishing iron bars.</p>
<p>Minutes before their escape, a student leader denounced the raid at a news conference as a &quot;murderous crackdown&quot;.</p>
<p>On Saturday police cut off food and medicine to the students. Dozens were rushed to hospital on Monday suffering from hunger and exhaustion.</p>
<p>Militant students find themselves isolated from a hostile public as they press their violent campaign for reunification.</p>
<p>Heroes of the battle for democracy in the late 1980s, when the middle classes rallied behind them, the radical students have now alienated ordinary South Koreans by embracing Pyongyang's blueprint for a single Korea.</p>
<p>Tuesday's assault was the worst campus violence since President Kim Young-sam took power in 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
