<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3542" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Hiap Aik gets approval to buy firm.</title>
<headline>Hiap Aik gets approval to buy firm.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hiap Aik Construction Bhd has received Malaysian Securities Commission approval to acquire Green Crescent Resources Sdn Bhd, its merchant banker said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Perdana Merchant Bankers said in a statement that the Securities Commission has revised the proposal submitted by the company.</p>
<p>Under the approval, Hiap Aik will acquire Green Crescent for 32 million ringgit, through an issue of 4.38 million new shares at 7.30 ringgit per share.</p>
<p>The company had proposed an issue of 7.5 million shares at an issue price of six ringgit per share.</p>
<p>The acquisition is also subject to the owners of Green Crescent providing a profit guarantee of 32 million ringgit in two financial years ending December, 1998.</p>
<p>Hiap Aik can proceed with the acquisition only after Green Crescent gets approval for a 20-acre property development project from the Selangor State Authority.</p>
<p>Hiap Aik will also have to develop the entire land. It cannot sell any part of it to anyone else, the statement said</p>
<p>- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
