<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3545" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul begins demolishing symbol of Japanese rule.</title>
<headline>Seoul begins demolishing symbol of Japanese rule.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea on Tuesday began knocking down Seoul's blue-domed capitol building in a bid to erase memories of Japanese rule of the Korean peninsula.</p>
<p>The capitol was built by the Japanese in 1926 in the grounds of the Kyongbok Palace, the principal royal palace of Korea's Yi dynasty which was deposed in 1910 when the Japanese began 35 years of colonial rule.</p>
<p>&quot;Now the black shadow which has overcast the Kyongbok Palace, the symbol of (Korea's) Yi dynasty, will finally disappear and be buried in history,&quot; Chung Yang-mo, director of the national museum housed in the capitol building, told reporters.</p>
<p>South Korea began the demolition process last year by plucking the tip of the dome off the building, the seat of the Japanese colonial government, as it marked the 50th anniversary of the end of World War Two.</p>
<p>&quot;We have finally moved everything, including sculptures, paintings and other historical objects,&quot; said an official at Ministry of Culture and Sports.</p>
<p>He said the demolition would take until the end of the year.</p>
<p>As part of a campaign to &quot;correct distorted history&quot;, South Korea is restoring the original palace and grounds before Seoul and Tokyo co-host the 2002 World Cup soccer finals.</p>
<p>South Korea and Japan established diplomatic ties in 1965 and the two have burgeoning trade, investment and tourism ties.</p>
<p>But surveys consistently show the people of each nation list the other as the country they most love to hate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
