<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3546" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Acer expects lower computer growth.</title>
<headline>Acer expects lower computer growth.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Acer Computer International (ACI) president William Lu said on Tuesday he expected computer industry growth by year-end to be in the &quot;low teens&quot; against analysts' projections of 17-19 percent.</p>
<p>Speaking at a news conference on ACI's interim results, Lu said he was doubtful growth would be as high as 17-19 percent. &quot;I expect the low teens,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>ACI reported a 14.4 percent rise in net profit to Singapore $14.7 million for first-half ended June 30 1996.</p>
<p>Turnover rose to S$511.0 million againt $402.7 million for the corresponding period last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The improved turnover was attributed to across-the- board improvements in many ACI territories, particularly in the Asian region, including Singapore, Malaysia, Hong Kong and India and South Africa,&quot; ACI said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Earnings also remained satisfactory despite increased competition, helped by strong economic recovery in the Latin American markets,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Lu said ACI planned to maintained a healthy profit margin in the highly competitive computer market by keeping ahead of competition via &quot;speedy product launches&quot;.</p>
<p>Lu was unfazed by competition from smaller computer companies which have spawned throughout the Asia-Pacific region, specifically in its manufacturing sites of Singapore, Hong Kong and Taiwan.</p>
<p>&quot;These companies are doing short-term businesses. If the industry changes, they will give up. Personally I regard them as a short-term phenomenon,&quot; Lu said.</p>
<p>Asia Pacific contributed about 67 percent of the company's total interim revenue, he added.</p>
<p>--Singapore newsroom (65 8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
