<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3549" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodia finally passes nationality law.</title>
<headline>Cambodia finally passes nationality law.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodian legislators on Tuesday passed a nationality law that is crucial for the holding of elections and could affect the status of minority groups.</p>
<p>Senior parliamentarian Son Soubert said passage of the law, which decides who can hold Cambodian citizenship, was vital.</p>
<p>&quot;Otherwise we cannot discuss the electoral law...(and) the immigration law cannot be applied totally,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>The government has said all laws will be in place by the end of the year for the holding of local elections due in 1997 and general elections in 1998.</p>
<p>Son Soubert tried to dismiss fears that the government would use the immigration and nationality laws to expel tens of thousands of ethnic Vietnamese and other minority groups.</p>
<p>He said King Norodom Sihanouk had guaranteed that all those who could prove residence in Cambodia before a 1970 coup that ousted him from power should be allowed to stay.</p>
<p>Cambodia is home to around 100,000 ethnic Vietnamese, many of whom have been here for generations but fled persecution in the 1970s, often losing their documentation.</p>
<p>Some legislators, including Son Chhay of the Buddhist Liberal Democratic Party (BLDP), were concerned about an article allowing foreigners to buy citizenship for $400,000.</p>
<p>Businessmen from places such as Hong Kong, which reverts to China in 1997, will not have to meet residential qualifications necessary for others but must pass a language test.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm worried that criminal people, people involved with the mafia and drug trafficking, will be willing to pay this money to use Cambodia as a scapegoat (for their crimes),&quot; Son Chhay told Reuters.</p>
<p>Both Son Chhay and Son Soubert also said some foreign businessmen had improperly bought Cambodian identification under the previous government that let them buy property, but their status would be clarified under the new legislation.</p>
<p>If the law was fully implemented, &quot;there's going to be quite a large number of these people jailed,&quot; Son Chhay said.</p>
<p>Son Soubert said most of Tuesday's session was spent discussing penalties for those using forged Cambodian passports or identification cards.</p>
<p>Legislators agreed to amend these articles to punish only foreigners using fake identification and hiked the proposed jail term to between five and 10 years from one to five years.</p>
<p>The assembly had on Monday dropped one controversial article which said naturalised Cambodians could lose their citizenship if they violated the constitution or other laws.</p>
<p>The law was tabled in June but parliamentarians had failed to complete debate when the National Assembly's three-month session ended in July. An extraordinary session was convened last week to finish the work.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
