<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3550" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Euroyen end lower after choppy day,await Fed.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Euroyen end lower after choppy day,await Fed.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Euroyen futures gave up some of their recent gains to end lower in choppy trade on Tuesday as players awaited the outcome of the Federal Reserve's policy-making meeting later in the day.</p>
<p>Both ends of the Japanese yield curve have been underpinned recently by expectations that the Fed will not hike U.S. interest rates, potentially placing Japanese rates on hold too.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as we see no movement from the Fed, that would take some supposed pressure off the BOJ (Bank of Japan), which would mean continued low rates in Japan,&quot; said a trader with a U.S. futures house.  </p>
<p>After trading to a high of 99.18, December Euroyen finished at 99.14 against its CME close at 99.15. Volume was relatively low at 10,340 contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;It was nervousness creeping in from people who are long,&quot; said a dealer with another U.S. institution. &quot;These levels are getting a little unrealistic. They're discounting no rate change for the foreseeable future.&quot;</p>
<p>He said December Euroyen should be well capped at 99.25, although selling pressure was likely well before that, from 99.18 upwards. Japanese government bond futures for September settled at 120.84 against their previous 120.97.  </p>
<p>Eurodollar futures were practically static as players held back ahead of the FOMC, due to begin at 1300 GMT.</p>
<p>December Eurodollars finished unchanged from their IMM close, at 94.20. March was also unchanged, at 94.10. Turnover for both months was a mere 12,100 lots.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market had completely priced in the lack of a rate hike. &quot;Eurodollars can't really go up from here. The maximum upside is 10-20 points while they could fall by 50-70 points, so I'd rather bet on the short side,&quot; said the trader.</p>
<p>-- Sonali Desai (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
