<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3553" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Turkey's Erbakan ends controversial foreign tour.</title>
<headline>Turkey's Erbakan ends controversial foreign tour.</headline>
<byline>Raju Gopalakrishnan</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's new Islamist prime minister on Tuesday ended a controversial foreign tour that has raised his nation's profile in Asia but put it on a potential collision course with the United States.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan was leaving for home from Indonesia, his fifth stop after visits to Iran, Pakistan, Singapore and Malaysia in his first foreign tour since taking office in June.</p>
<p>All but Singapore are Moslem-majority nations, and the tour represented Turkey's new drive to increase its standing in the Islamic world, aides of the prime minister said.</p>
<p>Turkish MP Hasan Huseyin Ceylan, a member of Erbakan's Welfare Party who was part of his delegation, said Turkey's relations with fellow Islamic nations had deteriorated in recent years as Ankara sought a greater role in Europe, and Erbakan's tour was aimed at shoring up the ties.</p>
<p>&quot;Turkey attaches great importance to promoting its economic, commercial, social and cultural relations with Islamic countries,&quot; Erbakan said in an address to the Indonesian Chamber of Commerce on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Turkey is capable of acting as a bridge between Europe and the Islamic world,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But the West has been wary of ally Turkey's tilt to the East since Erbekan took over as the country's first overtly Islamic leader in over 70 years.</p>
<p>A $23 billion gas supply deal with Iran signed by Erbakan on the first leg of his tour has drawn the ire of the United States and led to calls for sanctions against Turkey.</p>
<p>U.S. State Department spokesman Glynn Davies said &quot;signing this deal is not the kind of signal that we in the West should be sending to what is, in effect, a rogue government&quot;.</p>
<p>The deal was struck one week after U.S. President Bill Clinton signed a law to penalise companies investing in energy projects in Iran or Libya.</p>
<p>Turkish officials have said the law does not apply to the project and the United States has said it will study the agreement and the law before it decided on sanctions.</p>
<p>Members of Erbakan's delagation said the deal was necessary to provide Turkey with much needed fuel for electricity and noted that the deal was completed by the pro-West government of previous prime minister Tansu Ciller, who is foreign minister in the new coalition government.</p>
<p>&quot;The demand for gas in just Istanbul is greater than the amount than we get from Russia,&quot; said Ceylan. &quot;Turkey needs to buy gas and Iran offered a good price.&quot;</p>
<p>Energy Minister Recai Kutan dismissed the possibility that the United States would impose sanctions because of the deal.</p>
<p>&quot;Turkey and the United States have had good relations for over 50 years and this is only one event,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;It just happens to be one time when our benefits do not coincide.&quot;</p>
<p>Erbakan's tour also came amid a new outbreak of tension between fellow NATO members Turkey and Greece over the divided island of Cyprus. At least two Greek Cypriots were killed last week during protests in the United Nations-controlled buffer zone against Turkey's 22-year occupation of the island's northern areas.</p>
<p>Greece has warned Turkey that any military advance would lead to war and Erbakan was quick to react.</p>
<p>&quot;If the United States is to impose any sanctions on any country, that has to be imposed on Greece, because it is the Greek Cypriots who have engaged in this provocative action,&quot; he said in Malaysia on Sunday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
