<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3555" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore oil product steady, fuel oil set to rise.</title>
<headline>Singapore oil product steady, fuel oil set to rise.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore oil product prices were steady on Tuesday, despite crudes taking a breather from a recent rally, with fuel oil well supported by strong buying interests, traders said.</p>
<p>Gas oil was offered lower by a Singapore trader at $25.60 a barrel for 150,000 barrels for September 15-19 lifting, and was met with a bid by a US trader. Deals done Tuesday ranged at $25.65-$25.75. Traders said high gas oil prices were making it tough for Korean refiners to sell cargoes especially to China. Seven to 10 Korean cargoes were offered for September lifting at 40 cents a barrel over Singapore quotes fob with no buyers seen.  </p>
<p>Additional gas oil supplies were seen from Taiwan that has issued a tender to sell up to 250,000 barrels for end-September lifting. Traders were pinning hopes on Indonesia that was projected to buy around three million barrels for September, compared with about two million for August. Paper gas oil fell 30 cents late in the day on crude's weakness to be last traded at $25.45 from $25.75 earlier.</p>
<p>Jet fuel remained firm, with an offer seen at $28.70 for September 15-19. A US and a European major recently sold a jet fuel cargo each to Indonesia for September delivery at 40 cents premiums fob basis, traders said.  </p>
<p>Naphtha's recent rise with crude sidelined buyers. Strong US gasoline prices prompted talk of an open arbitrage to the states. But traders said although it works on paper, meeting US specifications would make this difficult. A Japanese trader was aggressive and matched bids from a Dutch and a French trader for 95-octane unleaded at $21.50 for September 4-8 and 10-14 lifting. Fuel oil was steady but was expected to rise this week. Prices of 180-cst surged over $10 a tonne within a week, hitting a three-month high of $104 on Monday, a rise from $92.50 on Aug 13. One buyer said fewer Mideast exports, due to higher domestic summer demand, have caused prices to firm. -- (+65-8703084)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
