<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3557" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: New Hong Kong - India air pact expected &quot;any day now&quot;.</title>
<headline>New Hong Kong - India air pact expected &quot;any day now&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Jim Gilchrist</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Acting Indian commissioner in Hong Kong, Dipak Mallik, said he expects a new air services agreement to be signed &quot;any day now&quot; opening up the potential for more flights between the two countries.</p>
<p>But flag carrier Air India said the cuts in capacity it imposed last month between Delhi, Bombay and Hong Kong will remain in force for the forseeable future due to poor demand and increased competition.</p>
<p>Y.D Mathur, Air India's manager for Hong Kong, Philippines, Macau and China told Reuters that load factors for both passenger and cargo have fallen to 60 per cent. Instead of five Boeing 747 flights a week, the carrier has substituted smaller Airbus A310 aircraft on three of the services to Hong Kong. The remaining two 747 services fly onto Osaka in Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there will be major changes when the air services agreement is signed. Daily flights by Air India are not likely in the near future. There is plenty of capacity on the route and I have no problem providing seats or cargo space,&quot; Mathur said.</p>
<p>Air India's most recent competitor is United Airlines which started a daily Hong Kong to Delhi service last December. Hong Kong's Cathay Pacific Airways Ltd flies to Bombay via Bangkok. India's national carrier also faces competition from other Asian carriers, Thai International Airways Ltd, Singapore Airlines Ltd and Malaysian Airline System Bhd all fly indirect services to India via their main hubs, Mathur said.</p>
<p>Mallik, said a new air services agreement was needed because the existing Indo-UK agreement expires when Hong Kong is handed back to China next year. The Sino-British Joint Liason Group set up to oversee the handover has already approved the new agreement, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect the new agreement to be signed any day now. The Hindi translation is being done now and after the agreement is signed commercial talks between the flag carriers will begin in October, Mallik said.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole purpose of signing this agreement is to continue with the air bridge when Hong Kong becomes part of China so obviously there is potential of increased flights otherwise why would we sign the agreement. How the expectation turns out I cannot predict,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>--Air Cargo Newsroom Tel +44 171 542 7706 Fax +44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
