<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3558" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia rubber closes up on Japanese trends.</title>
<headline>Malaysia rubber closes up on Japanese trends.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian rubber prices were quoted higher at the close after tracking a rebound in Japanese futures but the market was desperately short of buyers and other genuinely positive factors, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is really flat,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;There were some enquirers from (South) Korea for some CV and 20 but they were just checking and not serious in buying.&quot;</p>
<p>Buyers were generally awaiting lower prices, said dealers.</p>
<p>&quot;I see the market maintaining present levels,&quot; said another dealer. &quot;But if the SMR20 breaks the 300 level, it could go a long way down.&quot;  </p>
<p>At the close, the Malaysian Rubber Exchange and Licensing Board set market indicator price for September RSS1 buyer at 321 cents ($1.29) a kg, up 1.5 cents from Monday's close. September SMR20 buyer was one cent higher at 303 cents.</p>
<p>Trading houses offered the SMR20 at 303 cents, the SMR10 at 303 cents, SMR5 at 315-316, SMR CV at 378-80, SMR L at 360-65 and drum latex FOB at 252.</p>
<p>The INRO five-day average fell to 246.54 Malaysian/Singapore cents per kg on August 19 from 246.61 on August 18. The daily indicator dipped to 245.19 from 246.33.</p>
<p>-- Barani Krishnaan (603-230-7510) ($1=2.4930 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
