<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3564" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Jinxing reports 8.3 mln yuan interim loss.</title>
<headline>Jinxing reports 8.3 mln yuan interim loss.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shenzhen Jinxing Co Ltd said on Tuesday it incurred a 8.33 million yuan loss in the first half of 1996 against net earnings of 38,582 yuan in 1995.</p>
<p>The Shenzhen-listed company said it had main operating income of 1.86 million yuan in the January-June period of 1996, compared with 13.70 million yuan in 1995.</p>
<p>Jinxing, involved in foreign trade, cargo handling and real estate, blamed the loss on Beijing's tight credit policies and its lowering of export tax rebates.</p>
<p>Jinxing said its current liabilities stood at 92.84 million yuan by end June 1996 versus 1995's 85.71 million.</p>
<p>Current assets stood at 88.53 million yuan, compared with 75.47 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>Jinxing said losses were due to poor management of some subsidiaries but added that it was taking steps to sell unprofitable subsidiaries and trim liabilities.</p>
<p>The company said it would focus on streamlining management in the second half of this year, but gave no details.</p>
<p>Jinxing had net earnings of 168,800 yuan in 1995, down 97.98 percent from 7.60 million yuan in 1994 due to funding shortage.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
