<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3567" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Guangdong Weida to list A shares on August 23.</title>
<headline>Guangdong Weida to list A shares on August 23.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Medical appliance maker Guangdong Weida Group Co Ltd has received approval to list 13.875 million A shares in Shenzhen on August 23, the China Securities Bulletin reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The A shares were issued at 7.38 yuan per share in Jieyang city, southern Guangdong province, earlier this month, the bulletin quoted a company spokesman as saying.</p>
<p>Weida will list 1.125 million staff shares, offered at 1.60 yuan per share in 1994, along with the class A stock.</p>
<p>Weida's issue of the A stock has a projected price/earnings ratio of 12.51 times based on forecast net earnings per share of 0.59 yuan for 1996, the company said.</p>
<p>Following its recent A share offer, Weida's total share capital has been expanded to 58.875 million shares, including 30 million state shares, 13.875 million legal person shares and 1.125 million staff shares.</p>
<p>Weida plans to use the proceeds from the A share offer to expand its core business.</p>
<p>Weida said it has forecast after-tax profits of 34.95 million yuan for 1996, compared with 16.88 million yuan in 1995 and 11.32 million yuan in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
