<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3569" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MONGOLIA: Mongolia says cholera under control, 106 infected.</title>
<headline>Mongolia says cholera under control, 106 infected.</headline>
<byline>Irja Halasz</byline>
<dateline>ULAN BATOR 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mongolian officials said on Tuesday they had controlled the spread of cholera, which has infected 106 people since an outbreak of the disease this month in the north of the country.</p>
<p>An additional 23 people were suspected of having the disease, pending laboratory test results, and a total of 1,955 people were in quarantine across the country, health officials said.</p>
<p>Mongolian Minister of Defence D. Dorligjav said officials had controlled the spread of cholera by imposing strict restrictions on travel.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been able to restrict the spread of the disease,&quot; Dorligjav said in an interview.</p>
<p>Health officials said they believed the outbreak was not going to become an epidemic in densely populated areas like Ulan Bator, Darkhan and Erdenet.</p>
<p>Dorligjav commands civil defence troops that have sealed off the northern cities of Erdenet and Darkhan, Selenge province and parts of Central province since the disease broke out on August 8.</p>
<p>Officials were trying to evacuate foreigners trapped in quarantined areas, he said. About 30 foreigners have been evacuated from Erdenet by helicopter and more than 20 were to be evacuated from Darkhan.</p>
<p>Health officials have traced the virus back to a military unit in Khoetol, about 350 km (210 miles) from Ulan Bator. They believe it was spread through contaminated food.</p>
<p>&quot;The bacteria has been found in the area where leftovers had been dumped... From there, the bacteria spread to a nearby lake,&quot; Dorligjav said.</p>
<p>He said the bacteria had probably been spread by foreign food since Mongolia had never had a cholera epidemic before.</p>
<p>Health Ministry officials said nine people in Ulan Bator were infected and 10 more suspected of having the disease, but the capital's hospital for infectious diseases said there were even more cases.</p>
<p>&quot;We have 24 people taken into the wards suspected of having cholera. Of them, 12 have already been confirmed to have the disease,&quot; a hospital doctor said.</p>
<p>Police and soldiers guarded the capital's military hospital and the hospital for infectious diseases to enforce the quarantine.</p>
<p>Health officials on Tuesday imposed a quarantine on two more counties in Central province, which surrounds the capital.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MONGLA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ULAN BATOR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MONGOLIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
