<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3570" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai maize prices ease, soymeal firms.</title>
<headline>Thai maize prices ease, soymeal firms.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai domestic maize prices paid by feed producers eased to an average 4.28 baht/kg this week from 4.42 a week ago on increased supplies from harvests, traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A major feed producer said fresh Thai harvests, mostly from eastern Prachinburi and Chantaburi provinces, had raised domestic supply while parts of new crops from northeast and north central Thailand have started to arrive.</p>
<p>&quot;The fresh harvest is adequate to allow most feed plants to open for operation since early August,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Thailand's projected maize crop of four million tonnes from its 1996/97 (July/June) will continue harvesting until December.</p>
<p>Bangkok soymeal prices firmed slightly to 9.70 baht/kg from 9.60 a week ago because no additional Brazilian imports had been made this month, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to receive about 5,000-6,000 tonnes from Brazil in mid-September. I estimate total imports next month at over 10,000 tonnes,&quot; an official at Bangkok Produce said.</p>
<p>Feed producers said soymeal fetched a higher price this week as it was mostly made from fresh domestic high-protein soybean that cost more than imported soymeal.</p>
<p>Soymeal prices should ease in late September or early October when domestic soybean harvests start reaching the market.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662)-2529950/3</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
