<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3571" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL shares close higher, focus on second liners.</title>
<headline>KL shares close higher, focus on second liners.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share prices closed higher with buying again focusing on second liners, while blue chips continued to track a tight trading range, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;There was some renewed buying of blue chips in the afternoon but the focus remained on Second Board stocks,&quot; said one institutional dealer.</p>
<p>The benchmark Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange's Composite Index ended at 1,105.44, up 2.08 points, after moving in a four-point range. The Second Board index surged 10.64 points or 2.15 percent to 506.27.  </p>
<p>Market volume was 190 million shares, with gainers leading losers 290 to 258.</p>
<p>Khong Guan and Setron led volumes, rising 4.60 ringgit and 60 cents respectively to 18.80 and 6.80 ringgit. Khong Guan recently proposed to acquire a 32 percent stake in Setron through a share issue.</p>
<p>Blue chips Tenaga Nasional, Telekom Malaysia and Genting gained between five and 20 cents each. But Malaysia International Shipping Corp fell 30 cents to 7.40 ringgit on the back of lower half-year earnings.</p>
<p>-- Syed Azman (603-2308911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
