<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3578" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian rupiah stable, swap rates ease further.</title>
<headline>Indonesian rupiah stable, swap rates ease further.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indonesian rupiah was stable against the dollar in dull late trading on Tuesday as swap rates eased further on offshore selling, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no initiative at all in the market. Operators just stayed on the sidelines,&quot; one local bank dealer said.</p>
<p>He said the dollar-rupiah rate was moving in a narrow range between 2,341.5 and 2,342.5 in the afternoon.</p>
<p>He said operators were reluctant to go long on dollars because of the expensive swap costs but they also did not want to establish large short-dollar positions.  </p>
<p>Dealers said they expected no major trouble at the lawsuit hearing on August 22 filed by Megawati Sukarnoputri, ousted leader of the opposition Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI), against the government and the military.</p>
<p>&quot;But they also did not dare to take fresh positions. They wanted to wait further,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>The dealer said offshore operators were seen sustaining swaps unloading, possibly on speculation of a lower interest rate environment which may reduce swap points.</p>
<p>&quot;It was not drastic but the trend was there,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>He said operators might have parked the rupiah in the forward market as they offloaded swaps.</p>
<p>Spot rupiah was quoted at 2,341.0/42.0 at 1010 GMT against an opening of 2,341.5/42.5.</p>
<p>Tomorrow and today rupiah closed at 2,341.15/41.45 and 2,340.90/41.50, respectively.</p>
<p>Overnight swap was at 0.53/0.55 and tom/next at 0.53/0.56.</p>
<p>One-month swap was at 18.25/18.75, two-month at 34.5/36.0, three-month at 53.5/54.0 and six-month at 108.0/108.5 points.</p>
<p>The central bank kept its intervention rate at 2,335/2,453 and the conversion rate at 2,335/2,381 on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
