<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3579" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia's 14-month low on tin surprises market.</title>
<headline>Malaysia's 14-month low on tin surprises market.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The fall in Malaysia's tin price to a 14-month low on Tuesday was largely inexplicable though higher world tin stocks and a shift of funds to the equity market were possible factors, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Kuala Lumpur Tin Market (KLTM) closed at 14.97 ringgit ($6.01) a kilo on Tuesday, three cents lower than the previous close and a support level of 15 ringgit.</p>
<p>Three month tin on the London Metal Exchange closed steadily unchanged on Monday.  </p>
<p>&quot;But most European and American tin smelters are closed now for the summer holidays and the lower consumption is not unusual,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The KLTM's last lowest closing price was on June 1, 1995 at 14.60 ringgit.</p>
<p>There were offers for 156 tonnes compared to bids for 121 tonnes on Tuesday.</p>
<p>KLTM turnover fell to 128 tonnes from 145 tonnes. Buyers were Europeans, Japanese and locals. Traders said the Kuala Lumpur premium over the LME narrowed to $30 a tonne against $40 previously.  </p>
<p>&quot;The tin price is usually pinned to movements of copper and other base metals, LME stock figures and whether speculative funds are being moved to the equity market,&quot; he said. &quot;In this case, I can't see a major reason.&quot;</p>
<p>LME three month copper traded in a steady range of between $1,900 and 1,970 a tonne on Monday, before closing $15 higher.</p>
<p>Tin moved in a tight range between $6,150 and $6,160 on the London market on Tuesday, while LME stocks of the metal rose 155 tonnes to 10,795 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;The stock situation does indicate fundamental softness of tin,&quot; said a metals analyst in London.  </p>
<p>($1=2.4920 ringgit)</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230-8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
