<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3580" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: S. Korean refiners struggle to sell Sept diesel.</title>
<headline>S. Korean refiners struggle to sell Sept diesel.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean refiners are struggling to sell their gas oil (diesel) cargoes for September lifting despite the sharp price hike in Singapore, traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There are about seven to ten 30,000-tonne cargoes that are unsold for September loading,&quot; a South Korean trader said.</p>
<p>South Korean refiners are offering these cargoes at about 40 cents per barrel above Singapore spot prices on a free-on-board (fob) Korea basis, but no buyers have emerged.  </p>
<p>&quot;Even at a 30-cent premium we cannot ship the cargoes to China as the Singapore spot prices are very high,&quot; a Korean trader said. Singapore prices provide the benchmark for product pricing in South Korea.</p>
<p>Traders said Chinese buyers were willing to pay up to $193/tonne cost-and-freight basis to South China. But at prevailing spot prices in Singapore, these cargoes would land in China at least at $200 per tonne, c-and-f.</p>
<p>Spot gas oil prices in Singapore were last quoted at a high of about $25.70 a barrel or about $191 per tonne, fob on large purchases by traders.  </p>
<p>A total of four cargoes of between 150,000-to-240,000 barrels each traded in Singapore on Monday at between $25.65 and 25.75 a barrel, traders said.</p>
<p>One trader said the Koreans were having problems selling their gas oil as it is priced off Singapore spot prices which are based on different economics.</p>
<p>This is because the higher Singapore prices are sustained by spot purchases from Indonesia and trades covering recent sales to India and Nepal, the trader said.</p>
<p>The Korean barrels, on the other hand, have only one market for now, China.  </p>
<p>It was therefore not economical for Korean gas oil to be shipped further south beyond Thailand since Singapore has a greater freight advantage, another trader said.</p>
<p>In recent days, trading firms with Korean barrels were forced to take a risk and sell their cargoes at a possible loss in order to dispose off the product due to a lack of demand in North Asia.</p>
<p>But not many are willing to take this risk. Korean refiners are hoping for a downward correction in Singapore spot prices that would allow them to export again, the Korean trader said.</p>
<p>--Singapore Newsroom (+65-8703093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
