<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3581" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian crudes firmer, Brent/Dubai widens.</title>
<headline>Asian crudes firmer, Brent/Dubai widens.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crude oil prices in Asia were firmer after an overnight Brent and NYMEX rally as players continued to assess the market ahead of fresh month trading.</p>
<p>The Brent/Dubai widened out to $1.90/$2.00 from a day-earlier $1.70/$1.90 following the latest leg in Brent's rally.</p>
<p>Dubai intermonth quotes were steady at 28-32 cents for October/November and November/December versus a day-earlier October/November 30-32 cents and November/December 29-33 cents.</p>
<p>However, brokers said Brent and NYMEX futures were shedding some of their recent gains by late afternoon on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>At 1000 GMT Brent October futures were down 15 cents on the day at $20.70 and NYMEX trading on ACCESS was last traded at $23.02, down from $23.26 in New York.</p>
<p>Traders said there was demand for light sweet crudes to replace Australian barrels or for jet rich crude ahead of the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>A major with Australian operations bought 300,000 barrels of September Shua from a producer at Tapis quotes plus 55 cents.</p>
<p>Another major bought 650,000 barrels of September Griffin from an equity producer at Tapis quotes less 45 cents. A U.S. major bought 120,000 barrels of September Tapis at plus 60.  </p>
<p>Production at the 110,000 barrels per day (bpd) Cossack field in Australia could be cut back in September to as little as 50,000 bpd while a gas problem is sorted out.</p>
<p>In addition, the Shell refinery is facing strike action and Mobil's refinery is expected back at 80 percent production rate by Wednesday while they bring a cracker back up. But production will be below peak next week for repairs on a crude unit.</p>
<p>MidEast talk was quiet and players tested market sentiment. Oman values were put at flat to the MPM to seven cents premium.</p>
<p>--Singapore, N. Fullick (+65 870 3081), J. Oshima, Tokyo (+813 5473-3708)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
