<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3582" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore HSFO rally to continue on strong bids.</title>
<headline>Singapore HSFO rally to continue on strong bids.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The high sulphur fuel oil price rally was expected to continue, causing market jitters and talks that prices have become too high too fast, traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Prices for 180-cst prices have surged over $10 a tonne within one week, hitting a three-month high of $104 on Monday, an increase from $92.50 registered on August 13.</p>
<p>Cargoes of 180 cst were bid/asked between $103/$105 a tonne fob Singapore on Monday. The same Mideast trader who purchased a 180 cst cargo at $104 on Monday said he would still be keen to buy but is unsure where he would place his bid.</p>
<p>A Dutch trader said he would bid at $102 for 180 cst cargoes loading in early September. Both buyers said supplies in Singapore appear to be tight. One buyer said fewer Mideast exports, due to higher domestic summer demand, have caused prices to firm.</p>
<p>Others said reduced refinery runs in Singapore registering 1.156 million barrels per day (bpd) down from its normal 1.230 million bpd have exacerbated the tight supply situation.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a climb of $4 a tonne in Mediterranean prices on Monday have crushed talks that the arbitrage from the west has opened.</p>
<p>---Singapore Newsroom (65-8703082)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
