<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3584" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Hong Kong legislator rejects China committee.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong legislator rejects China committee.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong legislative councillor Christine Loh on Tuesday joined others in the pro-democracy camp in the colony who say they won't participate in a China-backed committee to choose a provisional legislature and chief executive.</p>
<p>Referring to both the 1997 &quot;Selection Committee&quot; and the provisional legislature, Loh said: &quot;I don't want to sit on either body.&quot;</p>
<p>Loh, a prominent pro-democracy politician, was speaking to the Singapore Foreign Correspondents Association.</p>
<p>Loh was elected in Hong Kong as an independent rather than as a member of the Democratic Party, which has also said it will not participate in the selection committee.</p>
<p>China says that after it takes over Hong Kong at midnight on June 30, 1997 it will abolish the legislative council elected under British rule, replacing it with a provisional legislature ahead of an election expected later.</p>
<p>A Beijing-appointed Preparatory Committee will pick the 400 selection committee members. Critics question the committee's independence and object to the idea of a provisional legislature.</p>
<p>The selection committee is also supposed to choose a chief executive to replace Hong Kong's British governor.</p>
<p>But Loh said: &quot;It seems to me that they have already decided, that is, China has already decided who this person will be.&quot;</p>
<p>China has said the selection process for the chief executive could be advanced from December to November, which suggested a candidate had been identified, Loh said.</p>
<p>She said the Chinese have said recently the person should be acceptable to Britain, which she doubted they would say if they had not already picked someone falling into that category.</p>
<p>Shipping magnate C.H. Tung is considered China's most likely choice, Loh said.</p>
<p>Loh, who plans to run when China holds elections for a new Hong Kong legislature, said she will proceed with plans to start a political party of her own.</p>
<p>&quot;Political parties in Hong Kong right now are more like glorified pressure groups&quot; than parties serious about taking power with a well-thought-out programme, Loh said.</p>
<p>She said her party would not simply advocate democracy, but take stands on such issues as the environment, women's rights and social justice.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
