<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3586" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta shares close higher after moderate trade.</title>
<headline>Jakarta shares close higher after moderate trade.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta share prices closed marginally higher on Tuesday due to active buying in secondaries and selected heavyweights, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Jakarta composite index rose 2.53 points, or 0.47 percent, to 539.61 points. Losers led gainers by 49 to 44, with 42 counters unchanged.</p>
<p>Brokers said overall trading was moderate with local-led active buying on secondaries and foreign-buying on selected heavyweights.  </p>
<p>But they said broad market sentiment remained uncertain with many players waiting for the result of the U.S. Federal Reserve meeting on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Brokers also said many foreigners remain sidelined, taking a wait-and-see position before upcoming court hearing of ousted leader Megawati Sukarnoputri.</p>
<p>The court hearing was postponed to August 22. &quot;I don't think there will be more disturbances but still, the market prefers to wait for the results,&quot; one foreign broker said.</p>
<p>Property firm Duta Anggada topped the active list with 16.4 million shares traded, rising 350 rupiah to 2,325.  </p>
<p>Brokers said the rise was due to continued rumours of possible joint venture with foreign partner. &quot;It boosted market sentiment towards Duta Anggada,&quot; said one foreign broker.</p>
<p>A company official confirmed the news and said negotiations with Singapore-based property firm were in the final stages and the deal was likely to be finalised this week. He declined to give further details.</p>
<p>Brokers said the rise of Duta Anggada boosted market sentiment toward other property stocks.  </p>
<p>&quot;Active property stocks were also due to market talk saying some big banks will gradually lower their interest rates,&quot; one local broker said.</p>
<p>Shipping firm Berlian Laju Tanker was also actively traded during the day after a news report saying the firm would import some vessels. It rose 175 rupiah to 2,200 on a volume of 8.4 million shares.</p>
<p>Heavyweights Telkom rose 50 rupiah to 3,275 on a volume of 2.2 million shares.</p>
<p>--- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
