<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3587" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Chinese yuan seen rising slightly in short term.</title>
<headline>Chinese yuan seen rising slightly in short term.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chinese yuan is likely to continue to rise after repeatedly hitting closing year-highs over the past few weeks, but room for further gains will be limited, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A rising trade surplus and record level of foreign exchange reserves would help support the yuan but the central bank would prevent it going to high, they said.</p>
<p>The local currency closed lower on Tuesday for the first time since July 24, at 8.3065 against the U.S. dollar. It had repeatedly hit year-highs but was unable to overcome a closing rate of 8.3059 on August 15, 1995, its record high.</p>
<p>&quot;The first fall in a month means that the yuan has begun to meet resistance after continuous rises in the past month,&quot; said one trader on the Shanghai-based interbank foreign exchange market, the China Foreign Exchange Trade System.</p>
<p>&quot;But market fundamentals have not changed and factors boosting the renminbi are still there,&quot; he added. &quot;In the next month or so, the yuan will continue to rise and will meet strong resistance only at the 8.3000 level.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank intervened in the market today to slow the yuan's rising momentum,&quot; said a second trader. &quot;Pro-yuan sentiment has also weakened a little after successive gains.&quot;  </p>
<p>Traders said main factors supporting the local currency were China's improving trade figures and rising foreign exchange reserves.</p>
<p>China posted an unexpectedly high trade surplus of $1.13 billion in July, its second month of surplus after five successive months of deficits, giving it a January-July surplus of $2.1 billion.</p>
<p>Early this year, Beijing predicted a rough trade balance for 1996 after a hefty surplus of $16.7 billion last year. Now it is expecting a $3.0 billion surplus this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign exchange supply clearly exceeds demand,&quot; said a Shanghai-based banker with the Bank of China. &quot;This has been reflected in surging reserves.&quot;</p>
<p>Foreign exchange reserves surged to a record $86.6 billion at the end of June, up from $73.5 billion at end-1995.</p>
<p>Other factors include rising direct foreign investment in China, which hit $19.6 billion in the first half of this year, up a year-on-year 20 percent.</p>
<p>But the analysts said the recent rises had made the yuan approach its highest levels of last year, which would limit room for further gains.  </p>
<p>&quot;The yuan is now just below its highest point last year in August 1995,&quot; said a foreign exchange trader. &quot;Technical charts show it will not be able to go far away from the 8.3000 level. We believe it will hit that level around the end of September.&quot;</p>
<p>The analysts also believe the People's Bank of China will not allow the yuan to rise too sharply.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank has insisted that the renminbi should be stable instead of fluctuating sharply,&quot; said a banking analyst. &quot;It has intervened in the past to prevent it from rising too sharply and will do in the future.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said they expected the central bank would most likely intervene again at the 8.3000 level.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
