<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3591" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Timorese enter Japan's Jakarta embassy, then flee.</title>
<headline>Timorese enter Japan's Jakarta embassy, then flee.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two East Timor youths entered the Japanese embassy compound in Jakarta on Tuesday seeking political asylum but then fled, a Japanese diplomat said.</p>
<p>&quot;They jumped over the front fence. They said they wanted to see a doctor and go overseas, but as we were asking for more information they ran away, outside the compound,&quot; diplomat Akira Nagai said.</p>
<p>&quot;They looked young but we did not have time to ask them their age,&quot; he said. &quot;They ran themselves. We did not expel them.&quot;</p>
<p>Nagai said embassy guards had seen the two men outside the compound earlier with two companions.</p>
<p>In November, 21 East Timorese broke into the Japanese embassy compound and left a day later for asylum in Portugal.</p>
<p>Following the incident, the embassy added an extra layer of barbed wire to the metal fence.</p>
<p>Since September last year 84 East Timorese have left for Portugal after seeking asylum in foreign embassies in Jakarta.</p>
<p>Portugal is the former colonial ruler of East Timor, a small enclave north of Australia invaded by Indonesia in 1975 and unilaterally annexed the following year.</p>
<p>The United Nations does not recognise Indonesia's rule in East Timor and regards Lisbon as the administering power.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
