<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3593" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai B shares end up on bargain-hunting. [CORRECTED 10:55 GMT]</title>
<headline>Shanghai B shares end up on bargain-hunting. [CORRECTED 10:55 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai B shares ended up in slow trading on Tuesday on bargain-hunting, with investors focussing on interim results, brokers said.</p>
<p>The index ended up 0.053 points or 0.10 percent to 51.813 points, on volume of 8.4 million shares worth $3.4 million. Of 41 B shares, 29 traded, with 13 up, six flat and 10 down. (Corrects value of transactions and number of B shares)</p>
<p>Brokers said that short-term market sentiment was still cautious despite the rise, with most firms having not published their interim results. The deadline for publication is the end of August.  </p>
<p>&quot;The anxiety over interim results prevents investors from actively building positions,&quot; one broker said. &quot;But the index will rise after all the results are published.&quot;</p>
<p>Shanghai Erfangji was the star, rising $0.006 or 5.88 percent to $0.108, on volume of 124,000 shares.</p>
<p>Heilongjiang Electric Power traded the most on institutional buying, up $0.010 or 2.80 percent to $0.366, on volume of 1.6 million shares.</p>
<p>Shanghai A shares fell on poor results announced by most firms, brokers said.  </p>
<p>But further losses will be limited by improved fundamentals such as falling inflation and an expected cut in bank interest rates, brokers said.</p>
<p>The A share index closed down 14.167 points or 1.62 percent to 860.453 points, on volume of 250.1 million shares worth 2.1 billion yuan.</p>
<p>The SSE 30 index fell 52.196 points or 2.38 percent to 2139.740 points.</p>
<p>China Jialing Industry performed the worst after posting lower-than-expected interim results, plunging 1.68 yuan or 14.55 percent to 10.27 yuan, on volume of 3.5 million shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
