<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3595" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel sets condition for Hebron troop pullout.</title>
<headline>Israel sets condition for Hebron troop pullout.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel said on Tuesday it would not redeploy its troops in the West Bank city of Hebron until the Palestinian Authority closed its offices in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Under a peace accord with the PLO, Israel at the end of March was due to have redeployed its troops in Hebron, the last major Arab West Bank city still under Israeli control.</p>
<p>&quot;We are demanding that Jerusalem offices be closed,&quot; Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was quoted by an official as telling a closed-door session of Israel's Foreign Affairs and Defence Committee.</p>
<p>&quot;(Palestinian President Yasser) Arafat himself promised to close two other offices but did not close them. Until they are closed there will be no progress, including on the issue of Hebron,&quot; the official quoted Netanyahu as saying.</p>
<p>Arafat adviser Ahmed Tibi told Israel Television on Tuesday that the Palestinian Authority was not operating offices out of Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Israel delayed its redeployment from Hebron after a spate of Moslem suicide bombings killed 59 people in Israel in February and March. Netanyahu, elected in May, has said he was examining the issue.</p>
<p>Palestinians view an Israeli troop withdrawal from Hebron as a litmus test for the peace process. Israeli troops are to remain in part of the city to guard some 400 Jewish living among the more than 100,000 Palestinians.</p>
<p>Israel occupied Arab East Jerusalem in the 1967 Middle East war and later annexed it, declaring both halves of the city its eternal capital. Palestinians view East Jerusalem as the capital of a future state.</p>
<p>The city's fate is up for negotiation in final peace talks which have yet to resume under Netanyahu.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
