<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3605" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordanians in Karak warn of further unrest.</title>
<headline>Jordanians in Karak warn of further unrest.</headline>
<byline>Suleiman al-Khalidi</byline>
<dateline>KARAK, Jordan 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Angry Jordanians in the southern city of Karak, kept in check by troops and a curfew after two days of riots against higher bread prices last week, warned on Tuesday of further violence if King Hussein rejects dialogue.</p>
<p>Residents spoke of rising frustration with the king's declared &quot;iron-fist&quot; response to youths who targeted banks and state institutions in what they said was a spontaneous expression of rage over hardship in the poor south.</p>
<p>&quot;The reaction of the government is not to calm things down. People are waiting for the moment to react,&quot; Ahmad Mahadeen, elected mayor of the city, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Riots began in Karak and quickly spread to nearby centres. By Saturday night there were clashes in Amman. Peace has been ensured in Karak since Sunday by a curfew and the army.</p>
<p>It was the worst unrest in Jordan since 1989, when riots followed a government decision to raise fuel prices. Then the king dumped his prime minister and began reforms.</p>
<p>Many warned of fresh trouble on Friday -- a week after a protest following prayers turned into clashes with police, who used tear gas to disperse demonstrators.</p>
<p>&quot;The government entered in force and continues to employ force to impose its control...it might be calm now but there is a gradual build-up in tension,&quot; one resident said.</p>
<p>The explosion of anger against King Hussein's government comes against a backdrop of widespread poverty in Jordan, few jobs for the rapidly expanding population and a growing gap between rich and poor.</p>
<p>Residents say heavy-handed security methods -- widespread arrests, late-night raids on houses and allegations of torture of detainees -- are feeding resentment of the government.</p>
<p>Residents feel betrayed by King Hussein's response and the government's attitude to what they say are years of accumulated grievances stemming from neglect of the poverty of the south.</p>
<p>&quot;The lack of concern by officials over the plight of the south has led to a feeling there is a gap between us and the government,&quot; said Abdullah Sarayrah.</p>
<p>Residents say the feeling is more painful as it comes from those who considered themselves the bedrock of the government's support. Most of King Hussein's tribally based army comes from the south.</p>
<p>&quot;For the first time the people have united against the government of (Prime Minister) Kabariti and signs are emerging of a common attitude against the regime, which people feel has let them down,&quot; said Yousef Rawashdeh, another city resident.</p>
<p>Residents draw comparisons between the 1989 troubles and this week's unrest, saying the deep-seated rage that emerged showed the alienation among King Hussein's traditional loyalists.</p>
<p>The few casualties have so far kept a lid on wider tribal unrest, say residents. But said one youth: &quot;A new explosion will be much stronger than the first and only God knows the consequences.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARAK, Jordan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
