<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3608" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Hizbollah says it will run against government in poll.</title>
<headline>Hizbollah says it will run against government in poll.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hizbollah said on Tuesday it would run against the government in Lebanon's parliamentary elections after being let down by a prominent government ally in the first round of voting on Sunday.</p>
<p>Hizbollah's solitary candidate in the opening round in Mount Lebanon, parliamentary deputy Ali Ammar, failed to win re-election on Sunday after Druze leader Walid Jumblatt, broke his alliance with the pro-Iranian group on the eve of polling.</p>
<p>Sheikh Hassan Nasrallah, secretary-general of Hizbollah (Party of God), was quoted on Tuesday as saying in a statement that the fundamentalist Shi'ite Moslem group &quot;will not run on official lists (of candidates) in either the Bekaa valley, the south or Beirut&quot;.</p>
<p>The official lists are those of pro-government candidates.</p>
<p>The remaining four rounds of voting in north Lebanon, Beirut, south Lebanon and the Bekaa Valley will take place over the next four Sundays.</p>
<p>Under the electoral law, the deadline for candidates to register is 10 days before voting is due in their region.</p>
<p>Ammar was humiliated in Baabda district which includes Beirut's Shi'ite Moslem southern suburbs, a Hizbollah stronghold.</p>
<p>He ran on an anti-government list headed by Maronite Christian Pierre Daccache and expected to receive Christian votes as well as support from Druze voters traditionally allied with Hizbollah.</p>
<p>But Jumblatt, a close ally of Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri who dislikes Hizbollah, switched his support on the eve of the vote to moderate Shi'ite politician Nabih Berri, Hizbollah's main rival in the Shi'ite community.</p>
<p>Jumblatt also launched a blistering attack on Hizbollah's guerrilla war against Israel in south Lebanon, saying the country could not be held hostage and risk a massive Israeli attack because of the group's activities.</p>
<p>Jumblatt, Berri and Hariri are pillars of the pro-Syrian political establishment which currently holds almost complete power in Lebanon.</p>
<p>Hizbollah has failed to reach an election pact with Berri's Amal movement in south Lebanon and the Bekaa valley, where Shi'ites are strongest. The two Shi'ite groups ran jointly in the last election in 1992 in which Hizbollah won eight parliamentary seats and its allies won four more.</p>
<p>Newspapers have expressed concern that violence could erupt, particularly in south Lebanon, if Hizbollah and Amal fight it out at the polls in the present election.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
