<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3610" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Republicans tar Clinton for rising teen drug abuse.</title>
<headline>Republicans tar Clinton for rising teen drug abuse.</headline>
<byline>Vicki Allen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Drug use among teenagers more than doubled from 1992 to 1995, a federal study said on Tuesday, prompting Republican charges that the Clinton administration was to blame.</p>
<p>Much of the increase was due to big jumps in the percentage of 12- to 17-year-olds who said they had used marijuana in the past month. Drug experts call marijuana, the most commonly used illicit drug, a &quot;gateway&quot; to harder drugs such as cocaine.</p>
<p>In 1995, the rate of past month use of drugs by such teenagers rose to 10.9 percent, more than twice the 5.3 percent low point reached in 1992, the Health and Human Services Department's 1995 National Household Survey on Drug Abuse showed. The survey put the total number of 12- to 17-year-olds at 22.2 million.</p>
<p>In presenting the findings, Health Secretary Donna Shalala took pains to emphasise that youth attitudes toward marijuana began changing as early as 1990 during the administration of Republican President George Bush.</p>
<p>&quot;What we are seeing is ... a multi-year trend that began before we came to Washington, before this administration came to Washington, this trend began, but it continues today,&quot; she said at a joint outdoor news conference at a local Boys and Girls Club meant to dramatise the dangers of drugs to youth.</p>
<p>Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole, campaigning in Louisville, Kentucky, called the report's findings &quot;nothing short of a national tragedy&quot; and said he would make the war on drugs the &quot;priority No. 1 once again.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The statistics confirm an upward spiral of drug abuse across the nation since President Clinton took office,&quot; Sen. Orrin Hatch, a Utah Republican who chairs the Senate Judiciary Committee, said in a letter to the White House.</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry said Clinton has focused much attention on the drug problem and would continue to do so.</p>
<p>&quot;This is something the president talks about regularly and has identified as an area that he wants to work on personally,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>McCurry rejected Republican charges that Clinton's initial cuts in the office of drug policy had exacerbated the problem.</p>
<p>Although drug abuse began rising sharply in the early 1990s, it remains way down from the 16.3 percent peak reached in 1979 among adolescents. That year, which was the peak for illicit drug use, rates were 38 percent for those aged 18-25, 20.8 percent for ages 26-34 and 2.8 percent for 35 and over.</p>
<p>In contrast, in 1995, the percentage of adults reporting past month drug use were 14.2 percent for those 18-25; 8.3 percent for those 26-34; and 2.8 percent, the same as in 1979, for those age 35 and older, the survey showed.</p>
<p>McCurry said he believed the administration's plan to fight drugs was on the right track. &quot;We think it's the right strategy to control use, to control imports,&quot; he said. &quot;Above all, this has to be a bipartisan effort that all join into.&quot;</p>
<p>Jim Copple, president of the Community Anti-Drug Coalitions of America, said blame should be shared by Republicans and Democrats for cutting funds for drug control programmes and losing interest in the issue.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
