<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3611" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pageant organizers deny ultimatum to Miss Universe.</title>
<headline>Pageant organizers deny ultimatum to Miss Universe.</headline>
<byline>David Bennett</byline>
<dateline>LAS CRUCES, N.M. 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Organisers of the Miss Universe pageant on Tuesday denied they had ordered their reigning beauty queen, Venezuela's Alicia Machado, to shed pounds or else give up her title.</p>
<p>&quot;We are distressed about the recent reports that the Miss Universe organisation has put Alicia Machado on notice that she must lose weight in order to retain her title as Miss Universe,&quot; said Martin Brooks, president of Los Angeles-based Miss Universe Inc.</p>
<p>Brooks, in a statement released in the resort town of Las Cruces where Machado is attending the Miss Teen USA beauty pageant, said Miss Universe officials were &quot;extremely happy with Alicia and feel she fulfils her obligations ... exceptionally well.&quot;</p>
<p>In an unusual development, officials of the Miss Venezuela Organisation said on Monday in Caracas that Machado had been given an ultimatum by Miss Universe organisers to lose 27 pounds (12 kg) in two weeks or risk losing the title.</p>
<p>She was 5 feet 7 inches (1.73 meters) tall and weighed 112 pounds (51 kg) when she became the fourth Venezuelan to win the crown in Las Vegas in May.</p>
<p>But on Tuesday Venezuelan pageant officials backed away from their earlier comments, with one official telling Reuters: &quot;She obviously has a weight problem which affects her swimsuit contracts but this does not mean she will be stripped of her crown.&quot;</p>
<p>Brooks emphasised on Tuesday that &quot;a weight requirement is not part of our titleholder employment contract.&quot;</p>
<p>Machado was attending the 1996 Miss Teen USA Pageant in her official capacity as Miss Universe. Teen pageant officials said the 19-year-old Machado was there as the pageant's special guest, not to shed pounds.</p>
<p>Machado was scheduled to make a public appearance during the teen pageant, which was to be held on Wednesday night at New Mexico State University and broadcast nationwide by CBS television.</p>
<p>Asked if Machado was overweight, Wendy Schwartz, a Miss Universe publicist accompanying the beauty queen, said, &quot;I suggest people tune in to the show tomorrow night and they can decide for themselves.&quot;</p>
<p>Miss Teen USA officials said Machado would not talk to reporters before the pageant and it was unclear if she would have anything to say publicly when the event was over.</p>
<p>After she was awarded the title in May, Machado told reporters in Las Vegas she planned to do &quot;something I haven't been able to do in three weeks: eat, eat, eat and sleep.&quot;</p>
<p>Those close to the beauty queen said she has difficulty sticking to diets and a weakness for pastas and cakes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS CRUCES, N.M."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
