<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3622" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Margaux Hemingway's death ruled suicide - coroner.</title>
<headline>Margaux Hemingway's death ruled suicide - coroner.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Model and actress Margaux Hemingway, who was found dead last month, committed suicide by taking an overdose of the sedative phenobarbital, the Los Angeles County Coroner's Office announced on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Coroner's spokesman Scott Carrier told a news conference the 41-year-old granddaughter of literary great Ernest Hemingway died of &quot;acute phenobarbital intoxication&quot; and that the levels of the drug in her body were so high she must have taken it intentionally.</p>
<p>Carrier said Hemingway apparently did not have a doctor's prescription for phenobarbital and investigators were trying to determine where she obtained it in such large amounts. The announcement followed six weeks of toxicological tests after the initial autopsy failed to reveal the cause of death.</p>
<p>Hemingway's body was found by friends sprawled on her bed in her Santa Monica apartment on July 1, just one day short of the 35th anniversary of her famous grandfather's suicide. It was not clear exactly when she died as the friends went to the home after she had not been seen for two days.</p>
<p>Hemingway, who gained fame first as a supermodel for perfume, later worked as an actress in such films as &quot;Lipstick&quot; and &quot;Killer Fish.&quot; She had a well-publicised bout with alcoholism after a near-fatal skiing accident and also battled bulimia. In addition, she had a history of epilepsy.</p>
<p>Her agent, Graham Kaye, told KNBC television in Los Angeles, &quot;Whatever demons she was fighting is over now and it's just time to let her rest.&quot;</p>
<p>Hemingway's body was cremated and services were held in July in her hometown of Ketchum, Idaho.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
