<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3638" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Former Whitewater partner sentenced to prison.</title>
<headline>Former Whitewater partner sentenced to prison.</headline>
<byline>Kieran Murray</byline>
<dateline>LITTLE ROCK, Ark. 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Susan McDougal, a former business partner of President Bill Clinton, was sentenced on Tuesday to two years in prison for her fraud convictions in the Whitewater trial.</p>
<p>U.S. District Judge George Howard handed down three concurrent 24-month prison terms and an additional three years probation for her role in a fraudulent loan scheme tied to the failed Whitewater land deal.</p>
<p>&quot;The court is persuaded it will take Mrs. McDougal out of circulation for a reasonable period of time and afford her the opportunity to do some reflective thnking,&quot; Howard said.</p>
<p>McDougal, 41, was convicted in May on four charges relating to a fraudulent $300,000 business loan she was given in 1986. Prosecutors alleged Clinton pressured an Arkansas banker to give McDougal that loan, but the president denied under oath any involvement in the deal.</p>
<p>Defence attorneys portrayed McDougal as a naive young woman at the time of the offences and said she unthinkingly followed the instructions of her ex-husband James McDougal, an Arkansas businessman.</p>
<p>&quot;He was always my teacher and my mentor ... everything Jim had done always seemed right to me,&quot; Susan McDougal said in pleading for leniency. &quot;I am truly sorry.&quot;</p>
<p>Susan and James McDougal were business partners with the president and first lady Hillary Rodham Clinton in the failed Whitewater real estate venture which lies at the heart of an independent investigation into Clinton's personal and political finances.</p>
<p>Apart from the prison sentence, Susan McDougal also was ordered to pay restitution of $300,000 plus interest to the U.S. Small Business Adminstration, which had insured the illegal loan.</p>
<p>James McDougal, 56, was to have been sentenced on Monday but won a temporary reprieve because he was cooperating with the team of independent counsel Kenneth Starr. He faced up to 84 years in prison for his conviction on 18 charges of fraud and conspiracy.</p>
<p>Former Arkansas Gov. Jim Guy Tucker, who was not a partner in the Whitewater deal but was convicted along with the McDougals on fraud and conspiracy charges in May, was sentenced to four years probation and fines of more than $300,000 on Monday.</p>
<p>Tucker, who resigned his office in July, avoided jail time because of a life-threatening liver problem that physicians said had a 50 percent chance of killing him within two years if he did not get a liver transplant.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LITTLE ROCK, Ark."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
