<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3654" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gingrich says FBI might owe apology to Jewell.</title>
<headline>Gingrich says FBI might owe apology to Jewell.</headline>
<dateline>MARIETTA, Ga 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. House of Representatives Speaker Newt Gingrich said on Tuesday the FBI would owe Richard Jewell an apology if investigators failed to link him to the deadly July 27 bomb attack on the Olympic Games.</p>
<p>The Georgia Republican also criticized the news media for effectively indicting the security guard in the public eye and suggested stronger privacy rights to protect citizens from the press in future.</p>
<p>&quot;If it turns out he did not do it, I think they (the FBI) owe him an apology. And, frankly, I think they need to rethink how they handle some of these cases,&quot; Gingrich told reporters after holding a news conference on federal welfare reform.</p>
<p>FBI officials were not available to comment on the speaker's remarks.</p>
<p>Jewell, 33, spent three weeks as the only named suspect in the bombing, which left two people dead and more than 100 injured in downtown Atlanta at the end of the first week of the games.</p>
<p>He was not charged and steadfastly maintained his innocence. But his suburban Atlanta home, where he spent nearly all of his time, was under continuous watch by members of the news media and by federal investigators.</p>
<p>Hordes of television cameras, photographers and reporters waited outside Jewell's apartment for days after news broke of his role as a suspect until they were asked to leave by apartment managers.</p>
<p>&quot;The level of attention the news media put this guy under, if it turns out he's innocent, should lead everybody to rethink what the rules of the game ought to be. And maybe we ought to have a little better sense of restraint in these kinds of situations,&quot; the speaker said.</p>
<p>He suggested the incident could point to a need for stronger protective rights for citizens. &quot;You could, for example, much more strongly protect privacy rights and you could more strongly protect trespass rights,&quot; Gingrich said.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe the ground rules ought to be that when you're dealing with someone who has not been charged, maybe there ought to be a different standard than when you're dealing with someone who has been charged,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;You go and ask him. Does he have a hard time right now going out to dinner?&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARIETTA, Ga"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
