<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3657" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gingrich touts welfare reform but gets complaints.</title>
<headline>Gingrich touts welfare reform but gets complaints.</headline>
<byline>David Morgan</byline>
<dateline>MARIETTA, Ga 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>House Speaker Newt Gingrich used a community learning centre as a backdrop to voice support for welfare reform on Tuesday but found himself fielding complaints about the program's finances.</p>
<p>The Georgia Republican signed a letter urging President Clinton to approve sweeping welfare reform legislation that would end the 61-year-old federal guarantee of aid to the poor and delegate broad powers to states.</p>
<p>President Clinton announced earlier this month he intended to sign the legislation into law this week.</p>
<p>The learning centre, called Coach's Corner Project Light, was based in an old school building converted into a multipurpose community centre for a 56-year-old federal housing project in this largely affluent Atlanta suburb.</p>
<p>Programme founder Bobby Lankford, a former NFL coach, said the centre used computer-based teaching to tutor about 40 neighbourhood children in reading and basic language skills.</p>
<p>A $35,000 U.S. housing grant purchased the center's computers, tutorial software and computer training for a largely volunteer staff. But Lankford said its $60,000 annual operating budget consisted entirely of private donations from churches, civic groups, foundations and other sources.</p>
<p>Gingrich extolled the virtues of community-based learning as an alternative to federal assistance, but a staff member, administrative assistant Verona Martin, interrupted him to complain the center's director had not been paid and it had no budget.</p>
<p>&quot;We're talking about teaching the kids, that's what we're here for. We're talking about doing it for the community. I think we should first pay the director. She has not had a penny,&quot; said Verona Martin, who described herself as an administrative assistant at the centre.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't have a budget. We don't have stuff in here that the kids need,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't run the programme. I'm just here because I think it's a good concept,&quot; Gingrich responded.</p>
<p>Lankford denied the woman's allegations, saying the centre did not owe anyone anything. A Gingrich spokesman later described Martin as a friend of a former centre director who resigned in June.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARIETTA, Ga"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
