<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3658" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RTRS-Budget hits Queensland hard, says Borbidge.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Budget hits Queensland hard, says Borbidge.</headline>
<byline>Greg Truman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A number of major Queensland projects including the Brisbane-Gold Coast rail link are under threat as the state scrambles to overcome an unexpected lashing in the federal budget, Premier Rob Borbidge said.</p>
<p>Borbidge said his government would have to do some swift recalulations for the upcoming state budget to make up a &quot;A$250 million shortfall&quot;.</p>
<p>Speaking to Reuters in New York where he was meeting with business and banking officials, Borbidge said the states had been particularly hard hit by the first coalition budget in 14 years.</p>
<p>&quot;The budget is necessary to turn Australia around,&quot; he said. &quot;But there will be substantial reductions to Queensland over and above what was forecast at the premiers' conference in terms of the better cities programmes and other cutbacks to services such as pathology and dental care.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I'd say the federal cutbacks to Queensland from the Premiers' conference and the budget amount to a $250 million shortfall,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The premier said he would have liked to have seen funding promises for exiting projects honoured, such as the dollar for dollar federal-state agreement on the Brisbane-Gold Coast link.</p>
<p>He said the state government will have to find $40 million &quot;which won't be easy&quot; if the line is to reach Robina as scheduled by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>The premier will get to work on the budget when he returns to Brisbane later this week.</p>
<p>After meeting with a number of leading banks in New York on Tuesday he was preparing to fly to the U.S. west coast for discussions with leading film studio executives.</p>
<p>Borbidge is attempting to build on Queensland's reputation as an attractive and economical sound site for major motion pictures.</p>
<p>He has also promoted the Queensland information technology industry while in the United States and urged investment, particularly in the mining sector.</p>
<p>He also told a business lunch in New York on Monday that he was &quot;quietly confident&quot; that Native Title issues &quot;would be resolved either by the high court or legislative change&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
