<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3661" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ill. senator defends Nigeria trip; denies office rift.</title>
<headline>Ill. senator defends Nigeria trip; denies office rift.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Sen. Carol Moseley-Braun on Tuesday defended her recent trip to Nigeria against criticism from human rights groups, and denied that the affair had caused her chief of staff to resign.</p>
<p>The Illinois Democrat, the only black in the U.S. Senate, said her visit was &quot;a private trip and certainly no secret.&quot;</p>
<p>She told a news conference that U.S. policy toward Nigeria's army ruler, Gen. Sani Abacha, has not been fair or even-handed and it was her duty as a senator to maintain a dialogue with him.</p>
<p>She also said she had a personal friendship with Abacha's wife and had known her son, Ibrahim, who was blown up in an airplane six months ago.</p>
<p>The Chicago Sun-Times reported on Friday that Moseley-Braun's chief of staff, Edie Wilson -- the third person to hold that post since she was elected to the Senate nearly four years ago -- had resigned because she had not been told of the Nigeria trip.</p>
<p>&quot;My private staff was aware of my whereabouts,&quot; Moseley-Braun said, adding that the trip was a private vacation. She said Wilson had agreed to depart before the trip, and released a letter from her saying &quot;we mutually concluded that it would be best to go our separate ways.&quot;</p>
<p>Amnesty International issued a statement last week calling the trip inappropriate and branding Nigeria &quot;a major human rights violator.&quot; Randall Robinson, head of the African lobbying group TransAfrica, called her visit deeply troubling.</p>
<p>Nigeria's military rulers have been under international scrutiny for rights abuses since last November when nine minority rights activists were hanged for murder.</p>
<p>The West African state has been in turmoil since 1993 when it annulled a presidential vote to restore democracy. Since then, many people have been detained including the presumed winner of that plebiscite, Moshood Abiola, as well as pro-democracy activists and journalists.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
