<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3665" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Top U.S. executives tempted by thrills of start-ups.</title>
<headline>Top U.S. executives tempted by thrills of start-ups.</headline>
<byline>Nick Louth</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A number of top executives in the telecommunications industry are abandoning the comforts of giant corporations for the thrills of building a new company and the hope of becoming seriously wealthy in the process.</p>
<p>&quot;I think this is not for everybody,&quot; said Alex Mandl, who on Monday resigned as chief operating officer of AT&amp;T Corp. to become chairman of Associated Communications, a tiny new company in the crowded arena of wireless services.</p>
<p>&quot;It requires a willingness to step out of the comfort zone of big Corporate America,&quot; Mandl said in an interview.</p>
<p>New technology and a new era of competition are giving executives with key skills huge opportunities in new ventures, even as thousands of others are losing their jobs.</p>
<p>Small companies with good technology can now beat established giants thanks to opportunities from the auction of new wireless licenses and the convergence of communications, computers and entertainment.</p>
<p>Mandl is not the first. In January 1995 Jim Barksdale left AT&amp;T wireless, where he was chief executive, to become president and chief executive of the then-obscure Netscape Communications Corp..</p>
<p>Across the technology field, start-ups have claimed Silicon Graphics Inc.  President Thomas Jermoluk, Dataquest Inc. Chief Executive Judy Hamilton, Sybase Inc. Chief Operating Officer David Peterschmidt and many others.</p>
<p>George Schmitt was chief executive of PCS PrimeCo, a national wireless venture where he had billions to spend building an advanced communications network for a group of regional Bells. Yet in August last year he took a half-million dollar pay cut to join little-known Omnipoint Corp.</p>
<p>What the recruiters expect is clear -- a winning market strategy, a star to attract a top management team and the use of wide industry contracts to minimize chances of failure.</p>
<p>The companies the executives leave usually recover, but can often take some short-term damage to their stock as investors try to work out the motivation for departure.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T's stock fell $1.375 on Monday to $54.125 on news of Mandl's resignation. It added 12.5 cents Tuesday.</p>
<p>As well as the big names, hundreds of vice presidents and middle-ranking executives have left long-distance firms and regional Bells to work for new companies in the industry.</p>
<p>Many have tough decisions to make, trading in long hours and a comfortable if pedestrian salary progression for a crack at serious wealth -- but with hours only workaholics would enjoy.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the opportunity to shape something risky, but a lot more satisfying,&quot; said consultant Mark Bruneau of COBA-MID.</p>
<p>Of course not even the big companies are so safe anymore. Greater competition and rapidly evolving technology are erasing the comfort zone for all but a few.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T is cutting tens of thousands of jobs as part of its split into three parts, as are the regional Bells, who will soon be fighting head to head with AT&amp;T in many markets.</p>
<p>In Mandl's case, it was an offer too good to refuse.</p>
<p>A $20 million signing bonus in cash to join Associated removes any personal worries should the new company fail, and dwarfs his AT&amp;T salary of around $1.3 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the other opportunities are stock rich, not cash rich like this,&quot; said Bette Massick of brokers Bear Stearns.</p>
<p>Should Associated succeed wildly, then Mandl's share options, which convert to an 18 percent stake in the company, should provide still greater comfort.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, it could not have been an easy decision. Mandl, 52, was considered by analysts as heir apparent to AT&amp;T Chairman Robert Allen.</p>
<p>Mandl declined to speculate whether his decision would have been the same if Allen were to retire this year instead of in three or four years.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Allen) was always consistent that I was a good candidate to succeed him, but beyond that you have to earn your stripes,&quot; Mandl said.</p>
<p>Netscape's Barksdale is pure inspiration for risk takers.</p>
<p>&quot;Barksdale had a terrific job at AT&amp;T. He could have been a candidate for the top job,&quot; Mandl said.</p>
<p>But now even Robert Allen must dream about being as wealthy as Barksdale.</p>
<p>Netscape, a dominant force in the world of Web browsers for the Internet, was a roaring success after its initial public offering a year ago. Barksdale has sold 2.2 million Netscape shares, but his remaining six million shares are now worth a cool $222 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
