<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3666" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Some U.S. pilot fatigue rules may be dropped.</title>
<headline>Some U.S. pilot fatigue rules may be dropped.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The president of the Air Line Pilots Association said Tuesday he thought the Federal Aviation Administration would drop some of its planned new rules aimed at alleviating pilot fatigue.</p>
<p>ALPA had said previously the proposed rules were &quot;an unsatisfactory degradation of current regulations.&quot;</p>
<p>The FAA proposed the rules following recommendations by the National Transportation Safety Board after it determined fatigue had been a factor in two aircraft accidents.</p>
<p>But the FAA proposals drew strong opposition from the airline industry as well as the pilots.</p>
<p>They would set &quot;duty time&quot; limits for the first time for pilots -- time on standby added to time flying -- but increase the length of time pilots would be allowed to fly before being required to take time off.</p>
<p>ALPA president Randolph Babbitt said that while the union backed the setting of overall time limits, it could not accept the proposed increase in flight time to 10 hours from eight.</p>
<p>Babbitt also said in a briefing during a union safety forum that the new rules failed to take into account for the fatigue stemming from circadian disruptions.</p>
<p>Pilots are hit by these, he said, when their schedules extend around the &quot;back side of the clock -- the hours between midnight and 6 a.m. -- and through several time zones.</p>
<p>The U.S. Air Transport Association, the trade group of the major airlines, objected to the regulations, saying the FAA had no research showing they would improve safety and that the rules would cost the airlines hundreds of millions of dollars.</p>
<p>FAA spokesman Curtis Austin would not comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
