<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3669" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</title>
<headline>Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain and oilseed exports reported by USDA and private export sources.</p>
<p>SOYBEAN TENDER - Pakistan is seeking 30,000 to 34,000 tonnes U.S. no. 2 or better yellow soybeans under PL 480, Title I. Delivery is slated for October 15-30. Bids must be submitted by August 28 and remain valid until August 29.</p>
<p>BARLEY TENDER - Saudi Arabia is in the world market for a 800,000 tonnes of optional-origin feed barley and will hold a tender on August 21, European grain traders said. It seeks 250,000 tonnes for September 25 arrival and 550,000 tonnes for delivery on October 15, they said.  </p>
<p>BARLEY TENDER - Syria's General Establishment for Cereal Processing and Trade said it was offering 50,000 tonnes of black feed barley for sale. It said August 20 had been set as a final date to receive price offers. Confirmation would be made on August 21. The quantity from the 1994 crop would be ready for shipment between September 15 and October 15.</p>
<p>WHEAT TENDER -  World Food Programme officials said on Tuesday the Bangladesh government planned commercial imports of 100,000 tonnes of soft wheat for November shipment.</p>
<p>&quot;But the purchase may be delayed if the present high price of wheat in the international market continues,&quot; one said.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDER - The CCC is seeking up to 33,000 tonnes of U.S. No.2 soft white wheat for donation to Bangladesh for Sept 10-Oct 5 delivery. Offers are due on August 27.</p>
<p>- Sri Lanka will tender on August 30 for 100,000 tonnes of U.S., Canadian or Argentinian wheat. It includes 50,000 tonnes of soft wheat for September shipment and 50,000 tonnes of hard wheat for October shipment.</p>
<p>- Syria's General Establishment for Cereal Processing and Trade was offering 100,000 tonnes of hard amber durum wheat for sale. The date to receive offers was Sept 3.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDER - The CCC seeks up to 16,000 tonnes of U.S. No. 2 hard red winter or soft red winter or soft white wheat for donation to Tajikistan for Sept 15-Oct 10 shipment.</p>
<p>- Jordan will tender August 28 for 90,000 tonnes of U.S. HRW or spring wheat and 10,000 tonnes of soft white or SRW wheat for first and second half October shipment, No. 2 or better wheat with option for equivalent origins in two 50,000-tonne lots.</p>
<p>SOYMEAL TENDER - The CCC said it is seeking 1,650 tonnes U.S. soymeal, 48 percent protein, for donation to Guatemala for September 5-25 shipment. Offers were due August 20.  </p>
<p>CORN TENDER - The South African Maize Board said it was inviting offers for the export of 33,000 tonnes of yellow maize for shipment in September and October out of Durban. The export tender closes on August 22. The board said the offer consisted of two units of 16,500 tonnes of maize. The shipping period for the cargoes was September 29-October 9.</p>
<p>CORN AND WHEAT TENDER -  The Cyprus Grain Commission said it accepted a tender of Oriac Incorporated Cairo for 18,000 tonnes of corn at $182.48 per tonne. It had also accepted a tender of Finagrain S.A. Geneve, for 12,000 tonnes of European milling wheat at $190.69 per tonne, C and F out of Limassol.  </p>
<p>MARKET TALK - Egypt has delayed any purchases of U.S. soft red wheat for now after buying U.S. soft white wheat at the weekend, and is exploring European and Argentinian markets, its main commodities buyer said. Egypt bought 150,000 tonnes of U.S. soft white wheat at $187.70 and $187.75 on Saturday and Sunday after originally seeking 50,000 tonnes of soft red or soft white wheat. U.S. exporters said Egypt was avoiding American soft red wheat because its vomitoxin content exceeded two parts per million specified by the GASC and had paid a premium of up to $2.00 a tonne for fungus-free white wheat.</p>
<p>- Malaysia will probably buy small parcels of corn totalling over 100,000 tonnes over the next month while the rest of the grain and meal trade in the region remained quiet, traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>- China has missed a golden opportunity to export corn and earn millions of dollars, and now has up to a million tonnes of the grain rotting in silos in the country's north, Far East traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>- China is unlikely to need to buy rice on the international market to make up for flood damage to domestic crops, traders said. No China inquiries for rice were reported by traders in China, Hong Kong, Singapore and Thailand.</p>
<p>--Doris Frankel 312-983-7305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
