<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3671" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT, CME oppose CFTC rule on trading errors.</title>
<headline>CBOT, CME oppose CFTC rule on trading errors.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chicago Board of Trade and Chicago Mercantile Exchange said they were opposed to a Commodity Futures Trading Commission amended rule aimed at enhancing U.S. futures exchanges' audit trails and surveillance.</p>
<p>The CBOT and CME said in separate statements that they already have exchange rules designed to detect fabricated or altered trades.</p>
<p>The CFTC's amended rule specifies that a member of a contract market must correct an error on a trading record with no more than a single line.  </p>
<p>If the error is illegible or obliterated, a copy of the trading card must be submitted to contract market personnel.</p>
<p>&quot;We really think it is one of the highest forms of micromanagement,&quot; a CBOT spokesman said.</p>
<p>The rules also apply to all trading records, such as orders received on the floor through electronic order routing systems and &quot;flashed&quot; orders, not just trading cards, the CFTC official said.  </p>
<p>&quot;This is a perfect example of how a regulatory body whose function is oversight just can't resist delving into the minutiae and becoming the micromanager of those they regulate,&quot; said CME chairman Jack Sandner.</p>
<p>According to a CFTC official, the rule will take effect 60 days after publication in the Federal Register. The rule is expected to be published on either Tuesday or Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The commission believes that this amendment would further limit the opportunity for the fabrication or alteration of trading records,&quot; the CFTC said in its proposal published in the Federal Register on June 6, 1996.  </p>
<p>Last week, the CFTC said a recent re-testing of the CME and CBOT's audit trail systems failed to meet regulatory standards of 90 percent verifiability of times and sequence.</p>
<p>The CFTC said the two exchanges must demonstrate to the commission that they had achieved 90 percent verifiability by January 1, 1997.</p>
<p>Derivatives desk 312-408-8750;e-mail derivatives@reuter.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
