<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3675" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. says Marines in Haiti only for training.</title>
<headline>U.S. says Marines in Haiti only for training.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Marines are not being sent to Haiti because of new troubles there but opponents of Haiti's new government should take the American troop presence as a sign they are being watched, a U.S. official said Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that they should realise that not only the United States, but also the United Nations and other nations in the hemisphere are watching very closely what's going on,&quot; said Capt. Mike Doubleday, a Defence Department spokesman.</p>
<p>The department announced Monday that 50 U.S. Marines would go to Haiti this week for seven to 10 days of training for contingencies such as protecting the U.S. Embassy or other U.S. troops in Haiti.</p>
<p>The Marines were scheduled to leave Tuesday but their departure has now been delayed until Wednesday, Doubleday said. Soldiers from the Army's 82nd Airborne Division went to Haiti for similar training in July.</p>
<p>The defence spokesman said the Marines were not being sent to Haiti in response to troubles such an attack Monday by uniformed men on a Port-au-Prince police station that killed one man and injured several others.</p>
<p>&quot;We certainly don't go down there in any kind of a provocative way,&quot; Doubleday said.</p>
<p>&quot;But on the other hand, I don't think that there's any reason for the Marines or the 82nd Airborne or anybody else to be shy about the fact that they have a capability, they have a (training) mission, and they are down there to fulfil that mission,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
