<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3678" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Accused mobsters charged with racketeering.</title>
<headline>Accused mobsters charged with racketeering.</headline>
<dateline>NEWARK, N.J. 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A dozen alleged members of the Genovese organised crime family were accused Tuesday of racketeering and other crimes, including infiltrating health maintenance organisations and bilking patients with inflated fees, New Jersey officials said.</p>
<p>Among those charged were Steven Mazzola, chief executive officer of Hasbrouck Heights, New Jersey-based Tri-Con Associates, a broker that supervised the operation of HMOs and more than one million customers in five states, New Jersey Attorney General Peter Verniero said at a news conference.</p>
<p>Mazzola was identifed as an alleged associate of the Genovese crime family who allegedly helped them infiltrate the health care industry, Verniero said.</p>
<p>The Tri-Con-run HMOs would inflate their fees, and money would be paid in kickbacks to Mazzola and to other members of the crime family, Verniero said.</p>
<p>Control of the HMOs reached as high in the crime family as its reputed boss, Vincent &quot;Chin&quot; Gigante, authorities said.</p>
<p>&quot;This scheme bilked the public of untold dollars through inflated billing,&quot; Verniero said, who said it was the first time to his knowledge that organised crime infiltrated an HMO.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not tolerate members of organised crime in New Jersey, now or in the future,&quot; he said. &quot;We will arrest them, we will prosecute them, we will punish them.&quot;</p>
<p>The suspects also were accused of controlling a Teamsters' union local in Union City, N.J., and a Hotel, Restaurant and Bartenders Employees local in Secaucus, N.J., authorities said.</p>
<p>The investigation showed that the crime family exerted control of the unions through Michael Sciarra, a former president of the Teamsters' local, they said.</p>
<p>During the two-year investigation, undercover agents compiled hundreds of hours of tape recordings of the alleged crime family members that will be used in the prosecution, authorities said.</p>
<p>They also stand accused of gambling, loansharking and other crimes, Verniero said.</p>
<p>The HMOs themselves were not accused of any crimes, officials said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEWARK, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
