<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3679" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Army troops arrive in California to fight fires.</title>
<headline>Army troops arrive in California to fight fires.</headline>
<byline>Adam Entous</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of U.S. Army troops arrived in northern California on Tuesday to reinforce fire lines as fierce blazes continued to blacken huge areas of bone-dry trees and brush across the western United States.</p>
<p>Weary firefighters were battling 34 large blazes across nine states. Five new wildfires were reported in Arizona, Montana, Nevada and Utah. But cooler temperatures and more favourable winds helped firefighters in California and Oregon.</p>
<p>In Colorado, a fire raging in the Mesa Verde National Park exploded in size overnight to 4,000 acres (1,600 hectares). Mesa Verde, with its Anasazi cliff dwellings, is a major archaeological preserve.</p>
<p>The National Interagency Fire Centre reported that 34 large fires in the West were scorching 501,458 acres (202,900 hectares) with the most intense blazes in California and Oregon. Tuesday's fire count was down sharply from Sunday, when the fire centre reported a total of 46 large fires on 502,970 acres (203,500 hectares).</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, we seem to be getting a handle on things,&quot; said Renee Snyder, a spokeswoman for the fire centre in Boise, Idaho. &quot;But by the end of the week, we're expecting more fire starts as the lightning increases again in the West.&quot;</p>
<p>On Tuesday, more than 19,300 personnel were assigned to the fires, supported by 153 helicopters and 30 airtankers. Faced with a shortage of crews, authorities called for help from the Army, prison inmates and firefighters from the East.</p>
<p>In northern California, reinforcements arrived from Colorado to help battle the Fork fire, 100 miles (160 km) north of San Francisco. The 600-person task force was made up of U.S. Army soldiers based in Fort Carson, Colorado. The group received a crash course in fire fighting on Monday.</p>
<p>The Fork fire expanded by 7,000 acres (2,833 hectares) overnight to 77,000 acres (31,160 hectares) on Tuesday, fuelled by 70-year-old hardwood, pine and brush, said Theresa Klepl, a fire information officer.</p>
<p>The blaze, estimated thus far to have cost $8.1 million to fight, forced authorities on Sunday to order the evacuation of 400 homes in Spring, High and Long valleys.</p>
<p>But authorities on Tuesday reported significant progress battling the blaze. The fire was now 25 percent contained.</p>
<p>In San Luis Obispo County, midway between San Francisco and Los Angeles, a wildfire has consumed 69,500 acres (28,130 hectares), up from 69,000 acres (27,920 hectares) on Monday. But fire officials said they expected to contain the blaze by Tuesday evening.</p>
<p>In the southwest corner of Colorado, the Mesa Verde National Park fire blew up to 4,000 acres (1,600 hectares) overnight from 600 (240 hectares) on Monday, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;This (fire) is the top priority in the Rocky Mountain region,&quot; said U.S. Forest Service spokesman Bob Irvine.</p>
<p>The wind-whipped fire has engulfed pinion pines and juniper trees, but officials said none of the park's major structures have been lost to the blaze.</p>
<p>About 350 firefighters from Colorado, Wyoming, Montana and Arizona, including a crew from the Hopi Indian tribe, were sent to the scene. Officials hoped another 100 personnel would also be sent in, Irvine said.</p>
<p>Oregon authorities said they expected later on Tuesday to fully contain the largest of the active fires in the central part of the state.</p>
<p>&quot;Things are looking much better,&quot; said Terry Virgin, information officer with the Central Oregon Interagency Dispatch Centre. &quot;It's been a long siege.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
