<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3691" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Plains feedlot cattle trade up $2 at $68 - trade.</title>
<headline>Plains feedlot cattle trade up $2 at $68 - trade.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Plains feedlot cattle markets Tuesday were active, with brisk sales at $68.00, up $2.00 per cwt from a week ago, according to feedlot sources.</p>
<p>About 45,000 head traded in the Texas Panhandle/western Oklahoma areas and about 35,000 in Kansas. Final figures for the day were expected higher as paperwork gets processed.</p>
<p>The day started slowly, with light sales of lesser grade cattle at $67.00, but quickly accelerated as packers started buying aggressively at $68.00, the sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;They (packers) bought every head we offered at $68.00,&quot; one source at a fairly large feedlot in the Panhandle said.  </p>
<p>Gains were powered by smaller showlists this week of market-ready cattle just as packers were running short on live supplies purchased two weeks ago, feedlot sources said.</p>
<p>Higher boxed beef prices at midday also were tied to the active packer buying, with boxes quoted up $1.00 to $1.42, with choice heavyweight cuts up $1.42 at $104.10, according to USDA. There were 178 fabricated loads sold.</p>
<p>Last week's declines in boxed beef prices reportedly encouraged renewed retail interest, resulting in a possible shift from pork for advertising features after the Labor Day holiday, market sources said.</p>
<p>--Bob Janis 312-983-7347--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
