<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3694" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - unchanged amid repricings.</title>
<headline>U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - unchanged amid repricings.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. municipal bond prices ended Tuesday's session mostly unchanged, but trading levels were slightly higher than in recent days, market participants said.</p>
<p>As expected, the Federal Open Market Committee ended its meeting this afternoon leaving interest rates unchanged and market participants relieved.</p>
<p>A few bid-wanted lists circulated throughout the day, &quot;but it didn't add up to a lot of bonds,&quot; one trader said. He estimated the total at about $150 million.  </p>
<p>The retail sector was extremely quiet, as it has been for the past several sessions, typical for August, traders said.</p>
<p>The new issue market saw several deals repriced in the afternoon.</p>
<p>JP Morgan Securities Inc raised yields on several maturities of Austin, Texas's $249.5 million utility system revenue bond deal, but left the top yield in 2021 unchanged.  </p>
<p>PaineWebber Inc repriced Alaska Housing Finance Corp's $158.2 million mortgage revenue bond deal, cutting the top yield in 2017 to 6.05 percent from 6.10 percent. To see the</p>
<p>In another closely-watched offering, Fleet Securities said it received the verbal award on Utica, N.Y.'s $24.5 million private placement. The top yield was 8.25 percent in 2019.</p>
<p>A market source familiar with Utica's deal said state officials purchased a &quot;moderate amount&quot; of the $11.4 million note portion of the beleaguered city's offering.</p>
<p>On the competitive side, Trustmark National Bank won $60 million Mississippi taxable general obligation bonds, and reoffered the 2008 and 2014 maturities at 7.13 percent and 7.40 percent, respectively. The rest of the deal was not reoffered.</p>
<p>Wednesday's calendar features seven competitive offerings totalling $156 million and an expected $681 million negotiated pricings. Underwriters said another $393 million of deals might be priced, depending on market conditions.</p>
<p>The largest competitive offering Wednesday is a $120 million Connecticut deal at 1100 EDT. The largest on the negotiated side is a $140.6 million Jersey City, N.J., refunding, via Merrill Lynch &amp; Co.</p>
<p>In futures Tuesday, the September municipal contract ended at 115-9/32, up 5/32. The September T-bond contract was down 1/32 to 110-28/32, moving the MOB spread six ticks higher to 141 ticks.</p>
<p>In secondary action, bids on Cook County, Ill., FGIC 5-7/8s of 2022 were down 1/8 from Monday at 99-7/8. Yields on Florida Board of Education FGIC 5-1/2s of 2026 were two basis points lower at 5.73 percent. --Steven Dickson, 212-859-1652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
