<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3699" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soybeans close higher as crop concerns build.</title>
<headline>CBOT soybeans close higher as crop concerns build.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT soybean futures closed higher on mounting concerns about potential cuts in 1996 U.S. soybean production, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The crop is late and the crop is looking smaller plus there was a little squeeze on August,&quot; said Ron Kucha of O'Connor and Co.</p>
<p>Crop scouts on the Professional Farmers of America crop tour of the U.S. Midwest this week confirmed that the crop was well behind normal maturity paces in the eastern growing region. &quot;Bean yields (prospects) look disappointing on the first day of the tour,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>USDA Monday said the U.S. crop as of Sunday was 56 percent good to excellent, down from 58 in that category the previous week. Also, 63 percent of the crop was setting pods, behind the 69 pace a year ago and the 74 percent average pace.</p>
<p>Gains in soybean futures were limited by a shift in weather patterns in the U.S. Midwest.</p>
<p>Meteorologists said weather patterns now suggest warm weather will remain in the U.S. Midwest through next week, rather than be displaced by a cold system as indicated Monday.</p>
<p>Soybeans closed 1-1/2 to 9-1/4 cents per bushel higher, with August up 9-1/4 at $8.24 a bushel.</p>
<p>Nearby August soybeans were strong relative to other months on short covering and position squaring before expiration of that contract slated for 1201 Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It was primarily shorts getting out of the August before expiration,&quot; a trader said. &quot;Some commercials were rolling out of the August and there's been zero deliveries of beans and meal.&quot;</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at 43,000, down from 52,053 Monday.</p>
<p>In the soybean options pit Refco Inc bought 600 November $7.25 puts at 10 cents and bought 200 November $7.00 puts at 4-1/2 cents. In late dealings Tenco Inc sold 400 September $8.00 calls at 5-6-1/2 cents, traders said.</p>
<p>Soybean options volume was estimated at 22,000, down from 26,160 Monday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
