<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3706" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME live cattle end mixed, feeders tumble at close.</title>
<headline>CME live cattle end mixed, feeders tumble at close.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME live cattle futures slipped on profit taking after setting new contract highs in August and October and ended mixed while feeder cattle tumbled late with November down the 1.500 cent limit in the closing range.</p>
<p>Strong cash cattle markets sparked demand for live cattle futures early and August climbed to a new high of 69.750 cents per lb and October rose to 71.700 cents before slipping late. Futures closed 0.500 cent higher to 0.275 lower with October off 0.100 at 71.275 cents per lb.</p>
<p>Packers stepped up bids by $2 per cwt for fed cattle and cattle feeders responded by selling at the $68 level. But futures failed to rise further after setting new highs as the sharp premium of futures to cash encouraged profit taking.</p>
<p>&quot;Live cattle (futures) have got a decent premium built in and its just wait-and-see time if cash is going to continue to improve,&quot; said Doug Harper, Brock Associates Inc Senior Lievestock analyst.</p>
<p>Cash cattle prices will likely stay at current levels until after Friday's monthly USDA Cattle-on-Feed report, traders added. Early estimates on the report ranged from 84 to 88 percent of a year ago for total Aug 1 on-feed numbers in the seven major feedlot states.  </p>
<p>July placement estimates ranged 100 to 116 percent of a year ago and July marketings 100.5 to 106 percent.</p>
<p>ADM Investor Services, Lind-Waldock, LFG and Rosenthal Collins sold October late while Refco and RBH bought, pit sources said.</p>
<p>In live cattle options, selling of deep in the money calls in October early, was noted. Commercials did risk reversals in February, buying puts and selling calls, traders added.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle futures were weighed down by Monday's late rally in corn futures which offset the easier tone to corn futures Tuesday. However, futures showed most of their weakness in the last few minutes of trade as a fairly large sell order in November sparked a break into the close.</p>
<p>Selling by LFG in November touched off sell stops in that month and locals turned sellers in nearbys. The stops took November down the daily limit to 63.000 cents in its closing range while other months broke to new days lows, traders said.</p>
<p>Smith Barney, ADM Investor Services and R.J. O'Brien sold October early while ING and locals bought, traders said. Lind-Waldock bought November early and sold on the break.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle closed 0.350 to 1.250 cent lower with October off 0.650 at 63.175 cents, traders said.</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
