<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3714" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bond issues proposed for Lions stadium in Detroit.</title>
<headline>Bond issues proposed for Lions stadium in Detroit.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new, $225 million domed stadium for the Detroit Lions football team would be partially financed with bonds sold by Wayne County and Detroit, local government officials said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Under a financing agreement announced at a news conference, Wayne County would issue $80 million of revenue bonds backed by yet-to-be-approved, so-called tourist taxes, Detroit would issue $15 million of limited tax general obligation bonds and the Detroit Downtown Development Authority may issue an additional $30 million of bonds for the project.</p>
<p>The county would also raise $20 million for stadium land acquisition and infrastructure costs principally from the sale of surplus land.</p>
<p>The Lions, meanwhile, would contribute $50 million toward the stadium and would be responsible for raising an additional $50 million in corporate contributions.</p>
<p>The 65,000 to 75,000-seat domed stadium would be part of a sports complex in downtown Detroit that would also house a new ballpark for the Detroit Tigers baseball team.</p>
<p>&quot;This isn't about baseball or football,&quot; said Mike Duggan, deputy Wayne County executive. &quot;This is about a blow for the rebirth of the city.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier in the day, city, county and team officials announced that the Lions would leave their Pontiac Silverdome home and return to Detroit, the city the team left in 1975.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, Wayne County and Detroit would form a six-member stadium authority that would lease the football and baseball stadiums to the teams.</p>
<p>The teams, which would have to commit to 35-year leases, would keep ticket and most concession revenues from the facilities, but would be responsible for operating the stadiums. Each team would also be responsible for any cost overruns on their stadiums.</p>
<p>As for the bond issues, Wayne County plans to place a referendum on the Nov. 5 ballot asking voters to approve a 30-year, 1 percent hotel/motel tax and 2 percent rental car tax to raise the revenues needed to pay off the $80 million of bonds.</p>
<p>The Detroit City Council would have to approve the city's $15 million bond issue. Detroit, through its downtown development authority, raised $40 million earlier this year through a tax increment financing bond issue for infrastructure costs related to the new ballpark.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the new city-county stadium authority has a Nov. 1 deadline under the agreement to assemble definate land purchase prices for the sports complex. If the deadline is not met, the teams can pull out of the deal.</p>
<p>The Lions team also has a Nov. 1 deadline for raising the $50 million of corporate contributions or the governments would pull the plug.</p>
<p>No state of Michigan money would be involved in the football stadium, according to officials. Gov. John Engler has already committed $55 million of Native American gaming revenues funnelled through the Michigan Strategic Fund for infrastructure-related costs for the ballpark.</p>
<p>The constitutionality of that contribution, which had been contested by a group trying to preserve the present Tigers Stadium, was upheld earlier this month by the Michigan Supreme Court.</p>
<p>Tigers management has yet to disclose how they will raise $145 million for the ballpark itself.</p>
<p>An opening date of April 1998 has been targeted for the new Tigers' stadium, but no completion date was mentioned by officials for the football stadium.</p>
<p>Lions officials have said they would honor their lease, which runs through 2004, for the Silverdome.</p>
<p>--Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97911">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
