<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3724" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pace heats up in U.S.-Cuba diplomatic war.</title>
<headline>Pace heats up in U.S.-Cuba diplomatic war.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Worsnip</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>An exchange of diplomatic expulsions between Havana and Washington is worsening the tussle between the two sworn foes over U.S. attempts to strangle the Cuban economy with new sanctions.</p>
<p>The State Department disclosed on Monday that Cuba last week cancelled the visa of an official at the U.S. interests section in Havana, Robin Meyer. In response, the department ordered out a Cuban diplomat in Washington, Jose Luis Ponce.</p>
<p>Meyer, known to have been particularly active in her contacts with opponents of Cuba's one-party communist system, was an obvious target for the wrath of the Havana authorities.</p>
<p>U.S. officials played down a direct link with the sanctions issue and there were suggestions that the Cuban authorities had delayed expelling Meyer until her visa came up for its annual renewal.</p>
<p>One official called it &quot;another example of the Cubans' intolerance of anything or anyone that questions their government's viewpoint on things.&quot; The official expected no more tit-for-tat expulsions by either side.</p>
<p>But Ponce, the expelled Cuban, singled out this year's anti-Cuban U.S. legislation, known as the Helms-Burton Act after its sponsors in Congress, as the key factor in the latest bout of tension between the two countries.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the approval of the Helms-Burton Act has been the most important element in the deterioration of the relations between Cuba and the United States,&quot; he said in an interview with Reuters Television.</p>
<p>Passed in March, the act attempts to isolate Cuba -- portrayed in Washington as the last authoritarian regime in the Western hemisphere -- by threatening sanctions against some foreign companies that do business there.</p>
<p>The U.S. effort, which resulted in executives of a leading Mexican firm being told this week that they would be banned from the United States, has exacerbated the long-running war of words between Washington and Havana.</p>
<p>Cuba, for instance, issued a testy note last Sunday complaining that the United States had so far repatriated only 16 of 27 illegal Cuban emigrants who were intercepted off Florida last week. It called this a &quot;flagrant violation&quot; of migration agreements between the two countries.</p>
<p>The declared aim of the United States is to bring democracy and a free market to Cuba, but a debate -- heavily influenced by domestic U.S. politics -- has long raged within the administration over the best way to achieve that goal.</p>
<p>Should the government of President Fidel Castro be crushed into the ground by tightening still further the 35-year-old sanctions against the island, as many Cuban-American activists and their supporters argue?</p>
<p>Or would it be more effectively undermined by encouraging more interchange between Cuba and the capitalist outside world, an approach some say worked with formerly communist Eastern Europe but that critics say has failed with Cuba?</p>
<p>In an attempt to get the best of both worlds, the Clinton administration has pursued a twin-track policy of tightening sanctions but promoting individual contacts by easing telephone traffic with Cuba.</p>
<p>Clinton actually opposed Helms-Burton until Havana forced him to change his stand by shooting down two light aircraft flown by Cuban exiles off the coast of Cuba last February, creating an outcry in the United States.</p>
<p>The administration is clearly anxious to minimise the impact of the law on U.S. allies in Europe, Canada and Mexico, who have protested bitterly that its overseas reach amounts to an attempt to push them around.</p>
<p>So far just two companies -- Canada's Sherritt International Corp. and Mexico's Grupo Domos -- have been sanctioned for investing in property confiscated by the Cuban government. Their executives have been banned from U.S. soil.</p>
<p>U.S. officials say between six and 10 other companies have quietly told Washington they are pulling out of confiscated property. But Cuban Vice President Carlos Lage this week laughed off the act's effectiveness, saying &quot;it will either have to be withdrawn or halted or people will get around it&quot;.</p>
<p>Clinton has, in fact, suspended for six months a key provision of the act allowing original owners of the property to sue foreign companies. And last week he appointed Under Secretary of Commerce Stuart Eizenstat, a former ambassador to the European Union, to placate angry allies and persuade them to agree on a joint strategy to promote democracy in Cuba.</p>
<p>The pay-off, U.S. officials say, would be a further suspension of the controversial provision on lawsuits, which may never come into effect.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
