<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3735" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME nearby hogs and pork bellies close limit down.</title>
<headline>CME nearby hogs and pork bellies close limit down.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>August and October CME hog futures and August pork belly futures all finished down their respective daily trading limits on pressure from increased hog runs and slaughter and lower cash pork and hog prices that touched off sell stops, traders said.</p>
<p>August and October hogs ended down the 1.500 cent per lb limit with August at 60.025 cents and October at 53.550. Other hog contracts closed mostly down 1.400 to 0.250 cent.</p>
<p>Declining cash prices on larger hog runs pressured hog futures from the start and sell stops were touched off around 54.000 cents in October and December.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that we are seeing a few more hogs show up has people worried about the supply side but more improtant than this, gives the packers a little more freedom to improve their margins,&quot; said Doug Harper, Brock Associates Inc senior livestock analyst.</p>
<p>Harper noted that packer buying interest will decline despite the large kill capacity the industry has because negative profit margins are starting to take a toll. Packers have been losing money the past two quarters and &quot;they are starting to feel pressure from stockholders. They have to lower their procurement costs.&quot;  </p>
<p>Traders cited indications for another $0.50 to $1.00 per cwt loss in cash hogs Wednesday which added to weakness and knocked hog futures into technical sell stops. Futures went limit down shortly after penetrating moving averages and falling below 54.000 in October and December, traders said.</p>
<p>August pork bellies settled down the limit at 91.375 cents per lb and other months ended 1.250 to 0.400 lower.</p>
<p>Bellies also declined on concern over the rate of hog slaughter, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Hog slaughter has continued to weigh on bellies,&quot; said John Fisher, partner in Skylane Trading and belly trader.</p>
<p>USDA estimated Tuesday's hog slaughter at 348,000 head, above 343,000 a week ago and 347,000 a year ago. The figure brings the week-to-date total to 668,000 head, up from 650,000 in the comparable period last week but below 673,000 last year.</p>
<p>After the close, the CME reported a net out-movement of 1.559 million lbs of frozen bellies from warehouses outside Chicago last week. The figure was under analysts' estimates of 2.0 million to 2.5 million lbs out.</p>
<p>In hog options, ADM Investor Services was again bidding for December 54 and 56 straddles.</p>
<p>There was buying of calls and puts in October, December, and February at lower futures prices, pit sources added.</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
