<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3739" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYCE cotton ends up on technicals, fear of storm.</title>
<headline>NYCE cotton ends up on technicals, fear of storm.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYCE cotton futures closed firmer on local buying and interest by one major U.S. merchant, which buoyed prices on the close, market sources said.</p>
<p>They attributed today's move to mostly technically inspired buying following four consecutive days of losses. &quot;We retraced 62.5 percent from last week's runup,&quot; said Sharon Johnson, an analyst with Frank Schneider and Co Inc.</p>
<p>While Tropical Storm Dolly was nearing Mexico's Yucatan Peninsula and could dump heavy rain on U.S. cotton-growing regions, the storm was not likely to harm crops. Nonetheless, the sudden news of the storms may have prompted some of today's buying, sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;At this point, the rains would probably be more beneficial but the specs may not know that,&quot; Johnson said.</p>
<p>Support in December was pegged between 72.50 and 72.25, while resistance was seen between 74.00 and 74.50.</p>
<p>The December contract closed up 0.89 at 73.40, having ranged from 73.45 to 72.60. October ended up 0.88 at 73.00, while the back months finished 0.93 to 0.18 firmer.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at 5,500 lots.</p>
<p>-- Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities 212-859-1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
