<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3740" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Minimum wage increase is 18th in last half-century.</title>
<headline>Minimum wage increase is 18th in last half-century.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The increase in the minimum wage signed into law by President Bill Clinton on Tuesday is the 18th since the minimum standard was introduced more than half a century ago at just 25 cents an hour.</p>
<p>President Franklin Roosevelt signed the Fair Labor Standards Act on Oct. 24, 1938, establishing a minimum wage of a quarter per hour and a maximum work week of 44 hours, and banning child labor.</p>
<p>Adjusted for inflation, the equivalent hourly wage today would come to approximately $2.75.</p>
<p>At the time, 25 cents could buy three 12 oz. boxes of cornflakes. A 10-pound sack of flour cost almost 40 cents.</p>
<p>The first minimum wage law excluded large sections of the labor force including farm workers and domestic help.</p>
<p>Later changes broadened the scope of the wage requirement to include retail and service industries.</p>
<p>The minimum wage was last raised in 1991 to $4.25 after a 10-year deadlock on the issue between Congress and the Reagan and Bush administrations.</p>
<p>According to Labor Department statistics, 10 million people earn an hourly wage of between $4.25, the current minimum wage, and $5.15, to which it will rise in September next year, when the two-stage increase signed by Clinton is completed.</p>
<p>Most of them work as harvesters, janitors and child care providers and in the retail and food service industries. Four in 10 minimum wage earners are the sole bread winners of their families, the department said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
