<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3742" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton-approved wage bill include bond provisions.</title>
<headline>Clinton-approved wage bill include bond provisions.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton signed a minimum wage bill that includes provisions of interest to the municipal bond market.</p>
<p>The U.S. tax code includes a little-known provision that permits issuance of small industrial development bonds for first-time farmers.</p>
<p>The Small Business Job Protection Act signed by Clinton today expands eligibility for such bonds by doubling the amount of farmland an individual can own and still be viewed as a first-time farmer. Also, bond proceeds can be used to finance farm purchases by individuals in the same family.  </p>
<p>Another current tax code provision lets investor-owned utilities issue tax-exempt bonds as long as the facilities operate in an area no larger than two continguous counties.</p>
<p>Previously, if a utility wanted to expand beyond two counties, all its outstanding tax-exempt bonds would become taxable.</p>
<p>The new law lets investor-owned utilities that currently qualify for the two-county issuing statute to expand beyond two counties. All outstanding bonds remain tax exempt until the first call date. But utilities cannot issue tax exempt bonds in the future, according to the new legislation.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're pleased with what's in the bill, but we're also pleased with what's not in it,&quot; John Vogt, senior vice president for the Public Securities Association (PSA) said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>He was referring to the fact that today's bill does not include Clinton's controversial proposal to repeal the two percent &quot;de minimis&quot; rule on corporate holdings of tax exempts.</p>
<p>PSA and other bond groups have warned that the de minimis provision would hamper municipalities' access to the tax-exempt bond market and drive up borrowing costs.  </p>
<p>But Vogt said the municipal bond industry's battle over de-minimis is far from over.</p>
<p>&quot;All indications from the Administration have been that they will repropose those tax increases in their next budget,&quot; Vogt said.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
