<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3748" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee ends higher after late bounce.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee ends higher after late bounce.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee prices ended higher Tuesday after a late-session bout of fund buying drove the market through key resistance levels, trading sources said.</p>
<p>After a very sluggish start to the day, the market perked up ahead of the close when light speculative buying pushed most-active December through nearby resistance at 114.50. Buy stops were activated at that level, attracting steady bidding on the part of commodity funds.</p>
<p>December settled at 115.05 cents per lb Tuesday, up 1.75 on the day and just above the widely-watched 115-mark. Dealers said the break through resistance could inspire some additional chart-driven buying at Wednesday's open.</p>
<p>Traders for the most part shrugged off the latest round of certified stocks data, released after the close of business on Monday. The report, which revealed a 6,259-bag drawdown in Exchange-deliverable coffee, came in largely as expected, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market didn't really react to the report,&quot; said one trader. &quot;The only people who care about the stocks are those who have September positions.&quot;  </p>
<p>He added that as long as September's open interest continued to decline in orderly fashion, a last-minute panic rally on September was less likely.</p>
<p>More important, they said, was the report of 19,000 bags of coffee reported as pending Exchange certification.</p>
<p>While the large pending tally had also been talked about ahead of time, dealers said it initially pressured the nearby switch. But the September-December spread widened back out to just above unchanged, however, aided by views that at least some of the 19,000 bags would not meet with Exchange approval.</p>
<p>Several traders also pointed out that even if the 19,000 bags were graded, September's 4,133 lots of open interest still dwarfed the 230 lots (34,516 bags) contained in the overall certified cache.</p>
<p>-- Wendy Pollack, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
