<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3749" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USDA buys 3.56 mln lbs frozen beef for schools.</title>
<headline>USDA buys 3.56 mln lbs frozen beef for schools.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Agricultural Marketing Service of the U.S. Department of Agriculture said it bought 3,560,400 lbs of frozen beef for distribution in the National School Lunch Program and other Federal programs.</p>
<p>&quot;To date, we've purchased approximately 45 million lbs of beef products at a cost of about $41 million since May 1 when we announced our accelerated beef purchase initiative,&quot; USDA Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman said.</p>
<p>&quot;These purchases, as well as other actions, represent the Clinton Administration's commitment to combating record-low prices for cattle producers,&quot; Glickman said.  </p>
<p>Glickman said other actions include offering nearly $40 million to help drought-stricken producers in the Southwest feed their livestock and expanded price discovery initiatives to assist all cattle producers in their marketing decisions.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, AMS bought 3,402,000 lbs of frozen beef for reprocessing at a cost of $.9624-$.9940 per lb and 158,400 lbs of beef in 1-lb chubs at a cost of $1.4015-1.4448 per lb.</p>
<p>Shipments of the reprocessing beef will take place between September 30 and October 25, 1996, the AMS said. Shipments for the beef packed in 1-lb chubs are to be delivered between October 28 and November 22, 1996.  </p>
<p>Prices paid and total purchases since this program was announced on May 17, 1996, follow:</p>
<p>					   Cumulative</p>
<p>Commodity		    Pounds (Lbs)   Dollars</p>
<p>Fine Ground		  20,750,400     19,189,000</p>
<p>Reprocessing Beef	  17,010,000     15,319,000</p>
<p>1-Pound Chubs		   633,600	  863,000</p>
<p>VPP Patties		   3,168,000	2,818,000</p>
<p>100% Patties		  1,544,400	1,600,000</p>
<p>Lean Patties		  1,425,600	1,582,000</p>
<p>Cooked VPP Patties	     39,600	   62,000</p>
<p>TOTAL PURCHASES	    44,571,600     41,433,000</p>
<p>Winning bidders for the fine frozen coarse ground beef for reprocessing included Aksarben Foods Inc (Omaha NE) 2,478,000 lbs, Fresno Meat Co (Fresno CA) 126,000 lbs, H&amp;H Meat Products (Mercedes TX) 168,000 lbs, and Supreme Beef Processors Inc (Dallas TX) 630,000 lbs.</p>
<p>Winning bidder for the fine ground beef in 1-lb chubs was Supreme Beef Processors (Dallas TX) 158,400 lbs.</p>
<p>(Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8720)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
