<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3771" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE world sugar ends up but remains within range.</title>
<headline>CSCE world sugar ends up but remains within range.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE world sugar futures settled slightly higher on fund buying after a dull and lightly-traded session, floor sources said.</p>
<p>The market set its 17-point range in morning trade and then drifted quietly for the remainder of the day. After opening a bit firmer, the October contract fell to its low of 11.70 on the reopen. Fund buying then carried the contract to its high of 11.87, and a dearth of selling interest helped prices hold within that range until the close.</p>
<p>October settled 0.09 cent a lb firmer at 11.81, having ranged from 11.87 to 11.70. Second-position March finished up 0.05 at 11.47, while the deferred contracts closed 0.06 to 0.02 higher.</p>
<p>Strong resistance was maintained between 11.92 and 11.94, over which fund buying is likely to emerge and carry the contract over the 12.00-cent hurdle.</p>
<p>Support was pegged at 11.53, basis October. Traders cited stops over 11.90 in October.</p>
<p>LCE white sugar futures closed higher, with October gaining $1.50 on the day to end at $353.30. December settled up 70 cents to $346.50.</p>
<p>-- Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities, 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
