<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3774" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. soybean progress behind average in key states.</title>
<headline>U.S. soybean progress behind average in key states.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cool, dry weather last week hampered soybean growth in key U.S. growing states and pushed crop ratings lower, state agricultural statistics services reported.</p>
<p>In Illinois, the leading soybean-producing state last year, 90 percent of the crop had bloomed as of Sunday, compared with the five-year average of 95 percent. Fifty-six percent of the crop had set pods, well behind the 82 percent average.</p>
<p>&quot;The northern districts continue to need warm weather to promote crop development,&quot; the Illinois crop report said.  </p>
<p>A lack of rain stressed Illinois soybeans in the week ended Sunday, causing the crop's rating to fall to 32 percent good to excellent, down from 40 percent the week earlier.</p>
<p>Iowa soybeans were progressing at a normal pace, with 85 percent setting pods, near the 86 percent average.</p>
<p>Iowa crop conditions were almost unchanged, with 69 percent rated good to excellent, versus 68 percent the week before.</p>
<p>Cool, dry weather stalled crop progress in Minnesota, where 70 percent of the soybean crop had set pods, against the average of 82.</p>
<p>&quot;Across the state, rain and growing degree days are needed for row crop development and hay growth,&quot; the Minnesota report said.</p>
<p>Fifty-six percent of Minnesota's crop was rated good to excellent, down from 58 the previous week.</p>
<p>While scattered showers last weekend were expected to aid soybean development in Indiana, the crop there was about 15 days behind the average pace. The crop was 42 percent podded, versus the average of 84.</p>
<p>Indiana crop conditions declined to 35 percent good to excellent, down from 43 percent the previous week.</p>
<p>--Alby Gallun 312 983 7294</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
