<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3780" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Support for Detroit bonds targeted in Lions move.</title>
<headline>Support for Detroit bonds targeted in Lions move.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>-The head of Oakland County, Mich., took aim Tuesday at county support for bonds issued for Detroit's convention center in the wake of the Detroit Lions football team's decision to eventually leave the Pontiac Silverdome for a new home in Detroit.</p>
<p>In a statement, Oakland County Executive L. Brooks Patterson said it was hypocritical for his county to send $4.5 million in hotel/motel taxes each year to help pay off $167 million of bonds issued for Detroit's Cobo Hall convention center.</p>
<p>&quot;Then Detroit turns around and uses the dollars we contribute to build a pool of cash that allows them to raid Oakland County business,&quot; Patterson said.</p>
<p>Rumblings last year of a possible Lions move to Detroit led Patterson to push for Michigan legislation allowing his county and others to yank revenues from the Cobo Hall bonds, according to Robert Dustman, Patterson's spokesman.</p>
<p>That bill was still being drafted earlier this summer, according to an aide to assistant Senate majority leader Michael Bouchard, R-Birmingham.</p>
<p>The bill would allow Oakland, Macomb and Wayne counties to keep revenues from their lodging taxes and apply them to their own tourism or economic development initiatives. The state would also be prohibited from diverting the fund to pay off the $167 million of revenue bonds Detroit sold in 1985 and refinanced in 1993 to expand Cobo Hall.</p>
<p>Revenues from a state-wide liquor tax would still be available to pay off the bonds under the proposed bill. Detroit officials have said the liquor tax generated enough revenues to cover debt service on the bonds, which were rated single-A by Standard &amp; Poor's Corp.</p>
<p>Dustman said that in light of the Lion's decision to build a new stadium in Detroit, he expected Patterson would encourage Bouchard to introduce the bill.</p>
<p>Bouchard was not available to comment Tuesday on whether he would introduce a bill this fall.</p>
<p>In his statement, Patterson also raised the specter that the team's decision to relocate to Detroit spelled the end of the Silverdome.</p>
<p>&quot;It now appears that at some point in the future the city of Pontiac will be saddled with a $50 million stadium that is paid for with taxpayer dollars and is destined to be levelled by the wrecking ball,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Patterson also said that the Lions and Pontiac were only $25 million to $30 million apart on negotiations on the team's lease for the Silverdome, which ends in 2004.</p>
<p>The Lions and Detroit and Wayne County officials announced Tuesday morning a plan to build a 65,000-seat domed stadium in downtown Detroit next to a new ballpark planned for the Detroit Tigers baseball team.</p>
<p>Pontiac officials were not available to comment on the news.</p>
<p>Earlier this month Pontiac's general obligation bond rating was upgraded by Standard &amp; Poor's to BBB from BB-plus. The possible move by the Lions out of the Silverdome, however, was not seen as a potential credit problem by the agency.</p>
<p>About $23 million of revenue bonds issued through a stadium authority are outstanding for the Silverdome, with most of the bonds -- $13.5 million -- maturing in 2004 and the remainder in 2006, according to Pontiac officials.</p>
<p>--Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97412">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97911">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
