<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3799" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Margaux Hemingway death said to be suicide.</title>
<headline>Margaux Hemingway death said to be suicide.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>An autopsy on model and actress Margaux Hemingway found that the granddaughter of novelist Ernest Hemingway committed suicide by taking an overdose of a sedative, it was reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>KNBC television, Los Angeles flagship of the NBC network, said the coroner's office had determined that Hemingway, 41, whose body was found on July 1 in her Santa Monica apartment, had died of acute phenobarbital intoxication.</p>
<p>She had a history of epilepsy but according to KNBC she did not have a prescription for the drug and investigators are trying to find out where she got enough of it to kill herself. A coroner's investigator declined to comment on the report.</p>
<p>The actress, whose films included &quot;Lipstick,&quot; &quot;Killer Fish,&quot; &quot;They Call Me Bruce?&quot; &quot;Over the Brooklyn Bridge,&quot; and &quot;Inner Sanctum,&quot; had a well-publicised bout with alcoholism after a near-fatal skiing accident and also battled bulimia.</p>
<p>Her agent, Graham Kaye, told KNBC, &quot;Whatever demons she was fighting is over now and ... it's just time to let her rest.&quot;</p>
<p>Hemingway's body was cremated and services were held in July in her hometown of Ketchum, Idaho.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
