<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3820" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Corn progress slow, conditions slip in key states.</title>
<headline>Corn progress slow, conditions slip in key states.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Development of the U.S. corn crop in some key states remained behind normal last week, and crop conditions in the eastern Corn Belt deteriorated due to a lack of rain, state agricultural statistics services reported.</p>
<p>&quot;Most reporters felt that corn and beans are about a week behind normal and could use some warmer weather to help speed up growth,&quot; the Iowa Agricultural Statistics Services said.</p>
<p>In Iowa, the leading U.S. corn-producing state in 1995, 14 percent of the crop had reached the dough stage as of Sunday, behind the five-year average of 38.  </p>
<p>The condition of Iowa corn declined slightly, with 75 percent of the crop rated good to excellent, down from 77 percent a week earlier.</p>
<p>Cool, dry weather also hindered development in Illinois, where 41 percent of the crop had reached the dough stage, versus the average of 74 percent.</p>
<p>The Illinois crop was rated 47 percent good to excellent, down from fifty-two percent in that category the week earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;Crops were under stress from lack of moisture last week but weekend rains provided much-needed relief,&quot; the Illinois crop report said.  </p>
<p>Nebraska was the only major corn-producing state where crop development was about at average pace. Fifty-eight percent of the crop had reached the dough stage as of Sunday, compared with the average of 57. Nine percent of the crop had reached the dent stage, versus the average of 18.</p>
<p>Nebraska corn was rated 83 percent good to excellent -- little changed from the prior week.</p>
<p>In Indiana, however, persistent dry weather caused a decline in corn ratings, with the crop rated 42 percent good to excellent versus 52 percent a week earlier.</p>
<p>Indiana topsoil moisture was rated 60 percent short to very short and subsoil moisture was 47 percent short to very short.</p>
<p>Corn in dough stage was 13 days behind schedule at 38 percent doughing versus the average of 75.</p>
<p>Ohio corn also was far behind the normal pace, with 12 percent of the crop in the dough stage, compared with the average of 70.</p>
<p>But Ohio crop conditions improved, with 45 percent rated good to excellent versus 39 the week earlier.</p>
<p>--Alby Gallun 312 983 7294</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
