<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3825" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Immigrant fast divides French ruling coalition.</title>
<headline>Immigrant fast divides French ruling coalition.</headline>
<byline>John Follain</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>One of 10 Africans taking part in a a 47-day hunger strike against French expulsion orders was taken to hospital on Tuesday as the marathon fast opened political rifts in France's ruling coalition.</p>
<p>Moussa Keita, a Malian man among the hunger strikers who are backed by 300 protesters occupying a Paris church, was driven away in an ambulance on Tuesday night, severely drained by his fast and complaining of pains in his stomach.</p>
<p>Keita, 29, was carried out of the church on a stretcher, wrapped in a metallic survival blanket. Two of the other nine hunger strikers were also in serious condition.</p>
<p>Earlier, Prime Minister Alain Juppe cut short a holiday in southern France and returned to the capital as the stand-off took an increasingly political turn, with senior politicians urging an apparently inflexible government to compromise.</p>
<p>Juppe met Gilles de Robien of the centre-right UDF, junior coalition partner, who broke with the official line by meeting representatives of the protesters and suggesting negotiations with the government and deputies of all parties.</p>
<p>&quot;These people want a dialogue which has been interrupted. They want a moratorium (on the expulsion orders) while talks take place,&quot; de Robien, UDF floor leader at the National Assembly, told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm going to pass on messages to the government. It's up to the government to listen or not,&quot; he added, insisting that his initiative was a personal one and not a mediation attempt.</p>
<p>He later said in a statement he had relayed his remarks to Juppe.</p>
<p>The protesters, who include 110 children, are in Saint-Bernard church surrounded by hundreds of sympathisers committed to preventing police from seizing them. The hunger strikers have been drinking sugared tea and eating vitamins.</p>
<p>Abubakar Diop, the immigrants' spokesman, said he hoped a solution would soon be found. &quot;Each side wants to come out of this with dignity. We have to start talking again,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The government, with an eye on voters of the far-right and anti-immigrant National Front, stood firm.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre, who has repeatedly rejected a compromise, advised &quot;cry-babies&quot; to read French laws.</p>
<p>De Robien's party was itself divided, with Urban Affairs Minister Jean-Claude Gaudin warning against any compromise.</p>
<p>Left-wing party leaders, trade unions and human rights groups kept up the pressure with a petition urging President Jacques Chirac, who is on holiday on the Riviera, to intervene and launch talks to avert &quot;the risk of a human tragedy&quot;.</p>
<p>The 22 signatories included Socialist Lionel Jospin, Communist Robert Hue, Louis Viannet, head of the pro-Communist CGT union, and Fode Sylla of the SOS Racism association.</p>
<p>At the Saint-Bernard church in the heavily immigrant Goutte d'Or neighbourhood, hundreds of supporters formed a human barricade around the clock to prevent a possible police raid.</p>
<p>The protest by mostly Malian immigrants has made newspaper headlines but does not appear to have rallied widespread support. A new march was planned in Paris on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Lawyers say the immigrants' status is a legal tangle ranging from some who are entitled to stay, to others who can be expelled outright, and yet others whose situation has become unclear following controversial 1993 laws to curb immigration.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
