<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3826" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German intelligence faces blushes over Libya deal.</title>
<headline>German intelligence faces blushes over Libya deal.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Liffey</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's BND intelligence service, under pressure from recent foul-ups, faced the prospect of fresh embarrassment after conceding it had been in contact with a man wanted for smuggling chemical weapons-making equipment to Libya.</p>
<p>The BND on Tuesday dismissed allegations by Stern magazine that the suspect, Lebanese-born Berge Balanian, had been a BND informer for four years.</p>
<p>But, in a statement, it said it had interviewed Balanian at length in connection with Libya's weapons programme in 1992, at a time when the smuggling operation was in full swing.</p>
<p>On Monday, German authorities announced they had arrested two German businessmen on suspicion of passing the high-tech equipment to Tripoli between 1990 and 1993.</p>
<p>They believe Balanian, a German citizen, arranged the deal and used firms he owned in Belgium to export the goods. They now are hunting him under an international arrest warrant.</p>
<p>The BND said in a statement that it had known since 1990 about Libya's intention to build a chemical weapons plant, and about the activities of a firm in Belgium, SIM, which Balanian joined no later than 1992.</p>
<p>BND agents questioned Balanian on nine occasions, beginning in September 1992.</p>
<p>But the agency, which is still fighting accusations that it lured smugglers into bringing highly radioactive plutonium to Germany from Moscow on a passenger airliner in 1994, failed to stop Libya getting its equipment.</p>
<p>&quot;(Balanian) merely reported in general terms about the situation in Libya; he gave no information about his own business in or with Libya,&quot; the BND said.</p>
<p>In an advance release from Thursday's edition, Stern had quoted Balanian as saying he had agreed his actions with the BND for four years, and that the BND must therefore have known about the smuggling operation.</p>
<p>&quot;For years I have been sticking my neck out, now they want to dump on me,&quot; it quoted him saying in an interview several weeks ago. Stern said Balanian was now probably in Libya.</p>
<p>The latest question-mark over the BND's effectiveness comes shortly after a scandal in which BND staff were investigated for embezzling over one million marks ($700,000) intended to buy the services of Russian officers leaving former East Germany.</p>
<p>The men were also believed to have sold information on the Russian military to a British secret agent, and the affair led eventually to the resignation of BND head Konrad Porzner.</p>
<p>News of the illegal exports is also worrying for the Bonn, government, which clamped down on the arms trade after German firms in the 1980s equipped a plant at Rabta in Libya suspected of making chemical weapons. Prosecutors believe Balanian also tried to supply equipment for Rabta.</p>
<p>The factory burned down in a mysterious fire in 1990. But earlier this year U.S. officials accused Libya of trying to build a new chemical weapons plant, this time underground, at Tarhuna, 65 km (40 miles) southeast of Tripoli.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LIBYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
