<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3828" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgians hopeful missing girls still alive.</title>
<headline>Belgians hopeful missing girls still alive.</headline>
<dateline>NEUFCHATEAU, Belgium 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian judicial authorities said on Tuesday that they were still hopeful that two teenage girls missing in the country's largest child sex scandal would be found alive.</p>
<p>&quot;There are elements that allow us to believe that the two girls are still alive,&quot; public prosecutor, magistrate Michel Bourlet told a news conference in this southern town.</p>
<p>He said police were still searching for teenagers An Marchal and Eefje Lambrecks kidnapped by convicted child rapist Marc Dutroux in the port of Ostend last August.</p>
<p>Bourlet called the meeting to quash a groundswell of rumours surrounding the abduction case after 14-year-old Laetitia Delhez and 12-year-old Sabine Dardenne were rescued from a makeshift dungeon in a house owned by Dutroux.</p>
<p>Events turned tragic when, after Friday's discovery of the teenagers, Dutroux led police on Saturday to the bodies of eight-year-olds Julie Lejeune and Melissa Russo buried in another house owned by Dutroux near Charleroi.</p>
<p>Prosecutor Bourlet declined to give any details on the grounds for his optimism. &quot;I will not give any details of the dossier,&quot; he said, adding that if there was something to report he would first tell the parents of the two missing girls.</p>
<p>&quot;We are focusing on trying to find An and Eefje. We are still hopeful,&quot; Bourlet told a packed conference room.</p>
<p>Dutroux, serving four months in jail for theft at the time, denied responsibility for the deaths of Julie and Melissa, kidnapped in June 1995, of starvation.</p>
<p>But he admitted paying two accomplices 40,000 francs ($1,300) for the girls.</p>
<p>The whereabouts of An and Eefje are unknown. Belgian media speculated the two had been found in the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>However, Bourlet firmly squashed that rumour.</p>
<p>Interpol in the Czech Republic -- one of a number of countries contacted on Tuesday -- said there was no trace of the girls on Czech soil.</p>
<p>Asked whether Belgium had been in touch with authorities in Great Britain, The Netherlands and Slovakia as well as in the Czech Republic, he said, &quot;We have contacts galore...we have contacts with Interpol, but also with others.&quot;</p>
<p>Bourlet said Belgian Justice Minister Stefaan De Clerck, who visited the prosecutor's office earlier in Tuesday, had agreed to rent special equipment used in Britain for property searches.</p>
<p>He was referring to devices used in the investigation into Britain's &quot;House of Horrors&quot; serial killings in which a dozen young women were murdered.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday the Central Bureau of Investigation of the Police asked John Bennett, the officer who dealt with the West investigation, for advice in their search for further possible victims of an organised paedophile ring.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEUFCHATEAU, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
