<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3829" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German intelligence had contact with Libya suspect.</title>
<headline>German intelligence had contact with Libya suspect.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Liffey</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's BND foreign intelligence service said on Tuesday it had been in touch since 1992 with a businessman wanted on suspicion of helping to smuggle hi-tech chemical-weapons manufacturing equipment to Libya.</p>
<p>German prosecutors suspect that Lebanese-born Berge Balanian arranged a deal between Libya and two German businessmen arrested this month for supplying the equipment to Tripoli between 1990 and 1993.</p>
<p>They are alleged to have used firms in Belgium which Balanian owned and Germany is now hunting Balanian, a German citizen, under an international arrest warrant.</p>
<p>The BND, already under pressure after a number of high-profile blunders, denied a report from the weekly magazine Stern that Balanian had acted as a BND informer for four years.</p>
<p>But it said in a statement that it had known since 1990 about Libya's intention to build a chemical weapons plant, and about the activities of a firm in Belgium, SIM, which Balanian joined no later than 1992.</p>
<p>BND agents questioned Balanian on nine occasions beginning in September 1992, but nonetheless failed to prevent the last of the deliveries to Libya, which prosecutors say ended in 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;He merely reported in general terms about the situation in Libya; he gave no information about his own business in or with Libya,&quot; the BND said.</p>
<p>In an advance release from Thursday's edition, Stern had quoted Balanian as saying he had agreed his actions with the BND for four years, and that the BND must therefore have known about the smuggling operation.</p>
<p>&quot;For years I have been sticking my neck out, now they want to dump on me,&quot; it quoted him saying in an interview several weeks ago. Stern said Balanian was now probably in Libya.</p>
<p>German prosecutors announced on Monday that they had arrested two men on suspicion of providing Libya with hi-tech mixing equipment programmed to manufacture the deadly gases sarin, soman and lost.</p>
<p>The news was embarrassing for Bonn, which clamped down on arms exports after German firms in the 1980s equipped a plant at Rabta in Libya suspected of making chemical weapons. Prosecutors believe Balanian also tried to supply equipment for Rabta.</p>
<p>The factory burned down in a mysterious fire in 1990. But earlier this year U.S. officials accused Libya of trying to build a new chemical weapons plant, this time underground, at Tarhuna, 65 km (40 miles) southeast of Tripoli.</p>
<p>The BND is itself trying to re-establish its reputation after becoming involved in a number of botched operations.</p>
<p>In the most high-profile case, it has had to fight allegations that it lured smugglers into bringing 363 grams (12.8 ounces) of highly radioactive weapons-grade plutonium to Germany from Moscow on a passenger airliner in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LIBYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
