<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3832" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: DNA tests clear UK schoolboys in French murder.</title>
<headline>DNA tests clear UK schoolboys in French murder.</headline>
<dateline>RENNES, France 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Genetic tests on five British schoolboys showed none of them raped classmate Caroline Dickinson, who was sexually assaulted and killed on a trip to France last month, French investigators said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A group of French police investigators, struggling for leads after freeing a Frenchman they said recanted a confession to Dickinson's murder, would continue questioning in Britain even though all DNA tests on teachers and classmates were negative.</p>
<p>The five boys were the only males staying at the youth hostel where 13-year-old Dickinson was raped and killed on July 18 who had not been given DNA tests in France because their parents' consent was needed.</p>
<p>The five final tests, carried out in Britain, were sent to France for analysis. The tests leave police with the theory that an intruder broke into the youth hostel during the night.</p>
<p>Dickinson was found dead in her bed by female classmates who shared a room with her the night she died in the village of Pleine-Fougeres in Brittany, north-west France. None of them noticed the killer.</p>
<p>Five French police arrived in Britain last week to quiz Dickinson's teachers and schoolmates who were in a 40-strong group from Launceston Community College in Cornwall visiting France.</p>
<p>Homeless Frenchman Patrice Pade, arrested soon after the crime, was released after DNA genetic tests showed he could not have committed the rape. French police said he recanted a confession to the murder.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RENNES, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
