<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3833" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Extra police join Belgian international child hunt.</title>
<headline>Extra police join Belgian international child hunt.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police drafted in more investigators on Wednesday as an international hunt widened for two teenage girls abducted a year ago by convicted child rapist Marc Dutroux in Belgium's deadly child-sex scandal.</p>
<p>Public Prosecutor Michel Bourlet said up to 30 extra investigators would join a team seeking An Marchal and Eefje Lambrecks, seized by captors in Ostend last August.</p>
<p>Dutroux has admitted kidnapping Marchal and Lambrecks. Their subsequent fate is a mystery.</p>
<p>&quot;There are elements that allow us to believe that the two girls are still alive,&quot; Bourlet told a news conference late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The investigations went international on Tuesday as Belgium grappled with shock revelations of deaths, abductions and imprisonment of children by paedophile kidnappers. Police opened communications with a number of countries in their efforts to find the two missing girls.</p>
<p>The media spotlight has been on the Czech Republic, Germany, the Netherlands and France. Dutch police reopened a number of dormant dossiers on missing children on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are at the moment establishing contact with police in other countries via the services of Interpol,&quot; Major Jean-Marie Boudin, spokesman for the Belgian Gendarmerie's special missing children squad, told Reuters.</p>
<p>At least 15 children have disappeared in Belgium in the past six years. Seven have now been found dead, six are still missing and only two have so far been rescued.</p>
<p>The nation was stunned at the weekend as Dutroux led police to the bodies of eight-year-olds Julie Lejeune and Melissa Russo. He admitted paying two accomplices 40,000 francs ($1,300) when they were abducted in June 1995.</p>
<p>The two were starved to death early this year.</p>
<p>Dutroux was formally charged on Friday with abduction and illegal imprisonment of children after police raided a house he owned in Charleroi and rescued 14-year-old Laetitia Delhez and 12-year-old Sabine Dardenne from a makeshift concrete dungeon.</p>
<p>Both girls had been sexually abused.</p>
<p>Michel Lelievre was charged with the same offence. Michelle Martin, Dutroux' second wife, has been charged as an accomplice, and Jean-Michel Nihoul with criminal association.</p>
<p>Dutroux denied responsibility for the deaths on the grounds that at the time he was serving four months in jail for theft.</p>
<p>But he did admit killing accomplice Bernard Weinstein for letting the girls die.</p>
<p>The two girls will be buried in a private ceremony on Thursday followed by a televised public memorial service in Liege at which police expect up to 100,000 people.</p>
<p>As the two friends lay side by side in white coffins on Tuesday, each bearing a brass plaque inscribed simply &quot;Julie&quot; and &quot;Melissa&quot;, weeping people filed past at the rate of 500 an hour from early till late as Belgium poured out its grief.</p>
<p>Against stern warnings from the prosecutor involved and his own mother, Dutroux was released 10 years early in 1992 from a 13-year sentence for multiple rape and child abuse.</p>
<p>Police searching a house in a Charleroi suburb occupied by Lelievre found narrow, trench-like cells dug in the cellar floor with evidence of occupation by children.</p>
<p>Child rights lawyer Michele Hirsch told Reuters the Belgian case was symptomatic of a global sickness.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether you talk about paedophilia, prostitution, pornography or the traffic in human organs, people are increasingly being treated as a primary resource,&quot; she said. &quot;It is a a global problem.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
