<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3837" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Police find new cells in Belgian child sex scandal.</title>
<headline>Police find new cells in Belgian child sex scandal.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police investigating Belgium's child sex scandal have discovered more cells in the basement of another house connected with Marc Dutroux who has been charged with abduction and illegal imprisonment of children.</p>
<p>During a search of the house in the Charleroi suburb of Marchienne-au-Pont, police found the cells with evidence that they had been occupied by children.</p>
<p>The house had been occupied by Michel Lelievre, an associate of Dutroux who faces the same charges.</p>
<p>Belgian television showed pictures on Tuesday of deep, narrow trenches cut into the cellar floor. The television said police believed Dutroux had kept kidnapped children in the trenches before passing them on for sex.</p>
<p>Dutroux was charged on Friday after police rescued 14-year-old Laetitia Delhez and 12-year-old Sabine Dardenne from a makeshift dungeon in another of his houses in Charleroi.</p>
<p>The convicted child rapist then led police to the bodies of eight-year-olds Julie Lejeune and Melissa Russo in the garden of another of Dutroux' houses at Sars-La-Buissiere near Charleroi.</p>
<p>The two girls were kidnapped in June 1995. They starved to death in February or March this year.</p>
<p>Dutroux has also admitted abducting teenagers An Marchal and Eefje Lambrecks in August last year.</p>
<p>Their whereabouts are unknown, but Belgian police contacted a number of other countries on Tuesday through Interpol in search of clues.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
