<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3838" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian judicial move said sought against Bossi.</title>
<headline>Italian judicial move said sought against Bossi.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian magistrates have asked parliament to decide if they can pursue judicial action against Umberto Bossi, firebrand leader of the separatist Northern League, political sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Magistrates in the cities of Bergamo and Tolmezzo have sought a green light from parliament before they continue probes that could lead to a trial on charges of making threatening comments against political adversaries.</p>
<p>The magistrates want a parliamentary commission to decide if comments Bossi made at rallies were punishable or whether he has special protection as a member of parliament under an article of Italy's constitution.</p>
<p>The magistrates have investigated Bossi in connection with accusations of inciting people to commit crimes and making defamatory and threatening remarks during political rallies last year.</p>
<p>In both cases he threatened that League members would seek out and punish those who voted for the far-right National Alliance.</p>
<p>A parliamentary committee is due to rule by the end of next month if Bossi's remarks constitute a crime for which he could be tried or whether he enjoys special immunity as an MP, the sources said.</p>
<p>Bossi's supporters attacked the moves.</p>
<p>&quot;These initiatives smack of pure fascism because they try to limit freedom of expression and thought,&quot; said Roberto Maroni, a former interior minister and leading member of the League.</p>
<p>They suggested there was a political agenda against the hot-tempered Bossi, whose League has set up a self-styled &quot;parliament of the north&quot; and wants independence from the rest of Italy.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Bossi accused the secret services of plotting to discredit his movement and called for supporters to destroy television relay stations owned by national broadcaster RAI as a step towards forming an independent northern state.</p>
<p>The League, standing on a federalist ticket, showed strongly in last April's general election and won more than 30 percent of the vote in parts of the country as Bossi took advantage of widespread discontent over high taxation.</p>
<p>But since the vote, he has turned his back on federalism and now is pressing for full-blown secession for the wealthy north from the poorer south.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
