<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3843" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Juppe cuts short holiday to return to Paris.</title>
<headline>Juppe cuts short holiday to return to Paris.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Prime Minister Alain Juppe cut short his summer holiday on Tuesday to return to Paris where his government faces problems including a widening political wrangle over a hunger strike by African immigrants.</p>
<p>Juppe, who is due to visit President Jacques Chirac at his holiday retreat in Bregancon on the French Riviera at the weekend to outline strategy, returned from the Landes district of southwestern France, officials said.</p>
<p>The conservative premier had been expected to return to Paris later this week but had left his official schedule vague, they said.</p>
<p>Juppe has already intervened twice during his holidays -- once on August 14 to help prop up the franc and again on August 17 to try to head off threats of labour unrest in the autumn.</p>
<p>His most pressing concerns include a 47-day hunger strike by 10 of about 300 African protesters at a Paris church.</p>
<p>The protest has divided the centre-right coalition, with some senior politicians on Tuesday urging the government to lift expulsion orders hanging over some of them.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
