<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3846" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Higher protein content seen for French wheat.</title>
<headline>Higher protein content seen for French wheat.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>French milling wheat is heading for a high protein content this year, with the national average reaching at least 12.2 percent against 11.2 percent last year, crop analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Initial results suggest a gain of at least one percent over last year,&quot; an analyst at France's technical grain institute ITCF told Reuters.</p>
<p>If this is confirmed, protein content would exceed the average for the last 20 years of 12 percent, which is also the level meeting the criteria set by French millers for bread-making wheat.</p>
<p>Protein content is especially strong this year because of extra nitrogen concentration in plants caused by the dry weather.</p>
<p>Crop experts said the only unknown was the possible negative impact on protein content of thunderstorms forecast in the Nord-Pas de Calais region where the harvest is still in progress.</p>
<p>Hagberg values, which are also important for milling, were judged &quot;satisfactory&quot; with the exception of France's number two &quot;Sideral&quot; variety at 200-210.</p>
<p>Germination problems linked to high temperatures, but also in some cases to sporadic showers, hurt the Sideral variety in the Northeast, the Loire and Bourgogne regions.</p>
<p>Millers prefer Hagberg values of 200 to 250 but have set a absolute acceptable minimum of 120.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5432</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
