<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3850" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian bonds pin hopes on Buba meeting.</title>
<headline>Belgian bonds pin hopes on Buba meeting.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian bonds trod water on Tuesday with dealers seeing little news to move the market until Thursday when the Bundesbank is expected to lower its 3.20 percent repo rate slightly after its regular council meeting.</p>
<p>But even that might turn out to be a non-event since the move, likely to be followed by the Belgian National Bank, is heavily discounted. Some say it is expected to the extent that when it happens profit-taking might force prices down.</p>
<p>Today's German M3 data which came out on the soft side left the hopes of a repo cut intact. Dealers said today's Federal Reserve Open Market Committee meeting would likely be ignored.  </p>
<p>With traders split on whether to switch to flattening trades or continue with curve steepening purchases at the short end on hopes of further gains, the market was practically stuck.</p>
<p>&quot;The trend remains pro-steepening...there is no appetite to buy 15- or 20-year paper,&quot; said one trader. Talk of a new 10-year benchmark bond in September would add to price pressure at the longer end, he added.</p>
<p>Most of the early action took place in the two- to three-year area, attention later shifted to the four- to seven-years which saw some selling pressure.  </p>
<p>But another trader said the market was overdiscounting the Bundesbank action on Thursday, limiting the upside. He recommended flattening trades.</p>
<p>For the longer term the yield trend was down, dealers said, pointing to a return of cash to the market. &quot;The consensus is that the market (prices) will go higher,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>But he added he would not buy at current levels. &quot;We have seen a nice rally of about half a point.&quot; He linked buying levels to the September German Bund future, which at 1625 GMT was down 0.07 at 98.01, failing to take out resistance at 98.25. The Bund future and the Belgian OLO contract are closely linked.  </p>
<p>The trader said he would buy again once the Bund future slipped below 97.90, noting a break above 98.25 meant the contract could gain another 30 to 40 basis points.</p>
<p>The Belgian contract was unchanged at 116.46.</p>
<p>The yield on the current benchmark, the 2006 OLO, firmed by a basis point to 6.58 percent.</p>
<p>The Belgian market's small outperformance versus Bunds in the afternoon reversed an early widening of the yield spread to 35 basis points, leaving the differential steady at Monday's closing levels of 33. -- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6816, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
