<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3854" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital market closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital market closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The PIBOR three-month interest rate future contract settled higher on Tuesday in dull summer holiday trade, helped by a stronger tone to the franc and expectations of German monetary easing following M3 data earlier in the day.</p>
<p>Ten-year bond futures also advanced in slim volume.</p>
<p>But analysts said with international events such as the FOMC meeting whose outcome is due later on Tuesday and Thursday's Bundesbank council meeting dominating, investors were mainly sitting on the sidelines.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is somewhat paralysed,&quot; said one analyst.  </p>
<p>The M3 data released showing a slowdown in monetary growth &quot;was in the right direction,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>But analysts were worried it had been reduced by one-off factors, such as reduced government borrowing needs, and said it did not give a clear picture of the money supply situation.</p>
<p>They said Wednesday's Ifo business climate index should offer further guidance on the outlook for German rates.</p>
<p>&quot;If it comes in a bit weak, there is a goodly chance the Bundesbank will cut rates,&quot; said one analyst. &quot;But in terms of the cut the market is talking about -- five or 10 basis points -- that cannot have much bearing on the economy.&quot;  </p>
<p>Even if the Bundesbank does cut, analysts expected the Bank of France to keep its monetary policy on hold for the moment.</p>
<p>&quot;For the franc point of view, a little widening of interest rate margins would be a stabilising factor,&quot; said an analyst. &quot;I think it would be inclined to sit tight and reassess the situation.&quot;</p>
<p>The franc advanced more than a half a centime against the mark, trading at 3.4148/53 per mark in late trade compared with its price late Monday of 3.4212/15. But it was still way off its best levels early last month when it was trading at just under 3.38.  </p>
<p>Analysts said at lack of domestic news ahead of the BoF and Buba meetings should mean more range trading on Wednesday.</p>
<p>One analyst said longer term, the French market was likely to remain in the doldrums waiting for the September budget. &quot;It does not anticipate a great deal of news until then,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At the same time, another analyst said the market was somewhat sheltered by the predominance of domestic investors. Just over 10 percent of French government bonds (OATs) are in foreign hands, down from one-third three years ago, he said.</p>
<p>There was little activity in the cash market and the 10-year OAT-bund spread remained steady at seven basis points.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
