<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3865" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French shares end near highs on rate cut talk.</title>
<headline>French shares end near highs on rate cut talk.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>French shares extended earlier gains to close over one percent higher, outshining most other European centres, as fresh talk of rate cuts allowed the market to claw back some of its recent chronic underperformance.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index closed up 33.05 points or 1.66 percent at 2,019.26, just off the day's high of 2,020.57.</p>
<p>The index closed at its highest level since August 2, before recent currency attacks on the franc.</p>
<p>The broader SBF-120 index ended 18.39 points or 1.31 percent higher at 1,423.34 points.</p>
<p>Market turnover was a moderate 3.4 billion francs.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the market pounced on a slowdown in German M3 growth in July as a further sign the Bundesbank might ease its key 3.3 percent repo rate, leaving room for a further cut in French rates needed to boost the economy. The rally picked up when the CAC-40 bowled out one resistance level after another.</p>
<p>But investors were awaiting German IFO data before deciding on the prospects of a German rate cut on Thursday and chances of a quick easing in French rates were even less certain.</p>
<p>&quot;I'll believe it when I see it. But few people are holding their breath,&quot; said one broker, adding that the market had plenty of catching up to do after lagging Wall Street all year.  </p>
<p>Most economist do not expect a French rate cut this week.</p>
<p>Brokers said the bourse had limited room to keep the rally going -- even with a new rate cut -- with foreign investors particularly wary of threatened union unrest in the autumn.</p>
<p>Short-term gains should be capped around 2,050, they said.</p>
<p>* GAN closed up 3.30 francs at 129 on a newspaper report that Caisses d'Epargne was poised to make a firm bid for CIC.</p>
<p>* Elf, up 12.70 francs at 376.90 and Total up 8.50 at 369.30. Both outperformed on Monday's oil price surge despite heavy profit-taking on oil on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>* Michelin flew up 7.30 francs to 240.20, or 3.13 percent, on a bullish U.S. client satisfaction survey</p>
<p>* Eridania, up 35 at 750, nearly five percent, on talk of improved Spanish olive oil harvest and lower corn prices -- both reducing key costs. Worries linger over H1 results.</p>
<p>* LVMH rose 36 francs to 1,140, up strongly on mainly technical grounds after piercing the key 1,100 level on Monday.</p>
<p>* Axa firms four francs to 287.50 but lags CAC-40 after 24.5 percent jump in first-half sales. Underlying sales rise 8.8 percent.  </p>
<p>* Pathe up again after BSkyB reports 66-percent profit rise. Share had risen four percent on Monday.</p>
<p>* Computer systems house Axime falls 109 francs to 611, after a blistering rise above 760 francs in the past year. A fund manager said its 1995/96 results disappointed and a broker downgraded profit forecasts for next year and the year after.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
