<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3866" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss bond market closing report.</title>
<headline>Swiss bond market closing report.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss bonds ended lower with the market mostly waiting for the Bundesbank meeting Thursday amidst speculation the German central bank could trim its repurchase rate.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank said Tuesday German M3 growth slowed to 8.6 percent in July from 9.6 percent in June on an annualised basis compared with the fourth quarter average of 1995.</p>
<p>Some Swiss traders expected growth to be below 8.00 percent in July. The market was still seen stuck in recent ranges, however, with the September Swiss confederate bond contract continuing to consolidate around 113.00.  </p>
<p>The latest M3 data raised hopes in some markets that the Bundesbank would move to lower the repo rate, which has been at 3.30 percent since February.</p>
<p>But one Swiss trader said that even if the German central bank does not cut rates, hopes for a rate cut down the line are likely to remain priced into the market for now.</p>
<p>In the short end, prices were also weaker even though the Swiss National Bank added liquidity to the money market this morning at rates slightly below the market, traders said.</p>
<p>An SNB spokesman said only that the SNB was remaining flexible in responding to demand in the market.  </p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial, +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
