<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3867" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish bonds barely moved, focus on U.S. FOMC.</title>
<headline>Irish bonds barely moved, focus on U.S. FOMC.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish government bonds were barely moved in thin late trade on Tuesday as the market awaited news of a possible rise in U.S. rates at the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is very little changed on the opening levels,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone is waiting on news from the FOMC. The dollar has been well bid which is supportive but the crucial thing is what happens to U.S. rates. That is the key for the next 24 hours,&quot; the dealer said.  </p>
<p>By 1510 GMT, the 8.00 percent bond due 2000 had eased six pence from Monday's close to 103.98 to yield 6.74 percent while the 8.00 percent bond due 2006 rose eight pence on the day to 103.40 to yield 7.37 percent.</p>
<p>The one-month money market rate, which has remained above the key 5.50 level since the beginning of August, was at 5.56/5.68 compared with 5.56/5.59 at the close.</p>
<p>Dealers said if the FOMC leaves U.S. rates unchanged then the next focus will be on the Bundesbank meeting on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;If the FOMC raises rates, then the Bundesbank meeting will not be as crucial,&quot; the dealer said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Should the FOMC not raise rates, then the Bundesbank will become the main focus of attention. So, all told, everything depends on what happens in the United States later today,&quot; the dealer added.</p>
<p>-- Damien Lynch, Dublin Newsroom +353 1 6603377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
