<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3868" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: United India denounces nuclear test ban pact.</title>
<headline>United India denounces nuclear test ban pact.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian political parties threw their support behind the government on Tuesday in firmly repudiating a draft nuclear test ban treaty.</p>
<p>The parties put up a united front to denounce the pact after India prevented the accord from being adopted by disarmament negotiators in Geneva.</p>
<p>Jaipal Reddy, spokesman for Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's 13-party governing coalition, told Reuters Television: &quot;India cannot be privy to this highly discriminating treaty.&quot;</p>
<p>In Geneva, Indian ambassador Arundhati Ghose told the Conference on Disarmament that the draft treaty would not halt efforts by nuclear weapons powers to perfect their arsenals using non-explosive techniques like computer simulation.</p>
<p>Ghose said the Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty (CTBT) did not promote the realisation of &quot;universal disarmament goals&quot;.</p>
<p>K.L. Sharma, spokesman from the main opposition Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), said: &quot;All parties in the country are united on this issue, that our country should not sign the CTBT.&quot;</p>
<p>During the 2-1/2 years of negotiations, India has demanded that the CTBT commit the five declared nuclear powers -- Britain, China, France, Russia and the United States -- to a disarmament timetable. The nuclear powers have resisted.</p>
<p>Reddy said the treaty represented the views of the five nuclear powers. &quot;They never care to address themselves with the security concerns of India because India is not a nuclear weapon state,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>New Delhi was further angered when the draft text demanded that India be among those that signed up to the treaty before it could enter into force.</p>
<p>India, along with Pakistan and Israel, is one of three &quot;nuclear threshold states&quot; that have the capability to swiftly build nuclear weapons. New Delhi exploded a nuclear device in 1974, but has not undertaken any nuclear tests since then.</p>
<p>Ghose said the government's views were &quot;shared across the Indian political spectrum&quot;.</p>
<p>In Geneva, U.S. disarmament ambassador Stephen Ledogar said the real reason India had blocked the CTBT was because &quot;New Delhi wants to maintain the Indian nuclear weapon option&quot;.</p>
<p>Shortly after taking power in June, Deve Gowda's United Front coalition reiterated it would retain the option to build nuclear weapons until universal disarmament was realised.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has clearly said it will not foreclose the nuclear option. It is linked to our security,&quot; an official in New Delhi said when asked to comment on Ledogar's views.</p>
<p>But the official, who asked not to be identified, said the main reason India blocked the CTBT &quot;was nuclear disarmament has to be total and comprehensive, and has to be in a timeframe&quot;.</p>
<p>Like the nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty (NPT) which was indefinitely extended last year, the CTBT is widely viewed in India as a discriminatory agreement that would divide the world into nuclear &quot;haves&quot; and &quot;have nots&quot;.</p>
<p>Ghose said arguments put forward by the nuclear weapons states before the International Court of Justice represented their understanding that the NPT legitimised both their possession of nuclear weapons and their right to use them.</p>
<p>&quot;The world was burdened indefinitely with a differential notion of sovereignty -- one entitled to nuclear weapons and another not,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Asked what India would do if the five nuclear powers tried to forward the CTBT to the United Nations General Assembly, Reddy said: &quot;We will cross that bridge when we come to that.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
