<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3882" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - August 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - August 20.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indian business and political stories in leading newspapers on Tuesday prepared for Reuters by Business News and Information Services Pvt Ltd, New Delhi. Telephone: 11-3324842, 11-3761233; Fax: 91-11-3351006</p>
<p>Internet : biznis.news@forums.sprintrpg.sprint.com</p>
<p>		   -------oo0oo-------</p>
<p>			TOP STORIES</p>
<p>Indian Express</p>
<p>TELECOMMUNICATION DEPARTMENT TO BE REVAMPED</p>
<p>The Communications Ministry has begun efforts to revamp the evaluation committee and activate internal vigilance in the Department of Telecommunications (DoT). The Communications Minister has passed orders to this effect. This is to check corruption and ensure transparency in the telecommunication tendering process involving millions of rupees. Meanwhile, several DoT officials were placed under suspension including Runu Ghosh, deputy director (finance), four sub-divisional officers and a general manager of the Mahanagar Telephone Nigam Ltd.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Times Of India</p>
<p>FORMER COMMUNICATIONS MINISTER'S WHEREABOUTS NOT KNOWN</p>
<p>The Indian High Commission in London has failed to ascertain the whereabouts of former Union Communications Minister Sukh Ram. Reports said the former Minister was not in London as was earlier suggested by the Central Bureau of Investigation (CBI). Sukh Ram was there last week before his houses were raided in Delhi and Mandi (Himachal Pradesh) which led to the recovery of 36.6 million rupees in cash. Various political parties wondered why the CBI had not contacted the former minister even days after its raid on his houses.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Hindustan Times</p>
<p>BHARATIYA JANATA PARTY GOVERNMENT IN GUJARAT MAY FALL</p>
<p>The Suresh Mehta Gujarat government was rattled by the decision of breakaway factions of the ruling Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) to launch a new party. Expelled BJP rebel leader Shakarsinh Vaghela was holding a rally in the state's capital city to launch his new party. The BJP, smarting under pressure, ruled out any threat whatsoever to the Suresh Mehta Ministry. The party said it was ready to sacrifice its government in the interest of party discipline. Meanwhile the state's Industry Minister Dilip Parikh was dropped and expelled from the party.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Financial Express</p>
<p>RECAST BOMBAY BOURSE INDEX MAKES CRASHING DEBUT</p>
<p>The recast Bombay Stock Exchange 30-share sensitive index (sensex) crashed on its debut. Selling pressure saw the recast sensex dip 86.33 points from the opening level of 3367.82 points. Panic selling by foreign investors and domestic traders was responsible for the crash, said brokers. On the National Stock Exchange (NSE) too, the prices of pivotals suffered a setback. The NSE-50 scrip index lost 26 points over the previous close of 1002.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>NEW BIDDING GUIDELINES FOR GLOBALLY-AIDED PROJECTS SOON</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry has decided to overhaul the competitive bidding norms for multilaterally aided project. The Ministry is preparing a standard National Competitive Bidding Document for domestic component of such projects. This document would be the first of its kind to cover the indigenous developmental aspect of an internationally aided project. The foreign segments of these projects would be covered under a revamped International Competitive Bidding Document. Sources said the revised documents would provide for better transparency and simplified norms.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>BAT IN FRESH PARLEYS WITH FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</p>
<p>UK-based promoter-cum-principal shareholder of ITC Ltd, B.A.T, wants the Indian company's board to be restructured. B.A.T has begun talks with the Industrial Development Bank of India and other major institutional share-holders in ITC. The British company is also seeking to raise its stake in ITC to 40 percent with the help of financial institutions (FIs). Currently, B.A.T's stake in ITC stands at 32 percent. The FIs are yet to respond to B.A.T's move.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>TATAS TO HUNT FOR NEW PARTNER AFTER UNISYS</p>
<p>Tata Sons may shell out over 900 million rupees for buying out the 40 percent equity stake of US-based Unisys Corp in Tata Unisys Ltd joint venture. Tata Sons is learnt to be looking for a new foreign partner to offload this equity at a later stage. Tata Sons was vying for US software giant Microsoft Corp for the purpose, said sources.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>The Economic Times</p>
<p>GOVERNMENT SPIKES FOREIGN EQUITY IN AVIATION</p>
<p>The Civil Aviation Ministry has spiked plans for foreign equity participation in the aviation sector. The move has not just grounded the controversial Tata-Singapore Airlines proposal but also ruled out fresh joint ventures in the aviation sector. While the firming up of the government stand on the issue would provide some protection to domestic carriers, the ministry has proposed to make Air-India cost-competitive and more efficient.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>STATE BANK TO RECOVER TWO BLN RUPEE AS PROFIT</p>
<p>State Bank of India (SBI) will recover as profit more than two billion rupees which had been written off as depreciation in its investment in government securities during fiscal 1995/96 (April-March). The SBI will benefit from the decision of the Reserve Bank of India to allow public sector banks to write back as profits, in the current year, the excess depreciation on government securities provided in fiscal 1995/96. Several banks which have had heavy securities portfolio planned to raise their profits this year through such a reverse entry, sources said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>PRIME MINISTER REJECTS STRATEGY BLUEPRINT FOR NINTH PLAN</p>
<p>Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda criticised the states for not implementing the ongoing economic reforms wholeheartedly. Addressing the first meeting of the reconstituted Planning Commission, Deve Gowda also rejected the blueprint of the Ninth Plan strategy paper based on the reports of the working groups and committees. The Prime Minister said states should fully shoulder their constitutional responsibilities in important sectors such as industrial infrastructure, power development, agriculture and allied services, irrigation, roads, and social sectors.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business Standard</p>
<p>PHILIPS EYES INDIA AS HUB FOR AUDIO, VIDEO BUSINESS</p>
<p>Philips, Europe's largest electronics major, is looking at India as one of the locations where it could shift a chunk of its audio and video business from Europe. The move is likely to be a part of Philips' worldwide restructuring exercise after it incurred heavy losses in the first quarter of the current year. Sources said in the next four years, the company would invest $400 million to expand capacities and modernise its Indian facilities.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>NOMINAL VALUE OF GOLD RESERVES DOWN 7.3 BLN RUPEES</p>
<p>The nominal value of gold reserves dropped 7.3 billion rupees between March 29, 1996 and August 19, 1996 due to steady fall of gold prices in the London market. India's gold reserves fell from 164.63 billion rupees ($4,659 million) on March 29 to 157,33 billion rupees ($4,410 million) on August 9. Sources said this might have an adverse impact on the exchange fluctuation reserve and, consequently, the fiscal deficit.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Observer</p>
<p>CONTROL OVER STATE-OWNED FIRMS IN EIGHT SECTORS RETAINED</p>
<p>The Department of Public Enterprises (DPE) has identified eight core sectors in which public sector units (PSUs) would remain under government control. They are telecommunication, power, petroleum, fertilisers, coal, ports, steel and shipping. DPE has also favoured the continuation of public sector monopoly in strategically important areas such as nuclear energy, defence, space and oceanography. The categorisation of the PSUs into core, non-core, essential, non-essential sectors is part of the government's move to revitalise the PSUs.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>INDUSTRIAL GROWTH 5.1 PCT TILL JUNE</p>
<p>The overall industrial growth was estimated at 5.1 percent during the period of April-June this year. On the other hand, the production performance of 24 industries, including core industries, for June this year indicates an overall growth rate of 4.5 percent, the Industry Ministry sources said. While six infrastructure industries such as coal, crude oil, cement, saleable steel, electricity, petroleum refinery products together registered a 4.7 percent growth in April-June 1996, it was only 0.5 percent in June, sources said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>GOVERNMENT LINES UP 20 BLN RUPEE 10-YEAR BONDS</p>
<p>The Union government would raise 20 billion rupees through the sale of 10-year, 13.85 percent government stock on August 26. The Reserve Bank of India said interest on the stock would be paid half-yearly on February 26 and August 26 and the stock would be repaid at par on august 26, 2006. The stock would be eligible for ready forward facility, sources said.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
