<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3887" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Afghan cabinet wants communists out of key posts.</title>
<headline>Afghan cabinet wants communists out of key posts.</headline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Afghan Prime Minister Gulbuddin Hekmatyar's cabinet has decided to remove communists with a criminal record from important government posts, a spokesman for the prime minister said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The spokesman, Qaribur Rehman Saeed, told reporters the decision, taken by a cabinet meeting on Monday, would be implemented after approval by President Burhanuddin Rabbani.</p>
<p>The first Islamic government set up by mujahideen guerrillas in April 1992 after the collapse of a communist government had announced a general amnesty for all civil and military employees of the previous regime.</p>
<p>Some important officials of the former government say they had links with the mujahideen groups and helped them in the fall of the communist government of then president Najibullah, who was backed by the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>&quot;There is anti-government propaganda going on in the offices by the communists who disobey the orders,&quot; Saeed said.</p>
<p>&quot;The general amnesty by the first mujahideen government is enough for them (communists). There is security for them in Kabul, that is enough.&quot;</p>
<p>He did not specify the officers to be dismissed.</p>
<p>At present, some of the military detachments in Kabul as well as several intellegence networks are run by military officers who held high positions in the communist government, against which the mujahideen groups fought for 14 years.</p>
<p>&quot;If we want to have a sound government the decisions should be implemented without any exception in order to prevent, to some extent, the current difficulties,&quot; Saeed said. &quot;Otherwise it will be pitiable.&quot;</p>
<p>Hekmatyar, a former rival to Rabbani, took office as prime minister for the second time in late June after a peace pact between the two men.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
