<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3893" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka sends truckloads of food to refugees.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka sends truckloads of food to refugees.</headline>
<byline>Mohan Samarasinghe</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Sri Lankan army said on Tuesday it planned to step up food supplies to the country's war-torn north, while separatist Tamil rebels accused the military of resuming its shelling of a rebel town.</p>
<p>A statement faxed from London by the Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam (LTTE) said the army had begun shelling Kilinochchi, 285 km (175 miles) north of Colombo, after a week-long pause.</p>
<p>An army spokesman denied the charge.</p>
<p>&quot;No, that is not true,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;We are only retaliating if and when they fire mortars at us.&quot;</p>
<p>The army's statement did not mention any bombardment, focusing instead on relief work for the refugees.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, aid workers voiced concern over the plight of some 600,000 civilians facing hunger in the country's north.</p>
<p>An army statement said it hoped to resume a normal supply of 50 truckloads per day soon. Nearly 300 trucks of food had been sent to the northern Wanni mainland since the army lifted a three-week blockade on August 12, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;The resumption of food convoys should alleviate a potentially dangerous situation,&quot; an official for the International Committee of the Red Cross told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Arrangements have been made to send 50 truckloads of food daily into the uncleared areas north of Vavuniya, as was done before the LTTE detained several convoys,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Regularly, convoys of lorries carrying rice, flour and other essential foodstuff have been leaving Vavuniya since the resumption,&quot; the statement added.</p>
<p>Aid workers confirmed the government had sent nearly 300 truckloads of food to the Wanni mainland.</p>
<p>The army launched an offensive on the northern rebel-held town of Kilinochchi on July 26. The military then banned food convoys to the rebel-held areas after accusing the rebels of taking the food and letting civilians go hungry.</p>
<p>The rebels, fighting a 13-year war for independence in the Indian Ocean island's north and east, denied government charges that it had hijacked food sent to civilians. The Tamil rebels accused the government of blocking food supplies to force refugees into army-held areas.</p>
<p>The Wanni refugee population had swelled since the beginning of the army assault on Kilinochchi.</p>
<p>The army has said its troops were digging in one km (half a mile) north of Kilinochchi, where the LTTE set up bases after being ousted from their northern Jaffna peninsula stronghold in April.</p>
<p>The Tigers say they have stalled the army's advance on Kilinochchi.</p>
<p>&quot;The army, which is stuck in the Paranthan area north of Kilinochchi is taking its revenge on civilians by firing artillery shells towards far away places,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Kilinochchi's 200,000 residents abandoned the town, with most of them fleeing to the surrounding jungles while others sought sanctuary with friends and relatives, aid workers said.</p>
<p>They said on Monday diseases like malaria, jaundice and septicaemia, or blood poisoning, were spreading widely among the refugees. Two children have already died of septicaemia.</p>
<p>The government says more than 50,000 people have died in the ethnic war.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
