<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3903" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian call money ends steady, gilts inactive.</title>
<headline>Indian call money ends steady, gilts inactive.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian call money ended Tuesday unchanged from the day's opening levels of 10.25-10.75 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>Most of the day's trade was around 10.5 percent, they said.</p>
<p>Dealers said call money rates seemed to have settled at the levels they were at in May and June before the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) reduced cash reserve requirements by one percentage point in the first week of July.</p>
<p>&quot;Call is likley to remain between 10 percent and 11 percent for the next couple of weeks,&quot; a dealer at a foreign bank said. &quot;Eleven percent will be a resistance level as banks can avail refinance against export credit from the RBI at this rate.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said call rates would pick up from mid-September as liquidity was sucked out of the system through government borrowings and corporate demand for credit started picking up.</p>
<p>&quot;Traditionally, the demand for credit picks up from mid-September,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;We can expect the 11 percent barrier to be breached then.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said the securities market was inactive barring a few stray deals in treasury bills and short-dated securities.</p>
<p>No trades were reported in commercial paper.</p>
<p>Dealers said a financial institution issued a one-year certificate of deposit on Tuesday at 15.25 percent.</p>
<p>Rates on inter-corporate deposits remained unchanged at 17-19 percent for top-rated borrowers.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
