<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3904" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan's Bhutto vows to end sectarian politics.</title>
<headline>Pakistan's Bhutto vows to end sectarian politics.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistani Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto vowed on Tuesday to end sectarian politics in her country, which has suffered a spate of violence between rival Moslem sects.</p>
<p>&quot;We are all Moslems and cannot allow anyone to take precious lives,&quot; the official APP news agency quoted her as telling reporters in the nearby town of Rawalpindi.</p>
<p>&quot;That is why we have vowed to put an end to sectarian politics,&quot; she said two days after 18 people were killed in an attack on a Shi'ite sect religious meeting at a village in the central province of Punjab.</p>
<p>Bhutto said she was deeply concerned about the sectarian violence in Punjab and the southern province of Sindh and a number of arrests had been made there.</p>
<p>Police said they had arrested three men in Chak-205 village southeast of the main southern Punjab city of Multan on suspicion of aiding gunmen who attacked the Shi'ite meeting there on Sunday. Shi'ite places of worship were being guarded, they added.</p>
<p>The attacks in Karachi and Chak-205, which followed several individual assassinations, raised fears that militants from the majority Sunni and the minority Shi'ite sects could plunge Pakistan into a new cycle of reprisals.</p>
<p>Shi'ites form about 15 percent of Pakistan's Sunni-dominated population of 130 million.</p>
<p>&quot;We are against sectarian politics and the groups involved need to be combatted and a culture developed to counter such trends,&quot; Bhutto said. &quot;With stringent measures against sectarianism, such type of politics will be eliminated from the country.&quot;</p>
<p>On Monday, the leader of the Shi'ite Tehrik-e-Jafria Pakistan movement, Allama Sajid Naqvi, said the country could face civil war if the government failed to check sectarian violence.</p>
<p>He spoke after leading funeral prayers for the dead Shi'ites at Chak-205.</p>
<p>On Monday, a previously-unknown Sunni militant group calling itself Lashkar-e-Jhangvi claimed responsibility for Sunday's killings, indicating it had retaliated for the killing of 12 Sunnis in an attack on a procession in Karachi last Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Karachi attack was on an Independence Day march of the militant Sunni Sipah-e-Sahaba Pakistan (SSP) group.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
