<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3934" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Afghan Taleban arrest six men over Russian escape.</title>
<headline>Afghan Taleban arrest six men over Russian escape.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Afghanistan's opposition Taleban Islamic militia has arrested six men while investigating the escape of seven Russian airmen held hostage for more than a year, a Pakistan-based Afghan news service said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Afghan Islamic Press (AIP) said the Taleban leadership had arrested three guards and three airport officials to investigate how the Russians were able to trick their captors.</p>
<p>The Russians escaped to the United Arab Emirates on Friday in their own plane along with three guards. The airmen, held in Kandahar in southern Afghanistan, had been allowed by Taleban leaders to visit their Ilyushin 76 cargo plane for maintenance.</p>
<p>UAE authorities were expected to hand over the three guards to the International Red Crescent on Tuesday.</p>
<p>AIP said the chief of Taleban, Mullah Mohammad Umar, spent Saturday at the airport to examine the possibility that the Russians' escape was a conspiracy.</p>
<p>A Taleban spokesman had said Taleban fighters had tried to block the runway with a jeep and then sent up a MiG fighter and helicopter in vain pursuit of the lumbering cargo plane.</p>
<p>The Russian's returned home to a hero's welcome in Tatarstan on Monday after travelling through Moscow from the UAE.</p>
<p>The airmen, working for the Tatarstan-based Aerostan company, were taken prisoner after a Taleban MiG-19 fighter forced their plane to land in August 1995.</p>
<p>The Taleban, which controls about half of Afghanistan, said the plane's cargo of ammunition from Albania was evidence of Russian military support for President Burhanuddin Rabbani's government. Moscow said the crew's nationality was coincidental.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
