<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3938" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India aviation chief opposes foreign equity - report.</title>
<headline>India aviation chief opposes foreign equity - report.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Indian newspaper said on Tuesday that the Civil Aviation Ministry had rejected a proposal to allow foreign companies to take equity stakes in domestic airlines.</p>
<p>The Economic Times quoted Civil Aviation Minister C.M. Ibrahim as saying the decision to retain a ban on foreign equity participation in the sector meant a proposed joint venture linking Singapore Airlines (SIA) and India's Tata Industries Ltd would not go ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;The union Civil Aviation Ministry has spiked plans for foreign equity participation in the aviation sector, thereby grounding the controversial Tata-Singapore Airlines proposal for once and for all,&quot; the newspaper said in a front-page article.</p>
<p>Civil Aviation Ministry officials could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>The newspaper said the ministry planned to devote its energies to shoring up loss-making Air-India, the national overseas carrier.</p>
<p>In 1991 India began dimantling the state's aviation monopoly as part of an economic reform programme, opening its air travel sector to more than a dozen domestically owned airlines.</p>
<p>In February 1995, Singapore Airlines and Tata Industries submitted a proposal to India's Foreign Investment and Promotion Board (FIPB) to launch the joint venture airline. Tata would hold a 60 percent stake and SIA the rest.</p>
<p>Since then the proposal has languished with the government, which has said the tie-up would have to wait until the nation's airport infrastructure was expanded.</p>
<p>- New Delhi newsroom +91-11 301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
