<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3939" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India BPCL Apr to Jul 96 sales up 9.6 pct.</title>
<headline>India BPCL Apr to Jul 96 sales up 9.6 pct.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The state-run Bharat Petroleum Corporation Ltd (BPCL) sold 5.04 million tonnes of petroleum products from April to July 1996, a company official said.</p>
<p>He told a news conference, late on Monday, this represented a 9.6 percent rise over the year ago period.  </p>
<p>&quot;Against an average growth rate of 4.78 percent for the industry during the period 1991/92 (April-March) to 1994/95, BPCL's sales increased by 7.34 percent,&quot; BPCL said in a statement.</p>
<p>This trend continued during 1995/96 and the company achieved its highest ever sales volume of 14.8 million tonnes, registering a growth of 11.7 percent, higher than the industry growth of 11 percent, it said.</p>
<p>The growth rate was high in the following products - LPG 13.3 percent, aviation fuel 10.1 percent, diesel 17.4 percent and furnace oil 20.4 percent, BPCL said.</p>
<p>BPCL achieved a 20.3 percent share of the Indian market in 1995/96, up from 18.8 percent in 1991/92.</p>
<p>BPCL said it planned to establish new refineries to bridge the gap between its refining capacity and its marketing requirements.</p>
<p>A contractor for project management consultancy would shortly be appointed for a new refinery at Bina in central India in partnership with Oman Oil Company, it said.</p>
<p>A 950-km cross-country pipeline from the Gujarat coast would transport imported crude to the proposed refinery. The idea was to execute the project as a turnkey contract, officials said.</p>
<p>This refinery will process six million tonnes of crude oil a year. BPCL is also pursuing various approvals for another new refinery planned in the north India in partnership with Shell International.</p>
<p>This refinery would have a capacity to process seven million tonnes of crude a year.</p>
<p>Petroleum Infrastructure Ltd, a joint venture between BPCL and Gujarat Gas Company is expected to commission a new LPG import facility in Okha on the western coast by September 1996, the BPCL statement said.</p>
<p>Petroleum Infrastructure is also planning a 4.0 billion-rupee dedicated port terminal to store LPG on the western coast.</p>
<p>To part finance capital expenditure and to broaden shareholder base, BPCL is planning a public issue of 15 million shares at a premium yet to be determined, officials said.</p>
<p>After the issue, the government holding in BPCL would come down to 60.2 percent from the current 66.2 percent.</p>
<p>BPCL also plans to tap the international equity market next year, company officials said, without giving any details.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
