<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3947" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dublin corners Korea fund market in Europe.</title>
<headline>Dublin corners Korea fund market in Europe.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Allen</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dublin is set to consolidate its claim to be the key centre for foreign investment into South Korea, helped by revived interest in specialist funds and the Korean government's efforts to encourage funds from abroad.</p>
<p>Fund managers and service providers say that in just three years Dublin has skillfully exploited Ireland's double taxation treaty with Korea to build an impressive block of 90 listings.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Korea funds started as a highly leveraged financing mechanism in the days when interest rates in Korea were in the high teens -- 16-18 percent,&quot; said David Dillon of legal firm Dillon Eustace, which set up the first Korea fund.</p>
<p>Around 600 funds are listed in Dublin, excluding dozens of &quot;sub-funds&quot; within umbrella structures.</p>
<p>On the back of a double tax treaty, originally negotiated to help a large manufacturing project, Dublin has created a highly lucrative niche market.  </p>
<p>Recent weakness in Korea's equity market has caused a lull with only six Korea funds being registered in Dublin so far this year. But industry sources say interest is picking up again, especially for yet-to-be-approved Korea bond funds, which will allow foreign investors access to local currency bonds.</p>
<p>Fund managers in London said on Tuesday the current wave of student protests on reunification with North Korea had had no impact on positive investor sentiment towards South Korea.</p>
<p>Ray Carroll at Davy Stockbrokers, which sponsors the Korea Leverage, Korea Gearing and Evergreen Korea funds, said Dublin had established itself as a centre with Korea expertise.  </p>
<p>Dublin has little competition in Europe. Luxembourg and Belgium's offshore centre do not have a tax treaty, and although Britain has one, the opportunity was never taken up.</p>
<p>The London Stock Exchange has only a handful of Korea vehicles, among them Schroders' $275 million closed-end Korea fund launched in 1987 and its Seoul Fund, a sterling-denominated British unit trust.</p>
<p>But Carroll noted there has been growing competition from Labuan, a Malaysian offshore financial centre set up 18 months ago which also has a double tax treaty with Korea.  </p>
<p>Fund managers say it is only slightly cheaper to list in Dublin but praise its responsive, flexible regulatory structure. One manager said Labuan was &quot;not perceived to have the quality of staff, services and infrastructure of Dublin.&quot;</p>
<p>The proposed Korea bond funds will propel Dublin to the centre of the Korea market just as the Korean government is beginning to open up access to foreign investors as part of preparations to join the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD).</p>
<p>&quot;If they were approved it would be a recognition of Dublin's standing as an offshore financial centre,&quot; said a UK-based fund manager.</p>
<p>-- London Investment Desk +44 171 542 6414</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
