<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3948" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: North Sea crude under pressure from weaker Brent.</title>
<headline>North Sea crude under pressure from weaker Brent.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea crudes were under pressure on Tuesday as Brent swaps and paper spreads failed to claw back early losses, traders said.</p>
<p>The prompt Sept/Oct intermonth paper spread was talked at +57/+59 cents, down about seven cents from early levels. Oct/Nov was pegged at +48 cents, about four cents weaker from Monday.</p>
<p>Oct Brent lost 22 cents to trade at $20.63 by 1514 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a broad feeling in the market that Brent was overheated and had to come down,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Brent CFDs fell further in early afternoon talk to Sept Brent +10 cents for the balance of this week.  </p>
<p>Next week's dates, which traded earlier at Oct +47 cents, traded again at +42 cents.</p>
<p>An Aug 29-31 Brent was on offer at Sept Brent +8 cents. Tuesday's sole set of dates (Sept 4-6) was kept well ahead of the five o'clock deadline by U.S. major Texaco and was already committed, traders said.</p>
<p>Other North Sea markets were quiet as buyers waited for premiums to weaken in line with the shallower Brent backwardation.</p>
<p>&quot;The other grades should come down but there hasn't been a trade today,&quot; said a trader.  </p>
<p>Mediterranean refiners found little to tempt them from the few cargoes on offer as they weighed up options in the face of appalling margins although there was no sign any had cut runs.</p>
<p>Syria's Sytrol was under pressure from buyers to keep prices down in current price talks for September cargoes with refiners asking for a rollover.</p>
<p>One trader said Sytrol had come down from an offer of Dated Brent -30 cents to Dated -38 cents while lifters were holding out for Dated -45 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the talks will last all week,&quot; an oil company trader said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
