<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3949" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK overnight rates firm on large shortage.</title>
<headline>UK overnight rates firm on large shortage.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>UK overnight cash rates ended firmer but off their day's highs after a larger than expected liquidity shortage of 1.45 billion stg.</p>
<p>In the gilt repo market, the 7.0 percent gilts due 2001 were again extremely well bid, while the Bank of England's announcement of a 7.5 percent 2.5 billion stg auction of gilts due 2006 next week was in line with market expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;The 7.0s of 2001 traded at 3.0 percent on the overnight and around 2.90 in the week,&quot; one trader said. &quot;I think it's 3.0 percent bid for two weeks, so it's gone really nasty today.&quot;</p>
<p>The trader said there was no obvious reason for the exceptional levels at which the stock was trading, nearly three percentage points below general collateral (GC).</p>
<p>&quot;I think someone is probably squeezing it a bit but nobody really knows,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some interest was still noted in the 6.0s of 1999 at around 5.25 percent.</p>
<p>Overnight GC ended at around 5.60 50 percent.</p>
<p>In the cash market, overnight rates initially rose to around 6.0 percent after the Bank of England took out only 50 million stg of an estimated 1.3 billion stg shortage in its early round of operations.</p>
<p>But the central bank weighed in more substantially in the subsequent rounds, fully clearing a shortage that was finally put at 1.45 billion stg.</p>
<p>Overnight cash ended at 5-3/4 3/8 compared with 5-1/2 5.0 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>One month was steady at 5-3/4 11/16 while three months was 1/32 lower at 5-25/32 23/32.</p>
<p>-- Richard Murphy, London Newsroom 44 171 542 2774</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
