<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3953" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London P&amp;I club reserves up, plans cautious growth.</title>
<headline>London P&amp;I club reserves up, plans cautious growth.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The London P&amp;I club improved its financial position last year and is ready to expand with caution, the ship-owners mutual insurer said in its 1996 annual report.</p>
<p>The protection and indemnity club more than doubled its accumulated reserve last year to $81.48 million from $37.69 million in 1994, while assets amounted to $372 million, up 4.8 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The club has never been in a stronger financial position. Our growing financial strength is gaining recognition in the market,&quot; chairman John Lyras said in a statement.</p>
<p>This was a comfortable, but not an excessive level of reserves, he told a news conference.</p>
<p>The London club was a medium sized club and had no plans to become one of the larger clubs, but would pursue a gradual growth strategy, Graham Edmiston, chairman of managing agent A Bilbrough &amp; Co Ltd, said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not in our interests to be overly greedy. We shall continue our natural growth of the last few years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>London club tonnage at February 19 totalled 26.97 million tonnes, up 1.18 million tonnes over the year.</p>
<p>The club maintained a selective new business policy, concentrating on bulk tankers and carriers, with most of its business in Europe, the Far East and Greece.</p>
<p>The average age of club vessels was 16.5 years compared with the world average of 18 years. The average size was 26,500 gross tonnes.</p>
<p>On the controversial P&amp;I issue of limiting the additional liability on shipowners in the event of a single catastrophe, Edmiston said he expected the limit would be reduced from the current $20 billion cap.</p>
<p>Pressure was growing among P&amp;I club members for the limit, which was agreed only after much debate last year, to be reduced, probably to around $2.0-3.0 billion.</p>
<p>Fourteen P&amp;I clubs form the International Group and provide insurance cover for more than 95 percent of the world's merchant fleet.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Insurance News 44 171 542 2769</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8200318">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
