<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3958" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FREIGHT--market dull, heralds mixed directions.</title>
<headline>FREIGHT--market dull, heralds mixed directions.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A dull day in the dry cargo freight market produced conflicting signals of future trends, broking sources said.</p>
<p>Conditions for Capers were described by brokers as steady to firm but for Panamaxes a mixture of stronger and weaker rates were seen.</p>
<p>The BFI was one point higher at 1,109 points and the BIFFEX was very thinly traded.</p>
<p>Unconfirmed reports were of Panamaxes fixtures for period timecharter, the 1981-built Alfios 63,408 dwt for two years to Scandinavian charterers, possibly Guinomar, at about $8,500 daily, and Despina 65,644 dwt passing Gibraltar August 22 for short period at under $9,000 daily.</p>
<p>Handy-size levels showed little evidence of recovery.</p>
<p>GRAIN--Egyptian chartering activity continued in the Atlantic.</p>
<p>ENC were said to have fixed a ten-year old Panamax delivery Continent for a trip via the  St Lawrence to Egypt at $6,800 daily. Although short business this represents an improvement on rates around $7,500 daily delivery loading port plus $100,000 bonus. K Line were linked with the fixture on subjects of Antonis I.</p>
<p>Angelicoussis 69,346 dwt delivery US Gulf mid-September trip Far East at a steady $12,000 daily plus $185,000 bonus, but the subjects are believed to be shaky.</p>
<p>From east coast South America Continental quoted 45,000 tonnes 55' Brazil to the Philippines for August/September and upto 40,000 tonnes 55' Rio Grande/China for September 5/20.</p>
<p>Kavo Midia 64,345 dwt was said to have fixed Nidera for grain busines to the Far East, but no details were released.</p>
<p>Iana fixed a handy-size from the Plate and Brazil to the Continent on private terms, and Continental fixed 25,000 wheat on subjects from Southampton to Chittagong for prompt loading at only $29.00.</p>
<p>COAL/ORE/FERTILISERS--Japanese charterers such as Mosk, Nitetsu and Navix quoted a number of new enquiries for Panamaxes for coal from Australia or Kalimantan to Japan, but the only fixture reported in these trades was Rubin Pioneer 69,235 dwt delivery Gladstone September 10/20 trip Japan at a weak $7,500 daily plus $95,000 bonus.</p>
<p>Carboex quoted a fresh enquiry for a prompt shipment of 65,000/10 coal New Orleans/Tarragona. A modern 64,000 dwt Panamax was fixed from the Continent for an ore trip via Norway back to the Continent at close to $8,250 daily.</p>
<p>HANDY-SIZES--CSAV booked LT Pragati 37,489 dwt delivery prompt Japan for three-five months business via west coast South America at $7,200, having a week previously taken Alcinoe 34,000 dwt for similar business at only $6,500 daily.</p>
<p>Alcestis 43,383 dwt fixed a scrap cargo from California to Malaysia on private terms, but brokers reckoned the rate was low.</p>
<p>Clan Line took George Lyras 35,730 dwt, with a capacity of 908 teu, delivery Hongkong for an east coast South America round at $8,500 daily.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
