<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3962" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: OPTIONS - Volatility trades struck in FTSE index.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - Volatility trades struck in FTSE index.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Volatility trades were the main deals struck in the FTSE 100 index by Tuesday afternoon as the market went higher, dealer said.</p>
<p>The biggest trade was from a buyer of 1,250 September 3850 calls at 75-1/2p who also sold September futures at 3895.</p>
<p>If the market falls, profits from the short futures will be offset by losses from the long calls and vice versa if the market rises. An increase in implied volatility will make the trade profitable.</p>
<p>Another deal was from a buyer of 500 December 3900 puts at 104-1/2p against buying futures at 3894.  </p>
<p>By 1357 GMT, September FTSE futures were up 12 at 3891, while the cash index gained 18.0 to 3881.7.</p>
<p>Over in stock options, mobile 'phone company Vodafone was active, the biggest deal coming from a seller of 750 November 260 calls at 8p.</p>
<p>The underlying shares were unchanged at 244-1/2p.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, a short strangle was the main deal in airports authority BAA and it involved selling 500 October 460 puts at 3p as well as 500 October 500 calls at 9p.</p>
<p>BAA was up 4p to 490p and the deal will make a maximum 12p profit if at expiry the shares are between 460p and 500p.  </p>
<p>Also active was confectionery and soft drinks group Cadbury Scheweppes, where the chief deal was the sale of 500 November 500 calls at 28p.</p>
<p>And in British Telecommunications a short position was rolled forward. This involved buying back 400 August 360 calls at 13p in a closing deal and opening a new position by selling 400 November 360 calls at 24p.</p>
<p>BT shares were unchanged at 373-1/2p as were those of Cadbury Scheweppes.</p>
<p>-- Pradip Mishra, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7954</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
