<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3963" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IBCA affirms Italy l-term foreign AA minus rating.</title>
<headline>IBCA affirms Italy l-term foreign AA minus rating.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>IBCA, the European credit rating agency, said on Tuesday it had affirmed the long-term foreign currency debt rating of Italy at AA minus.  </p>
<p>&quot;The rating applies to $92.9 billion of senior and unsecured foreign currency debt obligations of the Republic and sets a ceiling for the foreign currency rating of all Italian entities,&quot; IBCA said in a statement.  </p>
<p>IBCA also confirmed its rating of A1 plus for short-term foreign currency issues and assigned a long-term local currency rating of AAA to sovereign debt.</p>
<p>&quot;The small reduction in the public debt to GDP ratio in 1995 - the first since 1980 - signals a possible turning point in Italy's problematic fiscal policy,&quot; IBCA said in a statement.  </p>
<p>But IBCA said the path would not be easy.</p>
<p>&quot;A relatively small adverse shift in the macroeconomic environment will be sufficient to blow the government's public debt to gdp projections off course,&quot; it said. &quot;IBCA is projecting that the public debt to GDP ratio will rise this year, although it should fall in the more favourable macroeconomic environment expected in 1997.</p>
<p>The agency said that significant progress towards the Maastricht criterion of 60 percent was still a long way off.  </p>
<p>&quot;Furthermore, despite the mini-budget the inclusion of payments under the Constitutional Court rulings of 1994 means that additional payments will have to be made,&quot; IBCA said.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore only slight progress will be made this year in reducing the general government deficit. With much of Italy's growth still export-based, the slow-down in its European trading partners means that output growth will be substantially lower in 1996 than was seen in 1995.&quot;  </p>
<p>Assigning the long-term local currency rating of AAA to Italy sovereign debt, IBCA said this debt was worth 1,547 trillion lire (or $1,020 billion)</p>
<p>IBCA said it noted Italy's considerable strengths as a sovereign credit -- &quot;illustrated by the continued dynamism of the private sector, the current account surplus and the high savings ratio.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;These aspects of the economy have allowed Italy to sustain high public debt without having to draw on foreign savings,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>-- Kate Kelland, International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 8682</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
