<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3970" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - NYMEX crude set to retrace but resilient.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - NYMEX crude set to retrace but resilient.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX crude and products, perhaps getting ahead of themselves during the sharp gains of the last two sessions, were likely to take a step back in early trading on Tuesday to alleviate some overbought signals, chartists said.</p>
<p>But they quickly cautioned that crude and heating oil have left bullish fingerprints on both their daily and weekly charts, and would likely resume their upward march, either before or after the spot September crude expires later on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;One thing that did happen yesterday in the September was we took out an old high on the weekly chart from May at $22.90 and we're heading up on the weekly continuation to $23.75,&quot; based on a Fibonacci retracement level, said one technical analyst in Chicago. &quot;I think there is more upside left.&quot;</p>
<p>Her objective for October crude is $22.75 based on a Fibonacci projection. She subtracted the July 29 low of $19.56 from its August 13 peak of $21.87, multiplied by 0.38 and added that to $21.87. She also expected crude to reach resistance at $23.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll probably see some follow through buying and test $23 soon,&quot; she predicted. &quot;We're pretty friendly but it looks like it could be entering a temporary corrective phase.&quot;</p>
<p>She said stochastics on the daily chart were &quot;starting to fade,&quot; suggesting a consolidation phase. But she added that it must hold its high from July at $21.14, which based on its strong uptrend it should have no difficulty doing.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the tops are quite in yet. We're close but not there yet,&quot; said one commission house vice president in New York, referring to both crude and the products.</p>
<p>He said October crude's nine-day Relative Strength Index was at an overbought level of 78 percent but that its ability to break to the upside from a trading channel and settle above it were bullish signs.</p>
<p>October crude has been in an upward channel since spring and broke the top of it on Friday, he said. The top, crossing today at $21.86, should serve as support.</p>
<p>On a very short term basis, he said October crude's pivot point -- the average of the previous session's high, low and settlement -- is $22.32 today. The contract settled on Monday at $22.47 and last traded on ACCESS at $22.23.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to open below that pivot which is a bit more negative,&quot; he said. &quot;But they may try to run it up to that number early on and if they can't push it much beyond there then it will turn right around and come back down.&quot;</p>
<p>Resistance for September heating oil is at 62.75 cents a gallon, the top of an uptrending channel dating back to June, and support at its Friday high of 61.90 cents, he said.</p>
<p>For September gasoline, he said the top of a long-term channel dating to May crosses today at 65.80 cents, which is resistance, and support is at its Friday high of 63.50 cents.</p>
<p>-- John Hanley, London newsroom +44 171 542 8185</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
