<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3972" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Girls of 12 work as prostitutes in Britain - charity.</title>
<headline>Girls of 12 work as prostitutes in Britain - charity.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>British charities on Tuesday condemned the growth of child prostitution worldwide and called for tougher measures against sex offenders who abuse young people.</p>
<p>Reports by the charities Barnardo's and Save the Children were published as concern over the sexual abuse of children was heightened by a major police investigation in Belgium into a sex scandal in which two young girls have been killed.</p>
<p>Barnardo's, which offers shelter and care to children in Britain, found a girl of 12 working as a prostitute in Bradford, northern England, and heard about others who had started to offer sex when they were nine or 10 years of age.</p>
<p>It acknowledged that it would be hard to end such systematic abuse, but said: &quot;As a first step, Barnardo's believe that existing legislation should be tightened up.&quot;</p>
<p>A man found guilty in Britain of having sex with a minor under 13 faces life imprisonment, but the maximum sentence for having sex with a girl aged between 13 and 16 is just two years.</p>
<p>&quot;Attitudes must change to recognise that young women and girls on the streets are victims of abuse, and not prostitutes. Until this is achieved, no progress will be made,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Separately, Save the Children published an international report on child prostitution, entitled &quot;Kids for Hire&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Throughout Asia, Africa, Latin America and the countries of the North, there has been a growth in the number of under-age girls and boys involved in commercial sex work,&quot; Save the Children said in a report entitled &quot;Kids for Hire&quot;.</p>
<p>Both reports will be discussed at the first World Congress against the Commercial Sexual Exploitation of Children which takes place in Stockholm from August 27 to 31.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Save the Children said it was impossible to say accurately how many children were engaged in prostitution because of the illegal and hidden nature of the trade, but evidence from field workers showed it was getting worse.</p>
<p>The report said it was &quot;a major international scandal&quot; that every year thousands of children were sold, abducted or tricked into forced prostitution in countries other than their own.</p>
<p>For example, it was estimated that at least 100,000 Nepalese girls were working as prostitutes in India at any one time.</p>
<p>The main cause of child prostitution was poverty with children selling themselves to support their families, it added.</p>
<p>Sex tourism by people from rich countries was adding to the problem, it said, and men were looking for younger girls because they thought children were less likely to be tainted by AIDS.</p>
<p>The charity called on governments to implement laws allowing sex tourists to be prosecuted when they return home.</p>
<p>Barnardo's cited a UN convention calling on member states to &quot;protect the child from all forms of sexual exploitation and abuse&quot;, but said it was a complex issue.</p>
<p>Barnardo's official Sara Swann noted that most of the young Bradford girls had been put out to work by &quot;boyfriends&quot; whom they adored, despite being beaten and humiliated by them.</p>
<p>&quot;You can't force protection on a 14-year-old girl who says she's in love,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
