<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3974" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: S&amp;P rates Ostrava of Czech Republic, outlook stable.</title>
<headline>S&amp;P rates Ostrava of Czech Republic, outlook stable.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's said on Tuesday it assigned its A long-term foreign currency and A1 short-term issuer credit ratings to the City of Ostrava in the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>The outlook is stable and reflects that of the Czech Republic, S&amp;P said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Ostrava's foreign currency rating is constrained by the Czech Republic's sovereign ceiling,&quot; S&amp;P said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The ratings balance the city's strong financial performance and low debt burden with the multiple challenges of restructuring and diversifying its local industrial base, and of addressing major infrastructure needs,&quot; the agency said.</p>
<p>&quot;Strong operating balances averaging 30 percent of operating revenues over the past four years reflect prudent fiscal management, good expenditure controls and rapid growth in local tax revenues.&quot;</p>
<p>Ostrava's is the second Czech municipal rating following Prague's initial rating in 1994 and only the second municipality rated in the Central and Eastern Europe region, S&amp;P said.  </p>
<p>Ostrava with 329,000 inhabitants is the third largest city in the Czech Republic. Its economy in terms of output and employment continues to be dominated by heavy industry, particularly steel and heavy machine production.</p>
<p>Since the implementation of a new fiscal system in the early 1990s, which gave municipalities greater autonomy and own source revenues, Ostrava's financial performance has been strong, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook reflects that of the Czech Republic,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>Although Ostrava will be challenged by further industrial restructuring and decreasing state subsidies, financial performance is expected to be strong, driven by good tax revenues and prudent fiscal management, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>&quot;Additionally, the city's high self-financing level should enable future capital spending to be carried out without significant debt accumulation,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>--International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6784</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
