<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3976" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK &quot;House of Horrors&quot; police help Belgian sex case.</title>
<headline>UK &quot;House of Horrors&quot; police help Belgian sex case.</headline>
<byline>Merissa Marr</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police investigating Belgium's worst child sex scandal on Tuesday contacted the officer who led the investigation into Britain's &quot;House of Horrors&quot; serial killings in which a dozen young women were murdered.</p>
<p>The sight of Belgian police digging for bodies at the weekend evoked memories of scenes at the house of British serial killers Fred and Rosemary West, where British detectives excavated the remains of the couple's dismembered victims.</p>
<p>Belgian police had asked John Bennett, the officer who dealt with the West investigation, for advice in their search for further possible victims of an organised paedophile ring.</p>
<p>&quot;The Central Bureau of Investigation of the Belgian Police have today contacted Superintendent John Bennett and discussed aspects of their investigation because of the experience gained through the Cromwell Street enquiries,&quot; said police in Gloucestershire, where Bennett is based.</p>
<p>Apart from speaking to British colleagues, Belgian police have turned to countries such as the Czech Republic, Germany, the Netherlands and France in their search for two teenage girls who were abducted a year ago by a convicted child sex offender, according to Belgian media.</p>
<p>Fred and Rosemary West sexually abused and killed young girls and women who were then chopped up and buried beneath the cellar, bathroom and garden of a house labelled Britain's &quot;House of Horrors&quot;.</p>
<p>Police became suspicious when they could not trace their daughter Heather West and rumours led them to dig up the garden in Cromwell Street, in the western English city of Gloucester, in 1994.</p>
<p>In similar scenes, Belgian police at the weekend discovered the corpses of two eight-year-old girls thought to have been victims of an organised paedophilia ring who had been buried in a garden.</p>
<p>Convicted paedophile Marc Dutroux and associate Michel Lelievre led police to the corpses on Saturday. The two men were charged on Friday after police rescued two abducted young girls from a house owned by Dutroux.</p>
<p>The murdered eight-year-olds had been sexually abused, starved to death and buried in a garden after being kidnapped in June 1995.</p>
<p>Dutroux denied responsibility for the girls' deaths, telling police they died of starvation in late February or March while he was serving a four-month prison sentence for theft.</p>
<p>Dutroux's wife Michelle Martin was charged on Monday with being an accomplice in the abduction and illegal imprisonment of children.</p>
<p>In the West case, Rosemary West continues to protest her innocence. She was found guilty in November 1995 of murdering 10 women. Frederick  confessed to killing 12 women and girls but hanged himself in prison before he could face trial.</p>
<p>Their victims were mainly isolated young women whose disappearance went unnoticed. But they also killed their 16-year-old daughter Heather, Fred's eight-year-old stepdaughter Charmaine and a lodger who was pregnant with Fred's child.</p>
<p>The pair picked up girls and sexually tormented them before killing and burying them at their house.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
