<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3985" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Prince Charles spearheads British royal revolution.</title>
<headline>Prince Charles spearheads British royal revolution.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Reaney</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prince Charles, whose divorce from Princess Diana becomes final in a week, emerged on Tuesday as the main advocate of radical reforms of Britain's troubled monarchy to ensure it survives into the next century.</p>
<p>Buckingham Palace confirmed on Monday that the prince and other members of the Royal Family are part of a strategic policy committee considering changes.</p>
<p>But heir-to-the-throne Charles is said to be spearheading the reforms which, if enacted, could amount to the most sweeping changes to the 1,000-year-old monarchy since the 18th century.</p>
<p>Among the options being considered are ending the 8.7 million pound ($13.4 million) yearly salary the queen receives from the state, allowing the monarch to marry a Roman Catholic and changing the laws of succession to allow the oldest child, even if a daughter, to take the throne.</p>
<p>&quot;Charles is at the heart of a move for reforms...which amounts to a personal manifesto for how he wants to reign,&quot; The Daily Mail, a popular tabloid, said.</p>
<p>&quot;The heir-to-the-throne heads a secret &quot;cabinet' redesigning the monarchy,&quot; claimed The Daily Express.</p>
<p>The palace in characteristic fashion refused to divulge any details of the proposed moves or who is leading what is being dubbed a royal revolution.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a strategic committee which has the head of state, the queen, the Duke of Edinburgh (the queen's consort) and the Prince of Wales involved. It is a process of discussion and decision-making, but details of what is being discussed is something I am not prepared to go into,&quot; the prince's spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Neither are we prepared to go into the roles the individual members of the royal family play.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain's press, which follows every move of the royal family, correctly reported the breakdown of the marriages of Prince Charles and his brother Prince Andrew and other foibles long before the palace formally admitted them.</p>
<p>Newspapers said the comittee, which meets twice yearly, was formed after 1992, the year in which the royal marriages collapsed and the queen agreed to end her tax-free status.</p>
<p>Buckingham Palace said the committee has already been instrumental in the queen's decisions to pay tax and open up Buckingham palace to tourists to help pay for repairs at Windsor Castle, which was badly damaged in a fire four years ago.</p>
<p>Other moves the committee is reportedly considering are reducing the royal family to only include the monarch, the consort, their children and grandchildren and ending the the ruler's traditional role as head of the Church of England.</p>
<p>Many of the changes, including the 295-year-old ban on the British monarch marrying a Catholic and changing 11th-century rules giving boys priority over girls in succeeding to the throne, would involve changes in English law. None of the reforms are likely to be made quickly.</p>
<p>Consitutional expert David Starkey told the Daily Mail that if the moves were passed it would amount to &quot;the biggest privatisation of them all.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
