<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="3991" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-UK money growth slows, back in govt range.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-UK money growth slows, back in govt range.</headline>
<byline>Richard Murphy</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Growth in Britain's M4 money supply slowed to 8.8 percent in the year to June, the Bank of England said on Tuesday, while lending by banks and building societies continued to increase.</p>
<p>The slowdown in money supply growth from annual rates of 10 percent in May and June brought the figure back within the government's three to nine percent monitoring range for the first time since last November.</p>
<p>Some economists said it could suggest a softening in future inflationary pressures.</p>
<p>However, the British Bankers' Association said a strong 539 million pound increase in consumer credit in July could point to a strengthening of consumer spending.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength of consumer credit and housing market activity within the lending figures will be seized upon by the Bank of England as a potential threat to the inflation target,&quot; said Andrew Cates, an economist at UBS.</p>
<p>Seasonally adjusted M4 -- a broad measure of money supply which comprises notes and coins in circulation, personal and commercial bank deposits and certificates of deposit -- grew 0.4 percent in July from June, down from 0.7 percent in June.</p>
<p>Strong money supply growth is often seen as a pointer to future inflation and central bank Governor Eddie George has warned that interest rates might have to rise if it continued unchecked.</p>
<p>However, its reliability has been thrown into question this year because of special distorting factors such as a rash of corporate mergers and acquisitions.</p>
<p>The slowdown will, therefore, offer little new ammunition to Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke if he wants to cut interest rates again this autumn.</p>
<p>Clarke has cut rates four times since last December to their present 5.75 percent level, overruling the Bank of England on the last occasion in June. With an election looming by May 1997, he has a strong political incentive to do so again.</p>
<p>Jonathan Loynes, an economist at HSBC Midland, said money supply worries would not disappear overnight.</p>
<p>&quot;But with the Bank of England having singled out M4 as a key area of concern in its last inflation report, these numbers should at least help to calm fears of possible inflation dangers ahead.&quot;</p>
<p>The bankers' association said total sterling lending by major banks rose 2.677 billion pounds in July, below the recent average. But consumer credit rose strongly and mortgage lending showed continued steady growth.</p>
<p>Home loan approvals reported by the Building Societies Association (BSA) rose 3.768 billion pounds in July.</p>
<p>&quot;Transactions have been increasing since April and house prices have also been rising, encouraging more sellers into the market,&quot; said BSA deputy director general Ron Armstrong.</p>
<p>As well as being an important indicator of economic activity, the housing market is a key determinant of the so-called &quot;feel-good factor&quot; in a nation of home-owners.</p>
<p>&quot;The housing data are buoyant,&quot; said Michael Saunders, an economist at Salomon Brothers in London.</p>
<p>&quot;We suspect that the housing data again will be the more reliable guide to the real economy and that the real economy is accelerating and will continue to do so in coming months.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
