<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4002" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Halifax profits rise as float looms.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Halifax profits rise as float looms.</headline>
<byline>Jill Treanor</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's largest mortgage lender Halifax Building Society on Tuesday reported half year profits of 649 million pounds ($1 billion) and said its 10 billiion pound stock market flotation was on track for June 1997.</p>
<p>However, the society said its share of Britain's reviving housing market slipped as it took a 7.2 percent share of net mortage lending in the first half of the year and 15.2 percent of gross mortgage lending.</p>
<p>Halifax spokesman Gary Marsh told Reuters in an interview these levels were below its normal market share of around 20 percent because it had shied away from re-mortgaging which accounted for 30 percent of the total mortgage market.</p>
<p>The size of the re-mortgage market -- when borrowers do not move home but are lured by another lenders -- reflects the low level of transactions from home movers, said Marsh.</p>
<p>One analyst said the slip reflected the society's pursuit of profits as it prepared for a stock market flotation and a distinction from those societies which did not intend to leave the mutually-owned sector.</p>
<p>Building societies are owned by their savers and borrowers who will share in the proceeds of the flotations of those societies which intend to become banks next year.</p>
<p>However, societies which intend to remain owned by their members say they can undercut the mortgage rates offered by their soon-to-be-banking rivals as they do not have to satisify shareholders' demands for profits.</p>
<p>Marsh said Halifax members -- savers and borrowers -- would find out their share in the new bank with the publication of the new transfer document early next year.</p>
<p>They will vote on the flotation in February 1997 which means the flotation would probably take place in June, he added.</p>
<p>Most of the ten largest societies are seeking flotations to become banks because they say this gives them the ability to diversify from their traditional home-loan provider roots.</p>
<p>Halifax is already diversifing. It is in the process of merging with insurance group Clerical Medical and merged last year with rival building society Leeds Permanent.</p>
<p>This, along with the flotation, means further acquisitions are unlikely this year. &quot;We look at non-organic as well as organic growth, but that's the story for 1997,&quot; said Marsh.</p>
<p>He said that so far this year net mortgage lending is eight billion pounds and forecasts a figure of 16 billion pounds by year-end. But that is dwarfed by the 40 billion pounds of net lending in the boom year of 1988, said Marsh.</p>
<p>&quot;Transactions are still at very low levels...but coming back quite nicely,&quot; said Marsh, adding the housing market was showing signs of making a sustainable recovery which would avoid the previous boom/bust cycle.</p>
<p>The pick-up in the housing market has been fuelled by a low inflation, low interest environment, Halifax said, pointing to the lowest mortgage rates in Britain for 30 years.</p>
<p>But a further cut in the Bank of England's official 5.75 percent base rate might not feed through to mortgages.</p>
<p>&quot;If they (base rates) were to come down another quarter point you wouldn't necessarily expect further cuts in mortgage rates,&quot; said Marsh.</p>
<p>Halifax's benchmark standard variable mortgage rate is 6.99 percent, higher then the the largest remaining building society Nationwide which has a 6.49 percent rate.</p>
<p>Halifax said its 649 million pounds of half year profits represents a rise of six percent rise over the six month period to January 31. It is changing its year end from January 31 to December 31. ($1=.6466 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
