<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4013" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan's king collects pledges of loyalty.</title>
<headline>Jordan's king collects pledges of loyalty.</headline>
<byline>Dominic Evans</byline>
<dateline>RAMTHA, Jordan 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>King Hussein went to the north of Jordan on Tuesday to receive pledges of loyalty from officials and tribal leaders in the wake of rioting in the south that has led to widespread arrests.</p>
<p>King Hussein, repeatedly cheered by a crowd assembled on a plain outside Ramtha town near the Syrian border, said Jordanians had shown it was &quot;one great country always resolutely standing together in the face of all threats.&quot;</p>
<p>The king, who has vowed to crush the riots that followed a government decision to double bread prices, said the country had stood for &quot;dialogue and democracy and respect for human rights under the order of law in the face of all commotion.&quot;</p>
<p>Tribal elders and local officials gave speeches of praise and loyalty, part of an effort to show the king's continued popularity. State media carried scores of &quot;loyalty and support&quot; cables to the king from municipality chiefs, dignitaries and leading tribesmen -- his traditional bedrock support.</p>
<p>Armoured vehicles continued to patrol the southern city of Karak, the centre of two days of unrest that shook the kingdom last weekend, but security forces eased a curfew.</p>
<p>&quot;As of today people will be allowed to move for 10 hours a day at different intervals, from two hours at present. This will be increased depending on the situation before it is totally lifted when authorities deem that possible,&quot; an official said.</p>
<p>Security forces had detained up to 150 people since Friday, including 100 in Karak, an official said. Many were released while others will face trial, he said. Karak residents said 300 people had been detained but many were already free.</p>
<p>At least 14 leaders of a pro-Iraqi party blamed by King Hussein for inciting the riots had been arrested, officials said.</p>
<p>The Jordanian Arab Socialist Baath Party has rejected the king's accusations. Government critics and demonstrators said the unrest stemmed from rising economic hardship.</p>
<p>An Iraqi radio report, monitored by the British Broadcasting Corporation, denied Iraq was involved and accused the Jordanian government of bringing trouble on itself by unpopular policies.</p>
<p>Iraq's &quot;Mother of Battles Radio&quot;, a service for the Arab world, said on Monday night the rioting had been an explosion of popular anger with no outside intervention.</p>
<p>Once close relations between Jordan and Iraq collapsed a year ago after King Hussein gave refuge to defectors from Baghdad, including two sons-in-law of President Saddam Hussein, and called for change in Iraq.</p>
<p>King Hussein last week suspended the summer session of parliament, vowed an &quot;iron fist&quot; response to the country's worst unrest since 1989 and threw his weight behind the government of Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti who is trying to implement reforms backed by the International Monetary Fund.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RAMTHA, Jordan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
