<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4020" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Russia's Zhirinovsky vows to end embargo on Iraq.</title>
<headline>Russia's Zhirinovsky vows to end embargo on Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Hassan Hafidh</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian ultra-nationalist leader Vladimir Zhirinovsky vowed on Tuesday to mount pressure on the Russian government to help end U.N. trade sanctions on Iraq and blamed Moscow for delaying the establishment of good ties with Baghdad.</p>
<p>&quot;We are the (Russian) liberal democratic party...We will press the Russian government to lift the embargo,&quot; Zhirinovsky said on the second day of his visit to Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;Our stand is firm namely we are calling on (the Russian government) to end the economic embargo on Iraq and resume trade ties between Russia and Iraq,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Iraq is under crippling United Nations trade sanctions imposed after its 1990 invasion of Kuwait. The curbs include a ban on Iraq's oil exports and imports of goods apart from humanitarian needs for which Iraq has little cash to pay.</p>
<p>Baghdad signed on May 20 an agreement with the U.N. allowing it partial oil sales worth $2 billion every six months to buy food and medicine for the Iraqi people.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the deal) is a postive apportunity for Iraq to buy food and medicine...but the main goal is ending the embargo completely,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He also attacked the Russian government, blaming it for delaying enhanced ties with Baghdad.</p>
<p>&quot;Iraq is ready to improve bilateral relations but Russia is delaying that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said his party encouraged the establishment of a joint Iraqi-Russian company called Babylon in order to export foodstuffs, medicines and construction materials to Baghdad.</p>
<p>Zhirinovsky visited Iraq twice in 1995. Last October he was one of the figures invited to attend the referendum held on Iraq's presidency, which extended Saddam's term of office for seven more years.</p>
<p>Zhirinovsky polled only six percent of the vote in the first round of Russia's presidential elections.</p>
<p>Russia, supported by France and China, all permanent members of the U.N. Security Council, want a gradual easing of the sanctions on Iraq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
