<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4024" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares firm 1.5 pct in higher volume.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares firm 1.5 pct in higher volume.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish shares rose by 1.52 percent on Tuesday amid reaction buys which also caused turnover to increase, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's upward movement was mainly a reaction to the recent falls and I don't think it will last long. Tomorrow I expect the market to start with a rise but profit sales will come. I think the market will end the week at these levels,&quot; said Fahri Arabacioglu from Kentbank.</p>
<p>The IMKB-100 gained 1.52 percent or 947.77 points to end at 63,369.69. Daily volume rose to 5.09 trillion lira from Monday's 4.7 trillion.</p>
<p>Brokers said they expected horizontal and selective trade within 62,000-64,000 this week in limited cash entry as expectations had ended after firms' half-year profits had been announced.</p>
<p>But next week the index could spur higher if expectations on unaudited third quarter company results started.</p>
<p>The index shed 4.16 percent last week, after 2.1 percent a week earlier.</p>
<p>The market has been in a sharp downtrend since its record high of 73,531.3 on July 8, diving 15.04 percent since then.</p>
<p>The session's most active shares were those of the textile firm Akin Tekstil which gained 1,300 lira to end at 9,200. Shares of utility Aktas Elektrik also rose by 20,000 lira to 450,000.</p>
<p>The 85-share industrial index rose by 1.25 percent to 70,326.27 and the 15-share financial index jumped by 2.23 percent to 54,456.90.</p>
<p>Of the 219 shares traded, gainers outdid losers by 140 to 37 and 42 shares were stable.</p>
<p>-- Istanbul Newsroom, +90-212-275 0875</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
