<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4025" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan stocks improve after falling on bread riots.</title>
<headline>Jordan stocks improve after falling on bread riots.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordanian share prices improved on Tuesday after security forces eased a curfew in the southern town of Karak after protests against bread price hikes and the government proclaimed the crisis over.</p>
<p>The official Amman Financial Market 60-share index firmed 0.33 percent to 139.08 from 138.63 points on Monday but failed to jump over the 140 point psychological barrier.</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected the upward trend to continue now that the government appeared in control following riots that broke out in Karak on Friday and spread to nearby towns, forcing King Hussein to send in his army to restore order.</p>
<p>&quot;Investor confidence is starting to pick up,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;And the more things get under control the better the market will do even though business levels before the unrest were not that great.&quot;</p>
<p>The riots, the worst since 1989 unrest, were fuelled by the government's decision on Tuesday to almost double prices of bread in line with IMF-agreed economic reforms.</p>
<p>The market fell beyond the 140 point psychological barrier on Saturday and continued to ease before picking up.</p>
<p>A total of 153,851 shares changed hands in a bigger 515,929 dinar turnover in a cash-squeezed market, with no demand from foreign investors.</p>
<p>The market first broke the 140-point barrier at the end of June and has since slid to levels not reached since 1993. But it began a gradual pickup in trade at the start of last week.</p>
<p>Investors are eyeing half-year results and any signs of a possible easing of interest rates after prices dropped to near bottom levels.</p>
<p>The Pearl Investable Index -- an independent index of the 45 best-performing shares from the official market -- firmed 0.09 percent to 79.85 points. It was 16.40 percent down on last year.</p>
<p>Along with lack of institutional support, the market has suffered since the start of the year from a liquidity crunch blamed on high interest rates by the state to protect the dinar.</p>
<p>Large investors and institutions have avoided the market, which has fallen over 20 percent this year, with most of the trading dominated by floor traders.</p>
<p>Banks dominated on a 259,445 dinar turnover and an index rise of 0.67 percent, industrials had a 210,595 dinar turnover and an index fall of 0.09 percent while services had a 43,395 dinar turnover and an index rise of 0.22.</p>
<p>A total of 150,042 shares worth 85,779 dinars changed hands in weak trade in the parallel market.</p>
<p>--  Amman newsroom takes queries on +962 6 623 776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
