<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4027" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Celik Halat likely to miss sales target.</title>
<headline>Celik Halat likely to miss sales target.</headline>
<byline>Osman Senkul</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish steel wire and rope producer Celik Halat is likely to miss its 1996 export and domestic sales targets due to contraction in domestic and international markets, a senior firm official said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our export target was to match the 1995 level of $17 million. We think we will push up our exports to $15 million in 1996, 15 percent below the target,&quot; Gunay, board member and general manager of the company, told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>He blamed poor export performance on &quot;recession in Western markets.&quot;</p>
<p>The company is not able to achieve its target of increasing 1995 domestic sales by 15 percent because of political crisis in the first half of the year in which state run customers halted purchases, he said.</p>
<p>The firm's 1995 domestic sales were 1.06 trillion lira.</p>
<p>Many state companies did not open tender during the political turmoil which erupted in late September 1995 and hampered the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;But we are hopeful for the future begining from 1997. We started a $6 million production capacity expansion investment. About $2.5 million of it will be realised this year,&quot; Gunay added.</p>
<p>Celik Halat is now searching for new export markets such as Pakistan, Bangladesh, Portugal, Slovenia and Hungary.</p>
<p>Despite bleak picture in 1996, Gunay said Celik Halat needed to increase its capacity.</p>
<p>&quot;Because we are operating almost at full capacity with three shifts a day...our total production capacity will climb to 47,000 tonnes from the current 41,000 tonnes.&quot;</p>
<p>Celik Halat has a 65 percent stake in the domestic market.</p>
<p>A new competitor -- Beksa, a joint venture of Turkey's leading Sabanci Group and Belgium's Bekaert -- has begun test production.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't expect Beksa to enter into market and create competition before 1998,&quot; Gunay said. &quot;We will be competing in steel wires which are used in tyre manufacturing after then.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Cheap products from the East European countries are our main problem. They are cheaper by some 40 percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The company has applied to the Foreign Trade Undersecretary last week with damping charges against East European goods.</p>
<p>Celik Halat sells steel wires to tyre producers in Turkey, like Bridgestone, Goodyear and Pirelli.</p>
<p>The company reported 1.21 trillion lira of total sales in the first half, up from 806 billion lira in the same 1995 period. Its net profit went up to 158 billion lira from 49 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
