<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4030" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>YEMEN: Eritrea to remove troops from disputed island.</title>
<headline>Eritrea to remove troops from disputed island.</headline>
<dateline>SANAA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yemen said on Tuesday that France had assured it that Eritrea would pull out troops from a disputed Red Sea island by Friday at the latest.</p>
<p>&quot;French envoy Francis Gutman told me that Eritrea will withdraw from the (Lesser Hanish) island next Friday as a maximum date,&quot; Yemeni President Ali Abdullah Saleh told a group of judges.</p>
<p>France said on Monday that Eritrea had agreed to withdraw its forces from the island, cooling a dispute with Yemen that had threatened to derail an arbitration accord between the two Red Sea states signed in Paris in May.</p>
<p>&quot;Eritrea is going to withdraw from this island. In this way the arbitration procedure intended to peacefully resolve the two nations' differences can now proceed normally,&quot; a French Foreign Ministry spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>There has been no confirmation from Eritrea of the decision.</p>
<p>Yemen earlier threatened to take military action against Eritrea if mediation failed to defuse the crisis triggered by its sending troops to the island earlier this month.</p>
<p>Both states claim islands, which lie near tanker routes at the Red Sea's southern entrance, and fought briefly over them last December.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ERTRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANAA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YEMEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
