<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4038" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan eases curfew in Karak, arrests pro-Iraqis.</title>
<headline>Jordan eases curfew in Karak, arrests pro-Iraqis.</headline>
<byline>Rana Sabbagh</byline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordanian security forces eased a curfew in the southern town of Karak on Tuesday and have seized at least 14 leaders of a pro-Iraqi party blamed by King Hussein for inciting bread riots there, government officials said.</p>
<p>Armoured vehicles patrolled Karak where two days of riots began last Friday in protest against the government's doubling of bread prices under reforms backed by the International Monetary Fund (IMF).</p>
<p>&quot;Things are quiet in Karak,&quot; one government official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Another official said the curfew in Karak would be gradually eased.</p>
<p>&quot;As of today, Tuesday, people will be allowed to move for 10 hours a day at different intervals, from two hours at present. This will be increased depending on the situation before it is totally lifted when authorities deem that possible,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The first official said security forces since Friday had detained up to 150 people, including 100 in Karak. Many were released while others will be sent to court for trial, he said.</p>
<p>Those arrested included at least 14 leaders of the Jordanian Arab Socialist Baath Party, a pro-Iraqi organisation that King Hussein had blamed for the riots, the official said.</p>
<p>Three of the leaders were named as Omar Abu El-Ragheb, Ali Hyasat and Yasin Umoush.</p>
<p>Party officials were not available for comment. The party earlier denied any involvement in the unrest which government critics blamed on rising economic hardship and poverty.</p>
<p>Residents in Karak said 300 people there had been detained since Friday but many were already released.</p>
<p>An Iraqi radio station, in a report monitored by the British Broadcasting Corporation, denied that Iraq was behind the unrest and accused the Jordanian government of bringing trouble on itself through its pursuit of policies opposed by the people.</p>
<p>Iraq's &quot;Mother of Battles Radio&quot;, an external service for the Arab world, said on Monday night that the rioting had been an explosion of popular anger, with no outside intervention.</p>
<p>&quot;Every citizen in sisterly Jordan understands this, and knows that the government's attempts to accuse certain parties are a distortion of facts and an avoidance of reality,&quot; the radio said.</p>
<p>Once close relations between Jordan and Iraq deteriorated sharply a year ago when King Hussein gave refuge to two defectors from Baghdad, both sons-in-law of President Saddam Hussein, and called for change in Iraq.</p>
<p>Unrest broke out in Karak after noon prayers on Friday, three days after the government enforced the new bread prices. Riots quickly spread to nearby villages, prompting the king to send in the army to calm unrest. Violence also broke out in a working-class district of central Amman.</p>
<p>King Hussein suspended the summer session of parliament, vowed to stop the unrest with an &quot;iron fist&quot; and has thrown his full weight behind the government of Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti who has borne the brunt of widespread criticism.</p>
<p>State-run media carried scores of &quot;loyalty and support&quot; cables sent to the king from municipality chiefs, dignitaries and leading tribesmen -- his traditional bedrock support. The monarch had lunch with a leading tribe in northern Jordan on Tuesday.</p>
<p>While the government has proclaimed the crisis over, Karak residents say the government's use of force did not address their grievances and could precipitate more trouble once the army leaves.</p>
<p>The violence was the most serious in Jordan since 1989 when government price rises also sparked off riots. The king responded then by changing his prime minister and starting democratic reforms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
