<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4043" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt shuns U.S. SR wheat, eyes Europe, Argentina.</title>
<headline>Egypt shuns U.S. SR wheat, eyes Europe, Argentina.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egypt has delayed any purchases of U.S. soft red wheat for now after buying U.S. soft white wheat at the weekend, and is exploring European and Argentinan markets, its main commodities buyer said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're turning to European and Argentine wheat and hope they will offer competitive prices,&quot; Samir Shakankiri, vice president of the state's General Authority for Supply Commodities (GASC) told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We've delayed buying red American wheat for the time being and instead are exploring a variety of sources,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>On Saturday, GASC said it was seeking 50,000 tonnes of soft red French wheat for shipment in October or September and Shakankiri said he had already contacted Argentine exporters.</p>
<p>Egypt bought 150,000 tonnes of U.S. soft white wheat at $187.70 and $187.75 on Saturday and Sunday after originally seeking 50,000 tonnes of soft red or soft white wheat.</p>
<p>&quot;We're increasing our sources to include other types of wheat which GASC deals in,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>U.S. exporters said Egypt was avoiding American soft red wheat because its vomitoxin content exceeded the two parts per million (ppm) specified by the GASC and had paid a premium of up to $2.00 a tonne for the fungus-free white wheat.</p>
<p>Vomitoxin, a toxin produced by the fusarium fungus, has been recorded in heavy concentrations of up to 15 ppm in U.S. soft red wheat in parts of Ohio, Indiana and Michigan this summer.</p>
<p>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration advises a limit of one ppm of vomitoxin in grain for human consumption.</p>
<p>Shakankiri said Egypt's soft red wheat supplies were currently enough to cover local demand and that any wheat he would buy would be according to the conditions set by the GASC. --Miral Fahmy, Cairo newsroom +202 578 3290/91</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
