<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4051" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel to study initial public offerings of banks.</title>
<headline>Israel to study initial public offerings of banks.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Israeli government will consider selling shares in state-owned banks through international public offerings, a government source said.</p>
<p>Last week a group of investors led by Claridge, the Israeli investment vehicle of Canadian businessman Charles Bronfman, told the government it was dropping its bid for a controlling stake in Bank Hapoalim. The group was the main bidder for a stake in Israel's largest bank.</p>
<p>Meir Jacobson, managing director of the government's M.I. Holdings, in charge of privatising Israel's banks, said he recently submitted a proposal to the government for public offerings of the banks on U.S. and European stock markets.</p>
<p>Jacobson specified that the proposal refers to all the banks that have to be privatised and not specifically to Hapoalim.</p>
<p>He said a similar proposal had been raised previously, but was put on hold while discussions were going on with private investors interested in purchasing stakes in the banks.</p>
<p>The other group interested in purchasing control of Bank Hapoalim, led by Israeli businessman Eliezer Fishman, has yet to receive approval from the central Bank of Israel to bid for Hapoalim. The group includes Bear Stearns.</p>
<p>The government also intends to privatise its other banks including Leumi, Israel's second biggest bank. Leumi's privatisation has been stalled since last year when the only bidder for a controlling stake, Edmond Safra of Republic Bank, withdrew his bid.</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
