<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4063" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NOTICE OF SALE--Kern Community College Dist, Calif.</title>
<headline>NOTICE OF SALE--Kern Community College Dist, Calif.</headline>
<text>
<p>NOTICE OF INTENTION</p>
<p>			 Not To Exceed $13,000,000</p>
<p>		    Kern Community College District</p>
<p>			 (Kern County, California)</p>
<p>		 Limited Obligation Improvement Bonds</p>
<p>		    Kern Community College District</p>
<p>		   Assessment District, Series 1996</p>
<p>NOTICE IS HEREBY GIVEN,  pursuant to California Government Code Section 53692, that the Board  of Trustees of the  Kern Community College District, Kern County, California, intends to sell not to exceed  $13,000,000 principal amount of  Kern Community College  District Limited  Obligation Bonds  (Kern Community  College  District  Assessment  District),  Series 1996. Bids will be received on at 10:00 a.m., at the offices of Dale Scott &amp;Company,  Inc. 400 Montgomery Street,  Suite 805,  San Francisco,  CA94104, telephone (415) 956-1030 or by facsimile at (415)  956-1322, and the sale will be awarded  by the Chancellor of the  Kern Community College District or his designee on behalf of  the Board of  Trustees of  the Kern  Community College  District within twenty-six  (26)  hours  after  the  bid  opening  is  completed.  In  the  event   that  the  Chancellor  or   his</p>
<p>authorized designee  does  not  award  a  bid  on  the  date specified above, proposals  will be  received the  following Wednesday at the  same time  and place  specified above  and each Wednesday  thereafter  until  such time  as  a  bid  is  awarded  or  notice  to  the  contrary  is  given.   Further</p>
<p>information, including  copies of  the Preliminary  Official Statement, Official  Notice of  Sale and  Bid Form,  may  be obtained from the Financial Advisor at the above address. Dated:August 15, 1996</p>
<p>			  (From The Bond Buyer)</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
