<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4079" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USWC crude up with WTI, diffs flat with deal seen.</title>
<headline>USWC crude up with WTI, diffs flat with deal seen.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast light crude prices continued rising with cash West Texas Intermediate, while differentials coasted at last week's levels amid razor-thin business late Monday.</p>
<p>Activity ground to a near halt as traders left for a industry golf game.</p>
<p>Players heard talk that a major West Coast refiner bought a cargo of Alaska North Slope (ANS) early from the ANS's main seller.</p>
<p>The cargo reportedly sold for $1.95 off September WTI, the level of the last deal, done August 14.  </p>
<p>Northwest refiners said they were waiting for the results of Monday's pipe line nominations on the Inter Provincial Pipe Line (IPL) in Canada's midwest.</p>
<p>Surplus from the line could move west, offsetting their need to buy ANS, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It depends on (the grade's) price,&quot; one refinery trader said, adding his basic needs were filled, but he might need extra.</p>
<p>Prices for Kern River and Wilmington were notionally flat, as postings were unchanged from mid-July.</p>
<p>Prices for Line 63 tracked higher WTI values, with traders reporting no new deals.</p>
<p>Pre-nominations for Line 63 shipments will begin Tuesday traders said, with little change from last month's restrictions.</p>
<p>-- David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles bureau +1 213 380 2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
