<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4103" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Vermont's unemployment rate in July edges up again.</title>
<headline>Vermont's unemployment rate in July edges up again.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vermont on Tuesday said that its unemployment rate in July edged up one-tenth of a percentage point to 4.2 percent, the third month in a row that the gauge has risen, but the state dismissed the latest rise.</p>
<p>&quot;The increase is modest, however, and fundamental labor market conditions remained unchanged,&quot; said Susan Auld, the commissioner of Vermont's Department of Employment and Training, in prepared remarks.</p>
<p>Out of a total labor force of 323,100 people, approximately 309,500 people were working in July.</p>
<p>In June, when the unemployment rate stood at 4.1 percent, about 13,100 people were employed out of a total workforce of 321,900.</p>
<p>In July 1995, when the unemployment rate was 4.3 percent, there were about 305,300 people working out of a total labor force of 319,000, the state department said.</p>
<p>Unemployment rates for Vermont's 13 labor markets ranged from as low as 1.7 percent in Hartford-Lebanon to as high as 6.7 percent in Newport. These data, unlike the preceeding numbers, were not seasonally adjusted.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
