<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4139" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lie detector clears Olympic bomb suspect - paper.</title>
<headline>Lie detector clears Olympic bomb suspect - paper.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Olympic bomb suspect Richard Jewell passed a lie detector test in which he denied any involvement in the deadly July 27 attack, the Atlanta Journal- Constitution reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A polygrapher hired by the security guard's lawyers told the newspaper that the test results showed Jewell had nothing to do with the pipe bombing that left two people dead and more than 100 injured at downtown Atlanta's Centennial Olympic Park.</p>
<p>&quot;He didn't do it,&quot; Dick Rackleff, a former FBI agent now in private practice, said. &quot;There's not any doubt in my mind. He had no knowledge about the bomb. The tests show he absolutely was not involved.&quot;</p>
<p>Jewell, 33, who was hailed as a hero in the immediate aftermath of the bombing, still remains a suspect in the FBI's investigation. He has steadfastly maintained his innocence.</p>
<p>While working as a security guard at an AT&amp;T Olympic pavilion near the park, he discovered the green knapsack that contained the pipe bomb and helped police clear crowds from the area before it detonated.</p>
<p>In recent weeks, members of his legal team increasingly have gone public to support their client.</p>
<p>His criminal lawyer, Jack Martin, held a news conference near the bomb site to announce to reporters that the timing of the explosion and the bomb threat call to police ruled out any involvement by Jewell.</p>
<p>On Monday two civil attorneys newly hired by the security guard said they were looking into the possibility of suing the FBI, the news media and others over the way Jewell had been treated since the attack.</p>
<p>The polygrapher told the Journal-Constitution he spent 15 hours with Jewell on Aug. 4 and 15 while conducting the lie detector test and a pre-test interview.</p>
<p>Rackleff said he would stake his reputation on the findings. &quot;It's not a matter of choosing sides. It's a matter of establishing facts,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
