<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4148" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sprint Corp is expected to enter the race to make the Internet as widespread for customers as the telephone, The Wall Street Journal reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The telecommunications giant, which has 15 million customers and nearly $13 billion in annual revenue, plans to announce on Tuesday a new Internet-access service aimed at consumers, a Sprint executive said.</p>
<p>Although Sprint has been operating a major portion of the Internet since 1992 to serve businesses, the Kansas City, Mo., company has yet to target residential customers, a move that many industry watchers have been waiting for.</p>
<p>The newspaper also reported:</p>
<p>* Commonwealth Aluminum Corp will buy CasTech Aluminum Group Inc for $272.7 million.</p>
<p>* Chrysler Corp and Detroit Diesel Corp will announce plans on Tuesday to open an assembly plant in Brazil.</p>
<p>* U.S. economists are warming up to the idea of an economic slowdown in the second half of 1996.</p>
<p>* AT&amp;T Corp president Alex Mandl resigns to head tiny start-up company, Associated Communications Corp.</p>
<p>* The Dow Jones Industrial Average rose 9.99 points to 5,699.44. The Nasdaq composite index fell 2.74 points to 1,130.91.</p>
<p>* Department of Agriculture says farm cooperatives earned a record $2.4 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>* PepsiCo Inc launched a legal challenge in Venezuela to void the joint venture by Coca-Cola Co and the Cisneros Group, Pepsi's long-time bottler in Venezuela.</p>
<p>* Russian President Boris Yeltsin signs measures aimed at boosting revenues and slashing some of his most lavish campaign spending promises.</p>
<p>* A Sanyo Electric Co executive kidnapped in Mexico has been released. There was no word about whether a ransom was paid.</p>
<p>* Germany's Mercedes-Benz AG and Porsche AG are in talks to make a sport-utility vehicle.</p>
<p>-- New York newsroom, (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
