<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4152" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole slices into Clinton's lead, polls show.</title>
<headline>Dole slices into Clinton's lead, polls show.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole got a boost from his party's convention and has sliced into President Bill Clinton's still-solid lead, a New York Times/CBS News poll reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But the survey showed that many voters still are sceptical about Dole's tax-cut proposal and are split in their opinion about the former Kansas senator himself.</p>
<p>The poll showed 50 percent of registered voters surveyed would support Clinton, a Democrat, and Vice President Al Gore if the election were held today, while 39 percent backed Dole and his running mate Jack Kemp.</p>
<p>The 11-point gap represents a gain of 5 percentage points for Dole and a loss of 6 for Clinton compared with a Times/CBS News poll taken shortly before last week's Republican Party convention.</p>
<p>A separate CNN/USA Today/Gallup Poll put Dole's lead at 7 points, with Clinton ahead 48 percent to Dole's 41 percent. The poll said Dole picked up 11 points since the Republican convention, largely due to the selection of Jack Kemp as his running mate.</p>
<p>In a three-way race, 49 percent of voters in the Times/CBS poll said they would back Clinton, 37 percent would support Dole and 8 percent said they would vote for Ross Perot, the billionaire candidate of the Reform Party.</p>
<p>On Dole's proposal for a 15 percent tax cut along with a balanced budget, 32 percent of those surveyed said they thought taxes would go up if he were elected in November.</p>
<p>Twenty-four percent said taxes would decrease and 40 percent said they would stay the same.</p>
<p>Sixty-three percent of respondents said Dole had not explained his economic plan enough versus 27 percent who said he had.</p>
<p>Twenty-nine percent of voters had a favourable opinion of Dole and 32 percent did not. Fifty-four percent said he had made it clear what he wanted to do as president, and 40 percent said he had not.</p>
<p>The poll of 1,138 adults was conducted Friday through Sunday and has a margin of error of plus or minus three percentage points.</p>
<p>The CNN/USA Today/Gallup poll was based on interviews with 1,006 registered voters from Friday through Sunday and also had a margin of error of 3 percentage points .</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
