<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4155" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: California asks U.S. to repay its Civil War debt.</title>
<headline>California asks U.S. to repay its Civil War debt.</headline>
<byline>Adam Entous</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>California's state Senate passed a resolution Monday urging President Clinton and the Congress to reimburse the state for expenses it incurred during the Civil War.</p>
<p>Republican Assemblyman Mickey Conroy's resolution moved with little fanfare through the state Legislature. It was approved late Monday by the Senate by a vote of 32-to-1. It was backed earlier this year in the state Assembly.</p>
<p>The resolution &quot;memorializes&quot; Clinton and Congress to enact legislation that would finally repay the long-forgotten Civil War debt, now estimated to be worth $82 million.</p>
<p>Conroy maintains the Civil War debt represents the first unfunded mandate imposed on California by Washington.</p>
<p>In the early 1860s, the Congress and the administration of President Abraham Lincoln solicited financial support from the states -- California in particular -- with promises of repayment.</p>
<p>In 1863, California sold $668,570.86 in bonds to raise and maintain troops who joined the Union cause in the Civil War.</p>
<p>By 1865, California had raised a state militia of more than 13,000 men and enlisted nearly 16,000 who were mustered into Union service as California volunteers.</p>
<p>In the years after the war, the federal government reimbursed 25 states for their expenses. But California's debt remained unrecognized due to bureaucratic rules in Washington.</p>
<p>For decades following the Civil War, California officials demanded the money from Washington. But when the last court case involving the bonds closed in 1954, the issue faded.</p>
<p>The debate was revived in 1963, when then-state Attorney General Stanley Mosk called on the Senate to make good on the debt. Five years later, California Gov. Ronald Reagan took up the war bond banner in his skirmishes with Washington. But even Reagan would fail to secure repayment.</p>
<p>After Reagan, the issue was largely forgotten until 1995, when Rick Stevenson, a former president of the Sacramento, California, Historical Society and a Civil War expert, convinced Assemblyman Conroy to take up the cause.</p>
<p>According to Conroy's resolution, the state today could claim more than $81.7 million from the federal government, a figure that includes compounded interest over the years.</p>
<p>&quot;Historical evidence strongly suggests the federal government should have fully reimbursed the state for these bonds more than 100 years ago,&quot; a 1995 report by the state Assembly Office of Research concluded.</p>
<p>If the federal government repays the obligation, state officials said the money would be used to establish a military museum dedicated to California's veterans, including those of the Civil War.</p>
<p>Stevenson hailed the Senate vote on the resolution.</p>
<p>&quot;But the battle is not over,&quot; he said. &quot;The battle's not over until we get the money.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
