<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4161" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Children become focus of Weld-Kerry Senate debate.</title>
<headline>Children become focus of Weld-Kerry Senate debate.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two politically moderate millionaires from Massachusetts battling for a U.S. Senate seat Monday night debated a range of issues that always seemed to come back to children.</p>
<p>Massachusetts Republican Gov. William Weld, who is challenging Democratic incumbent Sen. John Kerry, has named welfare, taxes and crime as his big three issues, and took some heat for not naming education, which is the second largest industry in the state.</p>
<p>Weld defended himself saying, &quot;We are spending $1.2 billion a year more on K(indergarten) through 12(th grade) education than we did in fiscal '92. That's the biggest shift in budget priorities we've made.&quot;</p>
<p>But Kerry noted a recent General Accounting Office study found 92 percent of the schools in Massachusetts &quot;are in disrepair ... Education is the single most important thing we need to do in America. The Republicans are cutting Head Start. The Republicans are cutting safe and drug-free schools.&quot;</p>
<p>No matter the question, whether it was about personal sacrifice to the possible legalisation of assisted suicide, Kerry was able to turn it around to children.</p>
<p>When asked about any personal sacrifice he had made in his career, Kerry replied: &quot;I would not say that being in public life is a sacrifice...there are things that you pay as a price and that is what happens to our children.&quot;</p>
<p>He said being in Washington so much kept him from seeing them and being there for them.</p>
<p>When asked about legalising assisted suicide, he said: &quot;What I'd rather see us spending more time on ... is not how we're going to help people die, but how we're going to help people live beginning with children. And the fact is we have got an awful lot of kids who are increasingly in poverty.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
