<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4165" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: APRIL Group says pulp,rayon prices hurt Q2.</title>
<headline>APRIL Group says pulp,rayon prices hurt Q2.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Asia Pacific Resources Internatitonal Holdings Ltd, also known as the APRIL Group, said on Monday its second-quarter results were hurt by lower world prices for pulp and rayon fiber.</p>
<p>The Singapore-based company posted a net loss of $0.14 per share compared to a net profit of $0.11 per share the same period last year. Net sales for the quarter dropped 26 percent to $95.7 million.</p>
<p>The company said the average realized price of blended pulp dropped 59 percent and rayon fell 26 percent compared to last year.</p>
<p>But the company's finance director, Berry Kwock, said he is encouraged by the recovery in pulp prices over the last two months and the improvements in its Riaupulp unit's performance.</p>
<p>&quot;We are also very pleased with the ease with which Indorayon can switch between dissolving pulp and paper pulp production as this allows us to maximize sales and earnings by taking into account market pricing trends,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Higher interest charges in the second quarter also affected the company's profits. The higher charges came from long-term debt obligations incurred during the year.</p>
<p>APRIL Group said it expects the interest costs to be reduced in the second half of the year because of the ongoing conversion to U.S. dollar-denominated obligations.</p>
<p>The APRIL Group, a pan-Asian pulp and rayon fiber producer, said its projects in China are expected to start up in the latter half of 1998.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
