<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4168" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US W.Coast products steady as few traders in market.</title>
<headline>US W.Coast products steady as few traders in market.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast product prices were little changed in lifeless trade on Monday and players said ranges were hard to discern as most traders were attending an industry social event.</p>
<p>Traders saw prices falling modestly this week, with refinery problems resolved and production relatively normal.</p>
<p>CARB-grade gasoline in Los Angeles was up one cent from Friday to 68/69 cents a gallon, with premium four cents higher. Regular conventional gasoline remained at the 65/66-cent level.</p>
<p>CARB diesel was also flat from Friday at 69/71 cents a gallon, while low sulphur stayed at 69/70 cents.  </p>
<p>CARB diesel was also flat from Friday at 69/71 cents a gallon, while low sulphur stayed at 69/70 cents.</p>
<p>Traders saw at least two cargoes of jet fuel coming to the West Coast this week, drawn by the market's current premium to the East and Gulf Coasts.</p>
<p>Los Angeles jet fuel was talked one cent lower at 71.50/72.50 cents, but players expected prices to hold relatively steady as incoming cargoes were balanced by supply shortness following last month's numerous hydrotreater problems.</p>
<p>In San Francisco, conventional gasoline was three cents cheaper than L.A., while CARB quality was about five cents lower.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
