<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4169" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Reagan's 'Western White House' put up for sale.</title>
<headline>Reagan's 'Western White House' put up for sale.</headline>
<byline>Michael Miller</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former U.S. President Ronald Reagan and his wife Nancy have reluctantly listed their southern California ranch -- known during his presidency as the Western White House -- for sale, an aide said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Sadly, since President Reagan's illness, it hasn't been used,&quot; Reagan's spokeswoman, Joanne Drake, said in a brief statement.</p>
<p>Reagan announced in 1994 that he was suffering from Alzheimer's disease, and he and his wife have lived solely in their Los Angeles mansion since then.</p>
<p>Drake said the sale of the Reagans' sprawling ranch near Santa Barbara was being handled by Sotheby International Realty's office in Newport Beach, California. Sotheby spokesman Zachary Wright said the ranch would be listed in all Sotheby International's offices worldwide.</p>
<p>Wright said he was &quot;not at liberty&quot; to say how much the Reagans were asking for the 688-acre (278-hectare) property, which is called Ranch del Cielo. A neighbouring 1,400-acre (566-hectare) ranch was sold at auction for $2.5 million in 1988.</p>
<p>The ranch became a part of history when Reagan designated it the &quot;Western White House&quot; in 1981 shortly after taking office. During the eight years of his presidency he visited the ranch often, once telling a local reporter, &quot;When you get out there, the world is gone.&quot;</p>
<p>Reagan prized the privacy that the ranch, set in the rugged Santa Ynez mountains 30 miles (48 km) from Santa Barbara, afforded him.</p>
<p>During the Reagans' visits during his presidency, he ordered that only essential staff stay on the ranch. Generally the only others present were Secret Service agents, the White House physician and the military officer carrying the communications equipment always close at hand in case of nuclear war.</p>
<p>Other aides and the press contingent that followed the president stayed in Santa Barbara.</p>
<p>Reagan would spend time horseback riding the trails on the property that offered spectacular views of the Pacific coastline and the Santa Ynez Valley. He also exercised by chain-sawing fallen oak branches and using a hydraulic device to split logs.</p>
<p>The Reagans shared the ranch with a variety of domestic and wild animals, including deer, ducks, rabbits, dogs and cats, as well as the occasional mountain lion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
