<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4221" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fleet, NatWest form pact.</title>
<headline>Fleet, NatWest form pact.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fleet Financial Group and National Westminster Bank PLC said Tuesday they have signed an agreement that will allow both companies to provide banking services to corporate customers in the United Kingdom and the United States.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, NatWest will set up a representative office in Boston to provide Sterling and foreign currency account and cash management services to American companies that either have a physical presence in the UK or trade there.</p>
<p>Desks also will be created in Boston, New York and London, where each bank's customers can receive quick help in opening accounts and cash management. The offices will be staffed by employees who will bring specific expertise in their country's banking system to each marketplace, the companies said.  </p>
<p>Fleet will provide US Dollar accounts and cash management services to the US subsidiaries and offices of UK-headquartered companies.  Fleet currently markets US cash management services directly to UK companies from its office in London.</p>
<p>&quot;This agreement is a milestone in making global banking services more readily available, for our customers,&quot; said Fleet Financial Group President and Chief Executive Terrence Murray. &quot;It goes beyond existing banking alliances between American and European banks by giving Fleet and NatWest customers access to a full range of international banking services including extensive branch networks in the US, UK and Ireland.&quot;</p>
<p>NatWest Chief Executive Bernard Horn said believes the banks' &quot;combined strengths in market knowledge, product technology and customer service will ensure that our customers are provided with an unrivaled product. We can now offer our customers a wider and more sophisticated range of services in the US than previously was available.&quot;</p>
<p>NatWest supplies commercial banking services to about one-third of the companies in the UK and is the second largest retail bank in the UK with over 2,000 branches.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
