<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4234" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Italian Oven faces &quot;going concern&quot; problem.</title>
<headline>Italian Oven faces &quot;going concern&quot; problem.</headline>
<dateline>LATROBE, Pa 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Italian Oven Inc said Tuesday its latest financial statements had caused a &quot;going concern&quot; about its ability to continue operating.</p>
<p>Italian Oven said it was trying to resolve the shortage of operating capital by selling assets, seeking alternate sources of financing and restructuring corporate functions in an effort to reduce general and administrative costs.  </p>
<p>It said it had terminated or suspended without pay 10 employees or 25 percent of its corporate staff at its Latrobe, Penn headquarters, sold its Erie and Cranberry, Penn restaurants and entered into agreements with landlords, construction contractors and trade creditors to defer current payables.</p>
<p>Italian Oven said it had also reached an agreement with its principal supplier to provide food and restaurant supplies to its restaurants. It added that it had delivered its $1.1 million note to the supplier, which requires Italian Oven to make five daily installment payments per week of $30,000 through December 30, with all outstanding amounts due and payable on December 31.</p>
<p>To collateralize its obligations, Italian Oven said it had granted to the supplier a security interest in all of its assets.</p>
<p>It also said it had engaged Wheat, First Securities, Inc to assist and advise it in obtaining suitable financing of up to $4 million and exploring potential strategic partnerships.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LATROBE, Pa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
