<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4241" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gateway goes retail with Destination PC/TV.</title>
<headline>Gateway goes retail with Destination PC/TV.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gateway 2000 Inc said on Tuesday that it would make its Destination personal computers available through certain retail stores.</p>
<p>The computer, which combines the features of a big-screen television with those of a home compter, will start at $3,999, and be available at Nobody Beats The Wiz stores on the East Coast this week and CompUSA Inc stores throughout the United States by mid-September.</p>
<p>Destination will be the only Gateway product sold through retail chains, the company said.  </p>
<p>The Pentium-processor based system offers video images superior to those of television, Gateway said.</p>
<p>Both computer and television functions are controlled through a touchpad-equiped wireless keyboard and a wireless Field Mouse remote control/mouse.</p>
<p>The system is compatible with consumer electronics components such as VCRs, stereo systems, and laser disc players, and can accept video feeds from cable television systems, traditional antennas, or other video devices. Audio signals from the Destination system can be channeled through home stereo systems to offer surround sound capability.</p>
<p>--New York Newsdesk, 212/859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
