<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4318" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norwegian shares flat as investors wait on results.</title>
<headline>Norwegian shares flat as investors wait on results.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwegian shares remained flat for a second consecutive session on Tuesday with the market continuing to lack firm direction due to a mixed bag of half-year results.</p>
<p>The Total share index closed at 820.18 points, a gain of 0.05 percent. Turnover amounted to 608.26 million crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;Trade was slow with no direction today,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears to be a consolidation period after the heavy losses recently. But investors are also waiting to see what sort of results come out. They've been very mixed up to now.&quot;  </p>
<p>Metals producer Elkem posted a 33 percent rise in six-month pre-tax profits to come in above expectations at 598 million crowns.</p>
<p>But the company said it expected a weaker second half across all its markets and the share price dropped back from a high at 89.50 crowns to end at 87.50 crowns, a gain of 3.50 crowns on the day.</p>
<p>Energy group Hafslund and Norway's largest shipping company Bergesen are due to announce first-half results on Wednesday. Insurance company UNI Storeband and forestry group Norske Skogindustrier will post profits on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
