<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4322" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian bonds/futures closing report.</title>
<headline>Italian bonds/futures closing report.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian debt markets tumbled through support at the close as political worries and chart points collaborated to undermine them.</p>
<p>&quot;There are still political worries concerning the market, particularly on the budget in the autumn,&quot; said one trader referring to signs on Monday from the hard-left that it was limbering up for confrontation over Rome's privatisation and 1997 budget plans when parliament returns from its summer break.</p>
<p>The September future on LIFFE skidded 27 basis points lower to 115.71, piercing support at 115.81 and looking down at the next stop which is 115.50.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the 115.81 break triggered steeper losses.</p>
<p>The February 2006 Btp was 12 basis points lower at 101.03 while the spread over the 10-year benchmark Bund inched out on the day to 329 basis points.</p>
<p>Concern over the outlook for autumn for the Italian government is a nagging factor ready to undermine Italian assets but for the moment the market's main attention is on today's Federal Open Market Committee meeting.</p>
<p>The other focus is Thursday's Bundesbank council meeting, with slightly slower than expected M3 money supply growth of 8.6 percent keeping hopes of a waferthin repo rate cut alive.  </p>
<p>On the charts, traders said any move by the Btp future to the 116.00 area and above would see healthy selling interest. Others said the mood was bearish and if the future ended the week below 115.95 &quot;then it's definitely on a downtrend.&quot;</p>
<p>--Charlotte Cooper, Milan bureau +39 2 66129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
