<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4337" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German stocks await U.S. interest rate decision.</title>
<headline>German stocks await U.S. interest rate decision.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German stocks are likely to be steady on Wednesday, dealers said, amid limited expectation of a move on U.S. interest rates to inject life into the market.</p>
<p>The 30-share IBIS DAX index was up 6.72 points at 2,562.97 points at 1421 GMT, just above its floor session close at 2,560.26 points.</p>
<p>Traders said there was little movement in the afternoon as the market waited for the outcome of the FOMC meeting in the U.S. later on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Barring a rate move, technical signals also indicated that the DAX's upside potential was limited, dealers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The 30-share DAX is likely to meet resistance at 2,570 and the September future most likely will not break 2,574/75 points,&quot; a London trader said.</p>
<p>U.S. interest rates will be closely watched for a signal on the likely direction on German interest rates.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank meets this Thursday amid widespread expectations that it will cut its securities repurchase rate, or repo.</p>
<p>Among individual companies, dealers said the run of the utilities is expected to continue with RWE, the favourite on Tuesday, taking the lead.  </p>
<p>RWE was up 91 pfennigs at 55.37 marks in afternoon trade.</p>
<p>Half-year results due from utility company Viag AG would determine their share price development Wednesday, dealers said.</p>
<p>Viag stock was up 6.90 marks at 569.50 on Tuesday afternoon as investors bet on a strong earnings report.</p>
<p>Construction group Philipp Holzmann AG was also likely to be active after its release later on Tuesday of half-year results.</p>
<p>The stock dropped two marks to 374 marks in floor trade.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
