<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4341" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German wheat prices under pressure from harvest.</title>
<headline>German wheat prices under pressure from harvest.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German wheat prices are poised for further falls as the harvest makes progress across the country, brokers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The exception was the north, where some crops had not finished ripening and would take another eight to 10 days, although the weather was now dry and sunny.</p>
<p>&quot;Buyers and sellers can't agree as buyers point to good harvests elsewhere in Europe and to early indications of good German yields and protein contents,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sellers hope for Eastern European and North African demand and won't lower their quality wheat prices,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Hamburg grain exchange maintained its new crop bread wheat price (12.5 percent, 220 hagberg) at 282.50 marks.</p>
<p>This is 7.50 marks down from the start of the month.</p>
<p>Brokers said ex-farm bread wheat prices across the country of around 270-290 marks should be poised for further falls.</p>
<p>This would be especially the case in western regions, where French producers were marketing output that they could not sell abroad under restrictive EU export policies.</p>
<p>Feed wheat free Hamburg was lowered to 277.50 marks by the exchange, having shed five marks so far in August.</p>
<p>Brokers said local supplies could not compete with British and Danish offers at 265 marks cif northern Germany Aug/Sept.</p>
<p>But the local price of first-half 1997 feed wheat at 280 marks was below British offers at 282.</p>
<p>Fob Baltic prices of bread wheat for September-November delivery (250 hagberg) were in a 277.50-307.50 marks range, depending on lot size and protein content.</p>
<p>Brokers hoped high protein (13-14 percent) wheat at 300 marks and more would be marketeable in Spain, France and Britain, where 11-12 percent is more typical and where blending material is needed to achieve baking qualities.</p>
<p>Poland and Hungary suffered crop losses in the harsh 1995/96 winter and would also need to buy in quality wheat.</p>
<p>Farm union DBV will issue a new harvest report on Wednesday, and this should offer clues to the impact of weather disruptions to grain harvests earlier this month.</p>
<p>--Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
