<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4344" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Danish shares hit new records on half-year results.</title>
<headline>Danish shares hit new records on half-year results.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish share prices closed higher on Tuesday, with the KFX index hitting a new closing record again and further gains expected as good corporate interim results flood in.</p>
<p>&quot;The market undertone remains positive and there was a lot of activity today. The generally good first-half 1996 results should spark more gains tomorrow,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The KFX top-20 index closed at 120.59, 0.38 point up and a new all-time end-of-day record while the KFX September future rose 0.10 point to 120.50 with 124 contracts each worth 100,000 crowns traded.  </p>
<p>Unidanmark dominated the day, posting a better than expected interim pre-tax profit but disappointing the market a little with the share closing only two crowns up at 272 after fluctuating marginally earlier.</p>
<p>Den Danske Bank, its first-half 1996 result due on Thursday, closed unchanged at 396.</p>
<p>Otherwise ISS continued its recovery, putting on two crowns to finish at 133 while Tele Danmark rose by the same margin to end at 271.</p>
<p>Overall turnover for the day was 771 million crowns.</p>
<p>--Chris Follett, Copenhagen newsroom +45-339699652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
