<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4353" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Phoenix airport targets Lufthansa, KLM.</title>
<headline>Phoenix airport targets Lufthansa, KLM.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Officials at Phoenix, Arizona, airport said they aim to win Deutsche Lufthansa and KLM NV as new clients on the heels of British Airways and LTU International Airways.</p>
<p>Phoenix marketing director Ann Hastings said she aims to establish several European routes to the Arizona state capital over the next 18 months.</p>
<p>She told Reuters in a telephone interview while on a Germany sales tour: &quot;We want to plan with Lufthansa or KLM within the next 18 months.&quot;</p>
<p>These could be the parent airlines or their respective charter subsidiaries, Condor and Martinair, she noted.</p>
<p>British Airways launched the first international service to Phoenix on July 1 with the start of a daily DC-10 flight from Gatwick.</p>
<p>German leisure airline LTU has announced it will start a weekly Monday service from Duesseldorf on November 4.</p>
<p>Hastings said: &quot;Our top priority is to ensure and support these two initial European routes because the success of these routes will influence other airlines.&quot;</p>
<p>She noted: &quot;Travellers are very familiar with California and Florida and want new destinations. Arizona is tipped to be the next 'in' destination.&quot;</p>
<p>Germany is Arizona's largest European passenger travel market followed by the UK, she added.</p>
<p>Phoenix Airport handled 27.8 million passengers in 1995, a rise of 8.7 percent, with an approximate 50-50 mix of leisure and business travellers, she added.</p>
<p>--Air Cargo Newsroom Tel +44 171 542 7706 Fax +44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
