<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4356" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: ABB Switzerland sees lower net.</title>
<headline>ABB Switzerland sees lower net.</headline>
<dateline>BADEN, Switzerland 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>ABB Switzerland, a unit of electrical engineering group ABB Asea Brown Boveri AG, said it did not expect any easing of the tough competitive pressure in power plant business and it expects the 1996 results of the entire group to be below 1995.</p>
<p>ABB Switzerland's chairman Edwin Somm said in a statement that there are still excess capacities worldwide in the power plant business, resulting in a tough competitive situation.</p>
<p>Together with the Swiss franc, which remains strong, this has affected prices and profit margins, which could not be fully compensated by cost-reduction measures.</p>
<p>&quot;Up to the end of the current year, no significant relaxation of the situation in the power plant business can be anticipated,&quot; Somm said, adding:</p>
<p>&quot;Although the divisions Power Transmission and Distribution as well as Industrial and Building Systems are at the level of the preceeding year, for the 1996 business year one has to depart from the assumption that the result of the previous year will not be achieved.&quot;</p>
<p>ABB Switzerland's net profit rose to 340 million Swiss francs in 1995 from 285 million. For the first six months of 1996, ABB Switzerland reported a seven percent drop in net profit to 139 million francs.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BADEN, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
