<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4358" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian child rapist terrifies own sister.</title>
<headline>Belgian child rapist terrifies own sister.</headline>
<byline>Bert Lauwers</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The family of Marc Dutroux, main suspect in a Belgian child sex scandal, said on Tuesday they had begged the authorities to keep him in prison longer after his 1989 convictions for rape.</p>
<p>&quot;It was known that he was a sick man,&quot; sister Valerie Dutroux told Belgium's VTM television. &quot;To me he is no longer human. I was scared to death by him.&quot;</p>
<p>She said their parents had opposed Marc's early release and had &quot;begged&quot; authorities to keep him in jail.</p>
<p>Dutroux's mother Jeanine told De Morgen newspaper: &quot;Just like the parents of Julie and Melissa, I cannot understand how they could have released him after what became clear in 1989.&quot;</p>
<p>Dutroux, a 39-year-old father of three, led police to the bodies of eight-year-olds Julie Lejeune and Melissa Russo, who had died of starvation early this year after being kidnapped in June 1995.</p>
<p>He has been charged with kidnapping Laetitia Delhez, 14, and Sabine Dardenne, 12, has admitted abducting An Marchal and Eefje Lambrecks and is suspected of involvement in several other disappearances.</p>
<p>There was a national outcry when it was revealed that Dutroux was a convicted child sex offender who had been released 10 years early in 1992 from a 13-year jail sentence.</p>
<p>Valerie, who has a three-year-old son, said she had chosen a school surrounded by walls to help protect her own child.</p>
<p>Marc Dutroux, described by neighbours as a bizarre but quiet man with few friends, was the oldest of five children but considered the black sheep of the family.</p>
<p>The family moved to the Belgian Congo in 1956, shortly after Marc's birth, but returned in 1960. His parents, both teachers, divorced soon after.</p>
<p>He was described as a problem child who had to change schools at least four times.</p>
<p>&quot;Marc always had a problem with authority. He always had to be right and it was best not to contradict him,&quot; his mother said.</p>
<p>He was repeatedly caught red-handed by police for minor crime like breaking into cars but still managed to obtain a qualification as an electrician.</p>
<p>His mother said he fled home 23 years ago and severed all ties with the family.</p>
<p>His youngest brother committed suicide a few years ago. His two other brothers are mailmen.</p>
<p>Marc has a 12-year-old son Frederic from a first marriage and two children -- Andy, nearly three, and Celine, nine months -- with his second wife Michelle Martin.</p>
<p>Martin has been charged with being an accomplice in the abduction and illegal imprisonment of children.</p>
<p>She and Dutroux, who beat his first wife, had been living apart because she feared his rages.</p>
<p>Until his arrest, Marc had been living with Frederic. The two other children stayed with Martin.</p>
<p>He is officially unemployed but had been enjoying a health insurance benefit payment of 38,500 francs per month ($1,280).</p>
<p>&quot;He presented himself as a sick and disoriented man, blaming his stay in prison for his bad state of health,&quot; according to a dossier on Dutroux delivered to the media by Belgian Justice Minister Stefaan De Clerck on Monday.</p>
<p>The dossier said that Dutroux has always maintained his innocence but carefully complied with the conditions set for his early release.</p>
<p>Judicial authorities have been criticised for insufficiently monitoring Marc Dutroux after his release from jail.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
