<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4359" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: India halts nuke pact, angry backers press on.</title>
<headline>India halts nuke pact, angry backers press on.</headline>
<byline>Stephanie Nebehay</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States and its allies denounced India on Tuesday for preventing a nuclear test ban treaty from being adopted in Geneva and vowed to bring the pact to the U.N. General Assembly (UNGA) for signature.</p>
<p>The move by Indian ambassador Arundhati Ghose also drew immediate fire from rival Pakistan, whose envoy expressed concern about the &quot;nuclear ambitions&quot; of its eastern neighbour.</p>
<p>In a speech, Ghose confirmed India was vetoing the formal adoption of the treaty by the Conference on Disarmament and blocking its transmission to the United Nations in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;Our opposition to that text continues,&quot; Ghose said. &quot;We would not, therefore, agree to it being forwarded to the UNGA in any form by this conference.&quot;</p>
<p>New Delhi objects that the pact fails to commit nuclear powers to a firm timetable for total disarmament and does not stop them from making qualitative improvements in their nuclear arsenals through computer simulation and other costly methods.</p>
<p>It rejects a key clause saying that the pact would become law upon ratification by 44 states including India. In its view, this would infringe on its sovereign right to decide freely.</p>
<p>The five declared nuclear powers (Britain, China, France, Russia and the United States) were marshalling support to rescue the global pact and send the text via a special resolution to New York for action, according to Western diplomats.</p>
<p>The conference holds its next plenary session on Thursday to discuss the fate of the Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty (CTBT), a landmark pact banning all nuclear explosions.</p>
<p>U.S. disarmament ambassador Stephen Ledogar said: &quot;India has formally vetoed the treaty text and made it clear that it would take whatever step was necessary to prevent the text being acted upon by the Conference on Disarmament.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said India was alone among the 44 countries with nuclear arms or nuclear reactors in objecting to the pact's entry-into-force formula and accused it of insincerity in its arguments against the draft treaty.</p>
<p>&quot;The real reason is that the current government in New Delhi wants to maintain the Indian nuclear weapon option,&quot; Ledogar said. &quot;That's regrettable, but that's within the sovereign right of India.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem now is how the rest of us can do what we have to do,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now consulting, the rest of us, as to how, despite this most regrettable development in the Conference on Disarmament, we can get this text to New York for further action. That has to be done promptly. We have in effect played out the CD's options with this veto.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain's ambassador Sir Michael Weston agreed that India's rejection left no hope for reaching a pact through the Geneva forum, which began the negotiations in January 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course, we had always hoped it could be done by the CD in the orthodox way,&quot; Weston told Reuters. &quot;Now that looks clearly impossible.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;As far as the text goes, there are plenty of other ways to get it to New York if that is what people want to do,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Pakistan, a nuclear &quot;threshold&quot; state which has said it will not sign the pact unless India does, immediately took the floor after Ghose's speech to put the blame squarely on its rival.</p>
<p>Ambassador Munir Akram said in a speech: &quot;Today, the mask of the &quot;Smiling Buddha' has been torn off revealing the face of the Goddess of War.&quot;</p>
<p>Akram was referring to India's only nuclear blast in 1974, which was followed by the coded message &quot;the Buddha has smiled&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The leaders of our neighbour have proclaimed that they will keep their nuclear &quot;options' open, that they reserve the right to conduct nuclear tests, that they will go ahead with their short and medium-range missile programmes,&quot; Akram said.</p>
<p>But the Pakistani said his country would be against any procedural manoeuvres sidestepping the Geneva body.</p>
<p>&quot;We are all aware that the CTBT may well rise from the ashes, like the Phoenix, in the U.N. General Assembly.</p>
<p>&quot;Pakistan would regret any procedure that circumvents the C.D. -- the single multilateral negotiating forum on disarmament,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
