<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4364" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: FOCUS-Unidanmark betters forecasts.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Unidanmark betters forecasts.</headline>
<byline>Christopher Follett</byline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Denmark's second biggest banking group, Unidanmark A/S, on Tuesday posted better than expected first-half results but said it foresaw slowing profits growth for the rest of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;A slightly lower rate of growth is anticipated in the Danish economy for 1996 compared with the previous year, although continuing an upward trend throughout the year,&quot; Unidanmark said in a statement accompanying its interim results.</p>
<p>&quot;Operating profit in the second half of 1996 is projected to be lower than for the first half of the year,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Unidanmark announced a 1.275 billion crown ($221.5 million) pre-tax profit for the first half of the year, boosted by improved earnings from net interest, fees and lending. It earned 1.077 billion in the same period last year.</p>
<p>Operating profit for January-June 1996 was 1.264 billion crowns against 1.158 billion a year ago and better than average analysts' forecasts of 1.172 billion crowns.</p>
<p>The bank attributed its advance to net interest and fee income of 4.430 billion crowns -- 2.6 percent up on the first half of 1995 -- lower losses and bad debt provisions, stable expenses and bigger extraordinary income.</p>
<p>Mortgage lending rose from first-half 1995 to end-June 1996 by nearly 30 percent to 158.8 million crowns, Unidanmark said. Bank lending rose 7.4 percent and it forecast sustained growth for both, along with deposits, in the rest of 1996.</p>
<p>It saw lower net interest income for full-year 1996 than for 1995 due to current low Danish interest rates. Securities and foreign exchange results are dependent on market trends and loan loss provisions remaining unchanged in the second half.</p>
<p>It expected costs for the whole year to be largely the same as last year, but said that reorganisation both at branch and head office levels should cut expenses in 1997 and 1998.</p>
<p>Unidanmark said activity in its mortgage credit unit, Unikredit, continued to rise sharply, its market share of gross new residential mortgage lending growning to around 15 percent and interim pre-tax profits rising to 36 million crowns from the same 1995 period's seven million crowns.</p>
<p>Unidanmark was the second of Denmark's top banks to announce its 1996 half-year result. On Monday, third biggest bank BG Bank posted a better than expected 821 million crown pre-tax profit, compared with the previous year's 738 million crowns.</p>
<p>Denmark's biggest bank Den Danske Bank is to release its interim results on August 22. -- Chris Follett, Copenhagen newsroom +45-33969652 ($1=5.756 Danish Crown)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
