<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4365" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French UDF backs Maastricht criteria flexibility.</title>
<headline>French UDF backs Maastricht criteria flexibility.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Francois Leotard, the leader of France's UDF junior ruling coalition party, said on Tuesday flexibility on the Maastricht criteria for European monetary union could provide &quot;oxygen&quot; needed to boost the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;This oxygen will come notably from lower interest rates and obtaining a temporary margin of flexibility on the Maastricht criteria,&quot; Leotard wrote in Le Monde newspaper.</p>
<p>He said there was no question of delaying the 1999 deadline for moving to a single European currency and he was &quot;convinced the moment of truth would come before next summer&quot; on transition to a single currency.</p>
<p>In the countdown period, he said &quot;It would be a question of keeping the Maastricht criteria as objectives reflecting a medium term economic will.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This decision is essentially political. It's a question of giving the Maastricht treaty its true interpretation: the single currency is the goal and the criteria are the means,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Maastricht treaty calls for countries to reduce their public deficits to three percent of Gross Domestic Product (GDP) but allows for overshooting, in the treaty's own words if &quot;the ratio has declined substantially and continuously and reached a level that comes close to three percent&quot;.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe's conservative government has always insisted it will meet the three percent target. Economists are sceptical on this because of continued weak economic growth but widely believe the single currency can be achieved based on the treaty flexibility.</p>
<p>Leotard said in his Le Monde article that the short-term cost of preparing for monetary union was a &quot;mechanical slowing&quot; of the economy which prevented the government finding quick solutions for pressing problems.</p>
<p>Reducing public spending was &quot;an absolute necessity&quot; but would not produce benefits immediately, he said, adding that job creation would depend on better economic growth.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
