<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4373" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Bono-Bund spread seen wider if Buba fails to cut.</title>
<headline>Bono-Bund spread seen wider if Buba fails to cut.</headline>
<byline>Manuel Maria Ruiz</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Whatever the U.S. Federal Reserve and the German Bundesbank decide to do with their key money rates this week, the damage for Spanish markets would at worst be a widening of the Bono-Bund yield spread to about 270 basis points from 264 now, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Buba doesn't cut, the bond spread should widen to around 265-270 basis points, and if it does the gap should narrow to 255-260,&quot; said Alfredo Urrutia, chief economist at Societe Generale in Madrid.</p>
<p>Views are mixed on the possibility of a cut in the German repo rate from 3.30 percent now, although those expecting a move predict a trim of around 10 basis points.</p>
<p>No change in the German central bank's key money rate would mean a return to recent bond market lows, but the risk of a sustained sell-off is limited, analysts agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Buba doesn't cut on August 22 it will be negative for the markets, but not as much as if it doesn't move again on September 5,&quot; said Jose Maria Castellon, analyst at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>If the Bundesbank leaves the repo steady, the markets will continue to expect a cut next month, analysts said. But this still implied an initial negative impact on the dollar and peripheral European currencies after Thursday's meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;Initially we would move back to minimum (bono) levels and the mark would once again be the stronger currency,&quot; Alfredo Urrutia said.</p>
<p>&quot;The peseta will be nearer to 85 per mark than 84.50 if the Buba leaves rates&quot; he added.</p>
<p>German M3 data for July, which was at the lower end of economists' forecasts, have reinforced expectations of a cut in the repo rate.</p>
<p>Castellon said the market has already priced in a small cut.</p>
<p>&quot;For that reason I don't think it would affect the peseta much,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts have their doubts about German rates but are more certain that key U.S. money rates will stay on hold.</p>
<p>An eventual hike in rates on the other side of the Atlantic would prompt market volatility at first, they said.</p>
<p>A stronger dollar following a U.S. rate hike might help the peseta, but simultaneous Treasury and stock market losses could see parallel movements in Spain. This may serve to weaken the peseta against the mark.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom +341 585 2160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
