<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4376" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Axa up but lags index after H1 sales.</title>
<headline>Axa up but lags index after H1 sales.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Axa firmed but failed to keep pace with the CAC-40 index after a 24.5 percent increase in the insurance group's turnover for the first half.</p>
<p>At 1251 GMT the shares were up 2.7 francs or 0.95 percent at 286.3 francs. The CAC-40 index, in which Axa is weighted at 3.49 percent, was up 1.45 percent at 2,014.92.</p>
<p>Axa reported first-half turnover of 81.93 billion francs compared with 65,81 billion francs in the same period of 1995.</p>
<p>It said the increase primarily reflected the consolidation of Australian insurer National Mutual.</p>
<p>On a like-for-like basis turnover grew 8.8 percent.  </p>
<p>Mid-session volume of some 25,000 shares made Axa the tenth most active stock on the Paris bourse.</p>
<p>Brokers took on board the strong special factors surrounding consolidation in Axa's figures but said the underlying picture looked sound.</p>
<p>Some were surprised at the share's weakness in relation both to the market and to insurer UAP -- up 1.37 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Among the good factors is growth in life assurance,&quot; said Sami Gotrane of brokers EIFB. &quot;Much of that is NatMut but it was also up 16 percent in Europe where there was no acquisition and up 12 percent in France...,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
