<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4380" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek money rates hold in late calm trade.</title>
<headline>Greek money rates hold in late calm trade.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek depos and forex swaps firmed at mid-session but eased after the forex fixing to hold morning levels in late quiet dealing and the Bank of Greece drained overnight funds at an unchanged 12.80 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Rates have come down after the central bank's fixing where a total of 40 million ecus were sold,&quot; said a money dealer at a state bank. &quot;Dealing is calm and there is excess liquidity.&quot;</p>
<p>Surplus liquidity was estimated at over 100 billion drachmas by some dealers.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very quiet and rates are hovering around morning levels,&quot; said a forex bank trader. &quot;Developments in the forex market will be the main factor behind changes in drachma liquidity.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Unlike past national elections, the market has received the news about early elections calmly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some corporations and individuals could decide to close out positions the day of the announcement of early elections given that people in Greece buy the fact not the rumour but their impact will be limited,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Greek Prime Minister Costas Simitis will decide this week whether to call early elections next month, government spokesman Dimitris Reppas told reporters on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime minister is considering all options, he will announce his decision very soon, most probably within the week,&quot; Reppas said during Monday's briefing.</p>
<p>Based on Greece's constitution, elections, scheduled for October 1997, must be held within a month from the time they are announced.</p>
<p>The mark was quoted at 159.60/65 drachmas from Tuesday's 159.670 fix, the dollar at 238.02/12 drachmas from 237.920 and the Ecu at 300.62/72 from 300.730 drachmas.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Greece, the domestic money market's biggest player, quoted the following late rates:</p>
<p>** Overnight at 12.50-13.00</p>
<p>** T/N at 12.60-13.10</p>
<p>** S/N at 12.60-13.10</p>
<p>** One week at 12.70-13.20</p>
<p>** Two weeks at 12.80-13.30</p>
<p>** Three weeks at 12.90-13.40</p>
<p>** One month at 13.00-13.50</p>
<p>** Two months at 13.30-13.80</p>
<p>** Three months at 13.40-13.90</p>
<p>** Six months at 13.65-14.15</p>
<p>** Nine months at 13.85-14.35</p>
<p>** Twelve months at 13.95-14.55</p>
<p>--Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
