<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4386" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Pakhoed H1 tank storage result slips.</title>
<headline>Pakhoed H1 tank storage result slips.</headline>
<dateline>ROTTERDAM 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch tank storage and shipping group Pakhoed NV said on Tuesday first half group results from its tank storage business slipped to 45 million guilders from 66 million guilders in the first half of last year.</p>
<p>Pakhoed earlier announced a 4.6 million first half net profit, down from the previous 61.4 million, hit by 54.3 million guilders of restructuring charges.</p>
<p>The company said chemicals storage achieved a further improvement in results while edible oils were positive. &quot;In oil storage operations the developments were unfavourable,&quot; the company said in a statement with results.</p>
<p>Oil storage results in Singapore were hit because of the loss of a contract, Pakhoed said.</p>
<p>European tank storage made 26.5 million guilders in the first half against 47.5 million in the first half of 1995 while the rest of the world operation was flat at 18.5 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The distribution activities achieved lower results as compared with 1995,&quot; said Pakhoed, noting its Lambert Riviere unit had performed exceptionally well in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Market conditions have stabilised by now, because of which we expect a better second half year for Lambert Riviere as compared with the same period last year,&quot; Pakhoed said.</p>
<p>The firm said a lower profit contribution of its 28 percent share in Univar was due to the negative results of the U.S. division in the last quarter of Univar's 1995/96 year which corresponds with Pakhoed's first quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>Univar's Canadian and European divisions continued to perform well, said Pakhoed. Pakhoed in June said it planned a $300 million takeover of the Univar shares it did not own.</p>
<p>Results of logistics units rose to 25 million guilders from 23.1 million while shipping activities improved -- to 17.4 million from 14.7 million -- partly due to tax relief measures for the industry, Pakhoed said. -- Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I77003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROTTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
