<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4391" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spanish Treasury seen tightening bill rate.</title>
<headline>Spanish Treasury seen tightening bill rate.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The money markets could force a tightening in bill rates again at tomorrow's auction, dealers and analysts said.</p>
<p>At the last auction on August 7 the Treasury raised the average one-year bill yield to 7.136 percent from 7.056 percent in order to attract extra financing and traders said the rate could emerge at up to 7.15 percent this time.</p>
<p>Market sources said they had seen signs the Treasury was willing to pay higher yields and this would encourage bidders at the auction to raise their offers to force the yield higher.</p>
<p>&quot;At the last auction the Treasury gave a very clear signal that it was prepared to raise rates,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;It needs financing, the bills are very useful and the market's bids will set the price,&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>One year bills were trading at around 7.13/15 percent in the grey market this morning.</p>
<p>&quot;Depending on the volume and aggressiveness of the bids, I think the Treasury could raise the rate slightly (from last time's 7.136 percent),&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>Despite the holiday season dampening activity, the volume of bids should be slightly higher than last time's 289 billion pesetas.</p>
<p>&quot;There are 420 billion pesetas of bills maturing and demand will probably be higher than last time,&quot; the trader added.</p>
<p>Spanish interest rates in general are still expected to fall between now and the end of the year. Economists say the Bank of Spain can trim its key money market rate, now 7.25 percent, by between a quarter and three quarters of a point.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom + 34 1 585 2151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
