<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4395" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian child sex scandal part of a world trade.</title>
<headline>Belgian child sex scandal part of a world trade.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgium's shocking child sex scandal in which two young girls have been killed, two rescued and at least two are missing is symptomatic of a global sickness, child rights lawyer Michele Hirsch said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether you talk about paedophilia, prostitution, pornography or the traffic in human organs, people are increasingly being treated as a primary resource,&quot; she told Reuters in an interview. &quot;It is a global problem.&quot;</p>
<p>Hirsch was involved in changing Belgium's child protection laws last year after the unmasking of Briton John Stamford -- a Belgian resident and head of the Spartacus international paedophile ring -- who died during his trial last December.</p>
<p>She said there was plenty of evidence that paedophile sex tourism -- primarily to countries like Thailand, the Philippines and India -- really got into its stride in the 1970s.</p>
<p>Research has indicated up to 800,000 child prostitutes in Thailand, some 400,000 in India and some 60,000 in the Philippines.</p>
<p>However, a combination of tougher rules in Thailand and the Philippines and fear of Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome has changed the nature of the trade.</p>
<p>Paedophiles are now in the market for virgins, and the younger the better, Hirsch said. At the same time the trade in pornography -- video tapes, books and magazines -- has boomed.</p>
<p>Vietnam, Cambodia, and Latin America are emerging as major supplies of child prostitutes, but eastern Europe -- paricularly Russia and Romania are quickly catching up, Hirsch said.</p>
<p>East Europe is one of the newest markets, both for the supply of child prostitutes to their western neighbours and as consumers of pornography.</p>
<p>&quot;Organised crime, the Russian Mafia is heavily involved. It is big business,&quot; Hirsch said.</p>
<p>One of the factors in the Belgian case is just how wealthy the key witness, 39-year-old unemployed father of three Marc Dutroux, appears to have been.</p>
<p>Dutroux, a convicted child abuser who was charged on Friday with abduction and illegal imprisonment of children, owns at least six houses in Belgium and has admitted paying two of his associates 40,000 francs ($1,300) to kidnap a child.</p>
<p>In the end they turned up with two, eight-year-olds Julie Lejeune and Melissa Russo. The girls, abducted in June last year, starved to death in late February or early March. Dutroux led police to their bodies on Saturday.</p>
<p>Dutroux has also admitted kidnapping An Marchal and Eefje Lambrecks in Ostend last August.</p>
<p>The fate of the two girls is a mystery. Belgian media has speculated that they may have been sold into prostitution in the Czech Republic, although Interpol in Prague said there was no trace of the two on Czech soil.</p>
<p>Belgian investigators have found makeshift cells in some of Dutroux' houses where some of the kidnapped girls were certainly imprisoned, and confiscated large quantities of videos and magazines in their raids.</p>
<p>As far as Hirsch is concerned, this is all part of a pattern that will find echoes around the globe -- with increasing coordination and communication between different paedophile groups, some of which are now on the internet.</p>
<p>She points to radically different laws on child protection even in neighbouring countries, regardless of the morality, but says simply locking up the perpetrators will not solve the problem.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless we cure the demand there is no solution. We must treat the victims because time and again we find the abusers were themselves the abused,&quot; she says.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
