<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4401" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Cimpor seeks to buy foreign cement firms.</title>
<headline>Cimpor seeks to buy foreign cement firms.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Portuguese state-controlled cement group Cimpor-Cimentos de Portugal has potential to invest up to 250 billion escudos ($1.6 billion) in foreign acquisitions up to the year 2001, a company source said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The source said the investment plan depended on Cimpor's ability to maintain cash flow and not to allow debts to reach 30 percent of total assets. Cimpor has negligible debt now.</p>
<p>&quot;We will only make the investment if we find the right opportunities,&quot; the source told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We would be interested in making an investment if the expected profit exceeded the capital costs. We are looking for interesting opportunities for investment.&quot;</p>
<p>Cimpor would seek possible investments after the scheduled privatisation of a 45 percent stake in the company expected in October, the source said.</p>
<p>Cimpor was considering Spain, South America, and northern and southern Africa as potential areas to acquire cement manufacturers, the source added.</p>
<p>This month Cimpor bought Moroccan cement firm Asment Temara for 11.8 billion escudos ($77 million).</p>
<p>It also owns a subsidiary in Spain, Corporacion Noroeste, and in Mozambique, Empresa de Cimentos de Mocambique.</p>
<p>Cimpor shares stood at 3,370 escudos, up five, in volume of 10,750 shares on Lisbon bourse in early afternoon trade.</p>
<p>-- David Brough, Lisbon newsroom +351-1-3538254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
