<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4408" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>VATICAN: Pope in good health after abdominal problem.</title>
<headline>Pope in good health after abdominal problem.</headline>
<dateline>VATICAN CITY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pope John Paul, who suffered an abdominal problem last week, was in good health on Tuesday and took part in a seminar on Eastern Europe at his summer residence, the Vatican said.</p>
<p>Chief Vatican spokesman Joaquin Navarro-Valls told reporters he found the 76-year-old Pope in &quot;good form and spirits&quot; at the Castelgandolfo residence south of Rome.</p>
<p>He said the Polish Pontiff was taking active part in a two-day seminar on Slavic cultures attended by 17 academics and scientists from countries in Eastern Europe and elsewhere.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the Pope would return to the Vatican for several hours as planned on Wednesday for his weekly general audience.</p>
<p>The Pope entered hospital briefly for a checkup last week after complaining of pains and took antibiotics for the unspecified abdominal problem caused by a mild infection.</p>
<p>The infection also caused the Pope to suffer a mild fever.</p>
<p>A CAT (Computed Axial Tomography) scan showed nothing out of order, particularly in relation to a 1992 operation to remove an intestinal tumour that was starting to turn malignant.</p>
<p>The Pontiff looked rosy-cheeked but tired on Sunday when he last appeared in public at Castelgandolfo.</p>
<p>The Vatican has said visits to Hungary and France in September would go ahead as planned.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VATICAN CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VATICAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
