<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4424" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Atlas Copco says stronger crown hit H1.</title>
<headline>Atlas Copco says stronger crown hit H1.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish engineering group Atlas Copco said on Tuesday that the stronger crown had a nine percent negative hit on its earnings in the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>But, reporting a 12 percent rise in first-half profit after financial items, the company forecast earnings for the full year would still be higher than in 1995 even though demand was expected to remain unchanged.  </p>
<p>&quot;Demand for the full year 1996 is expected to remain unchanged compared to 1995 levels, and earnings are expected to improve,&quot; the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Market conditions are, however, still uncertain,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Atlas reported a 12 percent lift in profit after financial items to 1.57 billion crowns.</p>
<p>This profit included a gain of 342 million crowns related to the sale of VOAC Hydraulics and restructuring costs of 225 million crowns within the indsturial technology business area.</p>
<p>Sales for the half year rose six percent from a year ago to 12.37 billion crowns and orders received increased three percent to 12.98 billion crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;The strengthening of the Swedish crown had, however, a negative effect of nine percent,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1045</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32830">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
