<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4425" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: OMV 96 forecast based on weak polyolefins.</title>
<headline>OMV 96 forecast based on weak polyolefins.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian oil and chemicals group OMV AG said on Tuesday its forecast for flat full-year earnings was based on a conservative outlook for polyolefins in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Finance director Wolfgang Ruttenstorfer told a news conference that polyolefin prices in the first half were already well below year-ago levels, squeezing refining and plastics margins.</p>
<p>He forecast worse was to come in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to match our 1995 result, allowing for a significant deterioration in polyolefins in the fourth quarter,&quot; Ruttenstorfer said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the downturn does not happen there will be room to improve our full-year result,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In 1995, OMV posted a record pre-tax profit of 2.09 billion schillings and earnings before interest and tax of 2.19 billion.</p>
<p>Ruttenstorfer estimated polyolefin revenues were down by about one billion schillings in the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;We have undertaken a range of measures to compensate...cutting costs and increasing sales volume by 23 percent,&quot; he said. -- Janet McBride, Vienna Newsroom 43-1-531 12 254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
