<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4426" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German cocoa buyers take back seat in summer lull.</title>
<headline>German cocoa buyers take back seat in summer lull.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German chocolate manufacturers have shunned cocoa markets during August after taking cover at around the 1,000 stg a tonne levels seen in London futures last month, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Futures are trending higher and a strong sterling versus the mark is another deterrent,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>&quot;The past few weeks have been the dullest in years.&quot;</p>
<p>London September was up six stg at 1,020 at 1030 GMT.</p>
<p>Industry was reasonably covered and not worried about price rallies while high summer temperatures discouraged chocolate consumption and some plants remained shut, traders said.</p>
<p>Market speculation focused on an Ivory Coast harvest around 800,000-900,000 tonnes, which could bring a deficit of around 150,000-250,000 tonnes in the 1996/97 season.</p>
<p>&quot;That's why I think the current consumer attitude might be dangerous given that fourth quarter prices may well be a few hundred sterling higher,&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;But it would be a creeping increase and there is also a danger of a price collapse if the Ivory Coast suddenly comes up with record volumes and qualities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ivorian beans were quoted at 2.30 marks per kg for Aug/Sept compared with 2.17 marks in late July while the fourth quarter 1996 and first quarter 1997 price of 2.33 was up 0.09-0.11.</p>
<p>The cocoa butter ratio was marginally higher at 2.78 for 1996 dates, implying a 6.50 marks outright price for Aug/Sept and 6.45 for fourth quarter, liquid, ex-works.</p>
<p>The first quarter 1997 ratio of 2.72 implied a mark price of 6.40.</p>
<p>-- Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
