<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4433" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: India confirms nuclear test ban veto.</title>
<headline>India confirms nuclear test ban veto.</headline>
<byline>Philippe Naughton</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>India told the Conference on Disarmament on Tuesday that it could still not accept a draft nuclear text ban treaty, preventing its formal adoption in Geneva after more than two years of negotiations.</p>
<p>At a meeting called to examine the final report on negotiations for a Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty (CTBT), Indian ambassador Arundhati Ghose was fiercely critical of a text that she said was unbalanced and violated India's sovereignty.</p>
<p>She confirmed that India, which blocked the treaty last week, would veto its transmission to the U.N. General Assembly in New York for signature at the end of next month.</p>
<p>&quot;Our opposition to that text continues,&quot; Ghose told the conference. &quot;We would not, therefore, agree to it being forwarded to the UNGA in any form by this conference.&quot;</p>
<p>Her remarks were greeted with anger by India's neighbour and long-time foe Pakistan. &quot;Today, the mask of the smiling Buddha has been torn off, revealing the face of the goddess of war,&quot; Pakistani ambassador Munir Akram told the conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Pakistan would regret any procedure that would circumvent the Conference on Disarmament, the single multilateral disarmament negotiating forum,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Yet supporters of the treaty, which include all five declared nuclear powers, hope to bypass India's veto in Geneva and have the treaty signed anyway at the General Assembly.</p>
<p>The Conference on Disarmament, or CD, takes all decisions by consensus of its 61 member states. But if the treaty text were presented to the General Assembly in the form of a co-sponsored resolution, it would need only a simple majority of the 185 member states to be adopted -- although opponents of the treaty could also propose amendments to it.</p>
<p>It was not clear whether Ghose's remark that the treaty could not be forwarded to New York &quot;in any form&quot; meant the CD would not be able even to transmit the negotiating report to the General Assembly.</p>
<p>That report clearly says there is no consensus on the text, but Western diplomats said that since it refers to the text it would be procedurally easier to introduce the treaty in New York if the report was forwarded.</p>
<p>If not, a co-sponsored resolution could be more difficult to introduce if the treaty were still to be open for signature from the end of September.</p>
<p>India's main problem with the treaty is that it does not commit the five declared nuclear powers -- the United States, Russia, China, Britain and France -- to a timetable for full nuclear disarmament, and instead encourages the divide between nuclear &quot;haves&quot; and &quot;have nots&quot;.</p>
<p>After rejecting the treaty on those grounds, New Delhi was further angered when the draft text demanded that India was among those that signed up to the treaty before it could enter into force.</p>
<p>India, along with Pakistan and Israel, is one of three &quot;nuclear threshold states&quot; that have the capability to swiftly build nuclear weapons. New Delhi exploded a nuclear device in 1974, but has not undertaken any nuclear tests since then.</p>
<p>Ghose told the CD that New Delhi had led the call for a test ban treaty as far back as 1954, but the Geneva negotiations had ignored their mandate to negotiate a universal, balanced test ban.</p>
<p>She was particularly critical of the text's clause on entry-into-force, saying: &quot;It is unprecedented in multilateral negotiations and international law that any sovereign country should be denied its right of voluntary consent on adherence to an international treaty.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
