<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4439" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Fourth suspect in Belgian scandal appears in court.</title>
<headline>Fourth suspect in Belgian scandal appears in court.</headline>
<dateline>NEUFCHATEAU, Belgium 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Belgian court will decide later on Tuesday whether to formally charge a fourth suspect in a Belgian child sex scandal in which two eight-year old girls have died and at least four others were abducted.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision will be this afternoon,&quot; said Clement de Clety, lawyer of Brussels businessman Jean-Michel Nihoul who has been detained and faces charges of criminal association.</p>
<p>About the charge, de Clety told reporters that the only point was that Nihoul knew Lelievre and Dutroux.</p>
<p>&quot;(Nihoul) just gave (them) his car for two or three days to repair it and to pass it on to the technical control authorities. These are the only concrete points in the file, nothing more,&quot; de Clety said.</p>
<p>Convicted paedophile Marc Dutroux and associate Michel Lelievre were formally charged last Friday after police rescued two abducted young girls from a house owned by Dutroux in the southern town of Charleroi.</p>
<p>Dutroux led police on Saturday to the buried bodies of eight-year-olds Julie Lejeune and Melissa Russo who died of starvation early this year after being kidnapped in June 1995.</p>
<p>Dutroux's wife Michelle Martin was charged on Monday with being an accomplice in the abduction and illegal imprisonment of children.</p>
<p>Belgian media said earlier on Tuesday that the Dutch boyfriend of Nihoul's ex-wife had also been arrested. But court sources said the charges against him had been dropped and that he had just been questioned.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEUFCHATEAU, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
