<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4459" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSTANT VIEW - UK July M4, bank lending data.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - UK July M4, bank lending data.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following is a selection of economists' reactions to UK July M4 data showing M4 up a provisional seasonally adjusted 8.8 percent year-on-year:</p>
<p>KEITH WADE, SCHRODERS</p>
<p>&quot;It is a good figure. We had been expecting a slowdown in M4 because the figure had been boosted quite a lot this time last year, but most people hadn't expected the figure to come back into the monitoring range, which is about the first time for six or seven months.&quot;  </p>
<p>CIARAN BARR, DEUTSCHE MORGAN GRENFELL</p>
<p>&quot;A soft M4 figure, but most of the weakness was due to the PSBR figures coming in weak, in fact a repayment, last month. If you delve deeper into the figures, the consumer sector is picking up the baton of recovery. Net new commitments were very strong indeed, as was consumer credit. I wouldn't expect to see M4 fall much further and indeed it could well edge up again in the months ahead.&quot;  </p>
<p>BRIAN HILLIARD, SOCIETE GENERALE</p>
<p>&quot;Fairly positive. The PSBR moving to a debt repayment will have helped this particular set of figures so we would need to see continuing good public sector figures in the coming months. The Chancellor, I think, is keen to find stories to make an excuse for a rate cut. I'm not saying he will, but this is one extra factor which is going to reassure him, so I think it should be positive for gilts.&quot;  </p>
<p>JEREMY HAWKINS, BANK OF AMERICA</p>
<p>&quot;Headline M4 number came in beneath market expectations. However, the composition is not as favourable, with consumer credit up strongly to 539 million stg, nearly double that reported in June. This suggests that there may be some upside to Thursday's retail sales figures. If so, then the chances of another interest rate cut look remote.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Richard Murphy, London Newsroom 44 171 542 2774</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
