<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4476" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Thistle Hotels confirms flotation plans.</title>
<headline>UK's Thistle Hotels confirms flotation plans.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thistle Hotels Plc confirmed on Tuesday that it would be floating on the London Stock Exchange, with plans for a share offer which will kick off in September.</p>
<p>Thistle will use the cash raised to repay debt and invest in its hotel portfolio. The group is one of the biggest hotel groups in the UK.</p>
<p>Weekend press reports speculated that the float could value the company as high as 1.5 billion stg.</p>
<p>Thistle's parent company, Brierley Investments Ltd of New Zealand, is expected to retain a significant minority stake in the hotelier.</p>
<p>Brierley owns 70 percent of the company , with the remaining stake held by investment arms of the Goverment of Singapore.</p>
<p>In its interim results statement which reported a near doubling of pretax and pre-exceptional profits to 24.1 million stg, Thistle said an indicative price range will be accounced at the time of the share offer.</p>
<p>Under the float plans Brierley will reduce its stake to below 50 percent, said the Thistle press statement, with a reduction also expected by the Singapore government.</p>
<p>In addition, the UK hotelier expects to raise another 250 million stg of new money.</p>
<p>As part of its flotation plans Thistle will introduce an Owners Club which will give individual shareholders, with a minimum-sized holding, access to a range of benefits and discounts.</p>
<p>Small investors who buy shares and keep them will be known as Founder Members, enjoying greater benefits.</p>
<p>The minimum application for shares is 1,000 stg. Baring Brothers International Ltd will act as sponsor and financial adviser and Merrill Lynch International as global co-ordinator, bookrunner and stockbroker.</p>
<p>Thistle owns 64 four-star hotels out of a total of 100 with more than 13,500 bedrooms.</p>
<p>In its results statement for the 28 weeks to July 14, Thistle said occupancy levels and the average payment rate for rooms was up across all regions. It predicted a positive outlook for the British hotel market, affording opportunities for organic growth.</p>
<p>The group said its results were also boosted by a larger contribution from big-spender business and leisure guests.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
