<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4490" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - British export recovery still not secure, analysts say.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - British export recovery still not secure, analysts say.</headline>
<byline>Michael Peacock</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's exporters are making noises about improving fortunes but economists say that any recovery may be thwarted if European markets remain flat.</p>
<p>Britain's struggling manufacturing industry is plagued by weak export markets and stockpiles of unsold goods. But recent survey evidence has suggested an export revival is on the way, offering a glimmer of hope.</p>
<p>&quot;The prospects are reasonable for an improvement in exports although recovery is patchy,&quot; said Sudhir Junankar, associate director of economics at the Confederation of British Industry.</p>
<p>&quot;Exports should grow quite well over the second half of the year,&quot; he added. The CBI industrial trends survey showed export orders picked up modestly in the four months to July while the British Chambers of Commerce second quarter report said manufacturing exports rose for the first time in five quarters.</p>
<p>But Junankar said the risk to a revival was weak European markets. &quot;Companies expect Europe to improve but there's a danger recovery could be delayed somewhat.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists agreed that an improvement in European economies was the key for British exports and said the currency markets could slam the door shut on an export revival.</p>
<p>The strength of the German mark, which European countries chasing the holy grail of European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) are duty bound to track, means many of Britain's continental partners cannot blow off the cobwebs of recession.</p>
<p>And since about 57 percent of British exports head for Europe, that has posed serious problems to manufacturers.</p>
<p>&quot;UK exporters say order books are up, albeit from a weak level, but the mark remains too high to ease European recovery,&quot; said Michael O'Hanlon, chief international economist at PaineWebber. &quot;Britain's export markets will continue to languish.&quot;</p>
<p>The mark's strength means German exports, upon which the European powerhouse relies, are uncompetitive. And with most continental European countries trying to cut public deficits to meet EMU constraints, economic austerity has become entrenched.</p>
<p>There are glimmers of hope. German GDP fell 0.5 percent quarter-on-quarter in the first three months of the year. A small pick-up is expected in the second quarter, and further improvement thereafter.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a more than 50 percent chance of British exports recovering this year,&quot; said Ian Fletcher, policy executive at the British Chambers of Commerce. &quot;I would hope the talked of improvement in EU markets will prompt a modest recovery.&quot;</p>
<p>But he warned that the export revival was not uniform. &quot;Medium-sized firms continued to report lower orders and sales.&quot;</p>
<p>Fletcher said it was unrealistic to expect exports to return to the heady levels of late 1994 and 1995, when they acted as the engine of economic recovery.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, he said exporters reported improved conditions despite two key obstacles -- sterling's rally and the BSE crisis.</p>
<p>The pound jumped from 2.17 marks late last year to 2.38 last month, although it has since drifted back to 2.29. And British firms selling abroad have had to deal with the effects of the ban on British beef and beef products following the &quot;mad cow&quot; scare.</p>
<p>O'Hanlon said the fact exporters are reporting improved conditions was significant. &quot;But those remarks have to be put into context in terms of the low level at which this growth is starting.&quot;</p>
<p>Official figures from the Office for National Statistics support the idea of an export revival. They showed Britain exported nine percent more, in value terms, to the rest of the world in the three months to May, than in the previous quarter.</p>
<p>But O'Hanlon said the figures did not tell the whole story. &quot;Export values have been going up because inflation has been falling, it's not so clear that volumes have been rising.&quot;</p>
<p>Certainly the British Treasury's forecast that Britain's export markets will grown by about 6.5 percent in 1996, is starting to look suspect, even though exports to the United States and Far East have held up well as economic growth remains robust there.</p>
<p>&quot;Volumes are going to slow because of the general malaise in Europe. Downgrade expectations for the rest of this year and the first part of next,&quot; O'Hanlon said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
