<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4493" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian Broadcasting Corp Midday Update.</title>
<headline>Australian Broadcasting Corp Midday Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>FEDERAL LABOR SENATOR RESIGNS FROM PARTY</p>
<p>Queensland Labor Party Senator, Mal Colston, has resigned from the Labor Party and will serve out the rest of his term as an Independent.</p>
<p>Senator Colson has been in the Senate since 1975 and will end his term in 1999.</p>
<p>He says his voting patterns will be influenced by his long held Labor beliefs, but also by an acceptance that the present Government has an electoral mandate to pursue a number of issues. The Senator has given no reason for his resignation.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Federal Opposition leader, Kim Beazley, says he hopes Senator Colston will change his mind.</p>
<p>Labour sources say Senator Colston's differences with the ALP are personality, rather than policy based.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PARLIAMENT HOUSE RIOT MAY COST A$100,000</p>
<p>The cost of yesterday's riot at Parliament House in Canberra has been estimated at nearly A$100,000.</p>
<p>About A$75,000 damage was done to the foyer and forecourt when protestors smashed down doors.</p>
<p>Once inside they rampaged through the Parliament gift shop, where it will cost A$15,000 to repair the damage and replace looted goods.</p>
<p>The rioters were a breakaway group from a much larger peaceful protest which ACTU Secretary Bill Kelty called the most successful in the country's history.</p>
<p>That remark's angered deputy Prime Minister, Tim Fischer, and Deputy Labor Leader, Gareth Evans is furious at the violence.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PEACEFUL ABORIGINAL PROTEST</p>
<p>Organisers of an Aboriginal protest in Canberra have stressed the contrast between their peaceful protest today and yesterday's storming of parliament house.</p>
<p>One thousand Aborigines have conducted a march to Parliament House and staged a rally on the lawn, in protest of Federal government budget cuts to indigenous affairs.</p>
<p>Aboriginal representative Charlie Perkins says the 1,000 protestors have gathered from all over Australia.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PAEDOPHILE WITNESS AT NSW COMMISSION</p>
<p>A self confessed paedophile has told the New South Wales police Royal Commission that up to 100 paedophiles are active in Sydney.</p>
<p>Codenamed KR-248, the man says that in most cases boys are willing partners looking for friendship, care, or money to survive on the streets.</p>
<p>KR-248 told the Commission that children could be picked up at most beaches or any public toilets.</p>
<p>He says there are four main areas where paedophile rings operate around Sydney including one with up to 50 members based in the city.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>VICTORIAN GOVT APPEALS COURT DECISION</p>
<p>An appeal against a decision to allow parents of intellectually disabled people to sue the Victorian Government is underway.</p>
<p>Parents of residents at Melbourne's Kew Cottages won the right to take action, after a Supreme Court Judge last year refused to strike out a major part of the writ.</p>
<p>They want the State Government to improve living conditions at the cottages, which they say have been the subject of reduced budgets since 1986.</p>
<p>But the State Government has launched action in the Court of Appeal, arguing the Courts don't have jurisdiction to querie how Governments spend money.</p>
<p>The Court's been told a decision to provide funding to any service is purely an act of Government.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MULTI-MILLION DOLLAR SEAL VIEWING CENTRE</p>
<p>Victoria is to have a multi-million dollar seal viewing centre at Phillip Island.</p>
<p>Premier Jeff Kennett says the two stage development, off the Nobbies, will make the Island one of Australia's leading eco-tourist destinations.</p>
<p>The Seal Rocks Sealife Centre, will feature an information and dining area, and provide giant video screens showing Australia's largest colony of fur seals.</p>
<p>Mr Kennett says stage two involves an underwater viewing tunnel leading to a tower above the Seal Rocks, but he says that project is subject to a strict environmental effects study.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>WHALES AND YACHTS TRAFFIC JAM</p>
<p>In North Queensland, a traffic jam of whales and yachts is converging in the Whitsundays.</p>
<p>More than 100 yachts from around the country are preparing for the Hamilton Island Race Week series.</p>
<p>Race official Ian Grant is expecting some close encounters this weekend, as migrating whales also gather to breed.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BOON'S TESTIMONIAL LINE UP</p>
<p>In cricket, West Indian Brian Lara, England's Devon Malcolm and New Zealand's Sir Richard Hadlee are expected to take part in former test cricketer David Boon's testimonial match in November.</p>
<p>Two one-day games will be held, one at the Melbourne Cricket Ground on November the twelfth and at the NTCA Ground in Launceston on November 14.</p>
<p>Former Test captain, Greg Chappell, says current and former Australian players plus Tasmanian-born AFL players will be among those taking part.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
