<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4496" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Caution culls Australia stocks gains by close.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Caution culls Australia stocks gains by close.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>-----------------(Snapshot 4.20 p.m./0620 GMT)-----------------</p>
<p>AORD		2264.70   +3.20   DJIA  cl	5699.40   +9.99</p>
<p>SPI futures	  2283	+7   US 30yr cl	 6.80   +0.03</p>
<p>10yrbond futs    92.080  -0.005   Gold (NY cl)  $387.20   -0.85</p>
<p>AUD	   0.7873 (Mon 0.7865)   CRB Index cl   251.97   +2.42</p>
<p>NIKKEI	   21127.01  +20.60   FTSE cl	 3863.70   -9.20</p>
<p>S&amp;P500(Globex)   668.30   +0.10   NZSE40	  2167.79   +0.54</p>
<p>--------------------------(Aug 20)-----------------------------</p>
<p>*Stocks end firmer, early strength sapped by sellers as caution won out ahead of the budget. Turnover 345.49 million shares, value A$851.17 million, 995 traded, 311 unch, 420 up, 264 down.  </p>
<p>The Australian share market ended just firmer on Tuesday and well off its highs as cautious players cashed in gains ahead of the Federal budget, due later today at 7.30 p.m. (0930 GMT).</p>
<p>At 4.10 p.m. (0610 GMT), the All Ordinaries index was up 3.2 points at 2,264.7 while September share index futures were up seven points at 2,283, an 18.3 point premium to the underlying index.</p>
<p>Brokers said few investors were willing to hold courageous positions ahead of the budget, allowing a wave of caution to wash over the market in the afternoon session.  </p>
<p>&quot;The sellers took over in the afternoon. People are getting careful before the release of the actual figures,&quot; said a Sydney broker.</p>
<p>&quot;No-one wants to be too brave so you've seen some profit taking after a strong couple of days.&quot;</p>
<p>The afternoon losses were spread around, resulting in a mixed bag of closes among the leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;It was mixed at the end but all were well off highs at the end,&quot; the broker said.</p>
<p>Turnover impressed, topping A$850 million, as investors showed a healthy interest in an active bourse.  </p>
<p>Interest rate sensitive stocks like banks and insurers climbed early but fell back to with the rest of the market in the afternoon session.</p>
<p>Rises outnumbered falls by a ratio of about five to three, while about 31 percent of stocks traded remained steady.</p>
<p>In other local markets, bonds eased back from the day's highs amid some profit-taking after a steep rally had taken yields to the lowest level since March 1994.</p>
<p>Sentiment, though remained extemely positive ahead of the Federal budget.  </p>
<p>The Australian dollar slipped a touch in the afternoon, reversing early buoyancy as market participants squared positions ahead of the budget.</p>
<p>At 4.55 p.m. (0655 GMT) the local currency was at US$0.7875/80, below Monday's late US$0.7878/83 level and resting on a technical support level at US$0.7880.</p>
<p>FUTURES/OPTIONS - Futures trading was at active levels with an extended trading session due to the budget. Options trade picked up but was otherwise unremarkable.</p>
<p>Total options traded 40,858 (34,883)</p>
<p>Turnover in September SPI contracts totalled 11,365 (9,650)  </p>
<p>-----------------------(TECHNICALS)-------------------------</p>
<p>Short-term range    Support   Restnce   RSI-14  MA-10  MA-20</p>
<p>AORD   2240/2280     2240	2280	67.42   2233   2200</p>
<p>SPI    2250/2290     2260	2300	66.29   2243   2210</p>
<p>---------------------(KEY ACTIVES)--------------------------</p>
<p>*Nat Aust Bnk A$12.55 (-.03) 12.53/12.70 Vol:4,726,897 *ComBank A$11.05 (+.06) 11.02/11.11 Vol: 3,571,946 *Westpac A$6.04 (+.04) 6.011/6.10 Vol: 3,339,805 *ANZ Bank A$6.64 (+.01) 6.61/6.70 Vol: 3,480,216 Banks star early on budget hopes but fall back to earth.</p>
<p>*News Corp A$6.46 (-.04) 6.46/6.51 Vol: 3,289,046 U.S-biased media major softens with market in afternoon.</p>
<p>*BHP A$17.50 (-.04) 17.50/17.75 Vol: 7,175,078 Bellwether sees sellers after early surge.</p>
<p>*CRA A$19.42 (+.05) 19.35/19.50 Vol: 1,412,654 Major miner ends at midday levels despite afternoon dip.</p>
<p>*WMC A$8.75 (+.08) 8.68/8.81 Vol: 4,008,123 Gold/nickel miner ends firmer, completes mixed bag of leaders.</p>
<p>-- Walter Watson 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
