<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4503" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian wool tax creates new instrument.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian wool tax creates new instrument.</headline>
<byline>Michael Byrnes</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new financial instrument to allow trading in tax credits in Australia's 2.18 million bale wool stockpile is expected to produce the first market in titles to the liquidation value of the world's largest pile of wool.</p>
<p>In the lead-up to trading which begins next week, through Australia's Macquarie Bank Ltd, nobody knows if the tax title market will be big or small.</p>
<p>But with wool growers eager for liquidity after years of being locked into the stockpile in tough times, the signs are that the the new instrument will attract reasonable interest.  </p>
<p>&quot;We think if growers were given the opportunity of accessing their equity early they would be more than eager to consider it,&quot; Peter Walsh, assistant director of the Wool Council of Australia, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;From a buyer's point of view, it's a very leveraged instrument, a leveraged play on the wool price,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;From what I understand there would be ample buying interest in the market place.&quot;</p>
<p>Randell Heyman, division director of the treasury and commodities group at Macquarie, said some approaches had been received from potential buyers.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're still working on the document that allows us to sell entitlements. Until we have (that) and (buyers and sellers) understand all the risks, it's going to be hard to gauge demand,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Coming weeks would show how that progressed, he said.</p>
<p>Walsh sees up to 100,000 interested sellers of wool tax credits -- the growers who have paid the statutory authority Wool International (WI) a 4.5 percent levy on raw wool sale proceeds in the past three years for stockpile debt repayments.</p>
<p>In the process, they built up about A$360 million worth of credits to the stockpile.  </p>
<p>Australia's wool stockpile is presently valued at about A$1.8 billion, but carries debt of about A$1.0 billion, leaving about A$800 million in available equity after all costs have been met by WI.</p>
<p>WI has estimated the end net value on liquidation of the stockpile at between A$600 million and A$900 million after discharge of debt, with A$750 million the most likely figure.</p>
<p>The Australian government is still yet to state when the equity will be distributed, in cash or in shares in WI trading affiliate Wool International Holdings Ltd.  </p>
<p>Current estimates of the first WI equity return are between very late 1998 and late 19990. &quot;It could even be longer than that,&quot; Walsh said.</p>
<p>The basis of tax credit unit prices will be set by the estimated value of WI on liquidation of the stockpile (about A$750 million) divided by total tax paid (A$360 million), expressed in net present value terms.</p>
<p>Tax credit units would then trade at a discount or premium depending on expected future wool prices.  </p>
<p>Until a present report in progress on valuations in relation to each A$1.00 in tax was complete it would be hard to speak values, Heyman said.</p>
<p>While the new instrument would generate cash flow for wool growers, it would not affect the wool market itself, Heyman and Walsh both said.</p>
<p>&quot;All you're doing is swapping one participant for someone else,&quot; Heyman said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
