<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4504" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Senate elects defector as deputy.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Senate elects defector as deputy.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's Senate, the upper house of parliament, on Tuesday elected Mal Colston as its deputy president amid controversy over his decision to quit the Labor Party earlier in the day.  </p>
<p>&quot;My loyalties will be directed not to any particular party or group of parties, rather my loyalty will be directed to the Senate ...&quot; Colston said in parliament after his election.  </p>
<p>Colston resigned as a Labor party senator to complete his present term, which ends in 1999, as an independent in the Senate.</p>
<p>Labor opposition Senate leader John Faulkner said he was disappointed Colston had not made his loyalties to the Labor party clear.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very disappointing that he did not mention the Labor party as Mal Colston has been a Labor party senator since the mid-1970's,&quot; Faulkner told Australian Broadcasting Corp Radio.  </p>
<p>&quot;He was endorsed as a labor party senator ... and as far as I'm concerned he has a primary loyalty to the Australian Labor Party,&quot; Faulkner said.</p>
<p>But Colston had indicated to a senior Labor member earlier on Tuesday that he would support the Labor party on the key policy issues in parliament, Faulkner said.</p>
<p>&quot;It remains to be seen how he will vote, but I am sure all those people that cast a ballot for the Labor party in the Senate in Queensland and elected Mal Colston will demand that level of loyalty from Mal Colston,&quot; Faulkner said.  </p>
<p>Queensland Labor party state secretary Mike Kaiser said in a statement on Tuesday that he understood Colston had resigned because the federal Labor party had chosen someone else for the position of Deputy President of the Senate.</p>
<p>In a fax to Kaiser, Colston said he had resigned because of significant differences between himself and other members of the federal Labor party.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt in my mind that Senator Colston's decision to resign was designed to put a loaded gun to Labor's head, but the Party was not prepared to give in to blackmail,&quot; Kaiser said.  </p>
<p>Colston's resignation from the Labor party means he is no longer bound by party policy and can decide his own position on legislation.</p>
<p>The Labor opposition and minor parties hold the balance of power in the Senate and have pledged to block some of the new Liberal-National government's reforms, including the partial privatisation of Telecommunications carrier Telstra Corp.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
