<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4506" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-QNI cautious on metal price outlook.</title>
<headline>RTRS-QNI cautious on metal price outlook.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Queensland-based nickel producer QNI Ltd said on Tuesday it was cautious about metal price trends in the coming year with both nickel and cobalt prices still down on their levels of a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;We are cautious about metal prices. It will be interesting to see if there is the traditional pick up in European markets in September,&quot; QNI managing director Wyn Davies told a news conference following the release of annual results.</p>
<p>Earlier, QNI reported a 20 percent fall in net profit to A$85.89 million in the 1996/97 year ended June 30.  </p>
<p>Davies declined to forecast a profit trend for the current year's first half, pointing to a 35 percent downward price movement in cobalt and nearly 25 percent in nickel over the last 12 months.</p>
<p>But he said the world stainless steel industry was &quot;not in dire straits&quot; with no shortages of cobalt and plenty of demand.</p>
<p>&quot;The (profit) outlook is tempered by caution but we will have this year the benefit of increased production with the two new (refinery) roasters helping a better second half,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>QNI's new A$50 million upgrade of its Port of Townsville ore unloading facility would be fully operational next month, enabling a potential doubling of shipments, Davies said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, QNI's search for new orebodies would continue with its first shipment of ore from the Philippines due in the next 10 days, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are tentatively looking for other ore feeds in the South West Pacific,&quot; Davies said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22471">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
