<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4511" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Mobil says sees refinery at 80 pct Wed.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Mobil says sees refinery at 80 pct Wed.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mobil Australia Ltd said on Tuesday its 108,000 barrels-per-day Altona refinery in Melbourne was expected to be back at around 80 percent of normal output by Wednesday morning, following the repair of its cracking unit.</p>
<p>&quot;The cracker is being tested at moment and we're expecting on spec product to be produced tomorrow ... morning,&quot; a Mobil spokeswoman told Reuters.</p>
<p>The refinery's cracker extracts gas, gasoline, diesel and LPG products after the crude distillation proces.  </p>
<p>The refinery, which is currently running at 60 percent, would remain at sub-peak output until next week while repairs were carried out to one of its three distillation units, the Mobil spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>She said the refinery had switched to 100 percent Gippsland crude input from its usual practice of supplementing Gippsland crude input with imports.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment we're running on 100 percent Gippsland crude and that's because Shell aren't taking any crude from Gippsland so we need to take their share. We've in fact just sold a cargo we had on the way,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>The spokeswoman said the cargo had been ordered for the refinery two months ago but she was unable to elaborate on the cargo's size or to whom it was sold.</p>
<p>She also could not comment on current total daily crude oil input levels.</p>
<p>Gippsland crude accounts for about half of the refinery's normal crude supplies.</p>
<p>It is piped from the offshore Bass Strait fields owned 50/50 by Exxon Corp subsidiary Esso Australia Ltd and The Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd.  </p>
<p>A Mobil source said Monday the refinery, which has been at partial production since August 13, took about 11 megalitres a day of Gippsland crude oil at normal operating levels.</p>
<p>Shell Australia Ltd has reduced its crude oil intake due to a strike over work practices which has reduced production at its Geelong refinery and stopped distribution from its shipping and Lara LPG terminals.</p>
<p>A Shell spokesman was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>-- Melbourne bureau 61-3 9286-1435</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
