<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4514" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Australian Labor defector to support party.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Australian Labor defector to support party.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Labor Opposition Senate leader John Faulkner said on Tuesday that Mal Colston, a Labor senator who resigned from the party earlier in the day, had indicated he would support the party in the Senate.</p>
<p>&quot;Senator Colston has indicated to Gareth Evans, the Deputy Leader of the Labor Party, that he will support the party on all major issues before the Senate,&quot; Faulkner told reporters.  </p>
<p>Faulkner said Colston had been pre-selected and endorsed by Labor for decades and the Labor party expected him to show a minimal amount of loyalty on the floor of the Senate.</p>
<p>&quot;We will demand of Senator Colston that he show that minimal level of loyalty to the party that has supported him in public life for so long,&quot; Faulkner said.</p>
<p>Colston said he intended to complete his present term in the Senate as an independent.  </p>
<p>&quot;My voting pattern in that chamber will be influenced by my long held Labor beliefs, by an acceptance that the present government has an electoral mandate to pursue a number of issues and by what I judge to be the most appropriate course of action for the people of Queensland (state),&quot; he said in statement.</p>
<p>Colston was unavailable for further comment.</p>
<p>His resignation means he is no longer bound by party policy and can decide his own position on legislation.  </p>
<p>The Labor opposition and minor parties hold the balance of power in the Senate and have pledged to block some of the new Liberal-National government's reforms, including the partial privatisation of Telecommunications carrier Telstra Corp.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
