<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4518" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Bradford has reservations on NZ Forest Corp sale.</title>
<headline>Bradford has reservations on NZ Forest Corp sale.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prominent government backbencher Max Bradford said on Tuesday he had significant reservations about the sale of Forestry Corporation to a consortium led by Fletcher Challenge Ltd.</p>
<p>Bradford is the ruling National Party's candidate for the seat of Rotorua and has questioned the wisdom of a sale to the Fletcher consortium after reports that it may scale down the Waipa sawmill situated in his electorate.</p>
<p>Bradford said a major positive of the deal announced on Tuesday was the commitment by the consortium not to close the Waipa mill and to invest NZ$16 million in an upgrade.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Prime Minister (Jim Bolger) and Finance Minister (Bill Birch) have given me a commitment they will ensure the FCL joint venture will live up to its commitment,&quot; Bradford said.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore, the workforce should have no concern about their jobs.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I would have to say Fletchers' poor public relations image means they start behind the eight-ball,&quot; Bradford said.</p>
<p>He said he &quot;would not be honest...if he did not admit to some significant reservations about the sale to Fletchers&quot;.  </p>
<p>&quot;Nor can I say all my concerns, particularly with respect to the development of the best long-term strategy for forestry in New Zealand and a healthy investment programme which leads to jobs and higher incomes with this bid have been satisfied by ministers.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Fletcher Forests chief executive Michael Andrews had agreed to put the company's plans to the local communities in a few days.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
