<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4521" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-QNI says markets to remain volatile.</title>
<headline>RTRS-QNI says markets to remain volatile.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Queensland-based nickel producer QNI Ltd said on Tuesday that it expected nickel and cobalt markets to remain volatile in the 1996/97 year to June 30.</p>
<p>Earlier, the company reported a 20 percent fall in annual net profit A$85.89 million.  </p>
<p>In a statement to the Australian Stock Exchange, QNI chairman Max Roberts said company profitability had been affected by falling metals prices and poor weather conditions that impacted on ore availability.</p>
<p>&quot;Unusually prolonged poor weather conditions at mine sites in New Caledonia and Indonesia also affected ore supply availability and quality that impacted on production at the Yabulu refinery,&quot; Roberts said.</p>
<p>He also noted that the group's first income tax expense of A$28.5 million and restructuring costs had also depressed the operating profit after tax.  </p>
<p>&quot;The cost of restructuring operations and maintenance costs associated with the first ever refinery shutdown in June totalled A$9.3 million and also contributed to the decrease in operating profit,&quot; Roberts said.</p>
<p>As a result of the refinery shutdown, the company said annual nickel production was down seven percent to 26,637 tonnes while cobalt production slipped to at 1,425 tonnes.</p>
<p>By 2.30 p.m. (0430 GMT), QNI shares were steady at A$2.75 on turnover of 1.17 million shares.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22471">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
