<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4522" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Path seen clear for silver to trade higher.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Path seen clear for silver to trade higher.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Silver prices have turned a corner after breaching technical resistance levels and are now poised for further gains, Australian metals dealers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>COMEX silver ended up 13.300 U.S. cents an ounce at $5.210, after trading up to a session high at $5.240.</p>
<p>Technical resistance markers surrounding a price of $5.15 an ounce had been keeping a cap on the price.</p>
<p>&quot;We think silver could trade up to around $5.40 (an ounce) over the next couple of months,&quot; Ross Ryan, a dealer for Macquarie Bank said.  </p>
<p>End users of silver, such as photographic film manufacturers and jewellery fabricators are said to be willing buyers of silver under $5.00 an ounce, but may now re-think their buying strategies in light of the price run-up.</p>
<p>&quot;It all depends on whether silver keeps going up and the price is sustainable,&quot; another dealer said.</p>
<p>Silver has been stuck in a $5.00-$5.18 range for a couple of months and was long-due for a price move outside the range, the dealer said.  </p>
<p>Australia's MIM Holdings Ltd, which produced 12.6 million ounces of silver in 1995/96, making it one of the world's largest silver miners, would see about A$5 million added to its bottom line for each 10 percent gain in the price on an annual basis, a company spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Perth Mint on Tuesday quoted silver at US$5.23 an ounce (A$6.61).</p>
<p>-- James Regan Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
