<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4526" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: World sugar prices under threat, expert says.</title>
<headline>World sugar prices under threat, expert says.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>World sugar prices are forecast to fall at an underlying rate of more than two percent a year as cheaper alternative sweeteners increase their competitive pressure, a leading commodity expert said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If wages are to rise, successful sugar industries are likely to have to sustain yearly productivity increases of three percent or more if they are to remain competitive internationally,&quot; managing director of U.K.-based Landell Mills Commodities, James Fry, told the Sugar 2000 Symposium.</p>
<p>In a global view of the sugar industry, Fry said in every continent, sugar had lost market share since 1980 to cheaper,  calorie-free sweetener alternatives.</p>
<p>Sugar's proportion of world sweetener demand was below 80 percent in 1995 compared with more than 87 percent in 1980, Fry told the conference.</p>
<p>&quot;If sugar had been able to do no better than maintain its share of the world sweetener market since 1980, sugar demand in 1995 would have been 10 percent-or over 11 million tonnes - higher than it actually was,&quot; Fry said.</p>
<p>&quot;Production costs feed back to world prices,&quot; Fry said.</p>
<p>&quot;Low-cost producers in Australia, Thailand, Brazil, India and southern Africa will therefore continue to grow in importance while the role of high-cost producers in Europe, the United States, the Caribbean and Eastern Asia will diminish,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Fry said Australia's willingness to invest a higher proportion of sugar revenues in research and development than any other country &quot;bodes well for the future.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Australia's high yields in the field and good factory recoveries are targets for other producers (but) the gap between Australia's performance and that in other countries has shrunk,&quot; Fry said.</p>
<p>Technical progress was essential for international sugar industries' success, he said.</p>
<p>Fry said Australia, India and Thailand had lowered real field costs substantially since 1980. But when field and factory costs were combined, Thailand and Australia were the most competitive countries, he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100136">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
