<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4530" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ govt sells Forestry Corp for NZ$2.026 bln.</title>
<headline>NZ govt sells Forestry Corp for NZ$2.026 bln.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand government said on Tuesday it had sold its shares in Forestry Corp of New Zealand to a Fletcher Challenge-Brierley Investments-China International Trust and Investment (Citifor) consortium for NZ$2.026 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;This exceeds the book value of $2.024 billion and is a very good price,&quot; Finance Minister Bill Birch told a briefing.</p>
<p>FCNZ carries $426 million in debt and other liabilities and the net proceeds to the government will be $1.6 billion.</p>
<p>Birch said the proceeds would be used to repay foreign debt which was now eliminated.  </p>
<p>He said the purchase went to the highest bidder and the deal did not include any tax concessions.</p>
<p>&quot;Forestry tax laws are clear. Fletcher Challenge and its partners have no special ability to reduce Forestry Corporation-related tax,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>FCNZ's main asset is cutting rights to 188,000 hectares of mainly pine and fir forest in the central North Island.</p>
<p>FCL said it would invest NZ$260 million over the next seven to eight years in new wood processing facilities in the central North Island and it expects to generate 700 new jobs.</p>
<p>FCL also plans to ungrade FCNZ's current Waipa mill.  </p>
<p>Birch said Maori land claims were not affected by the sale and were protected under law.</p>
<p>In a separate agreement, the government has agreed to buy out FCNZ's long-term contracts from FCL unit Tasman Pulp and Paper for $30 million. The contracts had 34 years to run and related to FCNZ's obligation to supply logs to Tasman.</p>
<p>The sale is New Zealand's second largest privatisation after the sale of Telecom Corp of New Zealand Ltd in 1990 for $4.25 billion.  </p>
<p>The Fletcher /Brierley /Citifor group won the bid ahead of a Carter Holt Harvey consortium which included Malaysia's Jaya Tiasa and Te Ama, the commercial arm of Maori tribes who claim ownership of FCNZ's land.</p>
<p>U.S. giant Weyerhaeuser Co was another bidder.</p>
<p>The forests were valued in FCNZ's 1994/95 accounts at $2.1 billion.</p>
<p>In the 15 months to June 30, 1995, FCNZ made an after tax profit of $141.2 million on sales of $495 million.  </p>
<p>The land on which FCNZ grows its trees is owned by the government and is leased back to the corporation.</p>
<p>Maori tribes claim the land and are expected to become the eventual owners.</p>
<p>FCNZ controls 13 percent of New Zealand's commercial plantation forest but a greater proportion of the uncommitted woodflow.</p>
<p>Currently, it harvests annually 2.6 million cubic metres of radiata pine, 250,000 cubic metres of Douglas fir and 250,000 cubic metres of minor species.  </p>
<p>The corporation produces approximately 200,000 cubic metres of lumber annually, representing 6.9 percent of New Zealand's total production.</p>
<p>Japan and South Korea are the major markets for FCNZ'S logs.</p>
<p>FCNZ employs 700 people and its contractors employ a further 630.</p>
<p>Its Kaingaroa forest processing plan is technologically advanced and processes whole trees in a &quot;factory&quot; environment while its Waipa processing plant is one of the largest radiata lumber processing plants in Australasia.</p>
<p>Last year, the Forestry Ministry estimated that between  </p>
<p>NZ$4.5 billion and $6.4 billion would have to be invested in processing over the next 15 years if New Zealand was to maximise its value potential. Such an investment would create between 30,000 and 40,000 new jobs, Forest Minister John Falloon said.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
