<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4539" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Queensland cane growers expect record crop.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Queensland cane growers expect record crop.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Queensland sugar growers expect a record sugar cane crop this year totalling more than 37 million tonnes, some two million tonnes more than in 1995, Canegrowers chairman Harry Bonanno said.</p>
<p>&quot;Between June and December this year, about 6,300 growers will harvest over 37 million tonnes, our fifth successive record crop,&quot; Bonanno told a Sugar 2000 symposium.</p>
<p>Bonanno also said Queensland growers expected to produce more than five million tonnes of raw sugar this year, four years ahead of their target date.  </p>
<p>&quot;This is extremely creditable when it is considered that it was only in 1993 that we exceeded four million tonnes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>If sugar prices remained reasonably attractive to growers, the Queensland industry had the potential to produce more than six million tonnes by 2003, Bonanno said.</p>
<p>He told the sugar conference that increasing production efficiencies had seen the average 70 hectare farm producing about 5,600 tonnes of cane annually.</p>
<p>&quot;But with this year's falling sugar price, we must continue to improve our performance if we are to cope successfully with recurring fluctuations in price,&quot; Bonanno said.  </p>
<p>Queensland, the world's sixth largest sugar producer, produces more than 95 percent of Australia's raw sugar and virtually all its exports.</p>
<p>In the 1995 season, Australia produced a record 37.39 million tonnes of cane, of which 35.30 million came from Queensland, and 4.98 million tonnes of 94 net titre raws, of which 4.73 million tonnes were from Queensland.</p>
<p>Australia's raws output was the second highest on record.</p>
<p>The minor New South Wales crop is all used domestically.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100136">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
