<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4543" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian senator quits Labor opposition.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian senator quits Labor opposition.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A member of Australia's Labor Party opposition said he quit the party on Tuesday in a move that could affect government efforts to pass legislation through parliament's upper house, the Senate.</p>
<p>Mal Colston, a Labor senator, said his resignation took effect immediately.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is my intention to complete my present term in the Senate as an independent,&quot; Colston said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;My voting pattern in that chamber will be influenced by my long held Labor beliefs, by an acceptance that the present government has an electoral mandate to pursue a number of issues and by what I judge to be the most appropriate course of action for the people of Queensland (state),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Colston would not comment further. His resignation from the Labor Party means he is now no longer bound by party policy and can decide his own position on legislation.  </p>
<p>The new conservative Liberal-National government elected in March does not have a majority in the Senate and needs support of at least two non-government senators to pass legislation.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard, pointing to his landslide election win, has claimed a strong mandate from the electorate for several controversial moves, including selling one-third of government telecoms giant Telstra Corp.</p>
<p>The Labor opposition and minor parties holding the Senate balance of power have pleged to block some of the government reforms, including the partial Telstra privatisation.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
