<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4546" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Protests continue on eve of Australian budget.</title>
<headline>Protests continue on eve of Australian budget.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's new conservative government said it would hand down a &quot;fair&quot; budget on Tuesday night, but budget opponents rallied for a second day outside parliament, the scene of a riot the day before.</p>
<p>The five-month-old Liberal-National government was to announce its budget to June 30, 1997 at 0930 GMT. The budget will be its first and the first for a conservative Australian government in 14 years.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to be a fair budget, and we are looking forward to putting in place the measures that will help families and small businesses and get Australia moving,&quot; Treasurer Peter Costello told reporters on Tuesday morning.</p>
<p>The government has promised to cut A$4.0 billion (US$3.0 billion) from its maiden budget in a tough fiscal programme aimed at achieving a budget surplus within three years. The budget deficit for 1995/96 was A$10.3 billion.</p>
<p>But the sharp spending cuts already announced have provoked angry protests across Australia from workers, students, Aborigines and welfare groups.</p>
<p>Monday's riot outside parliament house began during a rally in the capital by up to 15,000 unionists, aborigines, students, welfare and other community groups.</p>
<p>Police in riot gear fought for two hours to control hundreds of protesters who stormed the foyer of Parliament House.</p>
<p>Aboriginal organisers of Tuesday's protest have promised a peaceful rally. About 600 Aborigines gathered for an overnight protest on the lawns of old parliament house.</p>
<p>The government has announced funding cuts of A$400 million for indigenous people over the next four years.</p>
<p>Financial markets are concerned about Australia's chronic national savings and external debt problems and are counting on Costello slashing the budget deficit, hopefully by more than the forecast A$4.0 billion.</p>
<p>Canberra, committed to no extra tax revenue, has already announced big spending cuts in aboriginal affairs, higher education and programmes to help the jobless find work.</p>
<p>Ideally, markets want a bottom-line underlying deficit of at most A$5.0 billion, half the 1995/96 shortfall. The underlying deficit excludes one-off items such as asset sales.</p>
<p>(A$1 = US$0.78)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
