<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4547" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FORECAST - Qantas net seen higher.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FORECAST - Qantas net seen higher.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Morrison</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Qantas Airways Ltd is expected to fly slightly above its prospectus net profit forecast of A$237 million for the year to June 30, 1996 but analysts said 1996/97 results could hit some turbulence over current wage talks.</p>
<p>Australian aviation analysts expect Qantas to report an annual net profit before abnormals of between A$237 million and A$249 million. The airline is expected to pay a second half dividend of 13 cents, making a total of 16.5 for the year.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the Qantas result would be helped by lower costs, on which the airline has focussed since it became a publicly-owned company in July 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;We have got an official figure of A$237 (million), but I really expect it to be around the A$240 to A$245 million mark and that would be largely driven by the cash flow being steered towards paying off debt,&quot; a Melbourne analyst said.</p>
<p>ANZ McCaughan aviation analyst Yasmin Allen expects Qantas to report a profit of A$237 million for 1995/96. &quot;I would not be surprised to see it come in above that,&quot; Allen told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Another Melbourne-based aviation analyst forecast Qantas to report a net profit right on the prospectus forecast of A$237 million while one Sydney-based analyst forecast a net profit before abnormals of A$239.1 million for the year.</p>
<p>&quot;They have done well on the cost reduction side and they have seen the market grow, but they have lost market share, so add all that up and I think they will come out about square,&quot; the second Melbourne-based analyst said.</p>
<p>Last week the Department of Transport released data showing that Qantas, including wholly-owned Australia Asia Airlines, had a 37.9 percent international market share in April.  </p>
<p>Qantas, which is 25 percent owned by British Airways Plc, forecast in its 1995 prospectus that its international market share would be 41.1 percent for the June 30, 1996 year.</p>
<p>Qantas, known as the 'flying Kangaroo' estimated a one percentage point variation from this forecast would affect the bottom line profit by A$48 million.</p>
<p>However, analysts said they were more interested in comments about Qantas' outlook for the 1996/97 year, as costs may increase, arising from current wage talks, renewed domestic competition, and continued pressure on international routes.  </p>
<p>Qantas has offered an eight percent pay rise over two years over two years on condition that productivity reforms are implemented, but unions want productivity gains to be rewarded by a wage rise over and above the eight percent offer.</p>
<p>Qantas shares took a dive to a record low of A$1.87 on July 24 as the market got the jitters that management had conceded to union pressure and award a wage rise above eight percent.</p>
<p>The unions initially made a claim for two consecutive annual wage rises of 10 percent but last month, Qantas chief executive James Strong said this claim would wipe out the airline's profit if successful.  </p>
<p>Qantas shares have now moved back to familiar territory and on Tuesday were trading at A$2.17.</p>
<p>Analysts expect Qantas to report a net profit before abnormals of between A$260 million to A$273 million for 1996/97, but some analysts said they would be ready to mark down these numbers if there were some very negative comments from Qantas.</p>
<p>They said the planned purchase by Air New Zealand Ltd of a 50 percent stake in local airline Ansett Airlines Ltd may pressure the 1996/97 results  </p>
<p>&quot;People have known what 96 will look like but 97 is going to be a different story for a whole mix of things and there should also be some impact from a combined Ansett/Air New Zealand when that starts to happen later this year,&quot; the Sydney analyst said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
