<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4551" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: OPINION - From the Beehive - NZ govt bumbling.</title>
<headline>OPINION - From the Beehive - NZ govt bumbling.</headline>
<byline>Ian Templeton</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The government's bumbling performance has left Beehive watchers scratching their heads over what master plan its celebrated strategists are following in the run-up to the election.</p>
<p>The last minute U-turn over the culling of Kiamanawa wild horses, the Michelle Boag affair, and a less than triumphant visit to South Africa by Prime Minister have left the government looking increasingly vulnerable.  </p>
<p>And its failure to ram home the political pluses in the sale of Forestcorp has compounded the appearance of a government running out of steam.</p>
<p>There may be another public backlash over the price at which Forestcorp is sold - largely because expectations have been built that it would go for around $2 billion, ignoring the $500 million or so of debt the SOE is carrying.</p>
<p>Even so, an announcement naming the successful bidders for the huge Bay of Plenty forest cutting rights is due after it goes to the government caucus tomorrow.  The latest opinion poll, admittedly from the relatively small sample of 500 voters, confirms a slump in support for the government.</p>
<p>National has dropped five percentage points to 37 percentin the last fortnight. That is a much sharper decline than had been expected, even by those realistic enough to believe  that the lead it had been enjoying for most of the year would begin to shrink as polling day approached.</p>
<p>The TV3-CM Research Gallup Poll wasn't all bad news for the government; it confirmed that New Zealand First's challenge, which last month's poll showed was beginning to bend, is still on a downward slope.  </p>
<p>NZ First has dropped four points to 17 percent, while Labour has regained its slot as the main opposition party with a one-point rise to 20 percent support.</p>
<p>The Alliance which has been campaigning vigorously against the sale of Forestcorp has risen five percentage points to 14 percent.</p>
<p>Among the smaller parties, the Christian coalition has risen from 1.7 percent in the last sampling at the beginning of August to 4.3 percent.  </p>
<p>Even though the party still has not reached the 5 percent threshold, the rise in support for the Christians in this poll parallels the upward movement recorded to other major poll conducted for the rival television channel.</p>
<p>With only 40 working days left to the election, it may take something spectacular to revive the government's hopes of a clear-cut election result.</p>
<p>So far they are showing little of the spirit that carried the All Blacks to their astonishing comebacks against the Wallabies and the Springboks.  </p>
<p>It's too far fetched to suggest, as some Beehive-watchers have done in recent days, that the master plan envisages an election outcome that makes governing by any conceivable grouping virtually impossible - thus forcing a second election some time in 1997, at a time when the majority of Kiwis will be so appalled at the lack o a helmsman at the wheel they will turn back in overwhelming numbers to the safest pair of hands.</p>
<p>For the government, there is considerable disappointment that positive economic factors are not yielding the political spin-off it had hoped for.  </p>
<p>The gains in employment, with the steady shrinking in the dole queues, have been virtually submerged in the backwash.</p>
<p>And the tax cuts do not appear to have influenced swinging voters, to any significant degree.</p>
<p>Still, Education Minister Wyat Creech could point to a good outcome from the protracted negotiations over a pay rise for secondary school teachers.</p>
<p>And possibly the Australian budget will have a flow-on effect to New Zealand, if the money markets there react to a deficit-pruning effort by the Treasurer Peter Costello.  </p>
<p>A further cut in official interest rates in Australia could produce cheaper money in New Zealand, too, and that could provide a boost for the local sharemarket, re-igniting greater confidence that the economy is moving in the right direction. But it is evident that the government has a real fight on its hands to come out on top on October 12.</p>
<p>(Note - The opinions expressed in this article represent the views of the author only. They should not be seen as reflecting the views of Reuters)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
