<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4552" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Hardie Boys says NZ no-confidence rules may change.</title>
<headline>Hardie Boys says NZ no-confidence rules may change.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Governor-General Sir Michael Hardie Boys said New Zealand may eventually opt to change the rules governing parliament so a vote of no-confidence would be taken only if there was a new government in waiting.</p>
<p>&quot;One day we might get to the position -- and it would require a general agreement to do it -- that we should have a constructive vote of no-confidence so that the vote is for no-confidence in one administration and confidence in another, so you know what the alternative is. But we haven't got to that yet,&quot; Hardie Boys said in an interview with Reuters.  </p>
<p>&quot;Maybe experience will bring everybody to realise that should be done. It would make my position much easier,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The governor-general has &quot;reserve powers&quot; to appoint or dismiss a prime minister or in special circumstances to refuse a dissolution of parliament. All other decisions must be taken on the advice of ministers.</p>
<p>Hardie Boys noted that even a caretaker government could remain in office until it lost a confidence vote.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
