<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4556" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ Electoral Commission attacks broadcasting rules.</title>
<headline>NZ Electoral Commission attacks broadcasting rules.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Electoral Commission on Tuesday released details of broadcasting time and funding for political parties for the coming election, but was critical of the system it operated under.</p>
<p>The commission said the criteria in the Broadcasting Act were deficient and neeeded to be re-examined after the election.</p>
<p>It said within the strict requirements of the Act it could not &quot;exclude a registered political party that some voters would consider not to be a 'serious' party or to have little chance of success&quot;.  </p>
<p>It said the allocation of money had not been increased since 1990 but now had to be divided among 20 elligible parties.</p>
<p>&quot;If the commission makes no allocation to a minor party, that party cannot obtain any broadcasting time,&quot; the commission said. However granting funds to small parties disadvantaged larger parties because they were prevented from buying more broadcasting time with their own funds.</p>
<p>The commission had $1.85 million to allocate and despite submissions to the government, no increase was approved.  </p>
<p>It allocated $534,360 to the ruling National Party, $431,540 to the main opposition Labour Party and about $250,000 each to the Alliance and New Zealand First.</p>
<p>The government's coalition partner United, with seven MPs in the House, received $93,000, the same as the Christian Coalition with only one MP and free-market party Act New Zealand which has no MPs. United has barely registered in opinion polls while the Christian and Act parties have regularly polled between two percent and five percent.  </p>
<p>The &quot;joke&quot; party McGillicuddy Serious, the Aotearoa Legalise Cannabis Party and the one MP Conservative Party each get $35,000 as do the Progressive Greens and the &quot;transcendentalists&quot; of the Natural Law Party.</p>
<p>Smaller amounts are allocated to eight other parties.</p>
<p>On top of the funds allocated, the 12 largest parties also receive free radio and television time on state broadcasters for their opening and closing addresses.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
