<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4558" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: More than 600 said missing after Vietnam storm.</title>
<headline>More than 600 said missing after Vietnam storm.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than 600 people are missing after a series of storms which struck northern Vietnam last week, and city authorities in Hanoi said on Tuesday they were placing the capital on maxmimum flood alert.</p>
<p>Voice of Vietnam radio said 34 people had been killed and 22 were missing following torrential rain in remote mountain provinces of northwest Vietnam over the weekend.</p>
<p>Efforts were continuing meanwhile in coastal provinces to the southeast of Hanoi to try to account for hundreds not seen since a whirlwind storm struck the area a few days earlier.</p>
<p>In an interview with the Tuoi Tre newspaper on Tuesday Agriculture Minister Nguyen Cong Tan said 635 people were missing and warned the true death toll was unlikely to be known for some time.</p>
<p>He said most of the missing had been aboard fishing boats caught at sea as the storm swept the coast.</p>
<p>Newspapers on Tuesday described the flooding as the worst to strike northern Vietnam in years.</p>
<p>The Saigon Times daily said water was being released from the massive Hoa Binh reservoir to the west of Hanoi in order to reduce flooding further upstream.</p>
<p>The newspaper quoted agriculture ministry officials as urging the evacuation of people living along nearby rivers.</p>
<p>City authorities in Hanoi placed the capital ity of 2.2 million people on maximum flood alert as water levels continued rising on the Red River.</p>
<p>They warned that tropical storm Niki was approaching Vietnam across the South China Sea and could bring further flooding later this week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
