<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4562" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan denies call for China capital-flow review.</title>
<headline>Taiwan denies call for China capital-flow review.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The central bank on Tuesday denied a newspaper report that said Taiwan's president had urged the bank to study how to control capital outflows to China.</p>
<p>The Economic Daily News reported in its Tuesday edition that President Lee Teng-hui had raised the issue in a meeting on Monday with central bank governor Sheu Yuan-dong.</p>
<p>The report said Lee also had pressed the central bank to find ways to better manage indirect investment by Taiwanese banks in China in an apparent bid to further limit the island's economic exposure on its long-time communist rival's turf.</p>
<p>&quot;The report, which was headlined the central bank to study controlling capital outflows to China, is absolutely not true,&quot; the bank said in a statement.</p>
<p>It said Sheu attended a routine monthly meeting in the Presidential Office on Monday to hear a speech related to biotechnology prospects, but did not meet Lee.</p>
<p>Speculation that Taipei might change its China policies has mounted since Lee cautioned on August 14 that the island needed to avoid over-dependence on the mainland as a target for investment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
