<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4564" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Dissidents face trial in wake of Vietnam congress.</title>
<headline>Dissidents face trial in wake of Vietnam congress.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Edwards</byline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam is expected to place two prominent intellectuals on trial this week nine months after the pair were arrested in a crackdown on dissent ahead of June's Communist Party Congress.</p>
<p>Dissident sources and Hanoi-based diplomats said Le Hong Ha, a former high-ranking party member, and Ha Si Phu, a leading academic, would appear in court in Hanoi on Thursday.</p>
<p>The two men are being charged under a catch-all section of Vietnam's penal code involving violations of national security. If convicted they face likely jail terms of between two and seven years. In serious cases the term can be extended to 15 years.</p>
<p>Their arrests late last year were widely interpreted as part of a broader crackdown on dissent as the Hanoi authorities prepared for the June congress.</p>
<p>Ha Si Phu, also known as Nguyen Xuan Tu, was detained following an interview with a foreign radio station and after distributing documents in which it is said he openly criticised the Hanoi government.</p>
<p>Le Hong Ha, whose also used the name Le Van Quy, was expelled from the ruling Communist Party in June last year after voicing support for an outspoken communist dissident Hoang Minh Chinh. Hoang Minh Chinh had been jailed a few weeks earlier.</p>
<p>Several international human rights groups condemned the arrests at the time.</p>
<p>The U.S.-based group Human Rights Watch/Asia said Vietnam -- which signed the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights in 1982 -- had placed itself in violation of international laws.</p>
<p>Official confirmation was not available on Tuesday and it was not clear whether outside observers would be allowed to attend the trial.</p>
<p>But foreign diplomats said the trial -- the first such case since the congress -- was likely to be watched for indications of the prevailing political mood in Vietnam.</p>
<p>The late-June conclave, the country's most important political event in years, saw a shake-up of the party leadership and the appointment of a number of security and defence-related personnel to prominent politburo positions.</p>
<p>But seven weeks after that event the picture remains hazy, and Hanoi's political rumour mill has fallen quiet. In some cases newly-appointed personnel have yet to take up their expected posts.</p>
<p>In a faxed statement the Paris-based pressure group Alliance Vietnam Liberte said Ha Si Phu's case was being followed closely by groups across Europe and North America.</p>
<p>It called on Hanoi to allow independent observers to attend the trial. The statement made no mention of Le Hong Ha's case.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
