<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4566" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan severs diplomatic ties with Niger.</title>
<headline>Taiwan severs diplomatic ties with Niger.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's foreign ministry said on Tuesday it had severed ties with Niger after the West African state renewed diplomatic relations with China.</p>
<p>Niger -- one of just 31 countries in the world which had recognised Taipei insteadof Beijing -- made an about-face on Monday and said the People's Republic of China was the sole legal government of China and Taiwan was part of its territory.</p>
<p>&quot;The Republic of China (Taiwan) deeply regrets Niger's submission to communist China's threats and temptations and has decided to terminate diplomatic relations with Niger with immediate effect and stop all cooperation between the two countries,&quot; a Taiwan foreign ministry statement issued late on Monday said.</p>
<p>&quot;Communist China forced Niger to stop relations with us as a condition for renewing their ties...,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Republic of China (Taiwan) government offers the strongest condemnation of such behavior from communist China. Our government...will continue to expand our external relations, and our position is firm and will never sway.</p>
<p>China has recently stepped up international contacts in a bid to counter a diplomatic offensive by Taiwan, which has relations with nine other African states, including South Africa. Chinese President Jiang Zemin visited six African countries in May, including Niger's neighbour Mali.</p>
<p>Taipei's decision to sever ties with Niger comes amid news that Taiwan's vice-president was on a secretive trip to an unspecified country where it has no diplomatic ties, apparently in Europe.</p>
<p>Vice President Lien Chan, described by one Taipei daily as &quot;travelling like a cat&quot;, made a brief and quiet stopover in Vienna and left only oblique clues as to his final destination.</p>
<p>Taiwan's state-funded Central News Agency said from Vienna that unsubstantiated reports had Lien &quot;heading north&quot; or perhaps going to a &quot;German-speaking country bordering Italy&quot; -- a clear reference to Switzerland.</p>
<p>Lien's move is expected to anger Beijing, which has tried to shut down Taiwan's international activity. Investors, wary that China-Taiwan tensions could quickly boil up again, sent the island's stock market reeling on Tuesday for the second day.</p>
<p>Any country which allows senior Taiwanese politicians on its soil may be set on a diplomatic collision course with China which has regarded Nationalist-ruled Taiwan as a renegade province since the end of a Chinese civil war in 1949.</p>
<p>The Vatican is the only state in Europe which has diplomatic relations with Taiwan, recognising Taipei as China's capital rather than Beijing.</p>
<p>Niger and Taiwan renewed relations in 1992, causing a break in the African country's ties with China, but winning Niamey a US$50 million Taiwan loan.</p>
<p>Taiwan, holding foreign-exchange reserves of US$85.18 billion, among the largest in the world, has set up a US$1 billion dollar fund to aid Third World development.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
