<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4568" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan 3-mth CD rate falls to near two-month low.</title>
<headline>Japan 3-mth CD rate falls to near two-month low.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>0208 GMT	     Aug 19</p>
<p> *Key overnight call	   0.48 pct	     0.46 pct</p>
<p> *TIFFE 3mth Euroyen futures 99.16		  99.19</p>
<p>-------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>Japan's key three-month certificates of deposit (CDs) rate fell to 0.60 percent in late morning on Tuesday, its lowest since June 26, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The low rate of the new issues indicates that there is a growing belief within the market that there won't be an interest rate rise in the next three months,&quot; a city bank trader said.  </p>
<p>About 30 billion yen worth of three-month CDs was issued at 0.60 percent in late morning Tokyo, traders said.</p>
<p>Three-month CDs had been issued at 0.62 percent and 0.61 percent earlier in the morning, before falling to 0.60 percent, the city bank trader said.</p>
<p>A broker said about 110 billion yen worth of three-month CDs was issued at 0.62 percent, while about 40 billion yen worth of three-month CDs was issued at 0.61 percent.</p>
<p>The three-month CD rates were down from Monday's 0.63 percent.  </p>
<p>About 140 billion yen worth of two-month CDs was issued at 0.60 percent. The rate was down from Monday's 0.61 percent.</p>
<p>One-month CDs were tagged with a sell quote of 0.51 percent. The rate was unchanged from Monday.</p>
<p>The key overnight call rate rose slightly in the morning to 0.48 percent, up from Monday's 0.46 percent.</p>
<p>Traders said this was due to increased fund demand on a bond settlement day.</p>
<p>The Bank of Japan conducted a neutral money market operation for the third consecutive day this morning. Traders said this was within market expectations.  </p>
<p>Key December three-month Euroyen futures on TIFFE stood at 99.16 as of 0249 GMT, down from Monday's 99.19.</p>
<p>&quot;The December Euroyen futures' slight weakness is due to concern about the current high level of prices,&quot; a trader for a second city bank said.</p>
<p>Lingering concern about a possible interest rate rise at Tuesday's Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting is also discouraging further buying, the trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Most traders think neither the FOMC nor the BOJ will raise rates soon. But there is still some concern about the possibility,&quot; he said. -- Masayuki Kitano, (81-3-5473-3748)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
