<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4571" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks end slightly higher on fund entry.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks end slightly higher on fund entry.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks ended slightly higher after moving in negative territory for most of the session on Tuesday as a market support fund helped bolster the flagging bourse, brokers asid.</p>
<p>The SET index ended 3.93 points higher at 1,071.41 on thin 2.4 billion baht. Decliners outnumbered gainers 162 to 142 with 127 unchanged. The SET-50 index was 0.36 points higher at 81.25.</p>
<p>&quot;The only reason (for the gain) probably is some slight investment from the support fund,&quot; said an analyst at a foreign firm.  </p>
<p>But stock analysts said the market, dogged by political worry for the past week, was still bearish. &quot;A lot of people are still looking to sell,&quot; the foreign analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;The SET index has not able to rise because of political uncertainty, we just have to wait for the political situation to clear,&quot; said an analyst at Adkinson Securities.</p>
<p>The bourse, in the doldrums for several months on marco-economic concerns, was hit by jitters last week when one of Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa's coalition partners pulled out of the government. Banharn is now facing what is likely to be a bruising censure attack in parliament.  </p>
<p>Part of a 21 billion baht market support fund entered the market late on Monday and was thought to have been supporting some stocks on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The fund was announced at the beginning fo the month after the market retreated 15 percent in July as foreigners, worried about the economy, off-loaded Thai shares.</p>
<p>Communications firm Advanced Info was most active, ending four higher at 320, while United Commmunication slipped six to 256. Bangkok Bank was unchanged at 206 and Finance One gained one to 103.</p>
<p>-- Robert Birsel (662) 252-9950</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
