<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4573" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore shares end up, speculators at play.</title>
<headline>Singapore shares end up, speculators at play.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brisk trading in second liners drove Singapore shares to close up on Tuesday. Sentiment was partly lifted by strong July trade figures.</p>
<p>Dealers said the focus was on shares hit by takeover manoeuvres or rumours. However, blue chip stocks were subdued with cautious bargain hunting in property and selective stocks.</p>
<p>The 30-share Straits Times Industrials Index was up 18.15 points at 2,123.81. The UOB SESDAQ index tracking second liners was firmer at 85.14, rising 3.91 percent or 3.20 points.</p>
<p>Advances led decliners by 245 to 107. Volume was 165.36 million shares.  </p>
<p>Transmarco shares were suspended at mid afternoon. Its last traded price was S$9.80, up S$0.95 on a turnover of 2.65 million shares. A joint bank statement said on Tuesday Putera Sampoerna's Miel Investment Corp had agreed to buy one million Transmarco shares at Singapore $8.55 each, up from last weekend's takeover offer of S$6.50 for each share.</p>
<p>Causeway Investment jumped to lead actives with a hefty 12.54 million shares amid takeover and other rumours. It rose S$0.09 to S$1.55. Electronic firm Fu Yu also traded heavily with 10.58 million shares, gaining 11 cents to S$0.64.</p>
<p>-Seah Beng Nah 65 8703080.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
