<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4576" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Improved trade data fails to lift Singapore dollar.</title>
<headline>Improved trade data fails to lift Singapore dollar.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Singapore dollar remained on soft ground on Tuesday, despite news of an unexpected rise in the country's non-oil exports for July, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Trade Development Board said Singapore's non-oil domestic exports rose a nominal 6.4 percent year-on-year in July to Singapore $7.28 billion after falling 6.1 percent in June.</p>
<p>A Reuters poll of eight Singapore-based economists had predicted a nominal year-on-year fall of 1.7 percent in July.</p>
<p>The Singapore dollar strengthened briefly to 1.4095 against the U.S. dollar after the data was released, but soon slipped back and was quoted at 1.4110/15 in late afternoon trade.</p>
<p>&quot;The market had turned short (against the U.S. dollar) and they are just buying it back,&quot; said a European bank dealer, adding that there were large U.S. dollar buy orders amounting to US$100 million to US$200 million in the market.</p>
<p>She said there was no indication the Monetary Authority of Singapore (MAS), the de facto central bank, had supported the U.S. dollar on Tuesday despite market speculation that it would try to curb appreciation in the Singapore dollar due to the slowdown in June exports.  </p>
<p>A local bank dealer said the U.S. dollar looked temporarily supported around S$1.4100 and was unlikely to weaken beyond S$1.4090 even if London players pushed it down.</p>
<p>Economists said the surprise rebound in July exports did not point to a long-term trend.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we're going to have problems growing exports in the second half of this year. The slowdown we've seen will continue,&quot; Liew Yin Sze, head of Singapore research at J.M. Sassoon, told Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>He said the MAS could be expected to maintain its policy of keeping the Singapore dollar stable and easing cost pressures on companies operating in Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;From here till probably the second quarter of 1997, there's not likely to be much action on the Sing dollar,&quot; Liew said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
