<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4579" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai T-bill repo rates mixed, spots mostly up.</title>
<headline>Shanghai T-bill repo rates mixed, spots mostly up.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Contracts on the treasury bill repurchase market in Shanghai ended mixed on Tuesday, with turnover falling to 8.43 million lots from 9.26 million.</p>
<p>The annual rate for the most active three-day contract rose to 18.60 percent from 12.70 percent and the seven-day contract ended little changed at 11.54 percent from 11.55 percent.</p>
<p>One lot is 1,000 yuan face value of treasury bills.</p>
<p>Traders said the surge of the three-day contract was due to a new A share issue today, with many institutions borrowing money to buy the share.  </p>
<p>Most contracts on the T-bill spot market in Shanghai ended mostly up on Tuesday on a technical rebound after Monday's losses, traders said. Combined volume of the nine-contract market fell to 2.26 million lots from 2.98 million.</p>
<p>The most active 10-year bond that matures in June 2006 closed slightly up at 118.97 yuan from 118.90 yuan, with volume falling to 1.89 million lots from 2.78 million.</p>
<p>Traders said the price of the contract would linger in a narrow range in the near future because of limited upward potential at such a high level but support from institutions and individual investors would prevent it from falling sharply.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
