<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4600" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Manila says Singapore to help modernise army.</title>
<headline>Manila says Singapore to help modernise army.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Manila's armed forces chief General Arturo Enrile said on Tuesday that Singapore had agreed to help modernise the Philippine army by selling it weapons and helping upgrade its armour.</p>
<p>Enrile told reporters that defence ties, which nearly broke down in the furore over the March 1995 hanging in Singapore of Filipina maid Flor Contemplacion for double murder, are now &quot;better than before&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking at Singapore as one of our sources for our equipment and weapon systems in connection with the modernisation of the armed forces,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Enrile said he sought Singapore's assistance when he met Prime Minister Goh Chok Tong and Defence Minister Tony Tan on Monday. He arrived on Saturday after visiting Indonesia and was scheduled to head for Malaysia later on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Enrile said military ties between the two countries were expanding rapidly. A naval exercise has been inaugurated this year along with the annual exercise between the two armies.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not far-fetched that some time in the future, we will be conducting joint exercises involving all services,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some of the armaments Manila would be interested in buying were automatic grenade launchers which Singapore was already producing and exporting, Enrile said.</p>
<p>The Philippines was also seeking technical support to upgrade its tanks and armoured cars and had proposed the creation of joint venture companies for the manufacture of items such as automatic rifles and armoured personnel carriers.</p>
<p>Manila has recently embarked on the first phase of a programme to overhaul its armed forces, reducing its size and replacing obsolete equipment in the navy and air force.</p>
<p>The Philippines will spend 50 billion pesos (US$1.9 billion) in the first five years of the modernisation programme running from 1996 to 2000, Enrile said.</p>
<p>The House of Representatives in Manila has already approved a budget of 330 billion pesos over 15 years to modernise the military. The sum is being reviewed by the Senate.</p>
<p>Some of the money will go into replacing obsolete planes such as the F-5, first commissioned in the mid-1960s and which pales in comparison to the U.S.-made F-16 fighter-bombers in the arsenals of Indonesia, Thailand and Singapore.</p>
<p>Another target for overhaul and replacement would be most of the World War Two-vintage ships handed to Manila by Washington, which are older than the men serving on them.</p>
<p>($1 = 26 pesos)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
