<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4602" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodian military meet Khmer Rouge near Pailin.</title>
<headline>Cambodian military meet Khmer Rouge near Pailin.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodian armed forces chief General Ke Kim Yan held peace talks in Thailand with the breakaway Khmer Rouge faction, a top official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The meeting went well and we only have some technical problems about how to (physically) reach each others' bases,&quot; co-Defence Minister Tea Banh told reporters outside parliament, adding that they were in radio contact.</p>
<p>He did not give any more details on the talks but said the government forces were just five km (three miles) from the guerrilla positions in some areas around Pailin but had problems linking up.</p>
<p>The government has also been holding talks inside Cambodia with guerrillas loyal to former top Khmer Rouge leader Ieng Sary from the base of Phnom Malai, north of Pailin.</p>
<p>Ieng Sary and his followers, including the commanders of substantial forces at Phnom Malai and Pailin, have publicly split with hardline Khmer Rouge rulers and said they want to stop fighting and work for national reconciliation.</p>
<p>The government has agreed to a ceasefire and to let the rebels remain in their zones but has balked at allowing Ieng Sary run for a new party in general elections slated for 1998.</p>
<p>Ieng Sary was foreign minister and deputy premier in the 1975-79 Khmer Rouge regime of his former brother-in-law Pol Pot. Both men were in 1979 sentenced to death in absentia for overseeing the death of more than one million people.</p>
<p>Tea Banh said there had been clashes between the rival Khmer Rouge groups near Phnom Malai, a forest-clad mountain area on the border with Thailand, but the government had not intervened as the dissidents felt strong enough to beat off any threat.</p>
<p>Khmer Rouge radio, which remains loyal to hardliners led by Pol Pot, claimed on Tuesday that &quot;the traitors in Malai&quot; had asked the government's 12th Division to help put down dissent from Khmer Rouge rank and file in the area.</p>
<p>&quot;The traitors have a lot of money and they can leave the bases easily but the people cannot leave, so the people are furious with them and have started planning to kill the traitors,&quot; it reported.</p>
<p>The Ieng Sary commanders, in a statement read out on state radio on Tuesday, denied Khmer Rouge claims there had been demonstrations in their bases. They said Pol Pot had publicly said violence should be avoided while sending small groups to fight the dissidents.</p>
<p>State radio said people had decided to cut off all radio and phone contacts with hardliners and called on all Khmer Rouge fighters to avoid fighting each other.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
