<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4607" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: FOCUS-Malaysia reaffirms tight monetary policy.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Malaysia reaffirms tight monetary policy.</headline>
<byline>Madhav Reddy</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The surprise intervention by Malaysia's central bank in the domestic money market on Tuesday is a clear indication its tight monetary policy will continue, dealers and analysts said.</p>
<p>Bank Negara's intervention, the first in nearly three months, suggested it was not about to allow interest rates to fall below the bank's desired level, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Bank Negara has sent a signal to the market that it is not yet willing to loosen monetary policy,&quot; said Desmond Supple, economist with research firm I.D.E.A in Singapore.</p>
<p>Bank Negara tendered for a one-month deposit in the money market, accepting bids in the 6.95 to 7.05 percent range against 6.95 percent at its last intervention.</p>
<p>The borrowing was part of the central bank's open market operations. Bank Negara intervenes in the local interbank market to keep a check on liquidity or set interest rates as part of its efforts to fight inflation.</p>
<p>But it has not been in the market since May 24 despite rising liquidity that had pressured rates downward and threatened to thwart the Bank's tight monetary policy.  </p>
<p>Many money dealers said Tuesday's move was surprising as they were beginning to get used to non-interference by the central bank and were taking on long-term loan commitments.</p>
<p>&quot;We had expected the central bank to sit out for some more time,&quot; a dealer with a local bank said.</p>
<p>He said it was widely believed the central bank was waiting for the turbulence in Thai and Indonesian financial markets, which was attracting funds to Malaysia, to pass before taking action.</p>
<p>Rates have fallen sharply in the last four to six weeks -- the benchmark three-month interbank had declined to 7.15 percent from a peak of 7.50.</p>
<p>&quot;The rates were threatening to go below Bank Negara's support level,&quot; another money market dealer said.</p>
<p>The reaction to Bank Negara's intervention was swift. Within minutes, short-term rates shot up by 10-20 basis points.</p>
<p>The one-month interbank rate rose to 7.10/15 percent from 7.00/05 before the intervention, one-week to 6.80/00 percent from 6.50/60 and two-week to 6.90/00 against 6.60/70.</p>
<p>There were gains in longer-term rates, too. The three-month interbank rate was up at 7.20/25 against 7.15/18 in early trading and six-month money rose to 7.25/30 from 7.23/25.  </p>
<p>The overnight rate opened at 7.5 percent against its closing level of 6.00/10 on Monday, the dealers said.</p>
<p>They said rates could rise further in the near term if the volume of funds taken in by Bank Negara was large. Bank Negara does not reveal how much money it borrows at these tenders.</p>
<p>&quot;Going by the rates at which it has taken money, it looks like (Negara) has cleaned out the market. It has covered the entire range in which one-month was being traded,&quot; said the head of money dealing at a foreign bank.</p>
<p>Many dealers said they expected Bank Negara to follow up by intervening in the market again in the next few days.</p>
<p>&quot;If that happens, the market will start believing that high interest rates are here to stay for some time,&quot; the foreign bank dealer said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
