<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4609" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Arrested man commits suicide with toilet paper.</title>
<headline>Arrested man commits suicide with toilet paper.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A man detained in a police cell in northern Japan committed suicide by stuffing toilet paper down his throat, police said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The 45-year-old man, arrested for allegedly setting fire to his own shop, was found on Sunday in the police cell with five metres (5.5 yards) of toilet paper stuffed down his throat, said a spokesman for Toyohira police in Hokkaido, northern Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;We tried pulling out the paper from his mouth, but he looked pretty suffocated already. He probably would have been dead in the cell if we had found him a few minutes later,&quot; the police spokesman said.</p>
<p>The man was taken to hospital but died on Monday.</p>
<p>Guards patrol the cells every 15 minutes, and the man was last seen squatting in the toilet in his cell, according to the spokesman.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't leave the toilets fully open to view because of human rights considerations...nor can we leave the toilets without paper,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Police said the man was drunk at the time of the arrest and said he had set the shop on fire because he was feeling irritated.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
