<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4611" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: S'tomo says unaware of rogue copper trades in 1991.</title>
<headline>S'tomo says unaware of rogue copper trades in 1991.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sumitomo Corp reiterated on Tuesday it was not aware of unauthorised trading by former star trader Yasuo Hamanaka when the London Metal Exchange (LME) made an inquiry about the firm's copper trading in late 1991.</p>
<p>In December 1991 Sumitomo sent a letter in reply to the LME, assuring the exchange that its copper trading was legitimate and in line with regulations, according to the text of the letter disclosed by trade sources last week.</p>
<p>The letter, dated December 8, was faxed to LME chief executive David King from the firm's non-ferrous metals division head Iwao Nishiumi in reply to the query.</p>
<p>&quot;When we sent the reply to the LME in December 1991, we were not aware of any unauthorised trades by Hamanaka. The letter referred to Sumitomo's normal copper trading,&quot; a Sumitomo spokesman said.</p>
<p>The 1991 LME letter asked if Sumitomo was having any problems in executing its heavy copper transactions, he said.</p>
<p>The letters were exchanged at a time of large price fluctuations, which some blamed on Hamanaka, who was fired in June this year after Sumitomo admitted it had lost $1.8 billion in copper trading over the last decade.  </p>
<p>The Sumitomo spokesman also said the company's then president Tomiichi Akiyama was aware of the exchange of the letters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
