<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4612" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai politician expresses himself with gifts.</title>
<headline>Thai politician expresses himself with gifts.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thaksin Shinawatra, the tycoon-turned-politician leader of the Palang Dharma Party which recently pulled out of the coalition government, is showering his former colleagues with expensive gifts.</p>
<p>Thaksin, who made a fortune in telecommunications and computers before turning to politics, is known for lavishing his friends and colleagues with expensive presents.</p>
<p>Last week, Thaksin said he sent a 145,800 baht ($5,832) bottle of Romanee-Conti wine to Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa after pulling the Palang Dharma out of Banharn's 13-month-old coalition government.</p>
<p>He said he sent the wine to apologise for leaving the government, which is now facing a no-confidence debate.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, deputy prime minister Somboon Rahong surprised bystanders when he drove up to government house in a brand new black Daimler car.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a present given to me by Thaksin,&quot; Somboon, a member of Banharn's Chart Thai party, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;He just said that he liked me, then gave me this. It is not appropriate for me to turn down a present given to me by a millionaire,&quot; he said, adding that he did not know the price of the present but estimated it was worth about six million baht.</p>
<p>($1 = 25 baht)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
