<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4616" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo precious metals firmer in line with New York.</title>
<headline>Tokyo precious metals firmer in line with New York.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yen-based Tokyo precious metals futures settled firmer across the board on Tuesday, following gains in New York precious metals overnight, traders said.</p>
<p>Spot gold rose slightly during Asian trading hours in tandem with firmer silver prices. Bullion was quoted at $387.30/60 per ounce at the Tokyo close, against $386.90/7.40 in New York on Monday.</p>
<p>Trade in silver futures was buoyant, backed by firmer spot silver prices, while trade in other precious metals was very thin. Gold futures prices ranged from unchanged to six yen per gram firmer, with benchmark June ending up three at 1,339 yen.  </p>
<p>In very thin trade, gold futures were stuck in tight ranges throughout the day with investors sidelined in the absence of fresh incentives.</p>
<p>Investors were also hoping to receive some direction from the U.S. Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting on Tuesday, although interest rates are expected to be unchanged.</p>
<p>Silver futures ranged from 2.6 yen to 4.0 yen per 10 grams firmer, with benchmark June ending up 3.4 at 182.0 yen.</p>
<p>Platinum group metals also ended firmer. &quot;Buying in palladium futures was noted after distant months hit their life-of-contract lows on Monday,&quot; one dealer said.  </p>
<p>One trader predicted spot palladium prices could soon recover to $127 to $128 after recent sharp falls.</p>
<p>Palladium futures ranged from unchanged to nine yen per gram higher. Benchmark June stood up five at 436 yen.</p>
<p>Platinum futures ranged from four to eight yen per gram higher. Benchmark June was up eight at 1,376 yen. -- Tokyo Commodity Desk (813-3432-7431)--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
