<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4619" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks close up on utilities rally.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks close up on utilities rally.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A rally in the utilities sector lifted Hong Kong stocks to a higher close on Tuesday, with the Hang Seng index closing above 11,300 points for the first time since March.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index closed 99.03 points higher at 11,312.51. Turnover was HK$3.44 billion compared to HK$3.71 billion on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;People are buying laggards. Most sectors have gained - banks, properties, H-shares, red chips - and now it is time for utilities which are still at a very low level,&quot; said Antony Mak, sales director at Vickers Ballas.  </p>
<p>The Hang Seng utilities sub-index rose 205.25 points, or 2.17 percent, to 9,676.05.</p>
<p>&quot;The utilities shares need to go up otherwise it is very hard for the (Hang Seng) index to move higher from this level,&quot; said Frederick Tsang, head of research at PrimeEast Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the (utility) shares have not performed well this year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>China Light and Power rose HK$0.80 to HK$33.30 and Hongkong Telecom added HK$0.30 to HK$13.10. Hong Kong and China Gas rose HK$0.25 to HK$12.55 and Hongkong Electric rose HK$0.30 to HK$23.30.  </p>
<p>However, analysts noted that volume was quiet this session.</p>
<p>&quot;It's partly because of the FOMC (Federal Open Market Committee) meeting and also because it is late summer,&quot; said Mak. The U.S. Federal Reserve meets later on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Analysts said cautiousness in the market may have buoyed the utility stocks which are considered a defensive play. They said if the Federal Reserve keeps rates steady at its meeting, the whole market could benefit on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Cheung Kong (Holdings) rose HK$0.25 to HK$56.50 and Hutchison Whampoa added HK$1.20 to HK$48.60. Both are due to release interim results on Thursday.  </p>
<p>Other property stocks were also firm with Sun Hung Kai Properties adding HK$0.75 to HK$77.00 and Hysan Development up HK$0.40 to HK$24.25.</p>
<p>Trading in Guangdong Investment shares was suspended during the afternoon. The company placed 80 million existing shares at HK$5.22 each on Tuesday, UBS Securities said. The stock fell HK$0.20 to HK$5.35 before the suspension.</p>
<p>Yaohan International Holdings rose HK$0.11 to HK$0.88 after it said it plans to privatise its Yaohan Hongkong Corp unit. Shares in Yaohan Hongkong fell HK$0.01 to HK$0.36.</p>
<p>-- Jennifer Genevieve (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
