<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4620" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan police admit poor handling of subway gassing.</title>
<headline>Japan police admit poor handling of subway gassing.</headline>
<byline>Yvonne Chang</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's police force on Tuesday rapped itself for poor scientific and technical knowledge in investigating the deadly nerve gas attack on Tokyo subways last year.</p>
<p>The National Police Agency's annual white paper for 1996, released on Tuesday, said police lacked expert knowledge when officers started investigations of the March 20, 1995, nerve gas attack on Tokyo subways which killed 11 and left thousands ill.</p>
<p>&quot;It cannot be denied that police were perplexed by the use of the nerve gas sarin,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Police could not immediately identify the poison gas first developed as a chemical weapon by Nazi Germany in the 1930s.</p>
<p>The report said a series of crimes allegedly committed by doomsday cult Aum Shinri Kyo (Supreme Truth Sect) represented an unprecedented, new type of organised crime.</p>
<p>This type of what police said was new organised crime left a lot for police authorities to consider in reviewing the prevention of organised crime, the report said.</p>
<p>Aum Shinri Kyo leader Shoko Asahara is currently on trial for a total of 17 criminal cases, including two sets of murder charges for the gas attacks. He could be sentenced to death by hanging.</p>
<p>The 15 other charges range from ordering the execution of rebellious followers to illegal manufacturing of drugs and weapons.</p>
<p>Asahara was also charged with allegedly ordering cult members to spread sarin gas in the city of Matsumoto, 150 km (90 miles) northwest of Tokyo, in June 1994, killing seven people and injuring 600.</p>
<p>The report noted how Yoshiyuki Kono, a victim in the Matsumoto sarin case, was wrongly identified as a prime suspect and that police formally apologised to him.</p>
<p>The white paper also noted that the current police system based on provinces was a hindrance to investigating nationwide crimes.</p>
<p>The report said the Tokyo Metropolitan Police was unable to search the cult's complex in Yamanashi Prefecture, adjacent to the capital, before the Tokyo subway gas attack because of police laws which have prevented investigations crossing prefectural borders.</p>
<p>The white paper suggested that Japan should consider introducing wider legislation to combat organised crime similar to laws in Europe and the United States which allow authorities to seize unlawfully earned money and to pay rewards for information in criminal investigations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
