<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4626" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Malaysia's Petco looks to raise sales to endusers.</title>
<headline>Malaysia's Petco looks to raise sales to endusers.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taking its cue from oil majors, the trading arm of Malaysian state oil firm Petronas is striking more term oil product contracts with end users at the expense of traders, industry sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Petco earlier this month signed its most recent term deal -- to supply South Korean refiner Hanwha Energy with up to 1.2 million barrels of jet/kerosene for this winter.</p>
<p>Trading sources said the term contract replaces a one-year contract Petco has with a Middle East trader, which expires next month.  </p>
<p>&quot;Petco is doing away with traders and trying new avenues for the marketing of their products,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>A Petco source declined to comment on the specifics of the deal but said it was in line with the company's aim of &quot;going international.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This is nothing new. We had contracts before with other endusers in Bangladesh, Pakistan and Zimbabwe,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>Petco was recently awarded a six-month contract, beginning in July, by the Bangladesh Petroleum Corp to supply diesel, jet fuel, kerosene and gasoline.  </p>
<p>It also has term contracts with Japanese and South Korean endusers for the supply of naphtha and low sulphur waxy residue, traders said. In the past, the company had term diesel contracts with Pakistan's Ministry of Petroleum and Natural Resources and Indian Oil Corp.</p>
<p>The moves by Petco reflect moves already taken by oil majors in the region who no longer have term contracts with traders and are actively selling directly to endusers instead.</p>
<p>As one trader said: &quot;The majors are today selling directly to endusers in China and are taking part in tenders which they had stayed away from in the past&quot;.  </p>
<p>&quot;What Petco is doing is not very different from this&quot;, he added.</p>
<p>Majors previously would not participate in regional tenders such as that issued by Vietnam, traders said.</p>
<p>Petco's move in North Asia is seen by traders as part of the company's effort to broaden their market presence from the Indian sub-continent and East Africa.</p>
<p>The company's term contracts in that area are mainly supported by their 40,000 barrel-per-day (bpd) processing agreement in Aden.  </p>
<p>The move into North Asia is Petco's way of selling directly the product it produces from the 100,000 bpd refinery in Malacca and the 50,000 bpd refinery in Kertih, traders said.</p>
<p>--Singapore Newsroom (+65-870-3093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
