<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4653" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai copper ends up on LME gains.</title>
<headline>Shanghai copper ends up on LME gains.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai copper futures ended up in slow trading on Tuesday on overnight gains on the London Metal Exchange, but copper futures will meet strong pressure due to rising domestic output and imports, traders said.</p>
<p>The most active December 1996 contract ended at 20,640 yuan ($2,492) per tonne, rising 90 yuan. It opened at 20,700 yuan, hitting an intra-day high of 20,710 and a low of 20,630.</p>
<p>September rose 10 to 21,080 yuan, October 50 to 20,850, November 40 to 20,600, the January 1997 contract 90 to 20,640 and February 100 to 20,660.</p>
<p>Combined volume fell to 6,095 tonnes from 19,135.  </p>
<p>Copper opened higher but profit-taking pushed contracts down steadily for most of the session.</p>
<p>Traders said LME gains made copper open higher, but poor fundamentals depressed long position holders and prevented further rises.</p>
<p>China imported 343,338 tonnes of uncast copper and copper materials in the first seven months, up 33.9 percent from the same period in 1995, China Securities News said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In July, imports of uncast copper and copper materials rose to 54,217 tonnes from 48,173 tonnes in June, it quoted customs statistics as saying.  </p>
<p>China's total copper output rose to 517,000 tonnes in the first seven months, up 9.82 percent from the same period in 1995, China Securities News said.</p>
<p>China imported 537,897 tonnes of copper in 1995 and has forecast total output of 750,000 tonnes in 1996, it added.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite overnight LME gains, profit-taking late in the session indicated many investors were doubtful about the room for further mid- and long-term rises,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Traders said Shanghai copper would continue to move in a narrow range of 20,500 and 21,000 yuan in the short term if copper on the LME stays above $1,920-70.  </p>
<p>Aluminium ended mixed. September fell 20 to 14,650 yuan. October did not trade. November rose 50 to 14,350. Combined volume fell to 75 tonnes from 225.</p>
<p>($1=8.3065 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
