<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4657" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul stocks end at 33-month low in slow trading.</title>
<headline>Seoul stocks end at 33-month low in slow trading.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks dipped on Tuesday to close at a 33-month low in slow trading as overall depression erased early selective buying of theme-backed small-sized shares, brokers said.</p>
<p>The composite stock index ended 6.61 points lower at a provisional 793.91, the lowest closing since November 12, 1993 when it closed at 791.47.</p>
<p>&quot;There don't seem to be any factors reversing the current depression stemming from fears of an economic slump,&quot; said Lim Bok-kyu of Hyundai Securities. &quot;Further fall is likely since the 800 pyschologically-supported line was broken.&quot;  </p>
<p>Brokers said the slowing economy, confirmed by poor first-half results of listed companies, would remain a major liability to the market for the rest of the year.</p>
<p>According to the Korea Listed Companies' Association, net profits at non-bank listed companies for the six months fell 53 percent from the corresponding period last year.</p>
<p>Rising interest rates ahead of the Korean Thanksgiving holidays in September further dampened market sentiment.</p>
<p>The yields on the three-year benchmark corporates rose to a new year high of 12.50 on Tuesday from 12.46 on Monday.  </p>
<p>Volume totalled 16.13 million shares, compared with 14.87 million on Monday.</p>
<p>Losers outpaced gainers 535 to 265 with 145 unchanged.</p>
<p>The Korea Stock Exchange said it halted trading in shares of Kun Young on Tuesday because the company defaulted on 1.26 billion won worth of promissory notes late Monday. It stood at 5,020 won before trading was suspended. A consortium of five small- and medium-sized local construction companies has agreed in principle to take over Kun Young.</p>
<p>Brokers said pharmaceutical shares rose on takeover rumours and good earnings prospects. -- KIM MYONG-HWAN (822) 727-5645</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
