<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4659" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong people scramble to join China panel.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong people scramble to join China panel.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A China-controlled body has handed out more than 10,000 nomination forms for Hong Kong people to join the panel that will choose the British colony's leader and legislature when it reverts to China in mid-1997.</p>
<p>The mad scramble began last Thursday when the Preparatory Committee opened the nomination process.</p>
<p>By noon on Tuesday, a committee spokesman told Reuters, 10,767 forms had been issued.</p>
<p>Hong Kong, a bustling capitalist territory of 6.2 million people, will revert to China at midnight on June 30 next year, ending a century-and-a-half of British colonial rule.</p>
<p>The first post-colonial chief executive and a provisional legislature will be picked in November by the Selection Committee, whose 400 seats are now being chased.</p>
<p>&quot;In the entire political history of Hong Kong, we have never seen such an enthusiastic response to any election process,&quot; independent political commentator Andy Ho told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;From this point of view, China can be considered to have been successful,&quot; Ho said.</p>
<p>The nomination process, which will last a month, has drawn a wide range of seat-seekers ranging from members of professional associations to business organisations, from local tycoons and politicians to resident foreign businessmen.</p>
<p>The popular Democratic Party is boycotting the process because it views as illegal China's plan to dismantle Hong Kong's fully elected Legislative Council and replace it with the appointed provisional council on July 1 next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
