<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4661" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia overnight rate rises on intervention.</title>
<headline>Malaysia overnight rate rises on intervention.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The overnight interbank rate was at 7.5 percent around 0645 GMT against 6.00/10 at close on Monday, dealers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said the market was tight after Bank Negara intervened in the money market to borrow for a one-month deposit at 6.95 to 7.05 percent against 6.95 at its previous auction.  </p>
<p>The dealers said rates could rise further by the close  of the day, though that would depend on the volume of funds taken in by Bank Negara.</p>
<p>&quot;Going by the rates at which it has taken money, it looks like (Negara) has cleaned out the market. It has covered the entire range in which one-month was being traded,&quot; said the head of money dealing at a foreign bank.</p>
<p>Earlier, other interbank rates rose by 10-20 basis points immediately after the intervention.</p>
<p>They said one-month interbank rose to 7.10/15 percent against 7.00/05 before the intervention.  </p>
<p>One-week money was at 6.80/00 percent against 6.50/60 and two-week at 6.90/00 against 6.60/70.</p>
<p>There were gains in longer-term rates too. The three-month interbank rate was up at 7.20/25 against 7.15/18 in early trading and six-month money rose to 7.25/30 against 7.23/25.</p>
<p>Earlier, Bank Negara Malaysia returned to the market after nearly three months to borrow for a one-month deposit at 6.95 to 7.05 percent against 6.95 previously.</p>
<p>Bank Negara regularly intervenes in the local interbank market to keep a check on liquidity or set interest rates as part of its efforts to fight inflation.  </p>
<p>But it has not been in the market since May 24, despite rising liquidity that has pressured rates downward, threatening to thwart the Bank's tight monetary policy.</p>
<p>Money market dealers said the intervention indicated that Bank Negara has not eased its tight monetary policy.</p>
<p>While the volume that Bank Negara took was not known, it appears to have given a psychological boost to interest rates, particularly short-term rates, dealers said.</p>
<p>- Madhav Reddy (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
