<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4714" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan TV says vice-president surfaces in Ukraine.</title>
<headline>Taiwan TV says vice-president surfaces in Ukraine.</headline>
<byline>Alice Hung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan Vice-President Lien Chan's secretive journey has taken him to the former Soviet republic of Ukraine, a state-funded television station said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;After Vice-President Lien mysteriously disappeared in New York (on Sunday), he made a brief stopover in Vienna and then flew to the Ukrainian capital Kiev,&quot; Taiwan Television said in its midday broadcast.</p>
<p>The broadcast gave no source for the information.</p>
<p>The latest report follows a flurry of rumours since Monday that Lien had arrived in various European nations.</p>
<p>China regards Nationalist-ruled Taiwan as a rebel province ineligible for foreign ties and has sought to isolate it diplomatically since a civil war separated them in 1949.</p>
<p>Last week China denounced Lien's transit stop in New York.</p>
<p>Taiwan's authoritative United Daily News, also giving no source for its information, said in its Tuesday editions that Lien would meet in Kiev with Ukraine's head of state.</p>
<p>Officials in Taipei declined to comment on the reports.</p>
<p>Ukraine recognises the communist government in Beijing, not Taiwan's exiled Republic of China, but has made clear its desire for better ties with Taiwan and its export-driven economy.</p>
<p>Taiwan had donated rice and medicine to help Ukraine and both sides were mulling setting up representative offices to boost economic ties, the television said.</p>
<p>&quot;Bilateral relations should improve after Vice-President Lien's visit,&quot; the television said.</p>
<p>Reports swirled in Taipei that Lien, a billionaire who is also the island's premier, was bound for Hungary, Spain, Austria, Switzerland or even Belarus or Poland.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister John Chang said on Monday that Lien, in transit in New York on Sunday after visiting the Dominican Republic, had made a detour to a &quot;third country&quot; where Taiwan has no diplomatic ties. He declined to say which country.</p>
<p>The Czech Republic and Austria are still smarting from Beijing's diplomatic tirades after Lien visited those two countries in mid-1995.</p>
<p>Beijing downgraded its U.S. ties after Washington allowed Taiwan President Lee Teng-hui to make a private visit in June 1995 and has only recently taken steps to mend relations.</p>
<p>Taiwan's diplomatic allies were cut to 30 on late on Monday after Niger renewed diplomatic relations with China. Taiwan's foreign ministry severed diplomatic ties with the West African state shortly after the announcement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
