<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4723" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan coincident index up on stronger output - EPA.</title>
<headline>Japan coincident index up on stronger output - EPA.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's index of coincident indicators rose above the key 50 mark in June for the first time since February because industrial output-related indicators were slightly stronger than three months ago, an Economic Planning Agency official told reporters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The index of coincident indicators, which measures current economic conditions, stood at 55.0 in June against 30.0 in May.</p>
<p>Coincident and leading indicator indices are compiled by comparing data with a set of figures from three months earlier.</p>
<p>The official said March industrial output data had been particularly weak, which helped June data climb above 50.  </p>
<p>Asked if the coincident index would stay above the 50 mark in July, the official said it was difficult to forecast and that much depended on July industrial production figures.</p>
<p>&quot;If industrial output rises 4.2 percent then conditions will not be so severe,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Ministry of International and Industry has forecast a month-on-month rise of 4.2 percent in output for July.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E71">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
