<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4732" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURMA: Burma sentences Suu Kyi aide, 2 others to 7 years.</title>
<headline>Burma sentences Suu Kyi aide, 2 others to 7 years.</headline>
<dateline>RANGOON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burma's military government has imposed a seven-year prison sentence on a personal assistant to democracy leader Aung San Suu Kyi and two other party members, National League for Democracy (NLD) sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;U Win Htein and two other NLD members were sentenced on August 16 to seven years imprisonment each,&quot; an NLD source told Reuters. &quot;They were charged for taking part in a video conspiracy fabricating the poor situation of the farmers.</p>
<p>He said the identity of the other two was not known nor was it known what section they were sentenced under, but said he thought it was likely under a sweeping Emergency Powers Act.</p>
<p>Win Htein, Suu Kyi's assistant was one of more than 250 NLD members arrested by the State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC) in a crackdown on democracy politicians ahead of a May 26 party congress at Suu Kyi's house.</p>
<p>Aye Win, a relative and personal assistant to NLD leader Su Kyi, was also arrested in the crackdown. His family told Reuters on Tuesday he had not yet been sentenced.</p>
<p>Most of the NLD politicians arrested by the SLORC were released after the May 26-28 party meeting took place. The government said at the time the arrests were made to prevent &quot;anarchy&quot; and unrest from the meeting.</p>
<p>But a handful of the NLD members, including Win Htein, remained in custody and were sent to Rangoon's Insein Prison.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RANGOON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
