<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4743" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Khmer Rouge defections add to coalition tension.</title>
<headline>Khmer Rouge defections add to coalition tension.</headline>
<byline>Leo Dobbs</byline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A split within Cambodia's secretive Khmer Rouge rebel group offers the biggest chance for peace in years but has ruffled feathers within the nation's strained coalition government, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The bottom line is that everyone in government is looking at how the Khmer Rouge can enhance their own interests. Everybody wants a slice of the Khmer Rouge,&quot; said one analyst, adding the rebel dissidents were also seen as election assets.</p>
<p>&quot;The Khmer Rouge becomes like a mercenary army. They (have) become a prized possession,&quot; said an Asian diplomat.</p>
<p>Second Prime Minister Hun Sen of the formerly communist Cambodian People's Party (CPP) was quick to make the most out of the announcements by former top Khmer Rouge leader Ieng Sary and two senior commanders that they had split from the hardliners.</p>
<p>The co-premier on Friday said Ieng Sary, who was sentenced to death in absentia for his role in the deaths of more than one million people under the 1975-79 Khmer Rouge regime, must be protected and his past put aside in the interests of peace.</p>
<p>First Prime Minister Prince Norodom Ranariddh, who heads the royalist FUNCINPEC party in an uneasy alliance with the CPP, has said Hun Sen's announcement on August 8 of thousands of defections in two key northwest rebel bases was premature.</p>
<p>He said on Saturday that any decision to allow Ieng Sary back into the national fold could not be taken by the prime ministers, but should be up to the members of parliament who had unanimously outlawed the group in 1994 after peace talks failed.</p>
<p>Analysts said Hun Sen seemed to have realised he had jumped the gun as he met Ranariddh on the weekend and agreed they must work out a common strategy and handle the issue in accordance with the constitution and law.</p>
<p>His gesture has helped, at least temporarily, to prevent the Khmer Rouge split from widening the rift between FUNCINPEC and CPP, which began in March when Ranariddh threatened to leave the government if the CPP refused to cede royalists more power to royalists .</p>
<p>Hun Sen warned that he would use force to prevent any attempt to break up the government and parliament and while the war of words has abated in recent weeks, suspicion, resentment and anger still lingers beneath the surface, analysts said.</p>
<p>The second premier's handling of the dissident Khmer Rouge guerrillas and apparently extra-legal promises of protection and rehabilitation had threatened to further torpedo relations between the coalition parnters.</p>
<p>&quot;He wants to take (the credit) for his own advantage,&quot; a senior royalist said after Hun Sen's announced the defections.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a delicate affair and we must not be happy before killing the tiger...let them get under our control first,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;Do you believe that if the CPP (alone) invited them to come that they will come?&quot;</p>
<p>Hun Sen has since acknowledged the key role being played by FUNCINPEC commanders, who were once allied with the Khmer Rouge.</p>
<p>One analyst said Hun Sen might have hoped that by embracing Ieng Sary he would be able to claim the allegiance of his own group of Khmer Rouge defectors and counter rebels who agreed to join the royalists in the northwest province of Siem Reap.</p>
<p>&quot;In politics there are no permanent friends, there are permanent interests,&quot; he said, adding that if Hun Sen managed to get his way over Ieng Sary, Ranariddh would be finished, but &quot;If this backfires, Hun Sen will be in trouble.&quot;</p>
<p>Several analysts believed the ultimate goal was to boost standing ahead of the next polls. &quot;This is the road to the 1998 elections, to the one real premiership,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He warned that the Khmer Rouge should not be underestimated and added that if all sides approached the developments from a national interest the outlaws would be finished.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not convinced yet if we are united...if we are it's a happy ending story for Cambodia.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
