<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4753" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan stocks end up on China shipping hopes.</title>
<headline>Taiwan stocks end up on China shipping hopes.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan share prices rebounded from an early slide on Tuesday to close slightly higher on news that China had issued rules governing direct shipping links with estranged Taiwan, brokers said.</p>
<p>China's official Xinhua news agency said the regulations were effective immediately, although Taipei still bans direct shipping links across the Taiwan strait.</p>
<p>The index ended up 9.93 points or 0.16 percent at 6,057.44, off an opening low of 5,988.12. Turnover was a modest T$29.94 billion.  </p>
<p>&quot;The news on direct shipping immediately triggered a rebound on China-concept shares, as it should help ease recent tensive Taiwan-China relations,&quot; said Alex Yang of National Securities.</p>
<p>China-concept shares are those in Taiwan firms with major investments or investment plans in China. Shipping giant Yang Ming Marine and Evergreen Marine rose T$1.1 and 40 cents to T$36 and T$46.5, respectively.</p>
<p>Speculation that Taipei might change its China policies has mounted since President Lee Teng-hui cautioned on August 14 that Taiwan needed to avoid over-dependence on China for investment.  </p>
<p>After seeing the opening break below psychological support at 6,000, bargain hunters immediately entered, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;A technical rebound after breaking 6,000 was widely expected,&quot; said Tank Hung of Yuanta Securities. &quot;Today's bargain hunters were likely foreign funds or government-related funds.&quot;</p>
<p>Many local institutional investors have sold heavily on recent Taiwan-China tensions. Foreign institutions have not.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign institutions in general are not pessimistic on Taiwan's stock market prospects,&quot; said Ben Lee of Nomura Securities.  </p>
<p>&quot;Foreign funds intend to establish their portfolios before Morgan Stanley starts to include Taiwan into its global indices in September,&quot; Lee said.</p>
<p>Brokers expected the index to consolidate in the near term as Taiwan-China tensions linger after President Lee's comment and Vice-President Lien Chan's secret journey to an unidentified country -- which is expected to anger China.</p>
<p>For Wednesday, a 6,020-6,100 range was seen.</p>
<p>-- James Peng (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
