<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4762" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia military pledges to end Irian kidnapping.</title>
<headline>Indonesia military pledges to end Irian kidnapping.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's military has pledged to rescue 13 forestry company workers held hostage in remote Irian Jaya province, the official Antara news agency reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will move to rescue them before long,&quot; army chief General Hartono was quoted as saying on Monday.</p>
<p>The hostages are employees of concessionaire PT Kamundan Raya, a subsidiary of the Djajanti Group. They were kidnapped last Wednesday when their base camp 60 km (37 miles) west of the town of Timika was attacked by a group of Irianese.</p>
<p>Timika is about 4,000 km (2,500 miles) east of Jakarta.</p>
<p>Hartono said the military thought the hostage-takers were criminals and not seperatist Free Papua Movement (OPM) rebels.</p>
<p>Antara gave no other details. Military officials in Irian Jaya said they had located the area where the hostages were being held and were ready to free them.</p>
<p>The kidnappers have sent sent three demands to the military in Irian Jaya: cessation of all logging; appointment of tribal leader Tom Beanal as a mediator; and the involvement of a human rights organisation in negotiations.</p>
<p>Beanal, an environmental activist, told Reuters from Timika, that he had not received the demand.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything regarding this kidnapping is still vague. I don't have much idea of what's going on, so I think I don't want to get involved,&quot; he said by telephone.</p>
<p>Indonesia faces limited resistance to its rule in Irian, a former Dutch colony it seized in 1963, especially from the OPM.</p>
<p>The OPM held 11 hostages, including five Europeans, for more than four months to publicise its fight for a free Irian Jaya.</p>
<p>In May, four British, two Dutch and three Indonesian hostages held by the OPM escaped after the army tried to rescue them. Two Indonesian hostages were killed by their captors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
