<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4765" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia priest said accused of insulting Suharto.</title>
<headline>Indonesia priest said accused of insulting Suharto.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police have accused an Indonesian Catholic priest of publicly showing hatred against President Suharto following last month's riots in Jakarta, a lawyer said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Police were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Legal Aid Institute, Munir, told Reuters that Father Ignatius Sandyawan would appear before police for questioning later on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Sandyawan has been accused of...publicly showing hatred against President Suharto, showing enmity against the authorities and harbouring criminals. He is not under arrest, but his arrest may come anytime,&quot; Munir said.</p>
<p>Officials have accused Sandyawan of sheltering three members of the leftist People's Democratic Party (PRD), including Budiman Sudjatmiko, its leader who is blamed for the July 27 riots in which four people died and scores of cars and buildings were set on fire.</p>
<p>Showing hatred against the president carries a maximum penalty of six years' imprisonment.</p>
<p>Sandyawan is the secretary of a team of volunteers trying to assist the victims of the July 27 riots, the worst violence in the city for more than two decades. He was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>The riots began after police stormed the headquarters of the Indonesian Democratic Party and evicted supporters of ousted party leader Megawati Sukarnoputri, the daughter of former founding president Sukarno.</p>
<p>The Kompas newspaper said on Tuesday that Sudjatmiko and two other PRD acitivists had come to Sandyawan for protection. The priest housed them in the home of his brother, Benny Sumardi.</p>
<p>Sumardi, who is also accused of harbouring criminals, and the activists were arrested last week.</p>
<p>Munir said authorities had accused 13 activists, including those from the PRD, of subversion in connection with the riots. Subversion is punishable by death.</p>
<p>An Indonesian court on Monday upheld the arrest of labour leader Muchtar Pakpahan on subversion charges.</p>
<p>Pakpahan, leader of the unrecognised Indonesian Labour Welfare Union, had appealed his arrest but a district court turned it down.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
