<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4774" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan trust banks may need outside support - Moody's.</title>
<headline>Japan trust banks may need outside support - Moody's.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some of Japan's major trust banks, hit by deteriorating asset quality and growing competition, are expected to require external support, Moody's Investors Service said in a report on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Moody's currently rates the long- and short-term deposits of Japan's seven biggest trust banks and Daiwa Bank Ltd, the only city bank allowed to engage in commercial and trust banking. It also rates the banks' financial strength.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect those banks with very weak financial fundamentals will ultimately require assistance either from the authorities or their respective corporate group members.&quot;  </p>
<p>An official of the rating agency gave a bank financial strength rating (BFSR) of E to Chuo Trust &amp; Banking Co Ltd and Yasuda Trust &amp; Banking Co Ltd, meaning they possess very weak intrinsic financial strength.</p>
<p>Moody's gave an E+ BFSR rating to Nippon Trust Bank Ltd and Mitsui Trust &amp; Banking Co Ltd. A plus rating is appended to ratings below the E category to distinguish those banks that fall into intermediate categories. It said Nippon Trust could get support from the Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi if it was needed since it was acquired by the former Mitsubishi Bank in November 1994.  </p>
<p>Despite having disposed of massive problem loans and posted credit expenses in the fiscal 1995/96 year ended March 31, non-performing loans at the trust banks will remain on their balance sheets, and &quot;trust sales of real estate collateral continue to be difficult and time consuming&quot;, Moody's said.</p>
<p>&quot;The banks are experiencing substantial pressure on their capital, and the true magnitude of the problem is not yet reflected in officially disclosed non-performing loan statistics,&quot; it said. Moody's also said that trust assets under discretionary management, particularly pension trusts, will grow, but will not be a significant contributor to earnings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
