<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4785" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam to try leading dissidents this week.</title>
<headline>Vietnam to try leading dissidents this week.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam will this week put on trial two prominent intellectuals jailed last year in a crackdown on dissent, a rights group and dissident sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said Le Hong Ha, a former high ranking Communist Party member, and Ha Si Phu, a leading academic, would face a court in Hanoi on Thursday on charges of disclosing state secrets.</p>
<p>The two men were arrested in November last year as part of a crackdown on dissent in the run-up to Hanoi's Eighth Communist Party Congress, which has held in late June.</p>
<p>Phu was said to have given an interview to a French radio station and to have distributed documents in which he criticised the Hanoi government.</p>
<p>Le Hong Ha had been expelled from the Communist Party after voicing support for Hoang Minh Chinh, another leading dissident.</p>
<p>The arrests of the two men were criticised at the time by international human rights groups that accused Hanoi of placing itself in violation of international laws.</p>
<p>The Paris-based Alliance Vietnam Liberte said in a statement on Tuesday that the case was being watched closely by several organisations in Europe and North America. It called for independent observers to be allowed to attend the court hearing.</p>
<p>Official confirmation of the trial was not immediately available.</p>
<p>The charges against the two men fall under article 92 of Vietnam's Penal Code and allow for jail terms of between two and seven years. In serious cases, however, the jail term can be extended to a maximum of 15 years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
