<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4803" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: MOF says to watch economy before any extra budget.</title>
<headline>MOF says to watch economy before any extra budget.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Minister Wataru Kubo told a news conference on Tuesday that the government would look at various economic movements before making a decision on whether to introduce a supplementary budget.  </p>
<p>Asked whether the government would introduce a supplementary budget in the event of an extraordinary session of parliament later this year, Kubo said: &quot;I realise there are many views on this. We must keep watch over various economic movements and make no mistakes.&quot;</p>
<p>But for now, he said, the ministry had not changed its view that it does not yet need to start considering an extra budget.</p>
<p>Asked about the impact of falling land prices on the government's scheme to wind up failed mortgage firms, Kubo said he could not deny that further price falls could cause difficulties in implementing the scheme.  </p>
<p>Asked about a Japanese newspaper report on Tuesday that Washington had asked Tokyo to delay for six years the entry of Japanese insurance firms' subsidiaries into the so-called third sector of the industry covering accidents and health care, Kubo said he could not reveal details of negotiations.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an issue in which both sides have to come up with a compromise when bilateral talks resume again,&quot; Kubo said.</p>
<p>Japan and the United States are at odds over the entry of Japanese insurance firms' subsidiaries into the third-sector niche market, where foreign firms have a strong foothold. The talks are scheduled to resume in September.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
