<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4806" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK's Cheung Kong, Hutchison to pay less for site.</title>
<headline>HK's Cheung Kong, Hutchison to pay less for site.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Hong Kong government has shaved more than HK$1 billion off the amount Cheung Kong (Holdings) Ltd and Hutchison Whampoa Ltd should pay for development rights for a reclamation site in Hung Hom, the Hong Kong Standard newspaper said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A company, equally owned by Cheung Kong and Hutchison, entered into a joint venture agreement with the Kowloon-Canton Railway Corp (KCRC) last December for the joint development of a commercial complex on the site.</p>
<p>The paper said a Lands Department official said the Hung Hom offer was &quot;between HK$3 and HK$4 billion&quot; and quoted an informed market source as saying the government had shaved more than HK$1 billion off the HK$4.5 billion it had previously asked for the site, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>Officials from Cheung Kong, Hutchison the KCRC and the government were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>The Standard said the KCRC was handling the negotiatings with the government, while Cheung Kong and Hutchison would pay the premium and all development costs.</p>
<p>The developers had three weeks to consider the offer, it said.</p>
<p>The project, to be completed in 1999, would generate a total gross floor area of more than 130,000 square metres.</p>
<p>It would comprise a 600-room hotel, three office towers, a shopping arcade, a cinena, car parks and other facilities, the paper said. -- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6590</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
