<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4807" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Daishinku to up mobile phone part output.</title>
<headline>Daishinku to up mobile phone part output.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Daishinku Corp said on Tuesday that it planned to boost output of crystal devices used in mobile phones in the business year starting April 1, 1997, to cope with robust demand.</p>
<p>It is planning to boost production at its plant in Tottori Prefecture, western Japan, a company spokesman said.</p>
<p>Crystal devices are core components of mobile phones, including the personal handy phone system (PHS) which is a cellular phone that is cheaper than conventional portable phones.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are planning to boost output in view of growing sales of mobile phones, especially PHSs,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The Japanese economic daily Nihon Keizai Shimbun said on Tuesday that investment for Daishinku's planned production expansion would be about five billion yen.</p>
<p>The expansion is expected to boost Daishinku's annual sales by five to eight billion yen, the paper said.</p>
<p>The company spokesman declined to confirm the figures in the Nihon Keizai report.</p>
<p>Daishinku posted parent sales of 31.24 billion yen in 1995/96.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
