<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4809" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper Editorials - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper Editorials - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>With 315 days to go before the British colony reverts to China, the Hong Kong media focused on issues related to the handover, the election of the 400-strong Selection Committee and the future official language.</p>
<p>The middle of the road HONG KONG ECONOMIC JOURNAL said the Democratic Party's refusal to join the Selection Committee might not prove to be political suicide provided the party could influence the establishment from the outside.</p>
<p>It said Hong Kong people should persuade Beijing to allow such political freedoms to counteract the lack of representativeness of the provisional legislature.</p>
<p>It said the Democratic Party should grasp any opportunity to talk to Beijing and fight for its legal existence after the handover.</p>
<p>It said time was running out and it was meaningless to quibble over the election of the provisional legislature and the chief executive. It said politicians should not ignore the reality that if Hong Kong people were forced to choose, most of them would go for money instead of democracy.</p>
<p>The pro-Beijing TA KUNG PAO said that the attempt by some people to ask the courts to judge the legality of the provisional legislature was ridiculous. It said the Hong Kong courts were a part of the British colonial structure, while the provisional legislature would be set up according to the Basic Law and the decisions of China's National People's Congress.</p>
<p>It said the colonial court had no power to judge the legality of the provisional legislature and the laws it would make.</p>
<p>The English-language HONGKONG STANDARD said the Government should do everything it could to encourage young people to want to learn Putonghua. It said Putonghua would make a more logical official language than Cantonese.</p>
<p>The middle of the road HONG KONG ECONOMIC TIMES said Hong Kong's unemployment rate was likely to drop further but it was still difficult for low-income, old and skilless people to find jobs.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 28436441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
