<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4812" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan key three-month CD rate falls to 0.60 pct.</title>
<headline>Japan key three-month CD rate falls to 0.60 pct.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's key three-month certificates of deposit (CD) rate fell to 0.60 percent in late morning on Tuesday, its lowest level since June 26, traders said.  </p>
<p>About 30 billion yen worth of three-month CDs was issued by late Tuesday morning, traders said.</p>
<p>A city bank trader said the issues of three-month CDs at such low levels were made possible due to receding fears of an imminent credit tightening.</p>
<p>&quot;The low rate of the new issues indicates that there is a growing belief within the market that there won't be an interest rate rise in the next three months,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>Three-month CDs had been issued earlier in the morning at 0.62 percent and then 0.61 percent, before falling to 0.60 percent, the trader added.  </p>
<p>About 110 billion yen worth of three-month CDs was issued at 0.62 percent, while 40 billion yen worth of three-month CDs was issued at 0.61 percent, a broker said.</p>
<p>The rates were down from Monday's 0.63 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
