<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4818" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: South Korean students end occupation of campus.</title>
<headline>South Korean students end occupation of campus.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean students fled a Seoul university building on Tuesday, ending a violent seven-day occupation of the campus in which they had demanded unification with North Korea, witnesses said.</p>
<p>The students left a science building hours after riot police backed by helicopters and assault troops stormed one of two occupied buildings on the Yonsei university campus and began arresting undergraduates branded by authorities as North Korean sympathisers, the witnesses said.  </p>
<p>Hundreds of students streamed out of the back door of the science block where they had been holding riot police at bay with gas cylinders and dangerous chemicals seized from laboratories, witnesses said.</p>
<p>It was not clear whether any students remained in the building, but witnesses said resistance on the campus now appeared to be over.</p>
<p>Many of the students raced into narrow alleyways surrounding the university and clamboured over rooftops to try to evade riot police. But some gathered on a main road and confronted riot police with rocks and iron bars.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
