<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4826" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MACAU: FEATURE - East meets West over rice cake and coffee.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - East meets West over rice cake and coffee.</headline>
<byline>Harald Bruning</byline>
<dateline>MACAU 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>In the narrow, cobbled streets of Portuguese-run Macau, a rocky outcrop on the south China coast, a humble rice cake has come to symbolise a meeting of cultures.</p>
<p>The cake, a twist of traditional Portuguese pastry fashioned from rice flour, is called Bolo de Arroz. So is the popular cafe run by Luisa Castanheira.</p>
<p>&quot;We named it Bolo de Arroz because rice cakes are a traditional Portuguese pastry and rice is associated with China, and here in Macau we are in China,&quot; Castanheira told Reuters.</p>
<p>The cake shop, which doubles as a Lisbon-style coffee house, has become an institution among local residents and tourists, almost three years after its opening by the Castanheira family from Portugal.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not just a cake shop and cafe but also a meeting place,&quot; said Castanheira, from Lisbon.</p>
<p>Some local Chinese call the shop &quot;the Portuguese cave,&quot; not only for its cavern-like layout but also because they consider it to be the territory's number-one hangout for civil servants on secondment for Portugal.</p>
<p>She said that while most of her customers were Portuguese, there was an ever increasing number of tourists from Hong Kong and elsewhere, as well as local Chinese dropping by.</p>
<p>&quot;The Portuguese tend to linger on, but many Chinese just come for takeaways,&quot; Castanheira said.</p>
<p>For Macau's 4,000-plus Portuguese expatriates, the Bolo de Arroz is the ultimate culinary blessing in the twilight years of Portugal's rule over the territory, which reverts to China in 1999.</p>
<p>For the majority Chinese population and foreign visitors, the Bolo de Arroz is one of the exotic attractions of Macau's unique Sino-Portuguese cultural -- and culinary -- heritage.</p>
<p>In the local Chinese dialect, Cantonese, the shop is called &quot;mai beng uk&quot; or rice cake house.</p>
<p>The Bolo de Arroz not only serves rice cakes but 100 other types of Portuguese-style cakes, sandwiches, cheeses and hams imported from Portugal.</p>
<p>The shop is in the basement of a residential building on Travessa de S. Domingos next to Macau's main square, the Largo do Senado. It seats up to 40 people, including several tables on a mezzanine gallery.</p>
<p>With the exception of a master pastry cook from Portugal, all its employees are Filipinos, some of whom have already picked up a smattering of Portuguese.</p>
<p>Castanheira is confident her shop in Macau will be around long after the change in sovereignty.</p>
<p>The family also runs three Portuguese restaurants in Macau, and is mulling proposals to open a Portuguese rice cake shop in the nearby British colony of Hong Kong, which China takes back in mid-1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MACAO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MACAU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MACAU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
