<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4839" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel says doesn't want to heat up Syria border.</title>
<headline>Israel says doesn't want to heat up Syria border.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A day after Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu warned escalation of violence in Lebanon would not be good for Syria, a senior government source said on Tuesday Israel was not trying to &quot;heat up the border&quot; with Syria.</p>
<p>The statement followed an Israeli Channel Two television report on Monday that Syria had tested a long-range Scud missile able to hit Israeli cities.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no intention to heat up the border with Syria,&quot; a government source who spoke on condition he not be named told Reuters.</p>
<p>During his first visit to Israeli-occupied south Lebanon since his May election victory, Netanyahu warned the Hizbollah guerrilla group that its raids on Israeli forces would only worsen the conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not good for Syria, Lebanon or Hizbollah or Israel. Therefore our choice is to try to reach a calming of the situation and guaranteeing security for all,&quot; Netanyahu said.</p>
<p>Israel says Syria, the main power broker in Lebanon with 35,000 troops there, could curb Hizbollah guerrillas fighting to oust Israel from a 15 km (nine mile) south Lebanon buffer strip the Jewish state has held since 1982.</p>
<p>Lebanon and Syria have both rejected Netanyahu's &quot;Lebanon First&quot; proposal -- by which Israel would withdraw from south Lebanon for the right security guarantees -- as a ploy to avoid handing the Golan Heights back to Damascus.</p>
<p>Israel captured the strategic Golan Heights in the 1967 Middle East war. Netanyahu says he will keep the plateau. Israel's previous government said it was ready to make painfull concessions on the Golan for full peace with Syria.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SYRIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
