<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4845" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Cyprus newspapers on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>ALITHIA</p>
<p>- American proposal for military talks is to be discussed at National Council session this afternoon.</p>
<p>- The Greek-Cyprus defence cooperation &quot;dogma&quot; will only be invoked in case the Cyprus military force is attacked, says government spokesman Yiannakis Cassoulides.</p>
<p>HARAVGHI</p>
<p>- The United States instists on military talks; President Clerides rejects proposal for a meeting with Turkish Cypriot leader Rauf Denktash.</p>
<p>- Cyprus Airways crisis still on, flight delays continue.</p>
<p>PHILELEFTHEROS</p>
<p>- Full parliamentary control over semi-governmental organisations. All decisions by management councils will have to be approved by parliament.</p>
<p>- Plenty of money in the market, not enough demand for loans, says A. Afxentiou, governor of Cyprus Central Bank.</p>
<p>SIMERINI</p>
<p>- Nicosia rejects a proposal put forward by U.N. Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali for a meeting between President Clerides and Turkish Cypriot leader Rauf Denktash.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
