<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4847" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: PRESS DIGEST - Turkey - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Turkey - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Turkish press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>SABAH</p>
<p>- Opposition Motherland Party (ANAP) leader Yilmaz causes confusion ahead of the ANAP annual conference by saying those with different views should form different parties.</p>
<p>- Exporters call for a realistic exchange rate to help boost exports.</p>
<p>MILLIYET</p>
<p>- Islamist premier Erbakan wants to reopen investigation of a plane crash in 1993 in which the head of the gendarmerie died.</p>
<p>- Two major unions agree joint action to protest against criticism of workers by Deputy Prime Minister Ciller.</p>
<p>HURRIYET</p>
<p>- New casino regulations, restricting opening hours and introducing a dress code, have reduced the number of gamblers and casino revenues.</p>
<p>CUMHURIYET</p>
<p>- Istanbul faces a hard winter with inadequate amounts of natural gas to meet the rising number of subscribers.</p>
<p>YENI YUZYIL</p>
<p>- Foreign investment in Turkey has began to decrease in the last two years while investment in emerging markets generally increases.</p>
<p>DUNYA</p>
<p>- Bus companies, leaving travellers stranded, continue to boycott the coach station in the major resort of Antalya in protest at the level of fees for using the station.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
