<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4850" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Egyptian press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-AHRAM</p>
<p>- Government to promote internationally 100 projects worth 75 billion pounds; work in 20 of the projects will begin this year. Prime Minister Kamal Ganzouri says government is working on removing obstacles to investment.</p>
<p>- Private sector will contribute in establishing tourism and development area to cost 3.65 billion pounds between Balteem and Hamasa.</p>
<p>- Social Fund will earmark $800 million for projects during the next stage; projects to concentrate on development and creating job opportunities in southern Egypt.</p>
<p>- Mubarak calls Yemeni president to discuss developments in the Red Sea and Arab and regional affairs.</p>
<p>- Mubarak congratulates Egyptian team to disabled olympics.</p>
<p>AL-AKHBAR</p>
<p>- Extremism rife in Israel -- Netanyahu to review new project on settlements in West Bank. Israeli government boycotts Oslo anniversary celebrations; Peres may meet Arafat to examine peace process.</p>
<p>- 10 percent of private education income to boost plan to introduce technology to education field.</p>
<p>- Tough security measures in place to track down suspects in armed robbery of Sohag gold shops.</p>
<p>AL-GOMHURIA</p>
<p>- Arafat threatens to take peace process to international arbitration; Israel drags feet over Hebron pullout. Peres says &quot;Lebanon First&quot; is laughable.</p>
<p>- 4.2 billion pounds turnover on stock market during past seven months.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
