<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4866" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: AMS first half disappoints, shares tumble.</title>
<headline>AMS first half disappoints, shares tumble.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chip producer Austria Mikro Systeme International AG reported on Tuesday a group pre-tax loss of 3.1 million schillings for the first six months due to losses at its two majority owned subsidiaries.</p>
<p>Sales reached 1.01 billion schillings, while net profit excluding minority interests hit 50.2 million. Comparative group figures are not available as AMS bought South Africa's SAMES and Germany's Thesys in the second half of 1995.</p>
<p>The results sent a shiver through investors and the share price shed 6.21 percent to record a new low for the year at 740 schillings in early Vienna trading.</p>
<p>&quot;AMS is a surprise. Three million losses for the whole group looks quite weak and it explains the sell-off,&quot; said a trader at an Austrian bank.</p>
<p>In the parent company, sales declined 12.7 percent to 710.4 million schillings, while pre-tax profit jumped 25.7 percent to 128.4 million schillings. Net profit was steady at 102.3 million schillings.</p>
<p>AMS said its 51-percent owned SAMES subsidiary posted a loss of 64.9 million schillings on sales of 87.6 million.</p>
<p>Thesys, of which AMS owns 51.25 percent, posted a loss of 83.9 million schillings on sales of 270.1 million.</p>
<p>&quot;As SAMES and Thesys are being transformed into becoming mainly suppliers of ASICs (application specific integrated circuits), they are expected to return to profitability,&quot; AMS said in a statement.</p>
<p>AMS expects ASICs production to account for some 50 percent of sales for SAMES and Thesys by the end of 1996 and &quot;provided problems in the microchip market do not worsen, SAMES should break even by the end of 1996 and Thesys by mid-1997.&quot;</p>
<p>The group net profit of 50.2 million schillings comprises the parent's 102.3 million schilling profit, SAMES' loss of 33.1 million schillings and Thesys' 43 million loss.</p>
<p>The figure also includes consolidation gains of 4.1 million schillings as well as 19.8 million schillings from a release of the negative differences resulting from the initial capital consolidation of 97.1 million schillings, which were disclosed as provisions for restructuring costs at the time of the two acquisitions.</p>
<p>For the full year, AMS reiterated that it cannot disengage fully from the development of the market, which continues to be determined by worldwide overcapacities.</p>
<p>&quot;The overall decline seen in the first half of the year has not bottomed out,&quot; AMS said, but did not elaborate.</p>
<p>-- Julia Ferguson, Vienna newsroom, +431 531 12274</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
