<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4868" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Pechiney may cut 3-3,500 jobs - unions.</title>
<headline>Pechiney may cut 3-3,500 jobs - unions.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>French aluminium and packaging group Pechiney may cut between 3,000 and 3,500 jobs by end 1998 under its cost reduction plan code-named Challenge, trade union sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The plan, which is aimed at cutting costs by between 1.5 and three billion francs by 1998 should be announced next month.</p>
<p>But a company spokeswoman said it would be premature to quote a job reduction figure.</p>
<p>The company has already said there would be no layoffs in France. Pechiney will hold a board meeting on September 19 ahead of the release of its first half earnings.</p>
<p>Company offficials said Pechiney may also hold a meeting of its group committee the same day to fine tune its estimate of the cost savings the Challenge plan will generate.</p>
<p>Pechiney employs 37,000 people worldwide, of which 19,000 are in France.</p>
<p>Pechiney swung back to profit in 1995 but wants to raise profitability to the level of its best competitors in all businesses. It sees cost savings as a way to meet investment needs without furher raising debt.</p>
<p>In a June interview with French business weekly Investir Pechniney chairman Jean-Pierre Rodier said profit in 1996 would probably remain unchanged from the previous year because while macroeconomic factors looked good it was still unclear when this would help sales volume.</p>
<p>Pechiney had a net profit of 1.47 billion francs in 1995 but this included 730 million francs of capital gains linked to the sale of assets.</p>
<p>-- Dominique Vidalon, Pais newsroom +331 4221 5432</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
