<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4871" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French government in a bind over hunger strikers.</title>
<headline>French government in a bind over hunger strikers.</headline>
<byline>Lee Yanowitch</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leading member of France's ruling coalition urged the government on Tuesday to compromise on its threat to expel 300 African immigrants entrenched in a Paris church, 10 of them on a hunger strike for a month and a half.</p>
<p>Gilles de Robien, floor leader of the centrist UDF, junior partner in the governing majority, met a delegation of the protesters for talks at the National Assembly.</p>
<p>&quot;We are ready to work day and night on such a delicate problem. Time is pressing,&quot; he told French radio as the hunger strikers began their 47th day of fasting.</p>
<p>&quot;A firm policy does not bother me in principle,&quot; he added. &quot;But there are special cases that deserve a close-up analysis. We are talking about men and women, not objects.&quot;</p>
<p>Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre has said he would only discuss terms for the Africans' repatriation, fearing that concessions could unleash thousands of similar demands and play into the hands of the far right anti-immigrant National Front.</p>
<p>The highly-publicised protest by mostly Malian immigrants, including 110 children, has backed the government into a corner.</p>
<p>Hundreds of supporters stood a round-the-clock vigil around the Saint-Bernard church to prevent a possible police raid as politicians both Left and Centre called for a humane solution.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is in a terrible bind. The protesters have too much support for the police to intervene,&quot; said Dominique Noguere, lawyer for the Human Rights League and some immigrants.</p>
<p>The opposition Socialists have agreed to a proposal by the Communist Party to ask President Jacques Chirac to intervene for the &quot;sans papiers&quot; (without papers) protesters.</p>
<p>The stand-off in the heavily immigrant Goutte d'Or district has grabbed headlines, but the protest does not appear to have rallied widespread support.</p>
<p>A demonstration in the heavily immigrant port of Marseille gathered only about 50 people on Monday. Another march was planned in Paris on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Greens leader Dominique Voynet praised de Robien's offer to talk with the immigrants. &quot;It shows that there are divisions within the majority, and that not everybody shares Mr Debre's blind obscurantism,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Outside the church, human rights activists, leftists and ordinary citizens lay on sleeping bags on the ground in the dark pre-dawn hours, ready to form a human barrage against a police raid they feared could be imminent.</p>
<p>&quot;The government thought it could stand by and watch the movement crumble, but they didn't count on so much support,&quot; said Huguette Cordelier, a teacher who had spent three nights sleeping outside the church with her husband.</p>
<p>Abubakar Diop, the immigrants' spokesman, said the hunger strikers were extremely weak and could not to receive visitors or members of the press.</p>
<p>&quot;At one point we asked them to stop their hunger strike because a little piece of paper is not worth dying for. But they have refused,&quot; he said. &quot;</p>
<p>Lawyers say the immigrants' status is a legal tangle ranging from some people who are entitled to stay, to others who can be expelled outright, and others whose situation has become unclear following controversial 1993 laws to curb immigration.</p>
<p>&quot;If the government can't tell the difference between illegal aliens and those who used to have papers but are refused them now, it doesn't know how to use the French language,&quot; Diop said.</p>
<p>Noguere said the problem affected many more foreigners in France than the 300 protesters. &quot;When the law was passed, its effects were not taken into account,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
