<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4879" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austria's Vranitzky says no NATO decision in 97.</title>
<headline>Austria's Vranitzky says no NATO decision in 97.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chancellor Franz Vranitzky has firmly denied Austria will decide on possible NATO membership next year, contradicting controversial comments by his defence minister a month ago.</p>
<p>&quot;(In 1997) we will certainly not make a decision on NATO membership,&quot; the Social Democrat leader said in an interview published in Tuesday's edition of the daily Der Standard.</p>
<p>Vranitzky said NATO membership would not necessarily grant the neutral republic greater security. The government should instead work for closer international cooperation through the Atlantic alliance's Partnership for Peace programme, he said.</p>
<p>Defence Minister Werner Fasslabend, whose conservative People's Party rules as junior coalition partner with the Social Democrats, said on July 22 the debate over NATO membership should be completed by the middle of 1997.</p>
<p>The remarks by Fasslabend, a staunch supporter of joining the military alliance, triggered a new round of a NATO debate which surfaced as an issue among Austria's political parties since the country joined the European Union in 1995.</p>
<p>The political right has generally argued for a swift decision, while the pro-neutrality left insists the issue must be decided by a national referendum.</p>
<p>A recent poll showed only 23 percent of Austrians support joining NATO.</p>
<p>Two weeks ago, conservative Foreign Minister Wolfgang Schuessel appeared to back off from Fasslabend's disputed comments for the first time, saying Austria was not negotiating a deal with NATO or planning to scrap its long-held neutrality.</p>
<p>Austria, perched on the traditional border between the feuding eastern and western blocs, has been neutral since 1955, when it inaugurated its post-World War Two constitution.</p>
<p>The Soviet Union, which occupied Austria after the war with its allies Britain, France and United States, demanded Austria enshrine neutrality as a central pillar of its national charter before it agreed to withdraw its troops.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
