<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4881" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Hunt for girls widens in Belgian sex scandal.</title>
<headline>Hunt for girls widens in Belgian sex scandal.</headline>
<byline>Bert Lauwers</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian police have turned to other countries in their search for two teenage girls who were abducted a year ago by a convicted child sex offender at the heart of a widening sex scandal, Belgian media said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The media spotlight focused particularly on the Czech Republic, but there were also reports that Interpol in Germany, the Netherlands and France had been asked for help.</p>
<p>There has been widespread speculation the two may have been sold into prostitution, possibly in the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>Officials in the case would only say there were foreign leads.</p>
<p>&quot;Unbearable,&quot; Het Laatste Nieuws newspaper said, referring to the tension being borne by the parents of An Marchal and Eefje Lambrecks, who went missing at the Belgian port of Ostend in August 1995.</p>
<p>BRTN radio on Tuesday quoted An's father, Paul Marchal, as saying it could still be a matter of days before the case was solved.</p>
<p>BRTN said a fifth suspect in the case had been detained after a series of house searches on Monday but magistrates in charge of the case in Neufchateau, southern Belgium, were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>The main suspect in the biggest child sex scandal in Belgian history is Marc Dutroux, a convicted child abuser and unemployed father of three.</p>
<p>Dutroux and associate Michel Lelievre were formally charged last Friday with abduction and illegal imprisonment after police rescued Laetitia Delhez, 14, and Sabine Dardenne, 12, from a cell in a house owned by Dutroux in Charleroi. Both girls had been sexually abused.</p>
<p>Michelle Martin, Dutroux' second wife, was charged on Monday with being an accomplice.</p>
<p>National euphoria at the rescue turned to dismay and anger at the weekend when Dutroux led police to the bodies of eight-year-olds Julie Lejeune and Melissa Russo, who had died of starvation early this year after being kidnapped in June 1995.</p>
<p>The children will be buried on Thursday.</p>
<p>The leader of the investigation into the case of British serial killers Fred and Rosemary West, whose house and garden in Gloucester contained the bodies of several murdered women, has offered to help Belgian investigators, BRTN radio said.</p>
<p>Brussels businessman Jean-Michel Nihoul arrived amid tight security at the Neufchateau court building on Tuesday. He is to be formally charged with criminal association, assistant magistrate Jean-Paul Pavanello said on Monday.</p>
<p>BRTN radio said the fifth arrested person is the Dutch boyfriend of Nihoul's former wife. His house in Brussels and caravan in Dinant, southern Belgium, have been searched.</p>
<p>Belgian newspaper Het Nieuwsblad said Dutroux abducted girls for a network with international links.</p>
<p>BRTN said a total of 15 house searches had been carried out on Monday.</p>
<p>Public anger spread further at the fact that Dutroux had been released for good behaviour 10 years early in 1992 from a 13-year sentence for rape and child abuse.</p>
<p>Former Belgian Justice Minister Melchior Wathelet, blamed by Julie and Melissa's parents for having approved Dutroux's release, said he too was shocked.</p>
<p>But he told BRTN radio he had released him in good faith on the basis of a full judicial report.</p>
<p>At least 15 children have disappeared in Belgium in the past six years. Seven have now been found dead, six are still missing and only two -- Delhez and Dardenne -- have been rescued.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
