<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4897" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: PRESS DIGEST - Italy - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Italy - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the top headlines in leading Italian newspapers.</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP POLITICAL STORIES</p>
<p>*Trade unions say they are not going to strike against secessionist Northern league party leader Umberto Bossi, as communist leader Fausto Bertinotti had suggested yesterday (all).</p>
<p>*Umberto Bossi says his party is ready to vote in favour of STET privatization if Prime Minister Romano Prodi goes to Mantova, capoital of the proposed independent Republic of Padania (all).</p>
<p>*The Democratic party of the Left (Pds) says there is still room for an agreement with Bertinotti over STET, but &quot;we can't go on like this anymore&quot; protest some party members such as Gavino Angius (all).</p>
<p>TOP BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>*Minister for Public Employment Franco Bassanini wants to stop double employment in the public sector. He is ready to send his inspectors to check how many people have more than one job and how much they earn (Corriere, Stampa, Repubblica, Unita').</p>
<p>*Certificates of deposit will be tax-exempt for non residents (Sole 24 Ore).</p>
<p>* The crisis of the car market is getting worse: for the first time there are signs that a lower number of cars are circulating in Italy (Sole 24 ore).</p>
<p>---------</p>
<p>Reuter has not verified these stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>--- Milan bureau +392 66129450</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
