<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4904" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights of stories in the Danish press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>BERLINGSKE TIDENDE</p>
<p>--- The issue of changing the early retirement system has split the Danish government which cannot agree on a plan to cut benefits for those who have capital savings.</p>
<p>POLITIKEN</p>
<p>--- Chinese authorities have agreed to meet Danish experts to discuss democratic elections and legal principles during foreign minister Niels Helveg Petersen's visit to China in September.</p>
<p>JYLLANDS-POSTEN</p>
<p>--- Medicine prices will rise next year as part of the new government budget for 1997 which will introduce cuts to medicine subsidies totalling 80-100 million crowns.</p>
<p>--- Scandinavian Airlines System (SAS) will not have to pay compensation of 150 million crowns to Swissair as had been believed, because the two sides agreed to end their partnership within the Quality Alliance peacefully.</p>
<p>BORSEN</p>
<p>--- Denmark is the only country to honour an OECD agreement on not subsidising shipyards, but it will be still harder for the shipyards to win orders without breaking the present agreement.</p>
<p>DET FRI AKTUELT</p>
<p>Danish dairy group MD Foods has not had the expected success with their yoghurt product Gaio in Great Britain. The product was launched in June last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
