<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4913" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Finland - August 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Finland - August 20.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the leading stories in Finnish papers this morning.</p>
<p>HELSINGIN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Head of Educational Board says regional school controllers should be reinstated after recent report of teachers' violent acts against handicapped children in special schools.</p>
<p>- Those with higher income to benefit most from the tax cuts next year, SAK trade union study shows.</p>
<p>- Finnish customs confiscated 5.5 million cigarettes coming from Latvia in the biggest smuggling attempt of cigarettes to Finland.  </p>
<p>- Level of education helps people earn higher salaries significantly more often than thought earlier, new study says. Men who study one year more may end up earning 15 percent more.</p>
<p>- Charter flights increasingly compete with regular scheduled flights as travel agencies now sell cheap charter flights also without accomodation.</p>
<p>- Finland's 1,000 Lakes rally, part of the world rally championships, likely to jam roads in central Finland -- 400,000 spectators and 100,000 cars expected.</p>
<p>- Helsinki preparing for its Festival Week beginning tomorrow with nearly 2,000 performing artists.  </p>
<p>- Police release eagle owl stuck in volley ball net.</p>
<p>KAUPPALEHTI</p>
<p>- Finland and Russia likely to strike deal on outstanding payments of 400 million markka in Russian debts to about 60 Finnish companies, industrial officials say.</p>
<p>- Price competition between Silja Line and Viking Line is harmful for both, investment bank Kleinwort Benson report says.</p>
<p>DEMARI</p>
<p>- Amount of work cooperative increased fast -- in 1993-1996 more than 100 new cooperatives formed with almost 3,000 workers, a study shows.  </p>
<p>- Eutrophication -- excessive seaweed growth -- the biggest threat to the Baltic Sea, already badly eutrophicated in some parts.</p>
<p>TURUN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Duck hunting season starts today but small catch expected as water fowl population has decreased 11 percent from last year, reserachers say.</p>
<p>-- Paivi Mattila, Helsinki Newsroom +358 - 0 - 680 50 292</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
