<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4914" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: PRESS DIGEST - France - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - France - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are leading stories in this morning's Paris newspapers.</p>
<p>LES ECHOS</p>
<p>-- Tourism up sharply in August in France after slow July.</p>
<p>-- French customs impounded 45 percent more copies of brand name goods in 1995 than 1994.</p>
<p>-- German mark is firm in run-up to today's Federal Reserve Bank meeting and Thursday's Bundesbank policy council meeting.</p>
<p>LA TRIBUNE DESFOSSES</p>
<p>-- Caisses d'Epargne is finalising a bid for Gan's banking unit CIC  and plans to revamp its own statutes.</p>
<p>-- Paris Bourse sluggish in run-up to corporate first half results announcements.</p>
<p>-- Banque Rivaud says the Canard Enchaine newspaper's revelations of a tax investigation at the bank were &quot;isolated facts, biased and inaccurate&quot;.</p>
<p>-- Franc slips on foreign exchange markets as operators remain wary of 1997 national budget and slim chances of Bundesbank rate cuts on Thursday.</p>
<p>L'AGEFI</p>
<p>-- Prime Minister Alain Juppe says he will announce tax cuts within two weeks.</p>
<p>-- Matif chairman Gerard Pfauwadel explains failure of linkup with Germany's DTB futures market and outlines new strategy, preparing for the euro currency.</p>
<p>LE FIGARO-ECONOMIE</p>
<p>-- Air France Q2 passenger miles up 19 percent while revenue per passenger falls 11 percent but the airline still expects to break even in 1997.</p>
<p>-- European competition commissioner Karel Van Miert says he is impartial about whether a company is state-owned or private, but a commitment to privatise makes a government's request for EC approval of state subsidies more credible.</p>
<p>THE INTERNATIONAL HERALD TRIBUNE</p>
<p>-- Bond and currency markets on tenterhooks, waiting for the Federal Reserve to take no action on interest rates.</p>
<p>LE PARISIEN</p>
<p>-- Prime Minister Alain Juppe says there will be no announcements of fiscal reforms before a working meeting with President Jacques Chirac in Bregancon on August 24.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5381</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
