<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4917" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: PRESS DIGEST - Germany - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Germany - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Tuesday morning's German newspapers:</p>
<p>FRANKFURTER ALLGEMEINE ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- Police search headquarters of reform communist Party of Democratic Socialism (PDS) in probe into assets hidden by East Germany's hardline regime.</p>
<p>- Prosecutors suspect German firms of providing equipment for poison gas factory in Libya.</p>
<p>- Finance Minister of Saxony state sees great opportunity to reform tax system.</p>
<p>- Liberal Free Democrats want further measures to reduce financial burden on companies.</p>
<p>- Wage negotiations for retail sector in North Rhine-Westphalia state make no progress.</p>
<p>HANDELSBLATT</p>
<p>- Main opposition Social Democrats (SPD) say comprehensive tax reform could begin in 1998.</p>
<p>- Mechanical engineering sector increases production from foreign bases.</p>
<p>- Insurance companies Berlin-Koelnische Versicherungsgruppe and Gothaer Gruppe plan merger.</p>
<p>- Mannesmann says its 1996 full-year results will be a slight improvement on its 1995 figures.</p>
<p>SUEDDEUTSCHE ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- Two managers from German firms in investigative custody as part of probe into export of equipment for Libyan poison gas factory.</p>
<p>- FDP says proposal by Bavarian finance minister to tax life insurance pay-outs is worth considering.</p>
<p>- Company health insurance funds hope to keep contributions stable until at least middle of 1997.</p>
<p>- Retailers vow to fight against plans to allow post offices to sell a wider range of goods.</p>
<p>DIE WELT</p>
<p>- Government announces plans to introduce performance-related pay for some academics.</p>
<p>- FDP repeats demands for early tax reform despite criticism from Chancellor Helmut Kohl.</p>
<p>- Federation of German Wholesalers and Exporters (BGA) disagrees with Chambers of Commerce over export performance of German companies. The BGA says German firms are losing ground.</p>
<p>- Life Insurance firms protest speak out against suggestions that their pay-outs to customers should be taxed.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom +49 228 2609760</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
