<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4923" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - August 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - August 20.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of stories in the Irish press on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>IRISH TIMES</p>
<p>- A man was being questioned by Irish police on Monday night following the seizure of cocaine and cannabis in Dublin with a street value of 1.5 million Irish pounds.</p>
<p>- Dublin-based financial services firm Taylor Asset Managers is facing an Irish Brokers Asssociation (IBA) hearing into two client complaints.  </p>
<p>- Irish exploration company Glencar plans to increase its stake in the Wassa gold project in Ghana from 45.2 percent to 61 percent at a cost of between $11.4 million and $12.2 million.</p>
<p>-Insurance company Hibernian Group warned that its motor premiums may rise after it reported that rising motor accident claims contributed to a 17 percent fall in operating profits to 11.2 million for the first six months of 1996.</p>
<p>- Unilever will find out on Tuesday how many Lyons Irish Holldings have accepted their offer of 323p per share.  </p>
<p>IRISH INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>- The Irish Department of Education has ordered an inquiry into aspects of a detailed financial report on one of the country's vocational educational committees.</p>
<p>- Irish police are investigating the deaths of two women in their homes in Dublin and Kerry.</p>
<p>- Irish exploration company Dragon Oil said at its annual meeting in Dublin yesterday that production from its oil well in the Caspian Sea has been increased by 20 percent.  </p>
<p>- Belfast-based exploration company Andaman may seek a listing on the London Stock Exchange if its proposed acquisition of an unnamed Asian oil and gas company goes ahead.</p>
<p>- Insurance sales staff at financial services firm Irish Life agreed by a narrow margin to accept a Labour Relations Commission initiative to open further talks with management at the company.</p>
<p>-- Dublin Newsroom + 353-1-6603377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
