<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4929" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Aug 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Tuesday morning's Austrian newspapers.</p>
<p>DIE PRESSE</p>
<p>- Vienna against lowering taxes despite Bonn's plans for overall tax reform in 1999 by easing tax burden on Germans.</p>
<p>- People's Party General Secretary Otmar Karas said the Freedom Party damaged Austria's reputation.</p>
<p>- Austria's travel agencies are suffering from dropping prices and late bookings.</p>
<p>DER STANDARD</p>
<p>- Chancellor Franz Vranitzky said in an interview that Austria would &quot;certainly not&quot; make a decision about joining NATO in 1997. An increasing number of People's Party officials are also urging the country to wait.</p>
<p>- People's Party social affairs spokesman Gottfried Feuerstein said he wanted to take in more foreigners as managers and seasonal workers at the expense of traditional guestworkers.</p>
<p>- Only four percent of Austrians own stocks.</p>
<p>- Heating equipment manufacturer Vogel &amp; Noot Waermetechnik AG said it was planning a dividend cut for 1996 to 10 percent from 16 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>KURIER</p>
<p>- Rate cut expected on Thursday. Adolf Wala, director general of the Austrian National Bank, said Germany had more room to manoeuvre in terms of interest rates than Austria.</p>
<p>- Despite an economic boom in eastern Europe, Austrian businesses are investing and exporting less to the region.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
