<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4933" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: FEATURE - Campaigners want power against child sex tourists.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Campaigners want power against child sex tourists.</headline>
<byline>Belinda Goldsmith</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Children's rights campaigners are urging governments worldwide to give their courts the powers to prosecute paedophiles who travel overseas to have sex with children.</p>
<p>Organisers of the first international conference on the sexual exploitation of children say lawyers and police often find themselves unable to take action against child sex tourists because the crimes fall outside their jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Awareness of the problem is growing, with the United Nations Children's Fund estimating at least one million children -- mainly from developing countries -- are forced into prostitution, sold for sexual purposes, or used in pornography each year.</p>
<p>But at present only 12 countries permit the prosecution of child sex tourists in their home countries for crimes committed against children abroad, or allow the investigation of such crimes by their nationals in other countries.</p>
<p>&quot;In other countries, penal provisions do not reach further than the territory of the country,&quot; said Madeleine Leijonhuvud, a Swedish criminal law professor who is joint organiser of the conference to be held in Stockholm from August 27 to 31.</p>
<p>&quot;It leaves lawyers and police frustrated as nothing can be done.&quot;</p>
<p>Leijonhuvud said there was an urgent need to strengthen and harmonise laws internationally, including a global agreement on the age of consent.</p>
<p>Laws regarding child pornography also varied widely, with Sweden, for example, still allowing possession of such material.</p>
<p>&quot;When any country does not live up to international standards -- like Sweden and child pornography -- it can cause problems for other countries trying to take action,&quot; Leijonhuvud told Reuters.</p>
<p>A Bangkok-based lobby group, End Child Prostitution in Asian Tourism (ECPAT), said penalties imposed on child sex tourists were not severe enough and were often lighter if the victim was a foreign child.</p>
<p>In Sweden, for example, a man last year received a custodial sentence of just three months when he was found guilty of sexually abusing a child in Thailand.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been suggested in relation to that case that the penalty would have been greater if the abused child had been Swedish,&quot; said Muireann O'Briain of ECPAT's working group on law reform and law enforcement.</p>
<p>ECPAT pointed to Australian legislation, introduced two years ago, as a model for other countries.</p>
<p>Of the 12 countries that currently allow their nationals to be prosecuted at home for sex crimes against children abroad, Australia has the highest rate of action and the most severe penalties, including jail terms of up to 17 years.</p>
<p>A 44-year-old man from Sydney was the first person to be imprisoned under the law in March this year, when he was convicted of offences against children in the Philippines.</p>
<p>Leaflets warning of the legal consequences are circulated in key destination countries for Australian sex tourists, such as Thailand and the Philippines, and are also distributed in Australian airports and by some travel agents.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt that (Australia) is doing more about this issue than any other industrialised country,&quot; ECPAT national director Bernadette McMenamin told Reuters.</p>
<p>Christian Aid representative Martin Cottingham, who is to attend this month's conference, said Britain needed to speed up its proposals for similar extraterritorial legislation.</p>
<p>&quot;(We want) early implementation and extra police resources to ensure prosecutions which will deter would-be child-sex offenders,&quot; Cottingham said in a statement.</p>
<p>The introduction of extraterritorial legislation is seen as only the first step against child sex tourists.</p>
<p>Stockholm conference organiser and former Swedish ambassador Tom Tscherning said resources needed to be set aside to help implement the laws, which includes gathering evidence abroad and bringing witnesses to court.</p>
<p>&quot;Cooperation between governmental law enforcement agencies and INTERPOL is vitally important,&quot; Tscherning told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Laws are the ultimate protection for children and not enough is being done either to make laws sufficiently strong or to enforce them when they are in place.&quot;</p>
<p>Sweden's Queen Silvia, patron of the conference, has joined the campaign for tougher laws against paedophiles.</p>
<p>In an unprecedented outburst during a recent television interview, she rebuked Swedish politicians for not taking firm enough action and called for the name and photograph of anyone who sexually abused a child to be published nationally.</p>
<p>The queen said she had seen some pornographic films involving children and was devastated by the images, saying all politicians should watch these films to make them act.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the worst thing I have ever seen,&quot; the queen said. &quot;It is torture of the worst kind.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
