<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4934" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FEATURE - French law seen doing little to cut unemployment.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - French law seen doing little to cut unemployment.</headline>
<byline>Penny MacRae</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Striving to cut record 12.5 percent unemployment, France's centre-right government has enacted legislation designed to spur companies to reduce working hours and hire more staff.</p>
<p>But economists doubt the move to shorten the working week -- last reduced to 39 hours from 40 hours in 1982 -- will have much impact on unemployment in the face of sluggish economic growth and labour market inflexiblity.</p>
<p>Economists suggest the measure is more a window-dressing attempt by the government to show voters it is taking some action to cut unemployment -- especially in light of President Jacques Chirac's pledge when running for office last year to make &quot;jobs, jobs, jobs&quot; his priority.</p>
<p>&quot;Unemployment is a key political challenge for the government,&quot; said a French economist who did not wish to be named. &quot;Chirac said he wanted to be judged on his jobs record and in the past year things haven't improved.&quot;</p>
<p>In fact, with the prospect of more layoffs ahead as a result of the government's austerity programme to meet deficit targets aimed at qualifying for a single European currency due to start in 1999, the situation may get worse before it gets better.</p>
<p>So far, economists say, the government has shown no taste for taking steps they say are really needed to cut unemployment -- loosening rigid labour policies that make hiring expensive and firing tough, allowing the minimum wage to fall in real value and significantly scaling back generous welfare schemes.</p>
<p>&quot;Most French unemployment is structural so to reduce it you need to have structural reforms of the labour market,&quot; said Jean-Francois Mercier of Salomon Brothers in London.</p>
<p>The new legislation, which came into effect last Thursday, was the result of a series of negotations between the government, unions and employers.</p>
<p>It says that companies which cut working hours by 15 percent and hire the same proportion of new staff will pay up to 50 percent lower social security contributions for the first year and 40 percent less for the succeeding six years.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it (the law's effect) will be pretty marginal,&quot; said Gwyn Hacche, chief European economist at James Capel.</p>
<p>&quot;It may add a small amount to employment but (lowering unemployment) is much more dependent on the level of demand in the economy and the latest indicators suggest the recovery is somewhat in limbo.&quot;</p>
<p>The law also allows employers to reduce working hours to avoid layoffs, a provision which economists say may be more useful -- at least in helping stem a rise in jobless.</p>
<p>France's largest union, the CFDT, which has led the drive for a shorter working week, would like to see tougher action by the government.</p>
<p>&quot;Decision-makers continue to think unemployment will be solved by the classic means of growth, consumption and investment,&quot; said CFDT head Nicole Notat, who is pushing for a &quot;massive&quot; reduction in the work week to as low as 32 hours.</p>
<p>Economists say a shorter work week without a corresponding increase in productivity would actually increase unemployment by driving up the cost of goods.</p>
<p>The government has chosen to leave it up to unions and business to work out &quot;voluntary agreements&quot; on working hours.</p>
<p>But progress has been slow and the French employers' federation, the CNPF, is sceptical that shorter working hours are a remedy for unemployment.</p>
<p>&quot;You only have to look around at our neighbours in Europe to see that those countries with the lowest unemployment have the longest working hours,&quot; said one senior CNPF official.</p>
<p>In Britain, for instance, there is no ceiling on the work week and unemployment is much lower at 7.6 percent.</p>
<p>Britain's lower jobless rate is &quot;the result mainly of the (free) labour market policies pursued by former conservative prime minister Mrs (Margaret) Thatcher in 1980s now bearing fruit,&quot; said Hacche.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no historical evidence that reducing working hours anywhere has led to real significant increases in employment,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Economists say even with incentives, businesses are unlikely to hire more workers until the economic climate improves.</p>
<p>&quot;If a company is worried about future demand, they will not hire even if they get incentives to reduce working hours,&quot; said Mercier.</p>
<p>In any event, economists say the trend toward lower working hours in the West may have come to a close as competition from developing countries becomes ever more intense.</p>
<p>&quot;The secular trend to reducing working time that the world witnessed during the 19th and 20th centuries has come to an end as a result of global competition,&quot; said one Paris economist. &quot;People may have to work harder and longer if anything.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
