<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4940" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian Alan Bond jailed for three years.</title>
<headline>Australian Alan Bond jailed for three years.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH, Australia 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Failed Australian businessman Alan Bond was sentenced to three years in jail on Tuesday for fraud involving the French impressionist painting, La Promenade.</p>
<p>The Western Australia District Court sentenced Bond after a jury last Friday found him guilty of four fraud charges, brought by the corporate watchdog the Australian Securities Commission, which carried a maximum sentence of 14 years in jail.  </p>
<p>Bond, who became a national hero in 1983 for winning the America's Cup yachting trophy, had appealed for a non-custodial sentence. His lawyer argued that a jail term could kill him.</p>
<p>But Judge Antoinette Kennedy said she was satisfied Bond's &quot;health problems could be monitored within the prison system&quot;.</p>
<p>Bond was found guilty of improperly using his position as director of his former corporate flagship, Bond Corporation Holdings, to allow his private company to buy Edouard Manet's La Promenade from Bond Corp for A$2.5 million (US$1.9 million), when its value was at least A$12 million.</p>
<p>Bond's Dallhold Investments Pty Ltd sold the painting a year later at auction in New York for A$17 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
