<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4941" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Budget hopes boost Australian stocks at open.</title>
<headline>Budget hopes boost Australian stocks at open.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian share market continued its climb at the opening on Tuesday with buying interest fuelled by expectations of a tight Federal budget from Treasurer Peter Costello later today.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index rose 13.2 points to 2,274.7, while September share index futures rose 11 points to 2,287, a 12.3 point premium to the underlying index.</p>
<p>The buoyancy of Monday afternoon had spilled over, with solid buying interest pushing the bourse to its highest level in nearly four months, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;What people want from the budget is still pushing it. They expect Costello to be firm,&quot; said a Sydney broker.</p>
<p>With opening volume levels well up on recent starting levels, buyers had clearly jumped down from the fence they had occupied for the last week.</p>
<p>&quot;Buyers from yesterday are still about and they have given it a bit of a go,&quot; the broker said.</p>
<p>The big banks remained in favour as did cylical stocks such as transport shares Brambles and Mayne Nickless.</p>
<p>Rises outnumbered falls by a ratio of about 14 to four, while about 41 percent of shares traded remained steady.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
