<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4942" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks modestly higher in morning trade.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks modestly higher in morning trade.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks were modestly higher in Tuesday morning trade, with gains in the utility and property sectors aiding the general tone of the market, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index rose 24.09 points to 11,237.57. Turnover was HK$817 million after the first hour of trade. The Hang Seng properties sub-index added 17.26 points to 21,062.19 and the utilities sub-index rose 76.98 points to 9,547.78.</p>
<p>&quot;There is still going to be buying in property counters ahead of their reuslts,&quot; said Kent Rossiter, institutional sales manager at Nikko Securities. &quot;There is a lot of focus on Hutchison and Cheung Kong which are the most imminent.&quot;</p>
<p>Shares in Hutchison Whampoa rose HK$0.50 to HK$47.90 and Cheung Kong (Holdings) was steady at HK$56.25. Both companies are due to release their interim results on Thursday.</p>
<p>In the utilities sector, China Light rose HK$0.30 to HK$32.80 and Hong Kong Telecom was up HK$0.10 at HK$12.90. &quot;The utilities had been left well behind by the market,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>However, analysts said gains in the market were likely to be capped ahead of the U.S. Federal Reserve's policy meeting later on Tuesday. &quot;As the market heads towards the 11,300 level we are still going to meet some resistance,&quot; said Rossiter.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is likely to be quiet waiting for the FOMC meeting. If there is no change in interest rates, the market should be able to move higher,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>H-shares succumbed to profit-taking after three consecutive winning sessions. The index of Hong Kong-listed mainland China companies fell 12.18 points to 823.34.</p>
<p>Shares in Yaohan International Holdings rose HK$0.10 to HK$0.87 after the company said it plans to privatise its loss making unit Yaohan Hongkong Corp Ltd. Shares in Yaohan Hongkong fell HK$0.02 to HK$0.35.</p>
<p>Cheung Kong Infrastructure fell HK$0.05 to HK$12.55. The company reported net profit of HK$347.2 million for the first half of 1996.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
