<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4943" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEPAL: Nepal textile mills end strike against tax hike.</title>
<headline>Nepal textile mills end strike against tax hike.</headline>
<dateline>KATHMANDU 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nepal's textile mills, closed for three weeks in protest against an increase in sales tax, re-opened on Tuesday after the government agreed to review a tax proposal, a senior industry official said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will open the factories as the government has agreed to consider some of our policy-related demands,&quot; Mahesh Lal Pradhan, president of Nepal Textile Industries' Association (NTIA), told Reuters.</p>
<p>More than 200 textile plants closed last month, throwing 20,000 people out of work, after the government raised the sales tax to 15 percent from five percent. The industry wants the government to restore the old rate.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Sher Bahadur Deuba, who is also Finance Minister, had assured the entrepreneurs that he would take care of the interest of factory owners, Pradhan said.</p>
<p>Factory owners said the sales tax hike had made Nepali products costlier than textiles imported from India or Tibet. Cheaper textiles were also smuggled in from India, they said.</p>
<p>Pradhan said the government had also agreed to make the valuation of imports realistic and take strong measures against smuggling.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NEPAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KATHMANDU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEPAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
