<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4946" id="root" date="1996-08-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Traders resent move against used car imports.</title>
<headline>Traders resent move against used car imports.</headline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bangladeshi traders on Monday took issue with a government plan to restrict imports of used cars in its drive against pollution and said it could push up prices.</p>
<p>&quot;It's absolutely wrong to put the blame on used imported cars. All re-conditioned Japanese vehicles... are sure to have anti-pollution devices as per Japan's export rule,&quot; said Abdul Haque, president of the Bangladesh Re-conditioned Vehicles Importers and Dealers Association.</p>
<p>The re-conditioned cars constitute nearly 90 percent of Bangladesh's total car imports.</p>
<p>Huque told a news conference the government served notice last month it was going to limit the age of used imported cars to three years, arguing the vehicles are polluting the environment. Currently, importers are allowed to bring in five-year- old used cars.</p>
<p>&quot;We are importing the cars that have in-biult anti-pollution devices and are safe,&quot; Haque said.</p>
<p>He said the government also imposed Value Added Tax (VAT) at a rate of 15 percent on sales of the cars, effective July this year.</p>
<p>He warned that the price of re-conditioned cars in local markets might be &quot;doubled or trippled&quot; because of such moves.</p>
<p>Bangladesh reduced import duty on car imports to 45 percent from 50 percent in fiscal 1996/97 which began on July 1. The country imported nearly 30,000 re-conditioned cars, mostly from Japan, in 1995-96.</p>
<p>The government earned 3.0 billion taka ($71.4 million) as tax revenue from car imports last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
