<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4949" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks close at record despite disruption.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks close at record despite disruption.</headline>
<byline>Dan Trotta</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite a rowdy protest that shut down floor trading for three hours, Mexican stocks closed at a record high Wednesday due to a combination of low interest rates, a strong peso and rosy economic sentiment.</p>
<p>The IPC index of leading stocks gained 0.31 percent, or 10.58 points, to 3,412.37 points, snapping Tuesday's record closing high of 3,401.79 points.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a big success, really,&quot; one trader said. &quot;It's a shame we had this problem. Who knows would have happened otherise?&quot;</p>
<p>About 200 student protesters and parents blocked the main entrances to the stock exchange building, scaring off traders and bolsa officials before the opening bell. But then about 30 or 40 riot police cleared the way to a back door, allowing personnel to enter.</p>
<p>Electronic trading began on time but with barely any volume. When floor trading by open outcry finally began three hours later, stock prices soared.</p>
<p>Within minutes, the IPC index peaked at 3,432.13 points, setting a new intraday high, before gradually winding down in the afternoon.</p>
<p>While the Mexican bolsa was shut down, the Dow Jones industrial average was tumbling into negative territory and the peso, vulnerable because of sharply lower interest rates from Tuesday's primary Mexican Treasury bill auction, started losing ground on the dollar.</p>
<p>But the peso held firm, and market leader Telmex's ADRs charged forward, effectively coming to the bolsa's rescue, traders said.</p>
<p>Telmex ADRs closed 3/4 higher to 34-1/8. Telmex L shares, the largest issue on the bolsa, were up 32 centavos to 12.74 pesos ($1.70) and Telmex A shares were up 50 centavos to 12.70 pesos ($1.70).</p>
<p>Other Mexican ADRs weathered the bolsa shutdown and the falling Dow.</p>
<p>Construction firm Grupo Tribasa posted big gains for the second straight day, up 3/8 to 4-3/4. In Mexico, shares rose 5.45 percent to 17.40 pesos ($2.33).</p>
<p>Other ADRs like Televisa, down 1/4 to 31-1/8, closed lower but regained earlier lost ground.</p>
<p>Texel led all gainers in Mexico, closing up 8.57 percent or 30 centavos to 3.80 pesos (51 cents). Situr B shares gained 7.95 percent or seven centavos to 95 centavos (13 cents).</p>
<p>Grupo Marti topped the list of losers by falling 4.26 percent or 10 centavos to 2.25 pesos (30 cents). Femsa was off 3.16 percent or 75 centavos to 23 pesos ($3.08).</p>
<p>&quot;The setback (from the protest) served the market by giving investors a chance to see what the reaction (in New York) would be to the latest economic indicators and the lower interest rates,&quot; said Esteban Rojas, an analyst with the Akra brokerage firm.</p>
<p>But once the bolsa peaked near what some considered a resistance level of 3,436 points, investors took profits, in part because of the continuing woes of the Dow.</p>
<p>Volume was heavy at 126.28 million shares. Of 101 stocks traded, 44 gained and 27 lost.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
