<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4950" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton said ready to announce tobacco curbs.</title>
<headline>Clinton said ready to announce tobacco curbs.</headline>
<byline>Robert Trautman</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton is expected to announce on Friday a long awaited series of restrictions to try to curb the growing use of tobacco by young people, White House officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The curbs would range from banning cigarette vending machines to limiting cigarette sponsorship of sporting and entertainment events popular with young people.</p>
<p>Clinton last year endorsed a Food and Drug Administration finding recommendation that nicotine was a drug, paving the way for FDA regulation of tobacco.</p>
<p>The proposed restrictions would include a federal law banning sales of cigarettes to people under 18 years of age -- up to now only loosely enforced local laws have banned such sales.</p>
<p>The White House officials said Clinton's announcement &quot;depends on whether OMB's (Office of Management and Budget) review is completed by Friday. It's not at all clear it will be,&quot; said a senior official who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>The FDA's final recommendations to curb teen smoking were sent to the OMB last week and White House spokesman Mike McCurry said he could not rule out Clinton making the announcement on Friday if the OMB review is complete.</p>
<p>The rules are thought to be little different from those Clinton proposed a year ago in an effort to stop minors from starting smoking, an increasing phenomena.</p>
<p>FDA Commissioner David Kessler, a pediatrician, has said that smoking is a children's disease, with almost all smokers beginning when they are young.</p>
<p>His agency says that 3,000 youths begin smoking each day and that 1,000 of them end up dying because of it.</p>
<p>Other curbs would prohibit tobacco advertising within 1,000 feet of schools and playgrounds, the corporate sponsorship of events aimed at young people and stop the sales or giveaways of wearing apparel with tobacco company logos.</p>
<p>McCurry said: &quot;He (Clinton) made a decision a long time ago to seek a proposed rule that would accomplish his objective of protecting the health of American children and to protect them from the addictive qualities of tobacco.&quot;</p>
<p>He said a Friday announcement has been discussed but nothing was decided as yet. He said FDA officials were at the OMB on Wednesday discussing the final review.</p>
<p>Sen. Edward Kennedy, a Massachusetts Democrat long involved in national health issues, said Clinton's expected move would be &quot;very very bold and significant.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;(Tobacco) is a gateway drug. The gateway drug in all substance abuses is basically smoking,&quot; Kennedy said.</p>
<p>There was no immediate comment on the likely announcement from the Tobacco Institute, the tobacco company lobby.</p>
<p>John Banzhaf, executive director of the anti-smoking group Action on Smoking and Health, said of the likely announcement: &quot;I think it's great,&quot; adding it was something his group had sought for 15 years.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's high time that cigarettes were regulated like every other drug.&quot; Banzhaf said.&quot;</p>
<p>But he predicted that the issue would end up in court.</p>
<p>Tobacco companies filed suit last year challenging the FDA's right to regulate tobacco.  That suit is pending. And it was likely to file another suit to block imposition of new restrictions on tobacco sales and advertising.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
