<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4952" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Collectible even if you can't ride one.</title>
<headline>Collectible even if you can't ride one.</headline>
<byline>Philip Barbara</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vintage surfboards became hot collectibles in the late 1980s, their value rising as Baby Boomers paid up for a piece of lost youth and museum curators eyed their beauty and cultural symbolism.</p>
<p>Boards in top condition from around 1967 and earlier rose from garage sale giveaway prices to thousands of dollars today, especially those ridden by champions or hand-shaped by respected craftsmen.</p>
<p>The Malibu Perpetual Surfboard, made of redwood in 1948 in California, was retrieved from a wood pile in 1979 but is unavailable today at any price -- a bid of $25,000 having been turned down.</p>
<p>Prices accelerated quickly for about five years but leveled off around 1994, though the rarest boards and ones in mint condition continue to appreciate.</p>
<p>With the sport's popularity growing on coastlines around the world and with many boards set aside in collections, prices are destined to rise again, top collectors say.</p>
<p>&quot;There are not as many boards out there any more. But it seems that around Christmas and tax time I get pretty good deals because people sell some&quot; for needed cash, said Tim Dion, manager at Beckers Surf Shop in Malibu, Calif.</p>
<p>Surfboards evolved from wooden planks to high-performance boards. Duke Kahanamoku, a champion swimmer from Hawaii, helped popularise surfing using a redwood board in the early years of the century.</p>
<p>In the early 1950s, boards of balsa wood with a coat of fiberglass were introduced, and in the 1960s styrofoam and fiberglass boards became the standard.</p>
<p>Hollywood films and rock-n-roll in the 1960s spread tidings of a carefree surfing lifestyle that hooked surfers and non-surfers everywhere, and pioneers in the subculture became legends.</p>
<p>The names of Californians and Hawaiians who surfed or hand-crafted the best boards are now associated with prized collectibles: Bob Simmons, Phil Edwards, Mickey Dora, Greg Noll, Hobie Alter, Dale Velzy, John Peck, Lance Carson and Dewey Webber, to name a few.</p>
<p>In addition to rarity and condition, some makers are more desirable than others.</p>
<p>A board by Bob Simmons is a benchmark for any collection. He is credited with originating the idea of covering a balsa wood board with fiberglass in the late 1940s, and one in excellent condition should fetch $5,000 and up, according to Steve Pezman, editor of &quot;The Surfer's Journal.&quot;</p>
<p>Collector Pete Noble turned down $25,000 for the Malibu Perpetual Surfboard, the centrepiece of one of the premier collections. For potential investment, he suggests avoiding restored surfboards on which dents, known as &quot;dings,&quot; and damage from the sun have been repaired.</p>
<p>&quot;These are aesthetically beautiful but they've lost the originality that hard-core collectors treasure,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The prices of most production boards are more modest, between $300 and $1,000. Collectors stress that weathered, beat-up boards may not have appreciated very much, no matter who made or rode it.</p>
<p>Collectors with many beautiful boards display them on loan at restuarants, museums, surf shops and professional offices.</p>
<p>The hobby does not yet have a reliable, oft-updated price guide. Appraised value is pretty much agreed upon by a knowledgable buyer and seller, discussed through writing and by telephone. Auctions are rare, informal and advertised through the grapevine.</p>
<p>There are different opinions, too, as to what is desirable.</p>
<p>&quot;A brand's popularity may be localised depending on what beach you surfed at,&quot; Noble said. &quot;A board may be hot in Santa Cruz or another California community but surfers in Daytona (Fla.) or Cape Hatteras (N.C.) may not think much of it.&quot;</p>
<p>Around 1967 a shorter style of styrofoam and fiberglass board about six- to seven-feet long became popular, but they are not as coveted as the older nine-to-10-foot &quot;longboards&quot; used until then. Yet collectors say these shouldn't be dismissed because demand may grow as the supply of longboards diminishes.</p>
<p>Replicas of older boards are being made, primarily for display. Craftsmen Greg Noll -- a pioneer among big wave riders -- and Dale Velzy are turning out redwood longboards for $3,000 to $6,000, and Pat Curren is using imported balsa wood for longboards.</p>
<p>&quot;If you can't get your hands on a vintage board for possible investment, I'd buy a Velzy or Noll wooden board. They're absolutely gorgeous for wall hanging and as a potential investment,&quot; said Lee Gerachis, owner of Malibu's Surf Shop in Ocean City, Maryland, and a long-time collector.</p>
<p>One tip: Try not to overpay. If you're considering paying big money for a beautiful board, know what you are buying.</p>
<p>If you have a cared-for board you want appraised or you want to buy one, surf shops and surfboard collectors clubs are helpful. Magazines such as &quot;Surfer's Journal,&quot; &quot;Surfer&quot; and &quot;Longboard&quot; run informative features.</p>
<p>With the rise in value, counterfeiters are in the market.</p>
<p>When buying a board, ask for original order forms and sales receipts. One good way to judge a board's authenticity is to know a craftsman's logo, which have evolved over the years and thus indicate age. &quot;It takes a trained eye to judge a board,&quot; said Gerachis.</p>
<p>Said Pezman, &quot;A board's oral history should get passed along with it, but people are now trying to emulate other fields of collecting by placing a board's history in writing&quot; as documentation.</p>
<p>Greg Escalante, a trustee member of the former Laguna Beach, Calif., Art Museum, sees surfboards as examples of functional sculpture. &quot;They have a glowing art spirit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Prices will continue to rise, collectors say, as collectible boards attract a wider ownership and art historians recognise that surfboards express the soul of a golden moment in America.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
