<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4953" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tobacco companies fighting more bad news.</title>
<headline>Tobacco companies fighting more bad news.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Gail Appleson, Law Correspondent</p>
<p>The tobacco industry's troubles deepened Wednesday with the White House expected to endorse strict new regulations on cigarettes on Friday and jury deliberations about to start in a key smoking case.</p>
<p>The timing of the White House announcement could hardly be worse for the industry, which is still reeling from a surprise $750,000 damage award earlier this month.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Michigan became the 13th state to sue the industry Wednesday, and on Thursday an Indiana jury is to start weighing whether cigarette makers can be held liable for a smoker's addiction that allegedly led to his death.</p>
<p>Tobacco stocks were already tumbling Wednesday on concerns about the Indiana trial when White House officials said they expected President Bill Clinton to accept the new regulations from the Food and Drug Administration on Friday.</p>
<p>The rules were expected to be similar to those the FDA proposed about a year ago. Those included barring cigarette billboard advertising near schools and playgrounds and eliminating mail-order sales, vending machines, free samples, self-service displays and sales of fewer than 20 cigarettes.</p>
<p>The tobacco industry has sued, challenging the FDA's legal authority to regulate tobacco.</p>
<p>Closing arguments were set to begin Thursday morning at the Marion County Superior Court in Indianapolis.</p>
<p>The jury, which is expected to start deliberations in the afternoon, will be the first panel to decide a smoker's wrongful death case since the surprise verdict by a jury in Jacksonville, Fla., on Aug. 9.</p>
<p>If the industry loses the case it will strengthen the view among plaintiffs' lawyers and jury consultants that jurors' attitudes are changing and that panellists are more willing to hold cigarette companies liable for a smoker's addiction.</p>
<p>&quot;If the plaintiffs win (the Indiapolis case) the tobacco companies are really in the soup,&quot; said Richard Daynard, a Northeastern University law professor who chairs the Tobacco Products Liability Project in Boston.</p>
<p>The stock of Philip Morris Cos. Inc., the world's largest cigarette maker, tumbled $3.875 to $87.625 on the New York Stock Exchange and RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp., the owner of R.J. Reynolds Tobacco, fell $1.375 to $25.25.</p>
<p>Other tobacco company stocks also fell, and the drop helped pull the entire stock market lower, analysts said.</p>
<p>Although the uncertainty from the trial was hurting stocks, the Indianapolis jury, unlike the Florida panel, was not shown certain inflammatory internal tobacco documents.</p>
<p>Jury consultants said the documents, which concern the tobacco industry's knowledge of nicotine and addiction, angered the Florida jury. The papers convinced panellists that tobacco companies try to keep smokers hooked and that smoking was not a matter of individual choice, consultants said.</p>
<p>The tobacco industry maintains that nicotine is not addictive and denies that it manipulates the level of nicotine to keep smokers hooked.</p>
<p>Personal injury lawyers have not been overly optimistic about the Indianapolis case because the documents were not allowed in as evidence. The case involves Richard Rogers, an Indianapolis lawyer who died of lung cancer in 1987. Rogers, who was 52 when he died, began smoking as a young child by stealing his father's cigarette butts.</p>
<p>When the case first went to trial last year, the jury was split 5-1 on whether Rogers &quot;voluntarily&quot; incurred a known risk by smoking.</p>
<p>&quot;Heads, we win and it becomes a smashing victory. Tails we lose and nobody thought we would win all of these cases,&quot; said Daynard of the Tobacco Products Liability Project.</p>
<p>A loss in the jury case without admission of the key documents could have severe implications for an industry that is facing mounting legal attacks across the country.</p>
<p>Since Monday, Kansas, Arizona and Michigan have joined 10 other states that have filed lawsuits aimed at forcing tobacco companies to pay for Medicaid costs of smokers. Oklahoma is expected to file a similar case on Thursday that will bring the number of states to 14 by the end of the week.</p>
<p>New Jersey also plans to file a Medicaid suit in the near future and several other states including Hawaii, Utah and Arkansas are also seriously interested.</p>
<p>There are also more than 200 cases brought on behalf of individuals in the state of Florida alone and a growing number of class actions including a second-hand smoking case involving flight attendants set to go to trial next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
