<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4956" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Crude oil prices fall after inventory reports.</title>
<headline>Crude oil prices fall after inventory reports.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crude oil prices moved lower Wednesday after government and industry reports showed crude inventories increased this past week.</p>
<p>Coffee prices rose again as traders were concerned about tight deliverable supplies, and lumber prices closed sharply lower after setting contract highs early in the day.</p>
<p>The Commodity Research Bureau's index of 17 futures contracts closed down 0.81 at 249.84 points.</p>
<p>Crude oil traders at the New York Mercantile Exchange have been hit by a double dose of bearish news.</p>
<p>Late Tuesday the American Petroleum Institute (API) reported U.S. crude oil supplies increased 296,000 barrels during the week ended Aug. 16. Traders had expected a decrease. On Wednesday the government's Energy Information Administration (EIA) report showed an 1.8 million-barrel increase in crude inventories for the week.</p>
<p>Both increases in inventories were attributed to a jump in imports. The API report showed daily imports averaged nearly 8.78 million barrels vs. 8.18 million the previous week.</p>
<p>NYMEX crude oil for October delivery closed down 39 cents at $21.72 per barrel. September heating oil closed down 0.69 cent at 60.98 cents per gallon and September gasoline was down 0.89 cent at 63.12 cents per gallon.</p>
<p>Coffee prices at the New York Coffee, Sugar and Cocoa Exchange rose in reaction to exchange data that showed a tight supply of coffee registered for delivery against the September contract.</p>
<p>Delivery of physical coffee against the September contract begins Thursday and traders noted that September's open interest was still relatively high, the equivalent of 839,000 bags as of Aug. 20, compared with 34,516 bags available for delivery.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a typical tight stock situation,&quot; said Smith Barney analyst Walter Spilka.</p>
<p>He said a decline in U.S. certified coffee stocks this week underscored the shortage of nearby supplies. Exchange inventories dropped 6,259 132-pound bags in the week ended Aug. 16, to 34,516 bags, one of the lowest levels in 10 years.</p>
<p>Another 19,000 bags were pending certification for delivery, but traders and analysts said not all that was expected to meet Exchange approval.</p>
<p>CSCE September coffee rose 2.55 cents to 125.05 cents per pound.</p>
<p>Lumber prices closed lower at the Chicago Mercantile Exchange after setting a contract high early in the session of $395.30 per thousand board feet.</p>
<p>The September contract dropped nearly the $10 daily limit in late trading, but closed down $8.30 at $386.50 per thousand board feet.</p>
<p>Reports that demand in the cash market had slowed prompted much of the selling, traders said. Random Lengths, a private lumber market information service, quoted cash spruce at $412 per thousand board feet, up $1 from last Friday. Traders said a larger gain had been expected.</p>
<p>&quot;That is the first sign that we have seen in a month that cash may finally be slowing,&quot; said Neil Schmaedick, Smith Barney Forest Products analyst. &quot;There seems to be enough secondary wood around.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
