<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4959" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Ad legend Maurice Saatchi made lord.</title>
<headline>Ad legend Maurice Saatchi made lord.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Advertising force Maurice Saatchi was elevated to the House of Lords by Prime Minister John Major Wednesday in a move industry experts said would give marketing new respectability and influence.</p>
<p>&quot;We are delighted that someone so influential in advertising has been recognised. ... It also recognises the industry's important contribution as an economic force for the good,&quot; said Andrew Brown, director general of the Advertising Association, the industry's main trade group.</p>
<p>But Major's decision to honour Saatchi as well as public relations expert Peter Selwyn Gummer, both advisers to the ruling Conservative Party on its latest pre-election campaign, triggered a political storm.</p>
<p>Saatchi, who helped the Conservatives win four general elections in a row, is behind a much-vilified newspaper campaign this month which depicts opposition Labour Party leader Tony Blair with devillish red eyes.</p>
<p>The ad -- now under investigation by the Advertising Standards Authority -- is part of the Conservative's &quot;New Labour New Danger' offensive, which has shocked many by the ferocity of its attacks on the opposition.</p>
<p>Gummer is the brother of Environment Secretary John Gummer and chairman of the Shandwick public relations company.</p>
<p>He and Saatchi are among 14 people who will be made life peers, a honour that dies with the recipient, unlike heriditary peerages.</p>
<p>The Labour Party criticised Major for recognising two of the architects of the &quot;dirtiest&quot; campaign in modern politics, who it said were being promoted merely for aiding the Conservatives.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
