<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4966" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Old allies clash over S.African economy.</title>
<headline>Old allies clash over S.African economy.</headline>
<byline>Ben Hirschler</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two years after South Africa's first democratic elections, Nelson Mandela's African National Congress is attempting an economic policy U-turn, bringing it into conflict with old allies on the Left.</p>
<p>Gone is the language of the liberation struggle, with its talk of redistribution and nationalisation. Instead, the ANC is singing the benefits of budget cuts and privatisation.</p>
<p>Critics talk of a sell-out. But ANC pragmatists argue that South Africa has no choice if it wants to boost economic growth and cut crippling unemployment afflicting one-third of the work force.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Trevor Manuel laid down the new economic gospel in June -- and insists he will not be blown off course.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got to concentrate on ensuring that we can implement a programme that will evolve a different kind of economy in this country, one that absorbs labour, creates employment, deals with these issues differently,&quot; he said earlier this month.</p>
<p>His macroeconomic strategy sets clear targets for the next five years. The aim is to double economic growth to 6 percent and create 400,000 new jobs a year by the year 2000, while cutting the budget deficit from more than 5 percent of GDP this year to 4 percent next and 3 percent in 1999.</p>
<p>But trade union leaders have condemned the policy, which runs counter to their own demands for greater state involvement.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no way the government will succeed in simply pushing its framework down our throats,&quot; said Zwelinzima Vavi, assistant general secretary of the Congress of South African Trade Unions (Cosatu).</p>
<p>&quot;It is the entire framework which we wish to discuss. We are not simply seeking the amendment of minor details here and there, but a complete reassessment of their view of the role of the state in stimulating reconstruction and development.&quot;</p>
<p>Cosatu is a key partner, together with the South African Communist Party, in the triple alliance that swept Mandela to office -- and its tough words have triggered fears of a damaging clash.</p>
<p>The big showdown with the unions could well come over privatisation.</p>
<p>After months of dithering, during which privatisation was euphemistically labelled &quot;restructuring state assets,&quot; Mandela has finally laid down the law, declaring:</p>
<p>&quot;Privatization is the fundamental policy of the ANC and it is going to be implemented.&quot;</p>
<p>The prize for the government is great. Economists estimate it could, in theory, raise as much as 100 billion rand ($22 billion) from selling state concerns -- enough to cut government debt by a third.</p>
<p>It is already looking for a foreign partner to take a 25-30 percent chunk of telecommunications group Telkom, and recently appointed Hong Kong and Shanghai Bank to advise on other privatisation options.</p>
<p>Other candidates include South African Airways, the state airports company, government oil companies, a forestry business -- and possibly electricity generator Eskom.</p>
<p>The plans to sell the family silver have set alarm bells ringing among union members, who fear job cuts, triggering protest marches and strikes. Together with a rash of industrial action in the mines in recent months, analysts say this has only underscored South Africa's reputation for labour unrest.</p>
<p>Cosatu denies it has a blanket opposition to privatisation, but insists government must keep control of essential services.</p>
<p>&quot;We must look at what are the proposals on the table. Are those proposals saying the government must move out of the provision of the basic services and out of the productive sector? If that is the proposal, we will reject it,&quot; said general secretary Sam Shilowa.</p>
<p>Big business, meanwhile, formerly at odds with the ANC, suddenly finds itself on the same side.</p>
<p>Trevor Manuel and his macroeconomic strategy are the toast of Johannesburg board rooms. Instead of worrying about government policy, business leaders' concern nowadays is rather whether government has the political clout to implement it.</p>
<p>&quot;If (the ANC's) political allies are seen to be delaying or in any way undermining what the government has committed itself to in terms of its economic programme, then quite clearly there will be consequences,&quot; said South African Chamber of Business director general Raymond Parsons.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign markets and foreign investors, as well as South African investors, are watching the implementation of the macroeconomic strategy with great intensity.&quot;</p>
<p>Foreign investment is crucial to the new economic strategy.</p>
<p>Without it, South Africa will not build the new industry needed to drive growth, create jobs and give the unemployed a viable alternative to a life of crime.</p>
<p>So far, foreign firms have been slow to put their money into South African bricks and mortar. The recent pummelling of the rand on the foreign exchange markets suggests overseas investors still need to be persuaded that government will deliver on its economic promises.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
