<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4967" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Brief look at competing &quot;canal&quot; proposals.</title>
<headline>Brief look at competing &quot;canal&quot; proposals.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY</dateline>
<text>
<p>A growing list of countries are seeking to compete with the Panama Canal. Here's a brief look at the proposals in each country:</p>
<p>NICARAGUA</p>
<p>Canal Interoceanico de Nicaragua (CINN) proposes building new deep-water ports on the Atlantic and Pacific Coasts as well as a 234-mile (377-km) high-speed rail link, some of it through virgin rainforest.</p>
<p>It also is being billed as a regional project, placing within easy trucking distance the Pacific and Atlantic ports that Honduras and El Salvador, respectively, currently lack.</p>
<p>HONDURAS</p>
<p>Thomas Elder of the New Orleans-based Trans-World Traders consulting firm, proposes a continuous loop rail system between Trujillo on the Caribbean Sea and Amapala on the Pacific side's Gulf of Fonseca.</p>
<p>Trains would be electrically powered versions of the French fast train or Japanese bullet train powered by natural gas coming from a Gulf of Mexico pipeline. One drawback would be a probable dependence on development bank financing, although presidential adviser Roger Marin said earlier this month that &quot;we are confident we can go through with the project.&quot;</p>
<p>MEXICO</p>
<p>The current outdated rail line of 255 miles (410 km) between the two coasts is due for privatisnister Carlos Ruiz Sacristan said several foreign and national investors are interested in whipping it back to shape. Feasibility studies, though, are a long way off.</p>
<p>COLOMBIA</p>
<p>In May, President Ernesto Samper called for the construction of a canal across northwest Colombia. Opposition leaders deride it as nothing but a smokescreen aimed at drawing attention away from his many political problems.</p>
<p>Samper said there were 25 possible routes the canal could take from the Gulf of Uraba on the Caribbean coast to somewhere over the Serranna de los Altos mountains on the Pacific.</p>
<p>But cutting through those mountains would be expensive, if not impossible, and would partly destroy what scientists describe as one of the world's most important rainforests.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72603">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
