<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4970" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Newbridge stock soars on solid earnings.</title>
<headline>Newbridge stock soars on solid earnings.</headline>
<byline>Sarah Edmonds</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>The stock of Newbridge Networks Corp. soared Wednesday after the maker of computer network equipment laid to rest lingering investor doubts about its earnings by posting a 64 percent increase in first-quarter profit.</p>
<p>The Kanata, Ontario-based company on Tuesday said earnings rose to Canadian $60.8 million ($44.4 million), or C70 cents a share (51 cents), in its fiscal first quarter ended on July 28, from C$37.1 million ($26.9 million), or C44 cents a share (32 cents), in the 1995 quarter.</p>
<p>The profits beat consensus estimates by two U.S. cents a share, and made plain that warnings about the company's first-quarter earnings from two analysts last month were unjustified, some industry analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a quarter that if you were a bear on Newbridge, you would have a very hard time finding anything to complain about. It all looked great,&quot; said Robert MacLellan at Dillon Read in New York.</p>
<p>Warnings from analysts at brokerages UBS Securities and Needham &amp; Co. in July sent Newbridge's stock diving. It has since recovered some ground.</p>
<p>But the earnings report after the market closed on Tuesday brushed away any cobwebs of concern and sent the shares soaring C$13.45 to C$80.25 on the Toronto Stock Exchange and $10 to $58.375 on the New York Stock Exchange Wednesday.</p>
<p>Revenues jumped 46 percent to a record C$286 million ($208.1 million) in the quarter, from C$196 million ($143 million).</p>
<p>Cowen &amp; Co. analyst James Kedersha raised his 1996 and 1997 earnings estimates after the first-quarter report. He said he bumped his 1997 estimate 10 cents to $2.25 a share and his 1998 forecast 15 cents to $2.85 a share.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a lot of controversy about Newbridge over the past quarter and a number of analysts have either downgraded the stock or cast serious doubts on its ability to make the quarter,&quot; Kedersha said.</p>
<p>&quot;It turns out that they didn't just make the quarter but they beat it,&quot; he said, adding that orders were strong and the company had a positive balance sheet. &quot;Everything you could want was there.&quot;</p>
<p>Newbridge makes and markets hardware such as multiplexers and switches that corporate users need to link their computers into local-area (LANs) or wide-area networks (WANs).</p>
<p>J.P. Morgan said analyst William Rabin upgraded Newbridge to buy from market performer and raised his earnings estimates to $2.22 a share from $2 for 1997, which ends in April, and to $2.76 from $2.40 for fiscal 1988.</p>
<p>The stock fell from a year peak of C$102 in May to under C$57 in Toronto in late July after the first profit warning.</p>
<p>Newbridge said Tuesday that it was on track for another strong year, and that it planned to renew its stock repurchase plan. Under the renewed plan, it can buy up to 4 million common shares, or 4.7 percent of those outstanding, during the next 12 months.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
