<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4974" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Minimum wage, health bills include small business benefits.</title>
<headline>Minimum wage, health bills include small business benefits.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Fromartz</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton this week signed into law a host of measures that will change everything from how much you can sock away in a small business pension fund to how quickly you can write off a gas station.</p>
<p>While the headlines focused on the main news -- the 90 cent raise in the minimum wage to $5.15 an hour -- business owners, home-based workers, and employees of small companies should be aware of the details in these bills.</p>
<p>The White House said the &quot;Small Business Protection Act&quot; included some $22 billion in tax breaks for small businesses over 10 years, paid for in part by reimposing a 10 percent tax on airline tickets. A health insurance bill also included significant tax breaks for the self-employed.</p>
<p>Here are the major changes that affect small and home-based businesses:</p>
<p>-- Pension plans. The new law alters 401(k) plans for firms with less than 100 employees, creating incentives for small companies employing some 10 million workers to set up retirement plans.</p>
<p>In the absence of a pension plan, the most an owner or a worker could sock away tax-free was $2,000 in most cases -- the amount of an IRA contribution.</p>
<p>Under the new law, employees can contribute up to $6,000 a year to 401(k) plans. The law requires employers to match employee contributions dollar-for-dollar up to 3 percent of their workers' salaries or make a blanket 2-percent contribution for all workers.</p>
<p>Owners get a break in setting up the plan, for they will be able to save up to $6,000 a year for their own retirement fund regardless of employee participation. Previously, the amount an owner could put away in a company plan was limited by the amount lower-paid employees saved.</p>
<p>The new law also minimises the paper work for the new 401(k) retirement accounts, cutting costs faced by small firms.</p>
<p>Once employees enter a plan they become fully vested, so they can take the entire pot of savings with them, including company contributions, if they quit. Previously employees became vested in steps.</p>
<p>-- Retirement accounts for non-working spouses. Under the law, a non-working spouse can make a full $2,000 contribution to an Individual Retirement Account (IRA) in 1997. Couples in which only one person works are now limited to a total IRA contribution of $2,250 a year.</p>
<p>-- Equipment tax write off. This is a good break for anyone who wants to write off the full cost of an expensive purchase like a computer or machine in the year it was bought.</p>
<p>Currently, the ceiling is $17,500 a year. Under the new law the write-off will rise to $25,000 by the year 2003, if you spend less than $200,000 a year on equipment.</p>
<p>-- Deductible health insurance premiums for self-employed workers. Under the new health insurance law, the portion of health insurance premiums that can be deducted by self-employed workers rises to 40 percent next year from 30 percent currently. It then climbs to 45 percent by 1998, and after 2002 rises steadily to 80 percent in 2006.</p>
<p>-- Small company medical savings accounts. Companies with less than 50 employees will be able to set up tax-free accounts to pay for medical expenses, if the workers have only catastrophic insurance. This measure is being provided as a test to 750,000 workers.</p>
<p>-- Educational assistance. The wage bill reinstates the exclusion from income taxes of up to $5,250 for employer educational assistance. This tax benefit expired at the end of 1994 but the bill has reinstated it retroactively and extended it until May 31, 1997. Post-graduate work, however, would be excluded for courses starting after July 1, 1996.</p>
<p>-- Employer tax credit for hiring. Employers will get a tax break for hiring people in targeted groups most in need of jobs or with the least skills, including welfare and food stamp recipients, former felons and young adults from certain targeted communities. The break amounts to a 35 percent tax credit on the first $6,000 of first-year wages paid.</p>
<p>-- Depreciation. Owners of convenience stores and gas stations will now be able to depreciate the cost of building their stores and buying equipment over 15 years from the current rate of 39 years.</p>
<p>Questions or comments on the Newbiz column can be sent to sam.fromartz(at)reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150214">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
