<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4975" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hunting for tax gifts in this election year.</title>
<headline>Hunting for tax gifts in this election year.</headline>
<byline>Linda Stern</byline>
<text>
<p>WASHINGTON - Congress and the President like to play Santa Claus in election years. They find a Christmas tree bill, load it with ornamental treats and hand it to us on our way into the voting booths.</p>
<p>This year is a little bit different. This year the Easter bunny comes to mind: first you have to hunt for your goodies, which are hidden in funny-looking baskets like minimum wage and health insurance bills. But once you find them, they are no less sweet.</p>
<p>Here are some of the gifts our legislators have bestowed this year. Make the most of them!</p>
<p>-- Spousal IRAs. Your turn to stay home with the kids? If you are a nonworking spouse of a working spouse, you can put $2,000 in your own Individual Retirement Account starting in 1997. That's way better than the $250 current law allows.</p>
<p>-- Educational Assistance. If your boss provided dollars for diplomas last year, there's a good chance you paid taxes on them. The tax break that exempted educational assistance from taxable income had expired at the end of 1994. The new law extends it retroactively, but after June 30, 1996, money you receive for graduate school will no longer qualify.</p>
<p>To get back extra taxes you may have paid for 1995, ask your employer for an amended W-2 form. Then file a 1040X with the Internal Revenue Service. That's an amended tax return.</p>
<p>-- Medical Savings Accounts. These new babies are a huge gift to the self-employed and employees of small companies with high deductibles on their health insurance.</p>
<p>&quot;They may not be a giveaway, but they are a tremendous benefit for people who can afford them,&quot; said Tom Ochsenshlager, a tax expert with the accounting firm of Grant Thornton.</p>
<p>Here's how the accounts will work: Set one up and you can feed it with pretax dollars up to 65 percent of your health insurance deductible (up to $1,463) each year. You can use the money to pay for health care expenses, including meeting your deductible, paying long-term care insurance premiums or premiums for special health coverage after you leave a job.</p>
<p>There are some wrinkles that make this better than the employer-sponsored health care savings account you may already have. In the first place, you don't have to use the money or lose it: If you have a particularly healthy year you can just carry forward the money until you have to use it.</p>
<p>If you take it out for other purposes, there's tax to pay plus a 15 percent penalty tax. But if you wait until you are 65, (that age will rise with the Social Security retirement age), you can withdraw what's left in your account without the penalty tax. It's like an extra IRA.</p>
<p>What if you don't want to tie up that money? The legislation gives you until your tax return is due to feed your account for a given year. So you could set up an account in January 1997 and wait until April 15, 1998, to fully fund it. Once 1997 is a done deal, you can add up the amount you've spent and put exactly that in your MSA. Tax deductible health care!</p>
<p>-- Tax-free tuition. Some states sell special education bonds and prepaid tuition programmes that will be able to accumulate earnings tax-free. Find out if your state has such a programme. If your kids are young enough to benefit from years of tax-free earnings before the tuition comes due, press your state legislators to start a plan.</p>
<p>-- Rich retirees rejoice! Have you socked away so much in your retirement plans that your annual withdrawals top $150,000? Forget that 15 percent excess distribution tax, at least for the next few years. In 1997, 1998 and 1999, you can take as much as you want out without paying it. Leave all that money to your heirs and they'll still have to pay an excise estate tax on it. So enjoy it while you can.</p>
<p>-- Or let it accumulate. Previous rules held that workers had to start emptying their 401(k) retirement plans by April of the year following the year in which they turned 70-1/2. The new law says that if you're still working you don't have to take those distributions, said Howard Golden, who tracked these bills for benefit consulting company Kwasha Lipton.</p>
<p>-- A bit of a home office break. Home office workers were hoping for a complete liberalisation of the rules. They didn't get it. But they did get back a piece of the writeoff: if your home office is your only office and you use it to store inventory, you can write it off even if you conduct all of your business away from your home office.</p>
<p>-- And one more health insurance break for the self-employed. This year you can deduct 30 percent of your health insurance premiums, and 40 percent next year. From 1998 through 2002, take 45 percent.</p>
<p>Assuming there's no change in status (either yours or the law's) between now and then, you can ratchet up your deduction in every year after that: 50 percent in 2003, 60 percent in 2004, 70 percent in 2005 and 80 percent in 2006.</p>
<p>You can Email Linda Stern at 72160.1546(at)compuserve.com or write to her care of Reuters, Suite 410, 1333 H St., NW, Washington, DC 20005. She regrets she cannot answer letters individually but will cover questions in upcoming columns.</p>
<p>(EDITORS: Linda Stern is a freelance writer who covers personal finance issues for Reuters. Any opinions in the column are solely those of Ms. Stern.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
