<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4979" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe public servants call off strike.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe public servants call off strike.</headline>
<byline>Emelia Sithole</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwean civil servants on Wednesday called off a strike that partially paralysed some critical essential services, the state news agency ZIANA said.</p>
<p>The agency quoted Palmer Chinosengwa, an executive member of the Public Service Association (PSA) union, as saying the strike over pay was suspended following an agreement by the government to discuss their grievances.</p>
<p>The civil servants had defied a government order to return to work by Wednesday morning, with their leaders saying they would only do so if the government committed to addressing the workers' complaints.</p>
<p>Chinosengwa urged all strikers to return to work on Thursday, but added they might walk out again if negotiations with the government scheduled for Thursday proved unsatisfactory.</p>
<p>&quot;The strike achieved something because we managed to force government to come to a roundtable and look critically at our grievances,&quot; Chinosengwa said.</p>
<p>PSA officials were unavailable for an independent confirmation of the report. However, state radio said two PSA leaders arrested by secret police earlier in the day had been freed.</p>
<p>Police spokesman Dave Njagu said the two, PSA executive secretary John Makoni and his assistant Charles Chiviru, were arrested while organising civil servants for a protest march at a government building.</p>
<p>&quot;The two men were picked up for forcing people to join the strike and the police are now looking into the charges,&quot; Njagu said.</p>
<p>The PSA called the strike -- which started on Tuesday and is a rare action by  civil servants -- to press demands for wage rises of around 30 percent and said increases of between three to eight percent recently awarded by the government were unacceptable.</p>
<p>Public Service, Labour and Social Welfare Minister Florence Chitauro declared the strike illegal, saying those who did not return to work by Wednesday would be sacked.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
