<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4980" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks weaken on profit-taking and lower bonds.</title>
<headline>Stocks weaken on profit-taking and lower bonds.</headline>
<byline>Betty Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stock prices fell in sluggish trading Wednesday as the market was pressured by profit-taking and a slump in bonds.</p>
<p>At 1 p.m. EDT, the Dow Jones industrial average was down 35.14 points at 5,686.12. In the broader market, declining issues led advances 12-8 on moderate trading of 202 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index was off 3.31 points at 1,121.36, and the American Stock Exchange index lost 1.46 at 557.83.</p>
<p>&quot;I suspect we'll remain in drifting, low volume, low volatility activity until after Labour Day (Sept. 2) and after that the focus will be on third-quarter earnings and preannouncements,&quot; said Ricky Harrington, a technical analyst at Interstate/Johnson Lane.</p>
<p>The 30-stock Dow index drew profit-taking after its 56-point climb over the past three trading sessions.</p>
<p>The selling pressure was also precipitated by a drop in one of its components, Philip Morris, which fell 1-7/8 points to 89-5/8 as another liability challenge to the tobacco industry headed to an Indiana court decision. The case was expected to be handed to the jury by the end of this week.</p>
<p>Investors are mindful of the selling pressure in Philip Morris shares following an Aug. 8 Florida jury ruling against the industry in a suit filed by a smoker.</p>
<p>&quot;The movement for lawsuits and the possibility of suits being lost is a genuine concern,&quot; Harrington said. &quot;It can be a negative for quite some time.&quot;</p>
<p>Among other tobacco shares, RJR Nabisco, parent of R.J. Reynolds Tobacco, fell 5/8 to 25-7/8, smokeless tobacco maker UST Inc. fell 3/4 to 31 and Loews slipped 1/4 to 77-5/8.</p>
<p>Overall market activity remained relatively quiet.</p>
<p>&quot;This is just nervous investors getting out of stocks in a thin market,&quot; said Marty Kearney, a trader at PTI Securities.</p>
<p>Frank Gretz, a technical analyst at Shields &amp; Co. said, &quot;Today is just a little rest. We were due for a correction since the market was a little overbought. People were complacent on what the Fed would do.&quot;</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the Federal Reserve, as widely expected, left interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>In the bond market, the Treasury's key 30-year bond lost 13/32 and its yield rose to 6.83 percent from 6.80 percent at Tuesday's close.</p>
<p>Among individual stocks, Newbridge Networks jumped 7-3/4 to 56-1/8 after the company reported upbeat results for the latest quarter.</p>
<p>Rexene Corp.fell 2-1/8 to 10-5/8 after privately-held Huntsman Corp. announced late Tuesday that it was withdrawing its unsolicited $460 million bid for the chemical firm.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
