<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4981" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Campbell to cut staff, sell Swanson -- report.</title>
<headline>Campbell to cut staff, sell Swanson -- report.</headline>
<dateline>CAMDEN, N.J.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Campbell Soup Co. is planning to cut its headquarters staff of 1,500, shut one of four major soup plants and divest some brand names, including Swanson frozen foods, the Philadelphia Inquirer reported Wednesday.</p>
<p>A Campbell spokesman called the newspaper report speculative but did not deny it, which cited company sources and Wall Street analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;We are engaged in a process to unlock resources to grow our company,&quot; said Campbell spokesman Jerry Buckley. He acknowledged that Campbell has commissioned a study of operations by the management consulting firm Coopers &amp; Lybrand.</p>
<p>&quot;We use consultants all the time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Buckley also said there is no deadline for the study and that no decisions are likely to be made soon.</p>
<p>Since David Johnson became Campbell's chief executive, the company has been retreating from the paternal interest in the city of Camden, where it was founded a century ago by the Dorrance family.</p>
<p>Johnson closed the company's original soup plant, costing Camden 900 jobs as part of a company-wide restructuring that cut 11,000 jobs.</p>
<p>Campbell has also changed the terms of its commitment to build a new headquarters building on the banks of the Delaware River, a key ingredient in the city's planned economic recovery.</p>
<p>Instead, the company offered to be the prime tenant for any developer willing to take the risk. Two expressed interest, but neither was able to obtain financing.</p>
<p>Last year Campbell sold its Mrs. Paul's frozen fish subsidiary.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAMDEN, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
