<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4985" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London precious metals drift, seek impetus.</title>
<headline>London precious metals drift, seek impetus.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold and silver shuffled in recent price ranges on Wednesday but showed potential to try to clear tough price barriers just ahead, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;(Gold) may this week re-try $388-$390 (an ounce). There's resistance there, but maybe not as much as people think. We've already been there recently,&quot; a dealer said, referring to gold's failed attempt to clear the $390 level this month.</p>
<p>Bullion closed at $387.25, down $0.30 from Monday's close.</p>
<p>Dealers attributed a slight easing of the precious metals to an absence of follow-through buying after a brisk rally by silver earlier in the week.</p>
<p>Gold had largely neglected responding in kind to silver's gains, managing only to edge up a bit.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw gold firm up a bit on back of the Monday rally in silver, but everyone is looking for follow-through. There's a danger it could drift back to where it started,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Silver ended a touch lower at $5.20 an ounce, off two cents.</p>
<p>Several dealers said they were looking for silver to make a break to around $5.30 an ounce, perhaps as soon as this week. But others were less enthusiastic.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is very slow. Everyone's waiting for some reason to do something,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Analysts cautioned it would run into layers of selling there after being in a downtrend for most of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;Silver needs help from gold now that it has broken above the $5.15 area,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;But stock markets are doing well and any sign interest rates are staying the same or going down is good for the whites (silver, platinum and palladium) on an industrial basis.&quot;</p>
<p>Platinum, like silver, eased slightly to finish at $399.00 an ounce, down $0.30. Its sister metal palladium closed just $0.10 lower at $125.50 after edging up from a tumble to 2-1/2 year lows earlier in the week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
