<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4987" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Unnerved German shares drop before Buba meeting.</title>
<headline>Unnerved German shares drop before Buba meeting.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares dropped on Wednesday after the closely-watched Ifo business climate index jumped in July, undermining hopes for a cut in Germany's securities repurchase rate on Thursday.</p>
<p>The blue-chip DAX index ended floor dealings down 16.52 points, or 0.65 percent, at 2,543.74 points. Shares extended their losses in the post-bourse electronic session so that the IBIS DAX index closed at 2,534.44.</p>
<p>Prices had taken an instant dip after the early morning Ifo index report showed a rise to 94.1 in July from June's 90.4, far exceeding expectations and indicating a level of business confidence that could stall any German rate cut.</p>
<p>All eyes will be on the Bundesbank's council meeting on Thursday. Dealers said there were still hopes for a repo rate cut and warned of a knee-jerk downward reaction should the German central bank fail to act.</p>
<p>&quot;The Ifo is of course negative but if I had to flip a coin I would still say a move is likely,&quot; said a Frankfurt trader.</p>
<p>A slew of disappointing corporate earnings reports also hurt the market.</p>
<p>Construction group Philipp Holzmann AG slumped 3.2 percent to 360 marks after it reported an 11.8 percent drop in output for the first six months of the year and said it expected a negative operating result for 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;We had expected a flat output number,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Diversified utility group Viag AG drifted lower to end IBIS down 6.85 marks at 562.50 marks amid mild disappointment at its report Tuesday night of a 21 percent drop in first-half pre-tax profit -- the lower end of expectations.</p>
<p>Steel and engineering group Fried. Krupp AG Hoesch-Krupp also dropped nearly two percent to 215.90 marks after predicting a difficult second half, which dealers said was interpreted as a profit warning.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
