<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4988" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Toro forms three-person management team.</title>
<headline>Toro forms three-person management team.</headline>
<dateline>BLOOMINGTON, Minn.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toro Co., the lawn products maker, said Wednesday it named a three-person management team that will be jointly accountable for the company's business.</p>
<p>&quot;Our strategy is to reconfigure the office of president and strengthen our company for a new way of doing business the rest of this decade and into the 21st century,&quot; said Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Kendrick Melrose.</p>
<p>Toro, which has been searching for a president since former President David Morris left the company last November, said the board of directors modified Melrose's CEO succession and created a new approach that would align business units and position Toro for greater customer responsiveness.</p>
<p>The new team will be comprised of two newly created group vice president positions and Melrose.</p>
<p>&quot;These two group vice presidents and I will be responsible for overseeing the development and implementation of Toro's business strategies and plans,&quot; Melrose said.</p>
<p>J. David McIntosh, vice president and general manager of Toro's consumer division, will become one of the group vice presidents. The other is Charles Lounsbury, vice president, distribution, parts, recycling equipment and corporate strategic planning.</p>
<p>Toro's stock slipped 12.5 cents to $31.375 in morning trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BLOOMINGTON, Minn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
