<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4989" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>Zimbabwe: Zimbabwe strikers defy order to return to work.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe strikers defy order to return to work.</headline>
<byline>Cris Chinaka</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwean civil servants defied on Wednesday a government order to end a rare strike over pay, leaving some critical essential services partially paralysed.</p>
<p>Tension rose among the striking workers during the day amid rumours that some Public Service Association (PSA) union leaders, including its influential executive secretary John Makoni, had been arrested by Zimbabwe's feared secret police.</p>
<p>Police spokesmen were unavailable for immediate comment, but PSA officials said they were definite their colleagues were in police custody.</p>
<p>Earlier, Makoni had told reporters that &quot;many&quot; of the southern African state's 180,000 civil servants would continue the strike that began on Tuesday and left only senior officials at work.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not changed our stance. Our position is still that we will only return to work once there is some commitment that the PSC (Public Services Commission) and ministry of public service, labour and social service will address our grievances,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the capital Harare, thousands of workers marched, sang and danced mostly around government offices and in a central city park, vowing only promises of higher pay would take them off the streets. Dozens of police kept a wary eye on the crowd.</p>
<p>Elsewhere around the country, state media reported that &quot;many workers&quot; were demonstrating, and that at least two provincial governors had been booed off the stage after attempts to persuade workers to return to work.</p>
<p>The PSA called the strike to press demands for wage rises of around 30 percent and said increases of between three to eight percent recently awarded by the government were unacceptable.</p>
<p>Local media reports said thousands of government employees were milling around their work places despite calls on Tuesday by Public Service, Labour and Social Welfare Minister Florence Chitauro to report to work.</p>
<p>Chitauro said the strike was illegal and those who did not return to work would be dismissed.</p>
<p>State hospitals were handling only critical cases and offering rudimentary services in the general wards, using senior nurses, army medical personnel and the Red Cross nurses, with thousands of their own nurses out on strike.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
