<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4992" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia unfazed by sanctions talk over Iran deal.</title>
<headline>Malaysia unfazed by sanctions talk over Iran deal.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad shrugged off on Wednesday the possibility of U.S. sanctions after the state oil company Petronas agreed to buy into an Iranian oil field.</p>
<p>&quot;We know the general feelings of the U.S.,&quot; he said in reply to questions from reporters. &quot;We are for working with the U.S. in certain matters, and where we disagree, we will not work with them.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We feel we have the right to make our own national decision,&quot; Mahathir said in the first official comment on the Iranian deal.</p>
<p>The French oil group Total SA on Monday said Petronas had taken a 30 percent stake in Iran's Sirri A and E fields through its Carigali subsidiary, in a deal approved by Iranian authorities. Petronas has declined comment on the reports.</p>
<p>The announcement by Total ended a search of more than a year for partners in the $600 million project and came two weeks after U.S. President Bill Clinton signed a bill which would punish foreign firms that invest $40 million or more annually in Iran's or Libya's energy sector.</p>
<p>Mahathir said the United States did not try to dissuade Malaysia from making the deal. &quot;Not that I'm aware of,&quot; he said when asked if there was any pressure from Washington. &quot;The matter didn't come to us.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Malaysia was opposed to unilateral pressures for sanctions against &quot;rogue countries&quot;.</p>
<p>Mahathir, taking a sarcastic tone, said: &quot;What we should do, really, is to have an international court to decide which country's citizens should starve to death. Countries should be labelled rogue countries and therefore their peoples should be starved to death. And when the World Court says we should starve all Iranians, then we will comply.&quot;</p>
<p>An Iranian official told Reuters earlier this week that Petronas sealed the deal before the new U.S. sanctions law was signed by Clinton.</p>
<p>Washington accuses Iran of sponsoring terrorism and seeking to develop nuclear weapons. Tehran denies both charges.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
