<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4997" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain aims to eliminate smog within 10 years.</title>
<headline>Britain aims to eliminate smog within 10 years.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The British government on Wednesday unveiled what it called the first comprehensive national air quality strategy in Europe with the aim of eliminating smog by the year 2005.</p>
<p>Under the new measures, authorities could close off parts of cities and stop cars if pollution gets too high.</p>
<p>Environment Secretary John Gummer announced targets for major cuts in the level of eight key pollutants ranging from benzene to ozone, which a consultation paper drawn up by his department blames for hundreds of premature deaths every year.</p>
<p>&quot;My aim is that in the first decade of the next century, children will begin to say to their parents &quot;what was smog?',&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;If we can do that, then we have made a major improvement to the environment and to the nation.&quot;</p>
<p>Speaking during a week in which record high temperatures have sent pollution levels soaring in London, Gummer insisted that British air quality had improved greatly from the 1950s and 1960s when heavy industry belched out smoke from factories across the land.</p>
<p>Improvements to industrial processes and to vehicle emissions already under way and the adoption of new European Union standards would bring further improvements -- but in many cases not enough to achieve the targets he now proposes.</p>
<p>So the government was planning a further crackdown on vehicle and industrial emissions, and was considering giving local councils radical new powers.</p>
<p>These could include the authority to close parts of cities temporarily to vehicles where pollution levels were too high, and to stop cars and trucks suspected of exceeding emission norms.</p>
<p>&quot;If we can deal with the 10-20 percent of cars that represent the worst cases of pollution, we can cut vehicle emissions out of all proportion,&quot; Gummer said.</p>
<p>He said the government did not plan to force people to give up their cars. But he wanted to see towns planned so that people could choose to have no car, or to reduce the number of cars in their household, without making a major sacrifice.</p>
<p>His plans were given a cautious welcome by environmental groups, but political opponents said the recognition of the need to change planning and transport policies came after 17 years in which the ruling Conservatives had supported the car culture.</p>
<p>&quot;The UK is now the most car-dependent country in Europe,&quot; the opposition Labour Party said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;This document, which has been trailed as evidence of new government concern about our environment, is in fact a remarkable admission of failure.&quot;</p>
<p>Two reports published on Tuesday warned of the dangers to Britons from pollution agents for which motor vehicles are largely responsible.</p>
<p>The British Lung Foundation published research showing even healthy people were in danger of suffering inflammation of the airways when exposed to the levels of low-level ozone common in summer in traffic-clogged streets.</p>
<p>The minority Liberal Democrat party released a research paper showing asthma has increased four-fold in the past 30 years and blaming the rise on increased traffic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
