<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="4998" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India minister hopes phone licences will not be hit.</title>
<headline>India minister hopes phone licences will not be hit.</headline>
<byline>Hari Ramachandran</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Finance Minister P. Chidambaram said on Wednesday he hoped an unfolding corruption scandal involving a former minister would not stall an ambitious telephone privatisation programme.</p>
<p>Federal police have filed a corruption case against former communications minister Sukh Ram, who oversaw the telephone privatisation programme until the Congress party was defeated in general elections in April and May.</p>
<p>No charges have been laid, despite the filing by the Central Bureau of Investigation (CBI).</p>
<p>Last week, CBI agents recovered more than $1 million in cash during a raid on two of Sukh Ram's homes. A senior Department of Telecommunications civil servant has been arrested.</p>
<p>Ashok Mitra of the Communist Party of India-Marxist (CPI-M) told Reuters on Wednesday that he had written to Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda asking for the suspension of all telecommunications licences granted during Sukh Ram's tenure.</p>
<p>Under India's telephone privatisation programme, the previous Congress government awarded licences to dozens of private joint ventures, involving Indian and foreign companies, to operate cellular and basic services.</p>
<p>A fourth round of bidding to grant basic service licences in remaining zones has not yet been scheduled.</p>
<p>&quot;I sincerely hope that none of the earlier decisions will be reconsidered because of revelations made now,&quot; Chidambaram told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope that those who have been given licences will move forward to implement those licences.&quot;</p>
<p>The minister said he was not aware of any impact from the suspected scandal on the privatisation process. &quot;But I hope that the process will not be stalled,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said the liberalisation of the telecommunications sector was high on the 13-party United Front government's agenda and it would ensure that the process moved forward.</p>
<p>&quot;The process of liberalisation in the telecommunications sector and introduction of private investments in the basic telecommunications services must go forward and I am confident will go forward,&quot; Chidambaram said.</p>
<p>Sukh Ram's whereabouts were still a mystery on Wednesday, five days after the CBI raided his homes.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said the Deve Gowda government was trying to remove the perception of corruption, which was one of the reasons that led to the defeat of the previous government.</p>
<p>&quot;We want it (corruption) to be minimised if not totally eliminated. But sometimes I am afraid some of these traders also encourage and feed corruption,&quot; Chidambaram said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
