<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5001" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian government calms voters over budget.</title>
<headline>Australian government calms voters over budget.</headline>
<byline>Terry Friel</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's new conservative government on Wednesday launched a campaign blitz to sell its deficit-slashing budget and calm community fears after two days of violent protests against spending cuts.</p>
<p>As workers cleaned up after rioting at parliament house, Treasurer Peter Costello said his budget, slashing spending by almost A$4.0 billion (US$3.1 billion), would repair the structure of the economy, put it on the path to prosperity into the next century and deliver on key election pldeges.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no smoke and mirrors in these accounts -- we have come clean with the Australian people,&quot; Costello said in the traditional post-budget address to the National Press Club.</p>
<p>After two days of clashes between police and demonstrators protesting against the spending cuts, the streets of the capital were quiet on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But the long-foreshadowed massive spending cuts triggered strong criticism from the Labor opposition, unions, students, Aborigines, conservationists, welfare and community groups.</p>
<p>About 150 protesting Aborigines attacked police with bricks, bottles and stakes near parliament house on Tuesday as Costello prepared to deliver the budget for the year to June 30, 1997.</p>
<p>On Monday, rioters stormed parliament house and clashed with police equipped with riot gear during a two-hour confrontation.</p>
<p>Costello's budget, the first by a conservative government in 14 years, halved the underlying deficit to A$5.6 billion in 1996/97 from A$10.3 billion in 1995/96.</p>
<p>The tough measures paid early dividends for the Liberal-National government in the financial markets.</p>
<p>After a mixed initial reaction, confidence returned and the Australian dollar rose and bond yields tumbled as markets became increasingly confident the government's debt reduction strategy would yield economic benefits, including lower interest rates.</p>
<p>Ratings agency Standard and Poor's Corp on Wednesday revised its outlook for Australia's short-term currency rating to positive from stable.</p>
<p>Costello and Prime Minister John Howard embarked on a flurry of media appearances on Wednesday to push the budget's merits and reassure voters the cuts were not as bad as critics had claimed.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a reformist government, this is a government which is building for the future, this is a government which is repairing Australia's finances for the next century,&quot; Costello said.</p>
<p>Parliament appears almost certain to pass the bulk of the budget, despite criticism by the opposition and minor parties.</p>
<p>Labor opposition treasury spokesman Gareth Evans said Labor would seek only minor changes to the budget when it comes before the upper house, the Senate, where the government does not have a majority.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want to be taken for a moment to suggest that the budget will survive intact,&quot; Evans told Reuters Financial Television in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;I am saying that it is a reasonable anticipation that the overall shape of the budget and its general flavour will survive,&quot; Evans said.</p>
<p>Despite its landslide win in the March national election which ended 13 years of Labor rule, the new government needs the support of at least two non-government senators in the 76-seat upper house to pass legislation.</p>
<p>(A$1 = US$0.79)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
