<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5007" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Shakespeare's Globe stages comeback, 400 years on.</title>
<headline>Shakespeare's Globe stages comeback, 400 years on.</headline>
<byline>Merissa Marr</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>London's new Globe Theatre, a faithful replica of the 20-sided arena where Shakespeare's finest works were first performed 400 years ago, staged its first performance before a packed house on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>The audience hissed, booed, groaned and roared with laughter throughout the 2 1/2-hour performance of &quot;The Two Gentlemen of Verona&quot;, one of Shakespeare's lesser-known plays.</p>
<p>&quot;It was live, it was brilliant, human and passionate. It wasn't stilted in any way,&quot; said Shauna Kanter, a theatre-goer from New York.</p>
<p>The theatre, partly open to the elements, was the dream of American actor-director Sam Wanamaker, who died of cancer in 1993 just as the wood-and-thatch framework was being put in place.</p>
<p>After a campaign lasting more than a quarter of a century, the 30 million pound ($46 million) arena on the south bank of the River Thames opened its doors for its first sell-out public season after a 350-year silence.</p>
<p>The audience, many of them clustered around the stage, replicated the behaviour of their less restrained Elizabethan predecessors by heckling actors during the performance.</p>
<p>But the onlookers rewarded the cast with cheers, encores and a standing ovation once the comedy had ended.</p>
<p>&quot;When you were in there, you felt like you were part of what was going on. The actors and the audience were working together,&quot; said actor Gary Taylor. &quot;It was so exciting.&quot;</p>
<p>The original Globe, situated 300 yards (metres) away from the current site, burned down in 1613.</p>
<p>Wanamaker's aim was to recreate, as far as possible, the conditions that Shakespeare's actors worked under in the 16th and 17th centuries.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm giddy! It felt like being 400 years back in time,&quot; said Rebecca Jones, a school teacher from Richmond, Va.</p>
<p>But although Wednesday's production went a long way to restoring Shakespearian authenticity, it departed drastically from some of the bard's traditions.</p>
<p>Gone were the flamboyant Elizabethan costumes, since the opening night's comedy was set in modern-day Italy with actors donning a mixture of colourful suits, sunglasses and trainers.</p>
<p>The cast included women and black actors, both unheard of in Shakespeare's day. The theatre rented out raincoats as well as cushions for the hard seats, but the skies stayed clear.</p>
<p>Although the theatre lies directly under the flight path of planes heading for London's Heathrow airport, the noise of jets overhead failed to dampen the actors' delivery.</p>
<p>The Globe has not yet been finished and the comedy was performed on a temporary platform to ensure the stage was aligned correctly before being set in oak.</p>
<p>The official opening night will take place on Saturday, although the theatre's official gala opening is 10 months away.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
