<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5011" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London rail unions split over &quot;tube' pay deal.</title>
<headline>London rail unions split over &quot;tube' pay deal.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>London underground train drivers were split on Wednesday over a pay and working-hours deal, with one union voting to accept the package while another rejected it and pledged to continue strike action.</p>
<p>Members of the Aslef union voted 60 percent in favour of the deal offered by the management of the underground network. Members of the Rail, Maritime and Transport union (RMT) voted by nearly four to one against it and said they would stage 24-hour strikes next Friday and Tuesday.</p>
<p>Britain has been hit by a series of strikes this summer. Postal workers, some firemen and overground train drivers are either taking or planning strike action.</p>
<p>The London underground drivers have been offered a 35-hour week in 1998, down from 38.5 hours now. But this would be paid for by an effective cut in pay, with annual wage rises below the rate of inflation over three years.</p>
<p>RMT leaders campaigned for a &quot;no&quot; vote.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, we did say we would moderate the cash claims to get real time off from the job, but this is daylight robbery,&quot; the RMT said in a leaflet to members.</p>
<p>The two unions paralysed the underground system four times this summer but called off a 24-hour stoppage due on  August 13 while the workforce was consulted on the latest offer.</p>
<p>The RMT represents around 900 of the 2,200 drivers on the underground. Aslef organises the rest.</p>
<p>The RMT's 24-hour tube stoppages on Friday and Tuesday will ensure disruption to the capital's transport system either side of a long holiday weekend.</p>
<p>Other RMT members belonging to seven regional train operating companies will also be on strike on August 23 and 27. One of them, North London Railways, runs overland services to and from London, which will add to the chaos.</p>
<p>RMT called for further talks with London underground management, saying only &quot;details&quot; stood in the way of a settlement. The below-inflation rises were &quot;the main sticking point&quot;, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
