<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5017" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: &quot;Break a leg&quot; brings bad luck to Globe actor.</title>
<headline>&quot;Break a leg&quot; brings bad luck to Globe actor.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The theatrical enjoinder to &quot;break a leg&quot; brought no luck to Shakespearian actor George Innes -- who broke one of his on stage on Tuesday night during the first public performance at London's newest theatre, the Globe.</p>
<p>Innes landed badly as he climbed down a rope ladder onto the stage at the Globe, a replica of the 16th century theatre where William Shakespeare's plays were first performed.</p>
<p>Actors traditionally say &quot;break a leg&quot; to one another before a performance instead of &quot;good luck,&quot; which they consider unlucky.</p>
<p>The actor at first tried to carry on in his dual roles as Thurio and Antonio in Shakespeare's &quot;Two Gentleman of Verona&quot; but the performance had to be halted once it became clear he was badly injured, a spokeswoman for the theatre said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know if anyone said &quot;break a leg' to George, but it's curious, isn't it,&quot; the Globe's Artistic Director Mark Rylance told London's Evening Standard newspaper.</p>
<p>The reconstructed Globe will open officially in June 1997.</p>
<p>Tuesday night's performance was a dress rehearsal in front of more than 1,000 people on the eve of what the Globe is calling its &quot;prologue season&quot;.</p>
<p>Innes' roles will be filled by other members of the cast, the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>The 20-sided theatre, built from wood and thatch and open to the elements, has been built just yards (metres) from the site of the original Globe theatre which Shakespeare part-owned.</p>
<p>The original was destroyed by a fire set off by a stage cannon in 1613. It was rebuilt a year later, closed by the Puritans in 1642 and dismantled two years later.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
