<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5021" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: &quot;Lord' Saatchi adds nobility to British marketing.</title>
<headline>&quot;Lord' Saatchi adds nobility to British marketing.</headline>
<byline>Paul Keller</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The elevation of advertising legend Maurice Saatchi to Britain's House of Lords will add new respectability and influence to the marketing sector, industry experts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are delighted that someone so influential in advertising has been recognised...It also recognises the industry's important contribution as an economic force for the good,&quot; said Andrew Brown, director general of the Advertising Association, the industry's main trade body.</p>
<p>But Prime Minister John Major's decision to honour Saatchi as well as public relations expert Peter Selwyn Gummer, both advisers to the ruling Conservative Party on its latest pre-election campaign, has sparked a political storm.</p>
<p>Saatchi, the advertising guru who helped the Conservatives to win four successive general elections, is behind a much-vilified newspaper campaign this month which depicts Opposition leader Tony Blair with devilish red eyes. The ad -- now under investigation by the Advertising Standards Authority -- is part of the Conservative's &quot;New Labour New Danger' offensive, which has shocked many by the ferocity of its attacks on the Opposition.</p>
<p>Gummer is the brother of Environment Secretary John Gummer and chairman of public relations company, Shandwick.</p>
<p>He and Saatchi are among 14 people, six Conservatives, six Labour and two others, who will be made life peers, a honour that dies with the recipient, unlike heriditary peerages.</p>
<p>The Labour Party criticised Major for recognising two of the architects of the &quot;dirtiest&quot; campaign in modern politics, who it said were being promoted merely for aiding the Conservatives.</p>
<p>But marketing heads welcomed the appointments saying they marked the coming of age of an industry that, in the past, has lacked weight and political clout in Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;Advertising needs to be and is being seen as an activity central to business and life in this country,&quot; said Nick Phillips, director general of the Institute of Practitioners in Advertising, the ad agencies' main body.</p>
<p>The advertising industry -- worth over 10 billion sterling a year in turnover -- is seeking political support for its activities, which, it says, sharpen the competitiveness of British businesses and maintain choice for consumers.</p>
<p>Saatchi's presence as an unofficial advertising spokesman in the non-elected House of Lords should aid this drive.</p>
<p>&quot;The industry needs as many parts of the political process to understand the role of advertising in the economy so to this extent Maurice's (Saatchi) promotion is a boost,&quot; Brown said.</p>
<p>John Hooper, director general of the Incorporated Society of British Advertisers, which represents many British multinationals, said the move would improve advertising's image, which has been &quot;poorly understood and poorly represented&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;My one regret is that by being wrapped up in the demonic eyes (advertisement) affair, it belittles the achievement and provides fodder for Labour and other critics,&quot; Hooper said.</p>
<p>British newspapers mainly agreed Saatchi was being honoured more for his skill in producing ads for the Conservatives -- which have included memorable slogaBritain isn't working&quot; and &quot;Labour's tax bombshell&quot; -- than for his record as a creator of advertising since 1970.</p>
<p>&quot;...How very convenient to be able to reward (Saatchi and Gummer) who do your party's work -- sometimes its dirty work -- with a seat in the Lords!&quot; the left-leaning Guardian newspaper said in its editorial column.</p>
<p>M&amp;C Saatchi, the ad agency Saatchi created with his brother Charles after being ousted from Saatchi &amp; Saatchi in December 1994, denied Saatchi's award was politically motivated.</p>
<p>The Daily Telegraph newspaper quoted it saying its chairman had &quot;made the British advertising industry respected throughout the world and created thousands of jobs in the process.&quot;</p>
<p>Jennifer Laing, chairman of Saatchi &amp; Saatchi, who took over after Saatchi's acrimonious departure, praised her predecessor.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an extraordinary honour (for Saatchi). It will heighten the profile of the industry,&quot; she told Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
