<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5029" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Top UK union sees Labour phasing in minimum wage.</title>
<headline>Top UK union sees Labour phasing in minimum wage.</headline>
<byline>Alan Raybould</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Labour government in Britain would honour its commitment to bring in a minimum wage, but it would not take much notice of what level the unions wanted and would phase it in gradually, according to a top union leader.</p>
<p>The Trades Union Congress (TUC) holds its annual conference next month and some member unions want to put pressure on Labour leader Tony Blair to fix a firm figure, but Ken Jackson, general secretary of the AEEU engineers union, doubts Blair will oblige.</p>
<p>&quot;Our view is that Blair will not be influenced by the figure that the TUC puts forward. He's his own man and he'll take a decision based on the economic situation at the time,&quot; Jackson told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>The TUC backs a minimum wage equivalent to half male median earnings. There is some dispute over what precise figure that gives, though 4.26 pounds ($6.50) per hour is most often quoted.</p>
<p>Jackson said he expected a Labour government to introduce a low minimum initially, then phase in a more meaningful figure &quot;over a couple of years&quot;, to cushion the impact on industry.</p>
<p>His union caused a rumpus at last year's TUC conference by saying pay rates higher up the ladder would have to rise accordingly, something which would raise worries about wage-led inflation, but Jackson has not changed his line.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no doubt, differentials will be maintained,&quot; he said. &quot;We're letting it be known that we're not prepared to see skilled people disadvantaged.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain's Labour Party was founded by the unions, which still provide much of its funding and command half the votes at its annual, policy-setting conferences.</p>
<p>However, Blair, who looks set to win the next general election, to be held by May 1997, has distanced himself from the unions and, calling the party New Labour, has jettisoned much of the party's socialist programme.</p>
<p>Jackson's union will not be rocking the boat, although it will, like the TUC, be trying to prod the party into a more positive attitude towards European Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>Labour is sitting on the fence on the single European currency, but a decision on membership -- assuming Britain meets the criteria -- would have to be made soon after a Labour government is formed.</p>
<p>&quot;If we're going to be a major player in Europe, we've got to be in there, and we've got to be making sure that the rules suit us this time, rather than joining when it's signed, sealed and delivered and we have no input,&quot; Jackson said.</p>
<p>Using the single currency would show companies wanting to invest in Europe that Britain was not an isolated outpost, and their investment was vital for creating jobs here, Jackson said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have got to remain competitive, attract inward investment....It would be far more difficult to attract inward investment if there was any doubts about our position at the centre of Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>In a New Labour vein, the AEEU will not be making any demands to take back into state ownership any of the companies privatised by the Conservative government since 1979.</p>
<p>Tight regulation and fiscal policy should be enough to ensure they invest adquately, for the public good, Jackson said, adding: &quot;There's no big deal in re-nationalisation.&quot;</p>
<p>He fully endorsed TUC leader John Monks' vision of forging partnerships with industry. &quot;We have got the same aims, that industry should be profitable, should be successful. But we should be part of it and share in it.&quot;</p>
<p>($1=.6471 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
