<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5034" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's OFT decides not to refer milk supply to MMC.</title>
<headline>UK's OFT decides not to refer milk supply to MMC.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The UK's Office of Fair Trading said it had decided not to refer the supply of milk under the Milk Marque cooperative to the Monopolies and Mergers Commission (MMC) but would &quot;monitor the situation closely.&quot;</p>
<p>In a statement, the OFT said Milk Marque, the raw milk marketing cooperative, had given assurances that it would make changes to its milk selling system which should meet its concerns about aspects of the operation.  </p>
<p>Milk Marque is the successor to the statutory Milk Marketing Board.</p>
<p>The OFT said the major change agreed by Milk Marque was that it would lower the price of milk if it received bids for less than 90 percent on offer, and hold a further round of bidding.</p>
<p>There will be no further bidding rounds, however, once the lowest price contract falls to the intervention price level.</p>
<p>Milk Marque will also operate a price cap on opening prices, to be set by reference to a 12-month average of prices.</p>
<p>The OFT decided that Milk Marque's inclusive price for both milk and transport did not alone warrant referral to the MMC.</p>
<p>The British government deregulated the milk market in November 1994, sweeping away the old Milk Marketing Board system in a move which sent milk prices sky high.</p>
<p>The Dairy Industry Federation made a formal complaint to the OFT at the time of deregulation that Milk Marque was abusing its dominant position in the milk market to inflate prices.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
