<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5038" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK proposes British Gas cuts 20 pct off charges.</title>
<headline>UK proposes British Gas cuts 20 pct off charges.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Industry regulator Ofgas on Wednesday proposed that British Gas Plc's pipeline operating company TransCo cut its charges to gas suppliers by 20 percent in 1997/98 and by 2.5 percent in the years thereafter.</p>
<p>Ofgas said in a statement that its final proposals could lead to a cut in average UK domestic gas bills of almost 30 pounds ($46.36) per year in 1997, rising to to over 50 pounds in 2001.  </p>
<p>These final proposals follow a draft released in May when the watchdog said TransCo, which is British Gas biggest moneymaker, should cut charges between by 20 to 28 percent in the year from April 1997, and by five percent thereafter.</p>
<p>&quot;If the proposals are accepted (by British Gas), TransCo's customers will benefit from substantial price cuts from April 1997 and continuing real price reductions in the following years,&quot; Ofgas director general Clare Spottiswoode said.</p>
<p>British Gas said in an initial reaction to the long-awaited decision that it was stil undecided whether to accept or reject the proposed regime. &quot;We have up until October 7 for further discussions and we shall be looking to use that time constructively,&quot; Philip Rogerson, British Gas deputy chairman, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Shares in British Gas initially rose on the news and were indicated 10 pence higher at 208 before the official start of trading on the London Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
