<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5046" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Southern Africa summit to tackle trade conflicts.</title>
<headline>Southern Africa summit to tackle trade conflicts.</headline>
<byline>Marius Bosch</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southern African Development Community (SADC) leaders meet in Lesotho on Saturday to grapple with the thorny issue of regional trade.</p>
<p>The one-day annual summit of the 12-nation SADC in the Lesotho capital Maseru will see regional leaders discuss protocols on trade, drug trafficking, energy and transport.</p>
<p>But the gathering looks set to be dominated by debate on a trade protocol aimed at eventually establishing a southern Africa free trade area, officials said.</p>
<p>South Africa dominates the regional economy, and many of its neighbours have been putting pressure on Pretoria for lower trade tariffs on their goods.</p>
<p>SADC groups Mauritius, Angola, Lesotho, Swaziland, Zambia, Zimbabwe, Namibia, Mozambique, Tanzania, Malawi, South Africa and Botswana.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, South Africa ended a four-year trade dispute with Zimbabwe by agreeing to lower tariffs on certain goods but shied away from Zambian requests for similiar treatment.</p>
<p>The South Africans said they favoured a regional trade pact rather than pacts with individual countries but acknowledge that agreement on the trade protocol would be difficult to reach.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible that the one on trade will only be initialled because it looks as if though (it) will be a difficult protocol to negotiate,&quot; a Foreign Ministry spokesman told Reuters. &quot;If it is not completed now it will just be initialled now and completed at a later stage.&quot;</p>
<p>The SADC secretariat said the draft trade protocol provides for the liberalisation of trade to boost economic development in the region -- which includes some of the world's poorest countries like Malawi and Mozambique.</p>
<p>&quot;The ultimate objective of the trade protocol is to create an integrated regional market in order to boost economic development, diversification and the industrialisation of the region,&quot; the secretariat said in a statement.</p>
<p>South Africa -- whose economy dwarfs that of the rest of the region -- formally joined SADC in 1994 after the the demise of apartheid and the election of its first democratic government.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe, seen as the leading regional power before South Africa's membership, said the trade protocol marked a turning point in SADC regional integration.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very important...because it will begin the process of making SADC a common market. The idea is to have a common market within 10 years and we hope that will be achieved,&quot; Industry and Commerce Minister Nathan Shamuyarirahe said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a real turning point, moving us from talking to action,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>SADC was formed 16 years ago to lessen the region's dependence on then apartheid South Africa</p>
<p>SADC officials said they expected all 12 heads of state at the meeting which follows a two-day meeting of SADC regional ministers which begins on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LESOT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
