<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5047" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African Moslem anti-crime group warns investors.</title>
<headline>S.African Moslem anti-crime group warns investors.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's militant Moslem anti-crime group People Against Gangsterism and Drugs (PAGAD) has told foreign investors to avoid the country because crime levels meant their money would not be safe.</p>
<p>&quot;I cannot see how we should allow investors into the country, their money is not safe here,&quot; PAGAD leader Farouk Jaffer told a news conference at a Cape Town mosque on Tuesday night.</p>
<p>&quot;They should not invest a cent in South Africa until PAGAD gives them the green light.&quot;</p>
<p>Jaffer and his lieutenant Ali Parker appeared at the news conference, guarded by youths with their faces hidden by Palestinian scarves, despite being sought by police in connection with the killing of a drug dealer by vigilantes earlier this month.</p>
<p>Jaffer said PAGAD would continue its campaign to rid South Africa of drugs and crime because the police had failed in the task.</p>
<p>&quot;We will intensify our campaign,&quot; he said. &quot;All drug merchants will be legitimate targets. We will use any means necessary to eradicate this scourge from society. We are peaceful, but we will meet force with greater force.&quot;</p>
<p>Police using armoured vehicles and a helicopter monitored the meeting at he mosque, attended by several hundred Moslems.</p>
<p>PAGAD and similar movements in other parts of the country have been marching through their neighbourhoods to the homes of drug dealers in a bid to highlight what they call the cancer destroying their communities.</p>
<p>During one of these marches in a working class, mixed race district of Cape Town vigilantes shot and burned to death gang leader Rashaad Staggie.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
