<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5048" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Futures trade begins on planned Ukraine currency.</title>
<headline>Futures trade begins on planned Ukraine currency.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Kiev Universal Exchange began on Wednesday futures trading in the Ukraine's new hryvna currency, which has yet to be launched, the exchange's accounts chief said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Since it is strongly rumoured that Ukraine's currency reform may be announced, or even started, on Ukrainian Independence Day on August 24, we decided to do some futures trading with the hryvna,&quot; Vadim Kovalenko told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a lot of interest,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Eleven contracts of 2,000 hryvnas each traded.</p>
<p>Ukraine has been promising to introduce the hryvna, the currency used during the times of the Kiev Rus empire about 1,000 years ago, since independence five years ago. However, the interim karbovanets currency has never been stable enough.</p>
<p>The karbovanets, unchanged at 176,000 to the dollar on the Ukrainian Interbank Currency Exchange on Wednesday, has been steady to higher during the last three months.</p>
<p>A two-week International Monetary Fund mission, due to leave Kiev on Friday, has also been discussing a $1.5 billion stabilisation fund to back the permanent currency.</p>
<p>The exchange started trading by valuing one hryvna at 100,000 karbovanets, Kovalenko said.</p>
<p>&quot;We calculated that the hryvna will be floated at that rate, or it will be one hryvna to one American dollar,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kovalenko said trading resulted in an average price of 101,604 karbovanets to one hryvna.</p>
<p>The contracts will be settled in the month the new currency is introduced, he said.</p>
<p>Hryvna futrues trading on the exchange was expected to continue daily unless clients lose interest, he said. --Natalya Zinets, Kiev Newsroom, +380 44 229 2264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
