<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5050" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Bratislava bourse backs off yr-high on VUB losses.</title>
<headline>Bratislava bourse backs off yr-high on VUB losses.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovak top shares closed mixed in thin trading on the Bratislava Stock Exchange (BSE) on Wednesday, with losses to shares of bank VUB dragging the SAX index down from its year-high.</p>
<p>VUB closed down 50 crowns at 2,250 crowns as the SAX index dropped 3.29 points to 223.05.</p>
<p>Brokers said they expected further losses to VUB since demand for the bank's shares is waning.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems the investor, who had been buying VUB in several previous weeks, pushing its price up, was satisfied already,&quot; Libor Briska of Creditanstalt said.</p>
<p>Oil and gas storage firm Nafta firmed 20 crowns to close at 2,000, though brokers called it a one-off move since only 11 shares changed hands and investors have generally stayed away from the issue since the government sold a large stake in the firm to a little-known firm at well below market prices.</p>
<p>Overall volume increased to 137,172 shares, from 91,312 shares traded on Tuesday, while turnover rose to 112.79 million crowns, from 71.89 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
