<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5052" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Bank, pharma shares lead Budapest bourse rise.</title>
<headline>Bank, pharma shares lead Budapest bourse rise.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian share prices soared in active trade across-the-board on the Budapest Stock Exchange on Wednesday, as market participants returned after a public holiday here on Monday and Tuesday, traders said.</p>
<p>The BUX index ended at 3,286.88 points, up 115.44 or 3.64 percent, as spot share turnover totalled 1.45 billion forints.</p>
<p>BUX index futures ended higher for all maturities, by 120.00 to 140.00 points.</p>
<p>The Budapest bourse geared up to match the price rises of Hungarian shares traded in London earlier this week, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;A rising trend started late last week (here) and this continued at the beginning of this week in London,&quot; Gyorgy Czipo of ING Barings said. &quot;Prices (of Hungarian shares) on the SEAQ reflected this,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This continued today and the two days (of public holiday) had to be 'made up for',&quot; Czipo said, adding that most shares rode the horse.</p>
<p>Bank and pharmaceutical shares led today's rise. OTP Bank which released what analysts called better then expected first half results last week, soared a massive 295 forints or 13.11 percent to end at 2,545.</p>
<p>Of its deals, OTP had a huge block deal for 110,000 units at 2,500 forints/share price.</p>
<p>Trading in OTP shares was halted for a few minutes due to too rapid intraday price rise, traders said.</p>
<p>The day's heavy gainers included the other bank, Inter-Europa Bank which jumped 5.73 percent to end at 33,200 forints, as well as two of the three pharmaceuticals, Egis and Richter, and chemical company Borsodchem.</p>
<p>Egis closed at 9,100 forints, up 430. Richter, which soared to a new high of 7,905 forints, came off the new peak to close at 7,800 forints, up 210.</p>
<p>Borsodchem ended at 2,780, up 120 but below its 2,860 forints daily high.</p>
<p>Traders said they expected the trend to continue this week but the pace of rise was likely to slow down.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
