<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5053" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares mixed, seen up on Thursday.</title>
<headline>Polish shares mixed, seen up on Thursday.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most Polish shares fell on Wednesday but gains by certain heavyweights pushed the main WIG index up and analysts said the dominant buying after price fixing signalled more rises at least on Thursday.</p>
<p>Analysts said it would soon be apparent if current rises represented an upward correction after the recent downtrend or the start of a new growth trend.</p>
<p>&quot;There should be gains tomorrow...and if there's growth to the end of the week then we can start talking about a growth trend,&quot; said Adam Drozdowski, an analyst at Bank Gospodarki Zywnosciowej (BGZ) brokerage.</p>
<p>The main market's all-share WIG index rose 0.3 percent to 13,218.4 points and turnover fell 21.1 percent to 104.1 million zlotys ($38.1 million) on both markets. Losers led gainers by 39 to 22 with 16 stocks flat.</p>
<p>Some analysts said a real growth trend had already started, sparked by firms releasing better July earnings results.</p>
<p>Analysts said another good sign was last week's news of 4.8 percent higher industrial production in July.</p>
<p>They said top gainer garment maker Prochnik, up 7.3 percent, was likely helped by its application last week for a return of 1.4 million zlotys ($0.5 million) in interest on overpaid taxes.</p>
<p>Analysts also said tyre maker Stomil Olsztyn, up 4.4 percent in active trade, was likely helped by Salomon Brothers' recent buy initiation for the stock.</p>
<p>Continuous trade turnover was at 1.2 million zlotys ($0.4 millon) after no stocks traded on Tuesday, with biggest mover industrial and trading conglomerate Elektrim up 4.8 percent.</p>
<p>Mass privatisation NFI units fell 1.1 percent to 91 zlotys ($33.3) in the main market session in 4.9-million-zloty ($1.8 million) trade.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
