<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5054" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia's Ingosstrakh to push forward at home, CIS.</title>
<headline>Russia's Ingosstrakh to push forward at home, CIS.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's second-biggest insurance company, AO Ingosstrakh, plans to occupy a leading position in Russia and Commonwealth of Independent States markets, focusing on property and liability insurance, it said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Insurance markets in Russia and the CIS must become the group's main challenge,&quot; Ingosstrakh said in a statement outlining its strategy for the next 15 years.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation on the Russian property and liability insurance markets, where the company's position is especially strong, are of special interest for Ingosstrakh.&quot;</p>
<p>Ingosstrakh said it holds 10 percent of the Russian property insurance market and 32 percent of the liability insurance market.</p>
<p>Ingosstrakh, which traditionally specialises in insurance abroad plans to develop its foreign business and venture into voluntary medical insurance and travel insurance for Russians, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;The group will strive to take the position of a well-known leader on the Russian market of voluntary insurance and to become one of the world's biggest insurance companies,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Ingosstrakh's 1995 pre-tax profit rose to 384.30 billion roubles ($72.3 million) from 41.00 billion roubles in 1994.</p>
<p>Ingosstrakh plans to diversify its activities by investing in Russian equities and real estate.</p>
<p>The company said it was working in an unfavourable environment where only 48 percent of Russians trust insurance companies and 57 percent never used insurance.</p>
<p>Ingosstrakh quoted official statistics saying Russians use less than one percent of income for insurance service.</p>
<p>In the first quarter of this year insurance premiums amounted to about 1.30 percent of gross domestic product, Ingosstrakh said.</p>
<p>--Julie Tolkacheva, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520 ($ = 5318 Russian Roubles)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
