<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5061" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Creditanstalt sets up first custodian in Romania.</title>
<headline>Creditanstalt sets up first custodian in Romania.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austria's Creditanstalt Investment Bank will launch next month the first depository and custodian company in Romania, a bank executive said.</p>
<p>&quot;Creditanstalt Depository will be depository for mutual and investment funds. It will also offer custodian services for international portfolio investors,&quot; said Dan Pascariu, head of Creditanstalt Financial Advisers SA (CAFA).</p>
<p>So far, local commercial banks have acted as depositors for the investment funds but none of them offered the full-range of services which a depository should provide under the law, such as computing net funds' assets.</p>
<p>Pascariu said the new company had 2.0 billion lei ($633,714) capital and would be integrated with the subsidiary which the Vienna-based bank planned to open in Romania.</p>
<p>Romania's investment funds industry has been hit by scandals since capital market regulator CNVM obliged the funds in March to adjust their values and quote them based on actual worth, not on projected six-month income values.</p>
<p>The new rules brought unit values down, two funds were suspended and investors rushed to withdraw deposits.</p>
<p>Last year Creditanstalt opened two officies in Bucharest -- CAFA and Creditanstalt Invest Romania SA (CIRO) -- aiming to advise potential investors and provide corporate services. CIRO manages a local unit trust.</p>
<p>-- Mirela Eremia, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
