<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5063" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech city Ostrava plans $50 mln foreign bond issue.</title>
<headline>Czech city Ostrava plans $50 mln foreign bond issue.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech city of Ostrava said on Wednesday it was planning to issue a roughly $50 million tranche of bonds on an unspecified foreign market by the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't say the precise specifications or form, we will decide on this on the basis of our analysis...(but) the total volume should be around $50 million,&quot; Radin Berka, deputy to the Ostrava city hall finance director, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Credit rating agency Standard and Poor's recommended the best time for the issue would be around the end of the year, either the end of November or the beginning of December, he added. He gave no further details.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Standard and Poor's said it had assigned Ostrava an A long-term foreign currency rating and an A1 short-term issuer credit rating.</p>
<p>&quot;Ostrava's foreign debt rating is constrained by the Czech Republic's sovereign ceiling,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>The ratings balance the city's strong financial performance and low debt burden with the multiple challenges of restructuring and diversifying its local industrial base and of addressing major infrastructure needs, it added.</p>
<p>The Czech Republic has an S&amp;P sovereign debt rating of A.</p>
<p>Ostrava's is the second Czech municipal rating following Prague's rating in 1994 and only the second municipality rated in the central and eastern European region.</p>
<p>-- Klara Gajduskova, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
