<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5070" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuelan bottler says Pepsi lacked commitment.</title>
<headline>Venezuelan bottler says Pepsi lacked commitment.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Venezuelan bottler Oswaldo Cisneros said he broke with PepsiCo Inc because the U.S. soft drinks giant was not as committed as Coca-Cola Co to his bottling enterprise.</p>
<p>&quot;They didn't want to get on the bus with me,&quot; Cisneros told leading daily El Universal in an interview published Wednesday.</p>
<p>In a surprise move Friday, Cisneros set aside his five-decade old relationship with Pepsi and announced he would be bottling for its global archrival Coca-Cola Co. As a result, Pepsi stocks will soon run out in Venezuela.  </p>
<p>Cisneros said the new venture would invest $500 million over the next five years. A $30 million advertising campaign is to begin next week.</p>
<p>Cisneros's move to Coca-Cola after a 47-year alliance with Pepsi is a harsh blow to Pepsi's operations in Venezuela. Its sixth largest market worldwide, Venezuela is one of just a handful of markets where Pepsi has dominated Coke with an 85 percent market share.</p>
<p>Pepsi filed a complaint Monday with Venezuela's Superintendency for the Promotion and Protection of Free Trade (Procompetencia) on grounds the Coke-Cisnero venture creates a soft drink monopoly.</p>
<p>-- Caracas newsroom, 582 834405</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
