<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5073" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico protests U.S. sanction against phone group.</title>
<headline>Mexico protests U.S. sanction against phone group.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mexican government said it formally protested on Tuesday to the United States over U.S. sanctions against telecommunications firm Grupo Domos, which the Clinton administration is seeking to punish for its business ties with Cuba.</p>
<p>&quot;Today the Mexican embassy in Washington delivered to the U.S. State Department a diplomatic note concerning the letter it sent to the Mexican firm Domos, based on the Helms-Burton law, telling of its decision not to give visas to directors of the firm and their families,&quot; the foreign ministry said.</p>
<p>&quot;In it the Mexican government reiterated the formal protest of the Mexican state at an unacceptable effort to exercise extraterritorial jurisdiction in Mexico, contravening the principles and norms of international law.&quot;</p>
<p>There was no comment on the case on Tuesday from Domos, which said on Monday that it had not yet been officially notified of the State Department's ruling.</p>
<p>&quot;We are awaiting the letters so that we can emit an opinion,&quot; Domos spokesman Hector Cuellar said in a telephone interview on Monday from Monterrey in northern Mexico.</p>
<p>The U.S. government said on Monday it would send letters to about six top Domos executives notifying them that they would be banned from the United States under the controversial Helms-Burton law if within 45 days the firm did not &quot;divest&quot; its business in Cuba.</p>
<p>The law, which has been angrily protested by Mexico, Canada and several European countries, was aimed at tightening 35-year-old U.S. sanctions against Cuba.</p>
<p>It threatened penalties against foreign investors deemed to be &quot;trafficking&quot; in properties confiscated by the Cuban government that were formerly owned by U.S. nationals or Cubans who later became U.S. citizens.</p>
<p>Domos, based in Monterrey, owns some 37 percent of Cuba's national telephone company, which was confiscated from a unit of the U.S. company ITT after Fidel Castro seized power in 1959.</p>
<p>Cuellar said Domos had paid $700 million for its stake in the phone company in 1994, and later sold 25 percent of its share to Italian telecommunications firm STET SpA for $291 million. STET has been warned by the United States it could also face penalties under the Helms-Burton law.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
