<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5081" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-CSR says plans new sugar by-products.</title>
<headline>RTRS-CSR says plans new sugar by-products.</headline>
<byline>Graeme James</byline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSR Ltd said it was close to patenting a process that will lead to a range of new products and applications for a by-product of its cane sugar production.</p>
<p>&quot;In new technology, CSR has combined with James Cook University in north Queensland which will lead to a range of new (sugar-based) products and applications,&quot; CSR senior technical officer Chris Allen told the Sugar 2000 conference here.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope to have a patented process in the very near future,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Allen did not disclose what products were planned but said there was a growing trend in the world towards natural waxes for use in a wide range of food and chemical additives.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe sugar cane wax has the potential to be the best (food) wax in the world,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Allen told the conference Australian sugar mills were &quot;fast approaching the point where it is very difficult to justify mill expansion on returns generated from sugar alone.&quot;</p>
<p>Sugar mills next century will find more uses for their sugar cane, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The mill will be a multi-function mill, producing a whole range of products. Sucrose may eventually be a small component compared to the others,&quot; Allen said.</p>
<p>Cuba already prduced 28 products based on sugar cane other than raw sugar, Allen said.</p>
<p>&quot;How will the Australian industry respond?&quot; Allen asked.</p>
<p>He said current sugar extraction processes were &quot;fundamentally flawed.&quot;</p>
<p>CSR had conducted trials on processing and cleaning of middle fibres in cane with the clean pith an excellent source of human dietary fibre, Allen said.  </p>
<p>Fibre components, molasses and sucrose all had further uses in a range of products, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are big opportunities in ethanol from bagasse as a fuel extender,&quot; Allen said.</p>
<p>&quot;The use of sucrose as a fermentation medium for very high value low-volume products offers enormous potential for the future,&quot; Allen said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
