<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5084" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Bonds boot Australian stocks higher by close.</title>
<headline>Bonds boot Australian stocks higher by close.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian share market roared back in the afternoon session to close higher on Wednesday after being dragged higher by futures and bonds markets that rallied strongly when Standard and Poor's revised Australia's credit outlook to positive from stable.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index surged 21.3 points to close at 2,286.0 while September share index futures jumped 31 points to 2,301 and were at a 15.0 point premium to the index.</p>
<p>After a lethargic and indecisive morning, buyers came out in force in the afternoon, with the banks in particular following the bond market to higher ground.</p>
<p>&quot;Futures and bonds have both gone ahead after the ratings agency did their bit and there's been a solid flow onto our market,&quot; said a dealer at a Sydney brokerage.</p>
<p>Other players agreed, adding that a positive reception to Tuesday's Federal budget had helped put a floor under the benchmark All Ordinaries index.</p>
<p>&quot;There was lots of futures-related buying and also some buying out of Asia in the afternoon,&quot; said dealer Paul Ford of Shaw Stockbroking.</p>
<p>&quot;Also, people have done their sums on what the budget means and see it as a good outcome. It was a slow morning but the market was certainly on an upward leg in the afternoon.&quot;</p>
<p>The interest rate sensitive banking sector received a double fillip with Commonwealth Bank shares climbing after its 16.6 percent higher full year operating profit of A$1.78 billion.</p>
<p>With that sector soaring, the banking index added 1.84 percent on the day, outperforming the overall market index, the All Ordinaries, which added 0.94 percent on the day.</p>
<p>Rises outnumbered falls by a ratio of about five to three, while about 34 percent of stocks traded remained steady.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
