<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5096" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China shows Taiwan economic carrot,political stick.</title>
<headline>China shows Taiwan economic carrot,political stick.</headline>
<byline>Benjamin Kang Lim</byline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>China has offered both carrot and stick to rival Taiwan, setting rules to pave the way for direct shipping links but dismissing the island's bid to rejoin the United Nations as impossible.</p>
<p>The Ministry of Foreign Trade and Economic Cooperation on Wednesday issued regulations that require cargo transport companies to seek its approval to operate directly by sea between China and Taiwan, the Xinhua news agency said.</p>
<p>The rules were issued one day after China's Ministry of Communications unveiled a separate set of regulations governing direct shipping links between the two sides, ignoring a decades-old ban by the island.</p>
<p>Taiwan has banned direct air and shipping links with China since Chiang Kai-shek's Nationalist troops lost the Chinese civil war to the communists and fled to the island in 1949.</p>
<p>China's new rules were music to the ears of many Taiwanese businessmen, who have poured more than $20 billion into China and are eager for direct transport links.</p>
<p>But Taiwanese authorities have been reluctant to lift the ban, which they view as their last bargaining chip in talks with the communists.</p>
<p>The animosity between the two sides was expected to deepen.</p>
<p>China has cancelled a trip by a high-ranking government delegation to Ukraine after a visit there by Taiwan's vice president Lien Chan, a Chinese diplomat in Ukraine's capital Kiev said.</p>
<p>Beijing, which views Taiwan as a rebel province and has sought to push the island into diplomatic isolation, was preparing to make representations with Ukraine, a former Soviet republic, a Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman said.</p>
<p>Ukraine recognises China but not Taiwan.</p>
<p>&quot;China firmly opposes any country with diplomatic ties with it developing any official relations or having any official contacts with Taiwan,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Taiwan's state radio said Ukrainian President Leonid Kuchma met Lien on Wednesday, but a spokesman for Kuchma denied this.</p>
<p>Lien surfaced in Kiev on Tuesday, two days after vanishing on a mysterious European mission. He made a secret detour to Ukraine after making a state visit to the Dominican Republic.</p>
<p>Taiwan state television showed Lien with his wife and other Taiwan and Ukraine officials posing at the University of Kiev, where the announcer said Lien had received an honorary degree.</p>
<p>On Taiwan's latest bid to rejoin the United Nations, the Liberation Daily in an edition seen in Beijing on Wednesday called it &quot;challenging the impossible&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the biggest joke in the world,&quot; the newspaper said.</p>
<p>Beijing took China's U.N. seat from Taipei in 1971.</p>
<p>Taiwan launched similar U.N. bids in 1993, 1994 and 1995 but China, with veto power as one of five permanent members of the U.N. Security Council, easily blocked them.</p>
<p>Beijing on Monday won a round in Taiwan's struggle for recognition, wooing the impoverished African country of Niger back four years after it switched recognition to Taipei.</p>
<p>Niger's switch left only 30 states recognising the exiled Republic of China government in Taiwan rather than the communist government in Beijing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
