<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5100" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Asia stocks buoyed by Fed policy, foreign funds.</title>
<headline>Asia stocks buoyed by Fed policy, foreign funds.</headline>
<byline>Edward Davies</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian stock markets gained almost across the board on Wednesday, boosted by the Fed's decision to leave U.S. interest rates unchanged and a return of foreign funds.</p>
<p>Seoul was a rare faller and dropped 0.60 percent as persistent worries on the economy overshadowed the market.</p>
<p>Tokyo stocks ended higher for the third straight day, relieved by the U.S. Federal Reserve's decision to leave interest rates steady.</p>
<p>But brokers said the market lacked energy to test higher levels.</p>
<p>The key 225-share Nikkei average closed up 148.01 points, or 0.70 percent, at 21,275.02, off a high of 21,391.00 set earlier in the day. Its September futures gained 80 points to 21,260.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the drags on the market has disappeared,&quot; said Haruo Nakaharu, a strategist at Toyo Securities Co Ltd. He was referring to Tuesday's Federal Open Market Committee meeting.</p>
<p>Hong Kong stocks ended the session sharply higher as the Fed's decision to leave interest rates unchanged boosted market sentiment.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index rose 123.99 points, or 1.10 percent, to 11,436.50. Turnover soared to HK$5.88 billion from HK$3.44 billion on Tuesday. Index constituents HSBC Holdings and CITIC Pacific both hit record highs.</p>
<p>&quot;No interest rate rise in the U.S. improved sentiment a bit further and high market liqidity also gave the sign that some overseas funds are coming into the market,&quot; said Ben Kwong, director of research at Dharmala Securities.</p>
<p>Jakarta shares closed higher on the back of bargain-hunting in selected big-capitalised stocks and secondliners.</p>
<p>The Jakarta composite index rose 2.60 points, or 0.48 percent, to 542.20 points.</p>
<p>Singapore's Straits Times Industrials Index surged 31.79 points, or 1.50 percent, to 2,155.60.</p>
<p>The gain was linked to advances in second line stocks and modest gains for blue chips.</p>
<p>Kuala Lumpur's Composite Index gained 17.38 points to 1,122.82 as blue chips surged on renewed institutional buying.</p>
<p>Thai stocks rose 2.01 percent as the entry of a market support fund boosted confidence and investors bought bank and finance issues, brokers said.</p>
<p>The SET index closed 23.62 points up at 1,095.03.</p>
<p>The South Korean bourse ended at a new 33-month low, dragged down by worries about the economy's health.</p>
<p>The composite stock index fell 4.79 points to close provisionally at 789.12.</p>
<p>Manila shares sprang out of the the doldrums after the return of foreign funds as the U.S. Fed left interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>The main index rallied 20.87 points to 3,111.56 after Tuesday's 1.98 point drop.</p>
<p>The Australian share market, the day afer the country's ight 1996/97 budget, rallied in line with futures and bonds markets after Standard and Poor's revised Australia's credit outlook to positive from stable.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index rose 21.3 points to 2,286.0.</p>
<p>Strong buying in shipping stocks pushed Taiwan share prices to a sharply higher close, one day after China issued rules governing direct shipping links with the island.</p>
<p>The weighted index shot up 120.34 points, or 1.99 percent, to finish at 6,177.78.</p>
<p>In Bombay, foreign funds and local institutions drove the benchmark index up 90.27 points to 3,406.33.</p>
<p>In late Tokyo trade, the dollar was at 108.34/39 yen and 1.4848/53 marks, against New York's Tuesday close of 108.31/36 yen and 1.4891/96 marks.</p>
<p>On SIMEX, October Brent futures were traded at $20.35 in late business, down 12 cents from London's Tuesday settlement.</p>
<p>Bullion ended at US$387.30/80 an ounce in Hong Kong, little changed on Tuesday's New York's close of $387.50/388.00.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
