<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5106" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China issues rules on cargo transport with Taiwan.</title>
<headline>China issues rules on cargo transport with Taiwan.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>China on Wednesday issued a second set of regulations to pave the way for direct shipping links with Taiwan despite a decades-old ban by the island.</p>
<p>The Ministry of Foreign Trade and Economic Cooperation (MOFTEC) issued regulations which require cargo transport companies to seek approval from it to operate directly by sea between China and Taiwan, the Xinhua news agency said.</p>
<p>Only wholly Chinese-owned cargo transport firms and joint ventures involving Chinese or Taiwanese companies would be allowed to engage in the business, according to the regulations which consist of 24 articles.</p>
<p>MOFTEC must decide within 45 days whether to approve an application, according to the regulations. If approved, the ministry will issue three-year licences, which must be renewed 30 days before they expire.</p>
<p>Cargo transport companies operating between China and Taiwan will be required to submit to MOFTEC quarterly reports of their transactions, the regulations said.</p>
<p>Violators would be punished, the regulations said without elaborating.</p>
<p>The new rules were issued one day after China's Ministry of Communications unveiled a set of rules governing direct shipping links between the two sides.</p>
<p>Taiwan's Nationalist government has banned direct air and shipping links and trade between Taiwan and China since losing the Chinese civil war and fleeing to the island in 1949.</p>
<p>In Taipei, Yang Ming Marine Corp said it had signed a slot-exchange pact with Japan's Kawasaki Kisen and the mainland's China Ocean Shipping (Group) Co covering global container shipments, including those originating in China and Taiwan.</p>
<p>Yang Ming said the new rules and the alliance would enable it to take China shipping business away from Hong Kong.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
