<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5107" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Gujing interim net hits 65.36 mln yuan.</title>
<headline>Gujing interim net hits 65.36 mln yuan.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anhui Gujing Distillery Co Ltd said on Wednesday its net interim profits hit 65.36 million yuan in the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>Per share earnings, under Chinese accounting standards, reached 0.62 yuan against a forecast target of 0.70 yuan per share for the full 1996 year, said an interim report published in the Securities Times.</p>
<p>Comparative 1995 figures were not available because Gujing did not become a joint-stock entity until end May 1996. Its 60 million class B shares were listed in Shenzhen in June 1996.</p>
<p>Gujing forecast 165 million yuan in net 1996 profits, versus 145 million yuan in 1995 and 123 million yuan in 1994.</p>
<p>Based in Haozhou city, in eastern Anhui province, the company based its profit growth target on ongoing moves to expand operations and produce spirits with lower alcohol content, in line with changing consumer demand.</p>
<p>The company recently received approval from the China Securities Regulatory Commission to offer 20 million class A shares for listing in Shenzhen.</p>
<p>Anhui International Trust and Investment Co is the main underwriter for the A share offer.</p>
<p>Gujing now has total share capital of 215 million shares, including 155 million state shares and 60 million B shares.</p>
<p>Gujing intends to use proceeds of 150 million yuan to expand production and finance construction of an electric power project, the report said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
