<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5108" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China tea officials call for quotas to end chaos.</title>
<headline>China tea officials call for quotas to end chaos.</headline>
<byline>Mure Dickie</byline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>China is considering new export quotas and stronger management of its tea industry to support slumping prices and revive trade, Chinese officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The State Council, China's cabinet, was reviewing proposals for a new trade association to regulate exports and end chaos that has helped drive down export prices by around a third over the past two years, said Wu Xiduan, general secretary of the China Tea Marketing Association.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to stop companies from indiscriminately exporting tea and from cutting prices for the sake of market share,&quot; Wu told Reuters.</p>
<p>Although China controlled more than 85 percent of the world market in green tea, fierce price competition by exporters and poor quality had helped send prices slumping, Wu said.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is critical and many of the problems come from the domestic tea industry,&quot; he said. &quot;Tea prices in the international market keep falling...domestic exporters continue to undercut one another to earn more.&quot;</p>
<p>Green tea export prices had fallen 34 percent over the past two years alone, Chinese state media said last month. In some cases hard-pressed growers were forced to sell their crops for less than the cost of production, Wu said.</p>
<p>The new proposals, submitted to the State Council by the ministries of agriculture, trade and other state bodies, called for the tea regulator to be made up of major exporters.</p>
<p>Officials say tougher management is needed to boost export quality, clamp down on tea smuggling and stem corruption caused by weakened central management.</p>
<p>Beijing's appointed regulator, the China Tea Import and Export Corp -- itself an exporter -- has lost effective control of much of the trade, they say.</p>
<p>Wu said an association of all major exporters would be able to re-establish order in exports of green tea, a key Chinese export for centuries.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the regulatory body would not be governmental, it would be driven towards sales and profits,&quot; he said. &quot;We want the (China Tea Import and Export) Corp to hand over the right to allocate quotas, to make things fair.&quot;</p>
<p>Major reforms of the trade in black tea was also needed, he said, but gave no details.</p>
<p>The State Council was also considering slashing tea export tariffs to around 15 percent from 23 percent, he said.</p>
<p>It was not yet clear when a decision would be made on the proposals, Wu said. State Council officials could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>Spiralling production costs and falling prices have left more than 80 percent of China's tea producers in the red, official figures show.</p>
<p>China exported 166,000 tonnes of tea in 1995, earning $280 million, but production fell to 502,000 tonnes, down five percent compared with 1994. Output in 1996 has been estimated at 510,000 tonnes, state media said this month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
