<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5114" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai B shares end up on Pudong share rise.</title>
<headline>Shanghai B shares end up on Pudong share rise.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai B shares ended sharply up on a rally by Pudong shares on news 98.7 billion yuan will be invested in Pudong over the next five years, brokers said.</p>
<p>The index closed up 1.004 points or 1.94 percent to 52.817 points, on volume of 14.6 million shares worth $6.0 million. Of 41 B shares, 39 traded, with 23 up, eight flat and eight down.</p>
<p>Shanghai will invest 98.7 billion yuan in Pudong's infrastructure in the next five years, four times the amount of the last five years, city media said late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Brokers said that the news sparked investor interest in Pudong shares and boosted the whole B share market.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank is sure to cut interest rates again at the end of this week, which will help the market climb further,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors believe the results of listed firms will improve in the coming months because the government is paying more attention to them, pushing up the index,&quot; a second broker said.</p>
<p>Shanghai Steel Tube was the star on speculative buying, jumping $0.012 or 10.71 percent to $0.124, on volume of 6,300 shares.</p>
<p>Pudong share Shanghai Jinqiao was the third winner, up $0.022 or 5.98 percent to $0.390, on volume of 530,500 shares.</p>
<p>Another Pudong share, Shanghai Lujiazui, rose $0.016 or 1.75 percent to $0.926, on volume of 1.8 million shares.</p>
<p>Shanghai A shares ended up on expectations of an imminent cut in interest rates, brokers said.</p>
<p>The index rose 11.548 points or 1.34 percent to 872.001 points, on volume of 314.2 million shares worth 2.8 billion yuan. The SSE 30 index closed up 36.777 points or 1.72 percent to 2176.517 points.</p>
<p>Yunnan Yunwei was the star on institutional buying, up 1.27 yuan or 9.81 percent to 14.22 yuan, on volume of 3.4 million shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
