<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5115" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong shares end strong after U.S. Fed meeting.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong shares end strong after U.S. Fed meeting.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks ended sharply higher on Wednesday as the U.S. Federal Reserve's decision to leave interest rates unchanged boosted market sentiment.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index rose 123.99 points, or 1.10 percent, to 11,436.50. Turnover soared to HK$5.88 billion, up from HK3.44 billion on Tuesday. Hang Seng index constituents HSBC Holdings and CITIC Pacific both hit record highs.</p>
<p>&quot;No interest rate rise in the U.S. improved sentiment a bit further and high market liqidity also gave the sign that some overseas funds are coming into the market,&quot; said Ben Kwong, director of research at Dharmala Securities.</p>
<p>Analysts said European investors had pushed the market up during the afternoon session, helping HSBC to close at a record high of HK$136.00, up HK$2.00. CITIC Pacific also closed at an all-time high of HK$35.20, up HK$0.50.</p>
<p>Ricky Tam, senior research analyst at Delta Asia Securities, said the next target for the Hang Seng index was 12,000.</p>
<p>&quot;After 11,300 the next target will be 12,000,&quot; he said, adding however that the blue chip index was likely to meet resisitance at 11,500. He said the Federal Reserve would probably leave rates steady until after the November U.S. presidential elections, which would help investor sentiment.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng utilities sub-index surged once again, adding 154.99 points, or 1.60 percent, to 9,831.04.</p>
<p>&quot;Because the Fed did not raise interest rates, most utility stocks are attractive now when you compare them to the 30-year bond yield,&quot; added Tam.</p>
<p>The U.S. long bond slipped 1/32 overnight to yield 6.80 percent following the Federal Reserve meeting. The Dow industrials rose 21.82 points to 5,721.26.</p>
<p>Louis Tse, executive director at Standard Capital Brokerage, said futures-related buying had helped lift share prices. &quot;The market is trying to squeeze short sellers on the futures.&quot; August Hang Seng futures rose 85 points to 11,395.</p>
<p>Guangdong Investment rose HK$0.30 to HK$5.65. Its parent Guangdong Enterprises said it would place 80 million existing shares of its unit with private investors at HK$5.22 each and subscribe to the same amount of new shares at the same price.</p>
<p>Hutchison Whampoa rose HK$0.40 to HK$49.00 and Cheung Kong (Holdings) added HK$0.25 to HK$56.75. Both are due to release interim results on Thursday.</p>
<p>COSCO Pacific Ltd slipped HK$0.20 to HK$5.80 on concerns about the impact of direct shipping links between Taiwan and China. China issued rules governing direct shipping links with Taiwan on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
