<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5116" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo stocks power higher as US keeps rates steady.</title>
<headline>Tokyo stocks power higher as US keeps rates steady.</headline>
<byline>Hiroko Nakata</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo stocks powered higher for the third successive day on Wednesday, getting support from Wall Street and the Federal Reserve's decision to leave interest rates steady.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the drags on the market has disappeared,&quot; said Haruo Nakaharu, a strategist at Toyo Securities Co Ltd. He was referring to Tuesday's Federal Open Market Committee meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. decision makes us believe that Japan will not raise its rates for the time being,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Although the market overcame one of its biggest hurdles, it still lacked energy to go even higher, brokers said.</p>
<p>The key 225-share Nikkei average gained 148.01 points, or 0.70 percent, to close at 21,275.02, but it was off a high of 21,391.00 set earlier in the day.</p>
<p>Although it was widely expected that the Fed would leave interest rates unchanged, many participants in the Tokyo market had been cautious, as trade was slow ahead of the meeting.</p>
<p>Brokers also said the market got psychological support from Wall Street, with the key Dow industrials climbing to 5,721.26, up 21.82 points.</p>
<p>Nakaharu said some investors were lured back to the market after being sidelined ahead of the FOMC meeting, and today's higher trade volume was a bright sign for the market.</p>
<p>Turnover was about 341 million shares on Wednesday, up from about 252 million shares yesterday.</p>
<p>But brokers said the market still lacked energy and analysts expected trading to remain somewhat sluggish at least until the Bank of Japan's &quot;tankan&quot; quarterly economic survey is released next Wednesday.</p>
<p>Kaoru Ichikawa, senior trader at Kokusai Securities Co Ltd, said: &quot;The market was boosted by the futures, but it was only in the morning.</p>
<p>&quot;There were no factors to hammer share prices lower, but also no factors to prompt chasing of the upper levels.&quot;</p>
<p>Kokusai's Ichikawa said participants found the bottom of the Nikkei average to be solid, but upward energy was still feeble due to lingering worries over a glut of new stock issues, including  West Japan Railway Co's (JR West) offering.</p>
<p>The Asahi Shimbun newspaper said on Wednesday the Japan National Railway Settlement Corp might auction 100,000 fewer JR West shares than the 750,000 it had been planning, due to a lack of investor interest.</p>
<p>But Ichikawa said that if the trading volume continues to rise, the market could absorb the JR West shares without any major problems.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the pace of the recent gains was fast, people took profits today,&quot; said Shuji Yasuma, general manager at Kankaku Securities Co Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;We could not chase the higher levels, and that was why the market lacked power,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
