<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5117" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Close Thai budget vote seen as bad omen for PM.</title>
<headline>Close Thai budget vote seen as bad omen for PM.</headline>
<byline>Sutin Wannabovorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The narrow margin by which the Thai budget won parliamentary approval shows that Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa faces an uphill battle in a forthcoming no-confidence debate, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The House of Representatives voted early on Wednesday 199 to 115 to approve the 1996/97 fiscal budget. The budget bill, which had been expected to sail through parliament easily, received only three votes more than the majority needed for passage in the 391-seat lower House.</p>
<p>The fact that the budget bill just scraped by, even though Banharn's coalition commands 209 seats, shows the instability of his 13-month old government, political analysts said.</p>
<p>They said it did not augur well for Banharn as he heads into next month's censure debate in parliament.</p>
<p>The opposition on Tuesday tabled a no-confidence motion against Banharn, accusing him of damaging the country through mismanagement and inefficiency. Debate is set to begin on the motion on September 11.</p>
<p>The budget vote came just a week after the Palang Dharma Party (PDP), formerly the third largest member in the coalition, pulled out of Banharn's government.</p>
<p>After the PDP withdrew, the six remaining coalition partners vowed to stick together at least until the budget bill passed through parliament. The 23-seat PDP also promised to support the budget bill in order to ensure its approval.</p>
<p>&quot;We all voted to support the bill except two of our MPs who were absent,&quot; deputy PDP leader Thawin Praison told Reuters.</p>
<p>If most of the PDP voted for the budget, it meant some of the coalition members of parliament (MPs) did not vote, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The absence of the government votes may be regarded as a message from those who were bargaining for power in (Banharn's) Chart Thai party,&quot; Chaiwat Kamchoo, a political science professor at Chulalongkorn University, told Reuters.</p>
<p>A senior member of the Therd Thai, a faction within the Chart Thai with about 30 seats in parliament, said his faction could not guarantee support for Banharn during the censure debate.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope the prime minister will be able to explain charges made by the opposition, but if he cannot clear himself I think the Prime Minister knows well what to do next,&quot; Boonchu Trithong, minister of university affairs, told reporters.</p>
<p>Some other coalition partners have said they could not guarantee support for Banharn during the no-confidence debate.</p>
<p>&quot;No party can guarantee to vote in support of the prime minister. We can say yes or no only after we listen to the accusations and see if the one who was accused can clear himself out of the charges.&quot; Suraporn Danaitangtrakul of second largest coalition member the New Aspiration Party (NAP) told Reuters.</p>
<p>Analysts speculate that the NAP leader, Defence Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh, who has made no secret of his ambitions to become prime minister, might break ranks with Banharn during the debate in an effort to form his own coalition.</p>
<p>Chulalongkorn University's Chaiwat said Banharn's shaky support from his own party and the coalition may force him to resign or carry out a major reshuffle before the vote.</p>
<p>Sukhum Naulsakul, political science lecturer at Ramkhamheang University, predicted the situation would force Banharn to resign before the non-confidence debate.</p>
<p>&quot;I am quite confident that Banharn will not dare to face a political grilling in parliament,&quot; Sukhum told reporters.</p>
<p>Banharn has denied allegations of impropriety and said he will face the censure debate in parliament. He has also said he will not resign.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
