<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5119" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China supports listed firms in run-up to 1997.</title>
<headline>China supports listed firms in run-up to 1997.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's state banks and local governments have taken measures to support listed firms to boost the stock market in the run-up to China's takeover of Hong Kong next July, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The government wants to ensure that the two stock exchanges in Shanghai and Shenzhen will recover from their two-year slump by July 1, 1997, and be able to compete better with the Hong Kong market, they said.</p>
<p>Many Chinese listed firms posted poor results in 1995, mainly due to bad management which made them unable to cope with tight money policies Beijing has implemented since mid-1993.</p>
<p>&quot;The central government wants to do window-dressing for the stock market before the Hong Kong takeover,&quot; said one stock analyst with a major Chinese brokerage. &quot;Performance of the listed firms has become a major concern.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Many listed companies were created out of state firms and their poor management meant they were hard hit by the past three years of austerity,&quot; said a broker with Shenyin &amp; Wanguo Securities. &quot;The support came right in time.&quot;</p>
<p>The first support came in late June when the People's Bank of China, the central bank, said it would provide easier credit to the nation's top 300 firms, many of them listed companies.</p>
<p>They included computer parts maker Shenzhen Kaifa Technology Co, conglomerate Shenzhen Lionda Holdings Co and Shanghai-listed Tsingtao Brewery Co.</p>
<p>Both Shanghai and Shenzhen authorities have promised to support blue-chip companies on the exchanges such as Shenzhen Development Bank Co and Shanghai Petrochemical Co, including providing them with preferential loans.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the Shanghai government promised preferential treatment to 100 local listed firms to speed up development of the city's stock market.</p>
<p>It said it would help to reduce cost of fund-raising for the firms, recommend good projects for them to invest in and offer favourable conditions in the course of mergers.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, the Shanghai branch of the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China signed an agreement to lend 1.07 billion yuan ($128.9 million) to 16 listed companies in the second half of the year including Shanghai Chlor Alkali Chemical and Shanghai Refrigerator Compressor.</p>
<p>Other banks have plans to support the firms, the official media have reported.</p>
<p>Chinese stock analysts welcomed the moves.</p>
<p>&quot;The measures are seen as important long-term positive news to the stock market,&quot; said Cong Yu, a senior stock analyst with China Finance Trust and Investment Co. &quot;But, in the short term, they will not be able to push up the market.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the support, company performance cannot improve in one day,&quot; said one analyst with China Guotai Securities. &quot;The measures are expected to make themselves felt by late this year or early next year.&quot;</p>
<p>In 1995, Shenzhen-listed foreign currency B share companies posted a combined 15 percent year-on-year fall in post-tax profits and their Shanghai counterparts were worse, with a combined loss of 28 percent.</p>
<p>The B market has been weak for more than two years.</p>
<p>The domestic A share market began to regain ground in April, with the national economy improving and a fall in inflation.</p>
<p>But interim results show that many firms still performed poorly in the first half of 1996, dampening market sentiment and preventing a full recovery in the short term, analysts said. ($1=8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
