<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5121" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan industry rebound fuels hopes for recovery.</title>
<headline>Taiwan industry rebound fuels hopes for recovery.</headline>
<byline>James Peng</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's economy showed signs of coming to life in July with a rebound in industrial output after two monthly declines, economists said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The year-on-year rise of 1.71 percent, disclosed by the economics ministry, raised the possibility that even the beleaguered real estate and construction sectors might be pulling out of their six-year-old freefall.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether or not industrial output continues to rise after July's rebound remains to be seen,&quot; said Nomura Securities economist Amy Huang.</p>
<p>&quot;But Taiwan's economy, with the government's stimulus package, should gradually recover in the fourth quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>Economics ministry statistics chief Chang Yao-tsung, in a telephone interview, said July's industrial growth was a signal and that exports could be expected to sustain growth of five to six percent in the second half.</p>
<p>&quot;Most government and private forecasts have been expecting better economic performance in the second half than in the first, with July's industrial output being a sign,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Private consumption will also rise because of gradual recovery in the real estate and stock markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Vice-president and premier Lien Chan has promised measures to boost competitiveness to bring Taiwan into the world's top five industrialised nations by 2000.</p>
<p>It stands between 14th and 18th now.</p>
<p>Lien has already ordered public construction projects to be speeded up to boost the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;The acceleration on public construction should help the recovery in coming months,&quot; Huang said.</p>
<p>The manufacturing index, including metals, machinery, information electronics, chemical and consumer products, rose 2.24 percent in July compared to July 1995.</p>
<p>The ministry said July brought a general recovery in all industrial sectors and took special note of the slowing rate of decline in the real estate and construction industries. Output in the two sectors fell 19.33 percent from July 1995.</p>
<p>Foreign orders for Taiwan goods rose 1.75 percent in July from a year earlier to US$9.77 billion, the ministry said.</p>
<p>Orders from the United States rose 13 percent to $3.08 billion due to continuous recovery there, the ministry said.</p>
<p>Orders from Hong Kong fell 7.04 percent to $1.69 billion. The ministry attibuted the decline to decreasing raw material demand from China, whose imports of Taiwan goods are routed through Hong Kong. China's own exports have slowed.</p>
<p>Economists expected a slowdown in trade with China to continue, with President Lee Teng-hui's warnings about overdependence on China's economy balancing out gains from a possible breakthrough in direct Taiwan-China shipping links.</p>
<p>&quot;As cross-strait relations remain gloomy, it's hard to see growth on trade with Hong Kong,&quot; the ministry's Chang said.</p>
<p>&quot;But direct shipping links between the two sides will gradually show positive effect on bilateral trade,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>China on Tuesday issued rules governing shipping with Taiwan that could allow the start of some semi-direct sea links despite Taipei's 47-year-old ban on direct relations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
