<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5131" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: APEC common stand on infotech still far off.</title>
<headline>APEC common stand on infotech still far off.</headline>
<dateline>DAVAO, Philippines 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asia Pacific nations have yet to agree on a U.S. proposal for a common information technology policy ahead of a World Trade Organisation meeting later this year, a Philippine official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Foreign Affairs Undersecretary Federico Macaranas was speaking in the southern Philippine city of Davao where senior officials of the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation forum are meeting ahead of an APEC summit in the Philippines in November.</p>
<p>The United States has been pressing for APEC's 18 member economies to set a common goal of tariff-free trade in information technology and related equipment by the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;There are many issues and this will not be final until the November ministerial meeting in Manila,&quot; Macaranas told a news conference.</p>
<p>Washington wanted APEC to adopt a common stance when the issue was discussed at the WTO meeting in Singapore in December.</p>
<p>&quot;We shall be looking forward for more discussions within APEC and outside APEC so that we can push for the early resolution of the issue,&quot; Macaranas said.</p>
<p>APEC groups Australia, Brunei, Canada, Chile, China, Hong Kong, Indonesia, Japan, South Korea, Malaysia, Mexico, New Zealand, Papua New Guinea, the Philippines, Singapore, Chinese Taipei, Thailand, and the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAVAO, Philippines"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
