<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5132" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China seen as Taiwan food giant's biggest market.</title>
<headline>China seen as Taiwan food giant's biggest market.</headline>
<byline>Mark O'Neill</byline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>If China's economy continues its rapid growth, the mainland will replace Taiwan as the biggest market for Taiwan food giant President Enterprises, the head of its first joint venture in China said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If the mainland's development is normal...its politics are stable with no chaos, and the economy grows at nine-ten percent a year, our turnover in China will surpass that in Taiwan,&quot; said Tseng Wen-liang, general manager of Shanghai President Enterprises Livestock Food Company.</p>
<p>Tseng's venture, which produces feedgrain, was set up on July 1, 1992, with investment of $14 million. Its local Shanghai partner holds 11.5 percent, Japan's Mitsubishi Corp five percent, and President the balance.</p>
<p>Since then, President has become one of Taiwan's biggest investors in China, with $200 million invested in 15 companies producing biscuits, instant noodles, drinks and other food and industrial products, most sold to the Chinese market.</p>
<p>The massive sums Taiwan companies have poured into political rival China has recently begun raising questions in Taipei.</p>
<p>Last Wednesday Taiwan President Lee Teng-hui said the island needed to avoid over-dependency on investment in the mainland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
