<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5133" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: APEC urged to ensure people's welfare put first.</title>
<headline>APEC urged to ensure people's welfare put first.</headline>
<byline>Ramoncito dela Cruz</byline>
<dateline>DAVAO, Philippines 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senior Asia Pacific officials were urged on Wednesday not to get bogged down in detail but to keep their focus on how to improve the welfare of the region's growing population.</p>
<p>&quot;It is important in our continuing work to revisit the mandate handed down by leaders to us in the past, so we may not lose sight of the ultimate objective of our work, which is to promote the well-being of the peoples in the region,&quot; Philippine Foreign Affairs Undersecretary Federico Macaranas said.</p>
<p>Macaranas made the remarks in the southern Philippine city of Davao at the opening of a meeting of senior officials from the 18 member nations of the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum.</p>
<p>Macaranas is chairman of the meeting, the third in a series of senior officials' gatherings to prepare for the APEC summit in the Philippines in November.</p>
<p>APEC is devising a comprehensive trade and investment liberalisation plan going into the next century.</p>
<p>The officials are trying to compile a total of 1,512 voluntary tariff reduction schedules into one overall plan to be presented at the APEC leaders' summit at Subic Bay north of Manila in November.</p>
<p>&quot;At this stage, APEC should not be concerned with mere number of projects, but in generating meaningful impact and benefits to the people,&quot; Macaranas added.</p>
<p>APEC groups Australia, Brunei, Canada, Chile, China, Hong Kong, Indonesia, Japan, South Korea, Malaysia, Mexico, New Zealand, Papua New Guinea, the Philippines, Singapore, Chinese Taipei, Thailand, and the United States.</p>
<p>It has identified 350 joint activities in 13 areas of economic and technical cooperations that address specific concerns of the communities.</p>
<p>APEC economic committee chairman John Curtis told a news conference early Wednesday that his committee, which has been meeting ahead of the Davao talks, had discussed how to address concerns over how to feed the region's growing population.</p>
<p>&quot;The focus of the economic committee is maintaining, strengthening economic growth by reducing economic disparities within the region,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAVAO, Philippines"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
