<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5142" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks rise in morning after Fed meeting.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks rise in morning after Fed meeting.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks moved higher in Wednesday morning trade after the U.S. Federal Reserve decided to leave interest rates unchanged at its policy meeting on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index rose 34.16 points to 11,346.67. Turnover was HK$1.51 billion after the first fifty minutes of trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Uncertainty as to whether or not there will be a rate hike has been moved aside. We have broken through 11,200. That now will be created as a support level,&quot; said Miles Remington, sales trader at Crosby Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a general confidence within this market that we will see positive news on both Cheung Kong and Hutchison,&quot; Remington added.</p>
<p>Cheung Kong (Holdings) and Hutchison Whampoa are due to release interim results on Thursday. Cheung Kong shares were steady at HK$56.50 and Hutchison rose HK$0.10 to HK$48.70.</p>
<p>Analysts said however that the Federal Reserve's decision to leave interest rates unchanged was widely expected and the Hang Seng index may have trouble sustaining this week's gains.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it will be a problem trying to sustain the market above 11,300,&quot; said one trader. &quot;We really have to convince ourselves that we are going to trade up again or we will go sideways.&quot;</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index closed above 11,300 points on Tuesday for the first time since March, rising 99.03 points to 11,312.51.</p>
<p>&quot;I think you have had a very good run. The market is probably due for a correction in the next few days,&quot; said Remington.</p>
<p>Shares in Guangdong Investment Ltd rose HK$0.20 to HK$5.55.</p>
<p>Guangdong Investment parent Guangdong Enterprises said it would place 80 million existing shares of its unit with private investors at HK$5.22 per share, before subscribing to the same amount of new shares at the same price.</p>
<p>Utility shares continued to rally after the Hang Seng utilities sub-index gained 2.17 percent on Tuesday. China Light rose HK$0.20 to HK$33.50 and Hongkong Electric added HK$0.20 to HK$23.50. Hong Kong and China Gas rose HK$0.10 to HK$12.65 and Hongkong Telecom rose HK$0.10 to HK$13.20.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
