<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5143" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore shares open firmer on speculative stocks.</title>
<headline>Singapore shares open firmer on speculative stocks.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brisk trading in speculative stocks pushed Singapore shares firmer on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the return of the SESDAQ speculative stocks. I doubt the trading activity is sustainable. Profit-taking is bound to set in sooner or later,&quot; said a dealer with a local brokerage.</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected bargain hunting in oversold blue chips on Wednesday, encouraged by positive sentiment stemming from Singapore's 6.4 percent non-oil domestic export growth in July and unchanged U.S. interest rates.</p>
<p>The 30-share Straits Times Industrials Index rose 14.51 points to 2,138.32 at 0221 GMT.</p>
<p>Market volume was 41.9 million shares with advances swamping decliners by 162 to 76.</p>
<p>Transmarco shares resumed trading and climbed steeply to a morning high of Singapore $11.90 (US$8.44) and was at S$10.70, up by S$0.90 at 0218 GMT. It was boosted by news that Indonesian Putera Sampoerna, through Miel Investment Corp, had increased his takeover bid to Singapore $8.55 per share.</p>
<p>Lindeteves-Jacoberg hit a high of $0.84, up S$0.015, on a turnover of 2.62 million shares. It saw a block deal of 500,000 units done at S$0.813 in early morning.</p>
<p>US$1=S$1.41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
