<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5147" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai parliament approves 1996/97 budget bill.</title>
<headline>Thai parliament approves 1996/97 budget bill.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Thai parliament approved the budget for the 1996/97 fiscal year after seven days of sometimes heated debate, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The House of Representatives early on Wednesday voted 199 to 115 for the record 984-billion-baht ($39.36-billion) budget for the fiscal year starting October 1, parliament officials said.</p>
<p>The balanced budget projects government spending to rise 16.7 percent in fiscal 1996/97 from the previous year.</p>
<p>The bill will be forwarded to the appointed Senate later on Wednesday for endorsement.</p>
<p>The bill received only three votes more than the majority needed for passage by the 391-member lower House, and the narrowness of the approval showed the instability of the 13-month old coalition government, a political analyst said.</p>
<p>Questions have been raised about the future of Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa's government since the third largest member, the Palang Dharma Party (PDP), quit the coalition last week.</p>
<p>The PDP pullout left a six-party coalition with 209 seats and a slim majority in parliament, and rivalry within Banharn's own Chart Thai party and threats of more coalition partners leaving have raised doubts about the government's stability.</p>
<p>The six remaining parties vowed to stick together at least until the budget bill was passed.</p>
<p>The government now faces a no-confidence debate. Opposition parties submitted a no-confidence motion on Tuesday, accusing Banharn of mismanagement and inefficiency, and debate on the measure is tentatively scheduled to begin on September 11.</p>
<p>($1 = 25 baht)  </p>
<p>The PDP pullout left a six-party coalition with 209 seats and a slim majority in parliament, and rivalry within Banharn's own Chart Thai party and threats of more coalition partners leaving have raised doubts about the government's stability.</p>
<p>The six remaining parties vowed to stick together at least until the budget bill was passed.</p>
<p>The government now faces a no-confidence debate. Opposition parties submitted a no-confidence motion on Tuesday, accusing Banharn of mismanagement and inefficiency, and debate on the measure is tentatively scheduled to begin on September 11.</p>
<p>($1 = 25 baht)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
