<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5148" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: FEATURE - Affluent East turns on to Teddy bears.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Affluent East turns on to Teddy bears.</headline>
<byline>Chris Johnson</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Andrew Lim gently strokes the tattered, greying yellow teddy bear sitting on his lap.</p>
<p>&quot;He's lovely, isn't he. Almost certainly made in the 1920s and probably by Farnell...mohair, he's fully jointed with sweet cardboard paws. I'd say this bear would go for S$6,000 (US$4,255),&quot; he says, turning the bear over with reverence.</p>
<p>Lim is one of a growing number of young, professional Asians who collect, study, make, and sometimes sell teddy bears.</p>
<p>He is not interested in the modern, mass-produced, soft toys that fill the windows of city department stores.</p>
<p>Each one of his collection of more than one hundred bears is special: either handmade by enthusiasts who have laboured long hours on works of art, tiny miniatures just inches high, or rare, old bears with valuable pedigrees.</p>
<p>A successful actor through his role in Singapore's popular television sit-com &quot;Under One Roof,&quot; Lim has dedicated more and more of his time recently to bears and now works regularly for the island's first teddy bear shop, &quot;Sasha's.&quot;</p>
<p>Tucked in a back-street close to the Raffles Hotel, the bear shop has become a Mecca for enthusiasts -- &quot;bearologists&quot; or &quot;arctophiles&quot; as they like to be called.</p>
<p>Visitors can admire the hundreds of antique and designer teddies, browse through its library of specialist teddy bear books and magazines, or sign up for a course in bear-making.</p>
<p>&quot;We get all kinds of people in here,&quot; said local collector Vanessa Martin, who set up the bear shop three years ago when she couldn't find a teddy bear she liked for her baby daughter.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't have a teddy until I was 18 and hardly any of my friends had them either,&quot; she said. &quot;We had stuffed toys, of course, but they tended to be plush, pink things shaped like elephants or other animals. There's no real tradition of teddy bears in Asia.&quot;</p>
<p>First made in New York in 1903, teddies got their name from president Theodore (Teddy) Roosevelt after his famous refusal on a hunting trip in Mississippi to shoot a bear tied to a tree.</p>
<p>The toys' popularity spread rapidly and the success of A.A. Milne's series of &quot;Winnie-the-Pooh&quot; books in Britain in the 1920's helped make teddies an essential part of middle class nurseries across North America and Europe.</p>
<p>Early teddies were usually rigid, fully-jointed, fairly life-like models of mohair stuffed with wood-shavings. They often had eyes made of glass or precious stones and involved a workmanship that has attracted Western collectors ever since.</p>
<p>But the allure of the teddy made little impact outside the West until a new generation of newly-affluent Asians began collecting them a few years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say it started in Japan,&quot; said Lim. &quot;In 1994 a bear, Teddy Girl, was bought for a record 110,000 pounds sterling ($169,200) at a Christie's auction in London by a Japanese man who was himself a toy manufacturer.&quot;</p>
<p>British collector and connoisseur Pam Hebbs, who successfully bid for Teddy Girl on behalf of her client Yoshihiro Sekihguchi, said Asians are now among the keenest and biggest buyers of antique bears.</p>
<p>&quot;These days I get faxes at my shop in London from so-called 'teddy bear agents' from all over Asia looking for investments for their clients. It is already big business and I don't think it has reached its peak yet,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Lim said most Asian collectors are looking for an old bear, possibly made by early German manufacturers Steiff.</p>
<p>&quot;The German teddy bears really started the whole market in Europe,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are many old Steiff bears around, but the most collectable are the black ones, which are very, very rare, or bears with their original collar. These are difficult to find because when they were bought, parents took the accessories off before giving them to the children,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Other collectable bear makes include Farnell from Britain in the 1920s or Merrythought made in England in the 1930s.&quot;</p>
<p>Hebbs said the widespread interest in collecting bears has spawned an entire industry making bear-related items that were in turn exciting more interest in teddies.</p>
<p>&quot;You've not just got teddy bears, but &quot;bearaphernalia:&quot; clothing, jewellery and ornaments. I've even got a pair of model bears in my garden,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Interest in teddy bears is so strong in Singapore that no less than eight other shops dedicated to selling the toys have sprung up in the city since Sasha's first opened in 1993.</p>
<p>A teddy bears' picnic held for charity in one of the city's parks in August attracted more than 1,000 teddy enthusiasts, parents and children all keen to show off their collections.</p>
<p>&quot;I am gob-smacked (stunned) at the interest in Singapore,&quot; said Hebbs, who attended the picnic to display and sell some of her collection. &quot;Singapore is now taking over as the place for teddy bear collectors in Asia.&quot;</p>
<p>As she sat on the grass surrounded by hundreds of fellow enthusiasts and their families eating lunch in the park, Martin said it was difficult to explain what drew her to teddies.</p>
<p>&quot;I suppose teddy bears are symbols of childhood. And I think there is a little girl or boy in all of us,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>(US$1 = S$1.41 = 0.65 STG)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
