<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5150" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Pesticide shares pulls Egyptian market to new high.</title>
<headline>Pesticide shares pulls Egyptian market to new high.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in newly privatised Kafr el-Zayat Pesticides and Chemicals jumped 62 percent on the Egyptian stock exchange on Wednesday on rumours of a takeover bid, brokers said.</p>
<p>The shares traded at a consistent 47 pounds in hundreds of transactions throughout late trading after closing at 29 pounds on Tuesday, the Capital Market Authority (CMA) said.</p>
<p>One broker said it was not immediately clear if the people behind the alleged takeover bid were already buying or if people were merely speculating on expectations of a bid.</p>
<p>The state sold about 390,000 of the shares at 29.00 pounds each earlier this month in an operation which put 65 percent of the firm in private hands. More than 18,000 of them changed hands in the frantic trading on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The performance of the shares help lift the CMA overall index to a new 17-month high of 233.78, from 233.55 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Volume was a heavy 40.20 million pounds ($11.8 million), dominated by Kafr el-Zayat and the big flour mills.</p>
<p>North Cairo Flour Mills extended its gains, closing 0.50 pounds up at 92.00. But Central Egypt Flour Mills ran out of steam, ending 0.25 down at 24.25 pounds.</p>
<p>The CMA index for openly traded firms fell to 334.98 poimts from 337.35 points on Tuesday. The index for the rarely traded &quot;closed&quot; firms rose to 160.97 from 160.08 points.</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +20 2 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
