<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5154" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan riots shake business sentiment.</title>
<headline>Jordan riots shake business sentiment.</headline>
<byline>Suleiman al-Khalidi</byline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan's business community said on Wednesday last week's bread riots shook investor confidence but the government is unlikely to backtrack on market reforms despite the heavy political cost.</p>
<p>Businessmen said while the troubles added uncertainty over the country's long-term economic outlook, the government's tough handling so far shows determination to push on with radical IMF-backed economic reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors were buoyed by the resolve the government showed to go ahead with economic reforms despite the political costs,&quot; said Ziad al-Basha, securities manager at the British Bank of the Middle East.</p>
<p>The Amman stockmarket, already suffering from lack of cash liquidity and little institutional support, has fallen by just under one percent since the two days of rioting but brokers say most investors remain in a wait-and-see mood.</p>
<p>Demand for the dollar, a traditional safe haven currency, has also increased, reflecting investors' jitters. Bankers say the Central Bank has offered dollars to exchange dealers to buttress the dinar, effectively pegged since last November at around 0.708 dinars to the dollar.</p>
<p>But so far businessmen are betting on the government's success in quelling unrest in the southern city of Karak, triggered by a doubling of bread prices this month and worsening economic hardship in the poorer south.</p>
<p>Hamdi al-Tabaa, head of Jordan's Businessmen's Association, said the government has to act fast to boost private sector investments to generate new jobs and absorb thousands of fresh graduates, whom the state sector can no longer employ.</p>
<p>&quot;The riots have added uncertainty but the government should take heed by reviewing obstacles to investment by reducing the role of the government in the economy,&quot; Tabaa said.</p>
<p>Some say the government's promise to confront protesters with an &quot;iron fist&quot; could backfire and lead to more unrest.</p>
<p>&quot;If they cannot maintain stability investors will get worried, but if the government overcomes this and moves ahead it could turn to its advantage,&quot; said a businessman who has worked in both private and state sectors.</p>
<p>Officials argue that the government's pressing on with the bread price hike signalled to the kingdom's creditors and donors it would not backtrack on IMF-directed reforms, including privatisation and streamlining a bloated public sector employing half the 900,000 workforce.</p>
<p>The riots have also brought home the urgency of tackling grinding poverty in desolate semi-arid areas that have fed the tension that exploded into violence on the streets. The World Bank puts unemployment at 20 percent of the workforce and official figures classify 25 percent of the 4.2 population as living in poverty.</p>
<p>Businessmen talk of need for action to tackle the growing social divide, the lack of equal opportunities, and minimal foreign investments by reducing red-tape and improving business confidence that will encourage projects in the more depressed regions of the country.</p>
<p>This will help job-generating investments to raise the private sector's share of the state-dominated economy, straddled with a $7.6 billion debt burden which outweighs Jordan's $6.4 billion GDP.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
