<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5157" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwait jumbo loan payments on schedule - bank.</title>
<headline>Kuwait jumbo loan payments on schedule - bank.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kuwait is on schedule in paying off a $5.5 billion sovereign loan and the outstanding principal of $1.57 billion is expected to be cleared by the end of 1996, the country's largest commercial bank said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The oustanding principal balance is now $1.57 billion, which should be fully repaid with the remaining two instalments scheduled for September and December of this year,&quot; National Bank of Kuwait said in a quarterly economic review.</p>
<p>The Kuwaiti government borrowed the money to help pay costs of reconstruction following Iraq's 1990-91 occupation. By mid-1995 Kuwait had paid about $1 billion in interest on the facility, analysts say.</p>
<p>At that time the loan, arranged by J.P. Morgan and Co , was the largest ever made to a sovereign state. The main lending banks came from five main markets -- Japan, France, Germany, the United States and Arab countries.</p>
<p>Kuwait's Central Bank Governor, Sheikh Salem Abdul-Aziz al-Sabah, was quoted by state-owned Kuwait News Agency in October 1995 as saying Kuwait would not borrow from the international markets again.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
