<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5159" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: FEATURE - Saudi airline polishes image, restructures.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Saudi airline polishes image, restructures.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Flag carrier Saudi Arabian Airlines Corp is polishing up its image and restructuring its organisation to turn the Middle East's biggest airline into an attractive commercial operation ahead of eventual privatisation.</p>
<p>The 51-year-old state firm has a new corporate identity and a fresh coat of paint on its fleet. It has hired image and management consultants and decided on a new name -- Saudi Arabian Airlines, no longer Saudia.</p>
<p>The oldest and biggest Gulf Arab carrier, with 12.5 million passengers annually, is spending $6 billion on 61 new state-of- the-art U.S. aircraft. Deliveries are due to start in 1997.</p>
<p>It has promised better service on board its current 109- strong fleet and vowed to turn the losses suffered for more than a decade, mainly due to subsidised fares, to profits.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now making a new start embracing every aspect of the airline's operation, aims, strategies, plans and programmes, fleet and route network,&quot; director general Khaled Ben-Bakr said, unveiling the carrier's new corporate identity in July.</p>
<p>&quot;We have restructured our organisation to make it more dynamic...with rapid response to market demands and customers' needs, able to work on a commercial basis,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Service on board the Saudia is similar to that on other airlines. &quot;It is pretty standard, but there aren't too many frills,&quot; said one business traveller.</p>
<p>Commercialisation is seen tied to a larger private sector role, which Saudi Arabia says in its five-year development plan to 2000 is one of the transport sector's top priorities.</p>
<p>&quot;Saudia is going to do it professionally and by the book. They are really trying to gain the confidence of the public so people will elect to fly on Saudia as a first choice and, if the opportunity arises, people will invest in Saudia,&quot; said leading Saudi economist Ihsan Bu-Hulaiga.</p>
<p>&quot;They have decided to operate Saudia as a business and the top man is an ex-professor and is systematic,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ben-Bakr joined Saudia in 1994 from King Fahd University.</p>
<p>&quot;They are commercialising and preparing for privatisation,&quot; said a Saudi analyst of the airline with projected revenue and spending of 8.48 billion riyals ($2.26 billion) this year.</p>
<p>&quot;But things take time. As Prince Sultan said they first must make it profitable and attractive to investors,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Last October Saudi Arabia signed the $6 billion contract for Boeing Co and McDonnell Douglas Corp jets. At the time Saudi Defence and Aviation Minister Prince Sultan said the deal was important &quot;because we are going to privatise it soon&quot;.</p>
<p>But analysts say privatisation is still some years off and will probably not occur until the new fleet has been paid off.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be gradual. They will probably privatise some supporting services and outsource some activities to contractors. Later on...shares in Saudia will probably be sold to the (Saudi) public,&quot; said Bu-Hulaiga.</p>
<p>He said one likely option was to split up the organisation into independent companies of various specialisations. The companies could then be offered separately to the the public.</p>
<p>Analysts said the carrier had the tricky task of getting a balance between providing reasonably-priced domestic airfares in the kingdom -- where cities are scattered over a 2.2 million square km (850,000 square miles) area -- with showing a profit.</p>
<p>&quot;The airline still has an important socio-political role,&quot; said an economist based in the kingdom, where a generous welfare system has been in place since the early oil boom years.</p>
<p>&quot;No figures are given but one can infer that Saudia has negative cashflow, hence the continuous support of the government,&quot; said one analyst, adding easy repayment terms for jet fuel was another form of government support.</p>
<p>Industry executives say up to 70 percent of the airline's operations are domestic and 30 percent international, but almost three-quarters of income is generated on international routes.</p>
<p>&quot;Domestic flights are cheap. It costs about $30 from here (Dhahran) to Riyadh (380 km or 230 miles away),&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Last year's 10 percent increase in economy class and 20 percent rise in first class fares to its 25 domestic stations is a start, but analysts see the 52 international routes remaining the major profit-earners, helped with the new long-range fleet.</p>
<p>&quot;Saudi Arabia is strategically located, it is the site of Moslem holy places which millions of people visit every year. The local population is huge and is growing fast, which must be good for the future of the airline,&quot; one explained.</p>
<p>The population of about 18 million, six million of whom are expatriates, is forecast to grow at 3.0-4.0 percent until 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;If it wants to prosper and to survive Saudia needs to compete domestically and outside,&quot; said Bu-Hulaiga, adding airlines in the region needed to join forces among themselves and with foreign operators, and enter into code-sharing alliances.</p>
<p>He said he expected the domestic Saudi market, where the airline has a monopoly, to open to competition in 10-15 years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
