<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5166" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. announces safety recall of school buses.</title>
<headline>U.S. announces safety recall of school buses.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. safety officials on Wednesday announced that school bus makers Blue Bird Body Co. and Harsco Corp. would recall a total of 11,500 buses that do not meet federal fuel system integrity standards.</p>
<p>National Highway Traffic Safety Administrator Ricardo Martinez said that during crash tests, a 1995 Blue Bird &quot;All American&quot; bus and a 1995 Wayne Co. &quot;Lifestar&quot; bus exceeded the maximum federal allowance fuel leakage.</p>
<p>A NHTSA official said Wayne had since gone pout of business and that Harsco agreed to take responsibility for the recall of the Wayne buses.</p>
<p>The official said that since the NHTSA was not aware of any crashes involving the models in which there was a fuel system fire, the buses should continue to be used until the companies had developed mofifications to remedy the problem.</p>
<p>Martinez emphasised that the risk of fatal injury to children in a school bus was four times less than in a passenger car, making the school bus one of the safest forms of ground transportation.</p>
<p>Once the modifications were developed, the NHTSA said, buses would be repaired at no cost to the owners.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I31000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
