<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5169" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S., China trade frictions to rise with defict.</title>
<headline>U.S., China trade frictions to rise with defict.</headline>
<byline>Donna Smith</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>China looks set to replace Japan as the biggest source of U.S. trade deficits and commercial frictions that Washington may find far more difficult to resolve, trade analysts say.</p>
<p>The Commerce Department reported this week that for the first time, the U.S. trade deficit with China in June surpassed the shortfall with Japan.</p>
<p>Economists said they expect China to top the monthly list periodically in the future as the U.S. shortfall with Japan shrinks and the imbalance with China grows.</p>
<p>&quot;In the long term, China is going to be our No. 1 problem,&quot; said Norwest Corp. chief economist Sung Won Sohn. &quot;And the problem with China is that they operate by a completely different set of rules. The concept of a free and open market is alien to them.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of Commerce Mickey Kantor blamed the shortfall on closed markets and Chinese trade policies that maximize exports while limiting imports.</p>
<p>Kantor said he did not expect to see a deficit this year with China much higher than the $34 billion shortfall last year, but that the administration was not happy with the trend.</p>
<p>&quot;Because of discrimination against U.S. goods in the Chinese market, we need to make more progress,&quot; he said. &quot;We need to make our trade agreements work.&quot;</p>
<p>The United States and China moved to the brink of a trade war earlier this year over what Washington said was Beijing's failure to enforce a 1995 agreement to protect copyrights and other intellectual property from rampant piracy. The dispute was resolved when China promised to beef up enforcement.</p>
<p>Trade analysts say they expect to see more such disputes with China as Washington presses Beijing to open markets to more U.S. good and even out the balance of trade.</p>
<p>The United States, they said, has some leverage in those disputes because it represents China's largest market. But they also argue that Beijing's leverage is growing as the United States becomes more dependent on China as an inexpensive source of a growing variety of consumer goods including textiles, shoes, toys and electronics.</p>
<p>In the long run, analysts said, it is in the interest of the United States for China to join the World Trade Organisation (WTO). Beijing wants to join the global trade system as a developing nation that would enjoy more lenient rules. Washington, noting the huge size of the Chinese economy, has objected and insisted China join the world body on more commercially acceptable terms.</p>
<p>Analysts said it is also in the long-term interest of China to join the global trading body if it wants to continue to attract foriegn investment and be assured of continued access to U.S. markets.</p>
<p>&quot;In order for China to attract foreign investment at the levels it must in order to continue to grow and deal with the demands of a huge populace, it has to be a full member of the global trading system,&quot; said David Rothkopf, a former Commerce Department official.</p>
<p>But Kenneth DeWoskin, a China expert at the University of Michigan, said the Chinese may have lost interest -- at least for now -- in joining the global trading forum because of the cost in terms of economic reforms that would be required in order to become a member and because they no longer fear losing U.S. Most Favoured Nation status.</p>
<p>During this year's debate on China's MFN, a number of key lawmakers made clear they would like to end the annual ritual and make the status permanent next year. The MFN status allows Chinese goods to enter the country at the same low tariffs granted most other trading nations.</p>
<p>&quot;The big benefit of joining the WTO is access to the North American Market -- and they have that -- and slighly improved access to Europe and Japan,&quot; DeWoskin said. &quot;But the cost is very high.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
