<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5170" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chrysler still seen as top choice for UAW target.</title>
<headline>Chrysler still seen as top choice for UAW target.</headline>
<byline>David Lawder</byline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chrysler Corp. remains the front-runner for the United Auto Workers' long-awaited choice Thursday of a strike target for labour negotiations with the Big Three U.S. automakers, industry observers said.</p>
<p>Chrysler, Ford Motor Co. and General Motors Corp. have all been lobbying hard to be selected as the target, which would allow them to craft an agreement that meets their needs and sets the pattern for the others to follow.</p>
<p>The UAW's decision, to be announced after a major meeting of the union's bargaining committees Thursday, will shift the industry's triennial contract talks affecting some 400,000 hourly workers into high gear.</p>
<p>&quot;This is really where the negotiations start,&quot; said Harley Shaiken, a labour relations professor at the University of California-Berkeley.</p>
<p>The UAW's labour contract with the Big Three expires Sept. 14. Talks began in June.</p>
<p>Shaiken said he favours Chrysler as the target because it is expanding and does not face the same need to slash costs and shed thousands of parts-making jobs that GM does to become competitive.</p>
<p>UAW President Stephen Yokich has said job security is his top priority in the new contract.</p>
<p>&quot;Chrysler offers an easier target up front,&quot; Shaiken said. &quot;Whoever the target is, the toughest issues will be at GM.&quot;</p>
<p>Some leaders of UAW locals also say they believe the union would be wise to bargain with Chrysler first, cement the pattern at Ford and tackle GM last.</p>
<p>Whitey Hale, president of UAW Local 326 at GM's Delphi Interior and Lighting Systems plant in Flint, Mich. -- a plant that GM has put up for sale  -- said the union could quickly find itself in a major national strike if it targets GM.</p>
<p>GM stood its ground in March in a 17-day strike over outsourcing -- giving work to outside companies --  at two Dayton, Ohio, brake plants, which shut down the automaker's North American operations and cost it $900 million.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it probably will be Chrysler,&quot; Hale said. &quot;You don't really want to get tangled up at GM. There are too many problems at GM.&quot;</p>
<p>Chrysler, which has not been the target in 23 years, is flush with cash, the most profitable of the Big Three and eager for labour peace.</p>
<p>&quot;We'd like to see that pattern fit our situation as opposed to somebody else's,&quot; Chrysler Chairman Robert Eaton said Tuesday, explaining his desire for Chrysler to be the target.</p>
<p>But the automaker's announcment Wednesday of $380 million in new investment in South America caused UAW bargainers to storm out of the Chrysler negotiating room because they thought it would cost U.S. jobs, officials said.</p>
<p>Chrysler spokesman Tony Cervone, said the tiff did not derail talks at the automaker, which explained that new truck and Jeep production in Brazil and Argentina would lead to more U.S. jobs. &quot;It seems like they were satisfied. They're meeting again today,&quot; he said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Ford, the target in the 1993 talks, remains a dark horse, but analysts say the automaker's cooperative relationship with the union could prove attractive to UAW leaders. Ford has shown some willingness to encourage its suppliers to allow the UAW to organise their plants, which could help stem the UAW's membership decline.</p>
<p>Analyst Joseph Phillippi of Lehman Brothers said he believed it will be easier for the UAW to give much-needed special consideration to GM if the union reached agreements with Chrysler and Ford first.</p>
<p>Process improvements at GM will cut assembly hours for cars and parts, leaving the automaker with thousands of excess workers over the next few years. Many of those will retire over the next several years, and the UAW may allow GM not to replace them in exchange for some restrictions on outsourcing, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;They have to cut a deal with GM on one issue -- managing attrition over the next five or six years,&quot; Phillippi said.</p>
<p>The UAW is picking the target about 10 days earlier than normal this year, giving itself more time to resolve contentious issues without a strike.</p>
<p>Another new twist is increased cooperation with the Canadian Auto Workers union.</p>
<p>CAW President Buzz Hargrove said the two unions were exchanging more bargaining than in the past, and he will participate in meetings Thursday that will determine the UAW's target. The CAW usually chooses a different target than the UAW.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
