<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5178" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYCE prepares to revive potato futures.</title>
<headline>NYCE prepares to revive potato futures.</headline>
<byline>Allan Dowd</byline>
<dateline>PORTLAND, Maine 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The potato is poised to return to agricultural high finance nearly two decades after it was forced out of the world of commodities trading.</p>
<p>The New York Cotton Exchange expects to win regulatory approval this month for a Sept. 17 start of trading of futures and options contracts for the humble spud, according to an exchange representative.</p>
<p>Organisers of the proposed market are confident it is safeguarded against the problems that bruised and then scandalised the old Maine potato futures market in the 1970s and rocked the New York Merchantile Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;There's been an evolution in the futures industry as a whole since that time,&quot; said Tim Barry, an NYCE economist. &quot;The exchanges and government regulators have a much greater ability to track the market positions of participants to ensure they perform their contract obligations.&quot;</p>
<p>An inability to meet contract obligations was one of the problems that plagued the Maine potato futures market. In 1971, a trader with gambling connections was fined. In 1976, a group defaulted on $4.25 million in contracts.</p>
<p>Three years later, the New York Merchantile Exchange was forced to suspend trading on potato futures and liquidate agreements after inspectors rejected so many truck loads for bruises that contracts could not be fulfilled.</p>
<p>The NYCE stresses its proposed market is very different from the old one.</p>
<p>By placing delivery points in several potato growing regions -- and having tighter inspection requirements at each one -- the exchange believes it has overcome deficiencies in the old market, which allowed delivery only in Maine.</p>
<p>NYCE-approved delivery points will be available in Idaho, Maine, Oregon, Washington, Colorado, California, Wisconsin and, for July contracts, in Texas and New Mexico. These areas produce more than 90 percent of the U.S. potato crop.</p>
<p>&quot;We're spreading out the deliverable supply such that we should minimise anything happening that impacts one area (from) having an overly large impact on the whole contract,&quot; Barry said.</p>
<p>Bruce Huffaker, editor of the Idaho-based North American Potato Marketing Newsletter, says the NYCE has &quot;worked very hard to blunt criticism&quot; by stressing differences between this market and the old one.</p>
<p>&quot;There are still people who are very opposed to trading potato futures contracts (and) some of them harken back to the problems with the Merchantile Exchange contract,&quot; Huffaker said.</p>
<p>The NYCE hopes it can develop the market to a daily trading level of about 1,500 contracts after the first year, but Huffaker thinks growers' concern about the makeup of the proposed contract may have been underestimated.</p>
<p>NYCE had originally expected to begin trading in late May, but the start was delayed while the proposed contract was revised to make it all U.S. No.1 Russet Burbank potatoes and to allow for a wider range of potato sizes.</p>
<p>&quot;(The changes) allow the contract to better reflect the actual price movement over more of what a grower grows and what a processor or a consumer uses,&quot; Barry said.</p>
<p>The NYCE officials plan to tour the Western potato growing regions in the next few weeks to promote interest in the market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORTLAND, Maine"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
