<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5180" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tosco turning a profit at former BP unit.</title>
<headline>Tosco turning a profit at former BP unit.</headline>
<byline>Ransdell Pierson</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tosco Corp., through a combination of tough management and good luck, is expected to turn a profit at its Trainer Township refinery, where British Petroleum failed, industry analysts said.</p>
<p>Tosco, considered by many as the Cadillac of independent refiners because of its consistent profitability and bargain-basement acquisitions, aims to add the 185,000-barrel-a-day unit, formerly known as Marcus Hook, to its list of successful turnarounds.</p>
<p>Connecticut-based Tosco bought the Pennsylvania plant from British Petroleum last February, but it was mothballed before the transfer when Tosco and BP's union workers failed to agree on terms to cut staff and end longstanding work rules.</p>
<p>Last month, after getting the results of an engineering study by Bechtel Corp., Tosco offered to reopen the refinery -- but only if members of the Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers Union agreed to the same terms they rejected late last year.</p>
<p>The union is expected to vote later this month and, if agreement is reached, Tosco hopes by next summer to restart the plant, which is located near Philadelphia.</p>
<p>Doug Terreson, a Morgan Stanley analyst, said timing may prove ideal for Tosco because he expects industry refining margins to show &quot;material improvement&quot; within the next 12 to 18 months.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to see 20 percent to 30 percent improvements in margins, so if the refinery comes on line next summer, Tosco should be a prime beneficiary,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;They could probably recoup their investment in three years,&quot; he said, referring to the $60 million Tosco paid for the refinery and the right to sell gasoline under the BP brand at 500 jobber-owned BP stations on the East Coast.</p>
<p>In a similar 1993 deal, Tosco paid only $20 million for BP's 90,000-bpd Ferndale refinery north of Seattle, aquiring BP's 500-station Northwestern gasoline marketing network in the process.</p>
<p>While the refining industry has been squeezed in recent years, Tosco has remained way out ahead of the pack. Its return on equity last year was an impressive 16.32 percent, better than the industry average 9.54 percent and a significant improvement on the S&amp;P 500's average 14.26 percent.</p>
<p>Before being mothballed, the Trainer refinery cranked out 105,000 bpd of gasoline, about 13 percent of the 760,000 barrels produced each day on the gasoline-hungry East Coast.</p>
<p>Solomon Brothers analyst Paul Ting noted Tosco already owns the 230,000-bpd Bayway refinery in Linden, N.J., the largest refinery on the East Coast. It bought the large refinery from Exxon Corp in 1993 for $175 million.</p>
<p>&quot;When you put the (Trainer) refinery and Bayway together, you will have cost-saving synergies and critical mass,&quot; Ting said, with both refineries able to coordinate their product slates and use the same East Coast retail outlets.</p>
<p>Tosco has said it aims to increase profits at Trainer by reducing throughput to 150,000 bpd -- upping the production of high-value, clean-burning gasolines while reducing the slate of heavier fuel oils.</p>
<p>A Tosco spokesman told Reuters that BP couldn't make a profit at the Trainer refinery in part because poor logistics made it difficult to shift crude and refined products around the site.</p>
<p>BP concedes that it didn't make a profit in any of its last four full years of ownership.</p>
<p>&quot;They had to perform a ballet to move things around, which costs more money,&quot; the Tosco spokesman said, adding Tosco intends to cure the logistics problem as part of its planned $50 million Trainer modernisation programme.</p>
<p>&quot;They got a great deal on the Trainer refinery. They bought it for less than its scrap-metal value,&quot; said another analyst familiar with Tosco's operations.</p>
<p>&quot;Now they'll take down the bad units and re-tweak its good units,&quot; he predicted.</p>
<p>&quot;As an independent refiner, Tosco doesn't have a large overhead structure. So they can make decisions fast and act fast and change product slates at the drop of a hat,&quot; the analyst added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
