<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5182" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. deficit up in July but trend is down.</title>
<headline>U.S. deficit up in July but trend is down.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The government's spending deficit doubled in July from a year earlier, the Treasury Department said Wednesday, but was headed down for the full 1996 fiscal year.</p>
<p>The monthly shortfall between spending and revenues was $27.1 billion last month, up from $13.6 billion a year earlier.</p>
<p>However, several special factors were at play last year that had the effect of temporarily lowering the monthly deficit in July.</p>
<p>The government moved some military and other spending normally scheduled for July 1 back to June 1995, which reduced July spending requirements. As well, there was a one-time boost to revenues in July 1995 from the sale of broadcast licenses.</p>
<p>Analysts said the long-term trend for the deficit remained positive.</p>
<p>So far in the first 10 months of fiscal 1996, which ends Sept. 30, the total deficit dropped 25.6 percent to $102.1 billion from $137.2 billion in the comparable first 10 months of fiscal 1995.</p>
<p>The Clinton administration forecast last month that the full fiscal 1996 deficit will drop to $117 billion from $163.9 billion for the full 1995 fiscal year.</p>
<p>Kathleen Stephansen, an economist with Donaldson, Lufkin and Jenrette Securities Corp. in New York, said the July deficit figure was &quot;very benign and fits well with the approximate $120 billion total set for the full year.&quot;</p>
<p>She added that a relatively strong economy has created brisk revenues through taxation for the government, as has a runup in stock market prices this year, which generated profits that are subject to taxes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
