<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5187" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: No indication of widespread aflatoxin problem - USDA.</title>
<headline>No indication of widespread aflatoxin problem - USDA.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. Agriculture Department official said Wednesday there was no sign of any widespread problem with aflatoxin in U.S. corn grown in Texas and surrounding states.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no indication of any widespread or regionalized problem,&quot; said the official, who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;There's always a farm here or there that does harvest their corn and may have some aflotoxin but there's no sign at all of any outbreak,&quot; the official said.  </p>
<p>Concerns were raised on Tuesday by reports from the University of Texas of high levels of aflatoxin contamination in corn harvested along the Texas Gulf Coast.</p>
<p>Corn containing aflatoxin, a potent carcinogen, in excess of 20 parts per billion (ppb) is barred by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration from human consumption and levels exceeding 300 ppb are barred from livestock use.</p>
<p>The USDA official said looking at Texas and Arkansas there were spots where a farm had had a problem with aflatoxin but said that was typical.</p>
<p>The official stressed the situation was nothing like years past when Texas and other states had been quarantined because of aflatoxin problems.</p>
<p>The USDA official also noted that much of the Texas corn crop had been plowed under due to the drought.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
