<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5188" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: A game where nothing seems normal.</title>
<headline>A game where nothing seems normal.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A few decades in the future, being &quot;normal&quot; is going to seem pretty weird.</p>
<p>A greenish haze will block the sun. People will be required to spend most of their time watching an endless array of commercials and monster truck rallies on TV. A police squad of &quot;Norm Troopers&quot; will relentlessly track down and jail anyone foolish enough to have an independent thought.</p>
<p>That's the setting for &quot;Normality,&quot; the new CD-ROM computer game from Interplay (DOS, $50).</p>
<p>You play the role of ace slacker Kent Zontal, who has just gotten out of the Neutropolis city slammer for whistling an unapproved tune. Outside your grungy apartment, there's a Norm Trooper waiting to haul Kent back to jail if he doesn't hear him doing some heavy-duty channel surfing.</p>
<p>While in jail, Kent received a mysterious note suggesting there might be a group trying to overthrow the evil forces that rule Neutropolis. The only way to find them is to get out of the apartment.</p>
<p>That's only the first in a long line of challenges in &quot;Normality.&quot; Along the way, you must discover a unique blend of coffee, unlock a deeper meaning in an espresso machine, outwit a secretary who believes everything she reads and figure out the purpose of the strange device that drops out of the sofa when Kent accidentally breaks it.</p>
<p>The graphics are first-rate, the virtual reality system lets you walk just about anywhere, the puzzles are challenging enough to keep players occupied for many days and the premise is delightfully bizarre.</p>
<p>But &quot;Normality&quot; is limited in the number of sound cards it can use and won't work at all on machines with a 486-SX chip.</p>
<p>Also, the game gets a little sloppy as it progresses.</p>
<p>At one point, I was told Kent couldn't lift a fire extinguisher because it was full. But, miraculously, he could carry it around after he filled it with paint.</p>
<p>Throughout a visit to a laboratory, Kent is wearing a Norm Trooper uniform, except in one scene where his uniform vanishes and he's dressed in his street clothes.</p>
<p>It's times like this when you wish someone had called the Continuity Police. It's not normal. But then, that's what this game is all about.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>&quot;Road Trips Door-to-Door&quot; (TravRoute Software, Windows95, $50) promises to give maps and directions from virtually any street address to any other address in North America. It generates directions with a minimum of fuss and offers turn-by-turn instructions on how to get from Point A to Point B.</p>
<p>But if you follow the program's advice too closely, you may find yourself making a trip to the hospital.</p>
<p>To test the programme, I mapped out some trips to and from my home. There were a few surprises. If I'm coming back from New York, the programme said, I should jump off the Interstate more than five miles before my normal exit so I could go along all the congested back roads. The programme called this the &quot;preferred route,&quot; even though nobody in their right mind would take it.</p>
<p>Only when I asked for the quickest path did the programme come close to suggesting the correct way. But then it told me to take an exit that doesn't exist. The only way to follow the recommendation would be to drive over a concrete barrier, crash through a guardrail and fly off an overpass.</p>
<p>Assuming I survived, I'd probably need some medical attention. No problem! &quot;Door-to-Door&quot; can get me to the emergency room, but only if I'm Captain Kirk and I can beam down. When I looked at the map showing my path, I noted that the green line I was supposed to follow inexplicably ended, reappeared a quarter of a mile to the east and told me to follow non-existent roads.</p>
<p>Then I asked myself, what if I craved a doughnut on the way to the hospital? So I asked the programme for directions to a doughnut shop. &quot;Door-to-Door&quot; dutifully sent me the wrong way down one of Providence's busiest one-way streets.</p>
<p>&quot;Door-to-Door,&quot; which will eat up at least 50 megabytes on your hard drive, warns that a route it suggests &quot;may be incomplete or inaccurate in some cases.&quot; And I did find cases where it recognised one-way streets.</p>
<p>It will probably give you decent directions in most cases. Just make sure your insurance payments are up to date.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
