<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5190" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ex-Perot boss listed as &quot;stand-in&quot; running mate.</title>
<headline>Ex-Perot boss listed as &quot;stand-in&quot; running mate.</headline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reform Party presidential candidate Ross Perot has listed James Campbell, his former boss, as a &quot;stand-in&quot; vice presidential candidate on forms filed with the Federal Election Commission, a Perot spokeswoman said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Sharon Holman said Campbell's name was used only because a name was required in the federal filing made in Washington and there was no chance he would be Perot's running mate.</p>
<p>Campbell, now retired and living in Los Angeles, was Perot's supervisor when he was a salesman years ago at the computer giant IBM.</p>
<p>&quot;This is just to hold the space for when we have the person who will be the vice president,&quot; Holman said.</p>
<p>In Perot's 1992 run for the presidency, James Stockdale was used as a stand-in candidate in federal filings and eventually became his running mate.</p>
<p>Holman said it was not yet known when the vice presidential nominee would be selected. &quot;We're simply going to take our time and move forward and make right decisions, not rushed ones. I don't have any timelines, but I know it's top priority for us,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
