<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5195" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: H&amp;R Block posts $52 million loss.</title>
<headline>H&amp;R Block posts $52 million loss.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo.</dateline>
<text>
<p>H&amp;R Block Inc. said Wednesday it lost about $52 million in its fiscal first quarter, almost half due to its ownership of CompuServe Corp., the online computer service that it is divesting.</p>
<p>Block, the country's largest tax preparation firm, said it had a consolidated net loss of $52.2 million, or 50 cents a share, in the three months ended July 31.</p>
<p>That loss, which included a net loss of $23.7 million from CompuServe, compared with net income of $5.2 million, or 5 cents a share, in the same period last year, when the online service contributed $27 million in net income.</p>
<p>Block, which is spinning off the struggling online service into a separate company, said CompuServe's results were treated as discontinued operations for both periods.</p>
<p>On Tuesday CompuServe, the nation's the No. 2 online service, reported a $29.6 million first-quarter loss, blaming a decline in subscribers and spending on a new family-oriented service and other improvements.</p>
<p>Block began the CompuServe divestiture in April with an initial public offering of 18.4 million shares of CompuServe common stock at $30 a share, which reduced Block's ownership to just over 80 percent.</p>
<p>The company, which is based in Kansas City, Mo., plans to complete the distribution of its remaining ownership interest in CompuServe to its shareholders on or about Nov. 1.</p>
<p>The giant tax preparation and financial services firm said its increased loss for the period was primarily due to higher expenditures on employee compensation, rent and other expenses, plus costs associated with its acquisition of other tax businesses.</p>
<p>In addition, the company noted, it traditionally posts losses in its first three quarters while most of its revenues from the tax business are generated in its fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Block's stock lost 87.5 cents to $27.50 on the New York Stock Exchange in early afternoon trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
