<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5199" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Where are the great Democratic Party orators?. [CORRECTED 18:02 GMT]</title>
<headline>Where are the great Democratic Party orators?. [CORRECTED 18:02 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Michael Posner</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Where are the great Democratic orators of yesteryear?</p>
<p>The party that produced former New York Gov. Mario Cuomo, former Texas Gov. Ann Richards and late Congresswoman Barbara Jordan is searching for new talent.</p>
<p>Of course President Clinton himself is capable of delivering a memorable address. But beyond him the ranks are thin and the keynote speaker at next week's Democratic National Convention in Chicago will be Evan Bayh, the little-known governor of Indiana.</p>
<p>Bayh will be hard pressed to eclipse Republican convention showstoppers including Elizabeth Dole's talk-show like testimonial to her husband Bob Dole, retired Gen. Colin Powell's baptism speech into Republican ranks and Representative Susan Molinari's keynote talk featuring her three-month-old baby.</p>
<p>&quot;Bayh is no Cuomo but a different kind of speaker,&quot; said one Democratic convention planner, recalling Cuomo's soaring keynote oratory in the 1984 convention that nominated Walter Mondale (corrects from &quot;soaring oratory of 1984 nominating Michael Dukakis&quot;).</p>
<p>Four years ago, Bayh delivered a short, punchy Democratic convention speech that few can even recall. The keynote address on Tuesday, intended to serve as a clarion call for the party to rally behind Clinton and Vice President Al Gore, is a chance for Bayh to show his stuff on the national stage.</p>
<p>Convention planners hope he will be a bright new light in the Democratic horizon although he is little known nationally. The son of former Indiana Sen. Birch Bayh and the youngest governor in the nation when first elected in 1988 at age 32, Bayh has won a strong reputation as the sort of moderate, mainstream executive the Democrats want to highlight -- a good fiscal manager, education leader and promoter of business.</p>
<p>Convention planners will show off a few others as rising leaders as well even though Republican congressional and state election wins in 1994 have cut into Democratic ranks. These include Detroit Mayor Dennis Archer and Representative Barbara Kennelly of Connecticut, co-chairs of the party platform committee; Albuquerque Mayor Martin Chavez; California Representative Nancy Pelosi and various challengers for Republican congressional seats.</p>
<p>Well-known Democrats will also be featured including first lady Hillary Rodham Clinton, as will party regulars such as Senate Democratic leader Tom Daschle of South Dakota, House Democratic leader Richard Gephardt of Missouri, Louisiana Sen. John Breaux and Illinois Sen. Carol Moseley-Braun.</p>
<p>Some of the spell-binding speakers of the past are expected as well, including Massachusetts Sen. Edward Kennedy and civil rights activist Jesse Jackson, who rarely fail to bring Democrats to their feet.</p>
<p>But their best political days may be gone and election losses also have left a trail of fallen stars such as Cuomo and Richards, who were trounced in the 1994 Republican sweeps.</p>
<p>Even former Representative Dave McCurdy of Oklahoma, a once bright prospect who gave a nominating speech along with Cuomo for Clinton in 1992, lost a 1994 Senate election.</p>
<p>Democratic planners also want non-politicians on the programme -- what the Republicans called &quot;real people&quot; -- who can talk about Clinton administration initiatives such as the family leave plan and the continuing growing economy.</p>
<p>These include Sarah Brady, the gun-control advocate and wife of former Republican President Ronald Reagan's press secretary James Brady, who was left partially paralysed from gunshot wounds in the 1981 assassination attempt on Reagan.</p>
<p>Actor Christopher Reeve, paralysed from a horse riding accident and an advocate of medical research, also will speak.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
