<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5202" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: 1968 convention marked sea-change in U.S. politics.</title>
<headline>1968 convention marked sea-change in U.S. politics.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Stern</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 1968 Democratic Convention marked a sea-change in U.S. politics, ending the rule of party bosses at presidential nominating conventions and bringing an era of social protest to a bloody climax.</p>
<p>For millions watching on television, the tumult inside and outside the convention hall blurred into one image.</p>
<p>Perhaps for the last time, a political convention was an unorchestrated event and participants in the history-making clashes between police and anti-Vietnam War demonstrators felt that effective change seemed possible.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a feeling in the Sixties that you could make a difference, that you could take on the issues of war and peace, of rights and representation. That sort of feeling is not present now,&quot; said John Shultz, author of two books on the convention and a professor at Chicago's Columbia College.</p>
<p>In the tightly scripted &quot;dramas&quot; organised for this year's conventions, Republican nominee Bob Dole arrived in San Diego by boat and President Bill Clinton scheduled a whistle-stop train trip to Chicago from Washington.</p>
<p>America's political scene in 1968, strained by three years of divisive war in Vietnam, was still dominated by an old guard represented by outgoing President Lyndon Johnson and local party bosses like Chicago Mayor Richard J. Daley.</p>
<p>Antiwar upheavals had already led Johnson to abandon his re-election effort and the 1968 election debacle, including revulsion over the Chicago events, sparked reforms that broke the grip of bosses like Daley over the nomination process and gave women and minorities a larger voice in the Democratic party's makeup and policies.</p>
<p>Starting in 1972, candidates focused on state primary elections that apportioned convention delegates. Daley himself was ousted from the Democrats' 1972 convention by the party's newly dominant left wing.</p>
<p>In 1968, Democratic nominee Hubert Humphrey was heckled for weeks after the Chicago convention and lost by a razor-thin margin to Richard Nixon. From 1968 to 1988, Republicans won five of the six presidential elections.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a sea change, the pivotal moment for American politics,&quot; said Don Rose, who served as a press liason for one of the protest groups at the 1968 convention. &quot;The behaviour of the city administration plunged a deep wedge into the (Democratic) party, splitting the party in such a way as to cost them their majorities for the next 20 years.&quot;</p>
<p>In Chicago, delegates dedicated to pro-peace candidates Gene McCarthy and the assassinated Robert Kennedy challenged the party's stance on the war and the overall status quo. A dramatic moment came when black civil rights leader Julian Bond marched a mixed-race Georgia delegation onto the floor.</p>
<p>Behind the scenes, then-Vice President Humphrey bowed to pressure from Johnson just an hour before a vote on the Vietnam War policy plank in the party platform. In an effort to stifle dissent, Daley flooded the convention hall with security men who made the proceedings eerily similar to what was happening out on the streets.</p>
<p>On tear gas-choked Michigan Avenue, thousands of protesters fought police and National Guardsmen, a shocking sight for an estimated 90 million Americans watching on TV.</p>
<p>The demonstrators were part of the huge generation of relatively well-educated baby boomers coming of age in a decade of civil rights victories in the South. Some were stoked by revolutionary ideas, culled from an explosion of cheap paperback books on philosophy. Others felt threatened by the thought of being drafted to serve in the war.</p>
<p>But when Nixon halted the draft in 1973, the &quot;culture of protest&quot; fizzled and fragmented. The American left fell into disarray, riven by &quot;identity politics&quot; -- or, &quot;who's the most oppressed&quot; -- said David Horowitz, a radical journalist turned author. Today the most intense U.S. demonstrations usually emanate from the political right, in anti-abortion protests.</p>
<p>Although the current younger generation displays a cynical apathy toward politics, that may change. &quot;There is a kind of ferment going on, there is something stirring, and it has the beginnings of something political,&quot; Shultz said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is concern about issues that affect them directly (such as government backing for student loans). If something isn't done about some of these issues, we could have some pretty wild conventions in the year 2000.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
