<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5204" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New Democratic convention, new Mayor Daley.</title>
<headline>New Democratic convention, new Mayor Daley.</headline>
<byline>Michael Conlon</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Another Democratic convention in Chicago, and another Daley as mayor.</p>
<p>But the inevitable comparisons that will be made next week when the Democratic National Convention returns to Chicago for the first time since its disastrous 1968 meeting may not run very deep.</p>
<p>&quot;I think most would say its a different time and a different place,&quot; Ed Burke, a veteran Demcratic alderman, said of the Daleys, father and son, and their city. &quot;The old politics is gone. New politics is in vogue.&quot;</p>
<p>At the time of the 1968 gathering Richard J. Daley, who died in office in 1976, had been mayor for 13 years. He sat atop an old-style party system that drew its power from the block level on up, demanding and rewarding loyalty.</p>
<p>Richard M. Daley, 54, eldest of the senior Daley's seven children, has been in office since 1989. By the time he took over City Hall, the town and its politics had been irrevocably changed by its first black mayor, Harold Washington, who had worked for reform and openness.</p>
<p>The younger Daley himself was elected on a promise of reform and outreach. In 1968 he was still a law school student. The most famous image of his father that year came from the convention floor where TV cameras caught him trying to shout d Abraham Ribicoff of Connecticut as he backed the protest candicacy of Sen. George McGovern.</p>
<p>To many it appeared Daley had called Ribicoff a &quot;f---ing Jew.&quot; Others said he did not use that phrase. But the scene, played alongside shots of antiwar demonstrators on the streets elsewhere in town, summed up the divisiveness that engulfed the party and its nominee, Hubert Humphrey.</p>
<p>&quot;Daley was obviously trying to suppress every kind of protest and debate,&quot; author and Columbia College writing professor John Shultz recalled. &quot;He wanted just what the Democrats and Republicans want now: A vivid snorefest.&quot;</p>
<p>While Daley was caught up in the tumult inside the convention hall, the head-bashing of protesters on the streets by Chicago's blue-helmeted police was blamed directly on him. His autocratic approach to the rule of law was epitomised four months earlier during inner-city rioting when he suggested police shoot to kill arsonists and maim looters. Daley aide Earl Bush later blamed the press: &quot;They should have printed what he meant, not what he said.&quot;</p>
<p>The younger Daley shares his father's blunt speaking style and penchant for misstatements and has proven just as popular with the voters who reelected him to a second full term in 1995. He also shares his father's satisfaction with his current job, with no ambitions for higher office.</p>
<p>Daley will serve as an honorary co-chairman of next week's convention. For at least four years he had wooed party leaders to bring the event back to Chicago, not so much to bury the past, he has said, but because conventions are good business.</p>
<p>&quot;This convention is not about politics, it's about civic pride,&quot; said his brother, William Daley, who is co-chairing the event.</p>
<p>Conventions themselves have changed in the 28 years since the Democrats last met in Chicago. &quot;Many would say conventions have become irrelevant in terms of real effect and are a vestige of a time gone by,&quot; Alderman Burke said. &quot;But they are still a celebratory gathering of party adherence.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
