<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5207" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Kmart looks for improved second half.</title>
<headline>Kmart looks for improved second half.</headline>
<dateline>TROY, Mich. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kmart Corp. Wednesday reported a profit for the second quarter as the struggling retailer's sales improved and costs declined.</p>
<p>Kmart posted net income from continuing operations of $34 million, or 7 cents per share, in the quarter ended July 31, compared with a loss of $54 million, or 12 cents a share, in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>The 1995 results included a loss from discontinued operations of $76 million.</p>
<p>Total sales for the Troy, Mich.-based company's 2,143 Kmart stores and 168 Builders Square retail outlets edged down 1.5 percent to $8.31 billion from $8.44 billion. Total comparable store sales rose 1.6 percent.</p>
<p>Comparable sales for U.S. Kmart stores increased 2.2 percent for the quarter, and 2.9 percent for the first six months of 1996, both below Kmart's expectations.</p>
<p>Kmart operates 134 stores in international markets.</p>
<p>The retailer's gross margin dropped to 21.7 percent of sales from 22.5 percent, as Kmart marked down prices to clear seasonal and discontinued merchandise and sold its auto service business.</p>
<p>Selling, general and administrative expenses fell by $117 million for the quarter.</p>
<p>The second-quarter results reflected weak performance at Kmart's Canadian operation, the company said.</p>
<p>Kmart said it expected sales of appliances and consumer electronics, as well as apparel and linens, to improve in the second half of the year.</p>
<p>During the second quarter, Kmart completed $4.7 billion in new financing through a three-year $3.7 billion credit facility and a $1 billion public offering of convertible preferred securities.</p>
<p>Kmart's stock rose 25 cents to $10.75 on the New York Stock Exchange at mid-morning.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TROY, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
