<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5210" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton to offer new tax breaks to business - aides.</title>
<headline>Clinton to offer new tax breaks to business - aides.</headline>
<byline>Steve Holland</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton is likely next week to propose tax breaks for businesses that hire people off the welfare rolls, aides said.</p>
<p>In doing so, Clinton will resist the political appeal of a broad tax cut and concentrate instead on smaller, more affordable tax incentives for the middle-class and poor.</p>
<p>&quot;He's not going to propose a tax cut like a Bob Dole tax cut that blows up the deficit. It's not in the cards,&quot; said a White House official involved in the planning.</p>
<p>Dole put some life into his flagging Republican campaign against Clinton this month by saying he would cut federal income taxes across the board by 15 percent if he is elected president on Nov. 5. The announcement helped pull his campaign out of its doldrums and put the ex-senator within striking distance of Clinton in public opinion polls.</p>
<p>Aides said the White House was in high gear looking at more targeted, affordable tax incentives beyond Clinton's already announced ways to help families pay for rising costs of higher education.</p>
<p>One likely proposal would put meat on the bones of the welfare reform bill that Clinton was to sign on Thursday. Liberal Democrats were unhappy that the bill would end federal assistance to many poor people.</p>
<p>Clinton was considering a plan to offer tax breaks to businesses that hire people on welfare as a way to create jobs in the inner city, aides said. He was to announce the plan either in his Aug. 29 convention speech in Chicago accepting his party's nomination for a second four-year term or on his four-day whistlestop train tour to the convention.</p>
<p>&quot;What the president has to do is show that we can implement welfare reform effectively, and one of the things we have to do is create jobs for those welfare-dependent mothers who have to move from welfare to work,&quot; an aide said.</p>
<p>&quot;So you can obviously expect a lot of focus on job creation and particularly job creation in inner-city areas where there are concentrations of welfare recipients.&quot;</p>
<p>Another idea that has been discussed is liberalising rules that limit homeowners' ability to avoid the capital gains tax on the sale of their home.</p>
<p>Clinton's caution on broad tax cuts reflects concern that such a move would explode the budget deficit or require deep cuts in programmes for the poor and elderly. Democrats dismiss the Republican argument that cutting taxes would trigger economic growth, which would generate new tax revenues.</p>
<p>&quot;That is the wrong thing for America,&quot; Clinton said in New York on Sunday. &quot;I won't do that.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole has accused Clinton of engineering &quot;the largest tax increase in the history of the world&quot; when he raised taxes in 1993. The president said on Sunday he had no intention of raising taxes if re-elected but could not rule out the possibility of doing so in an emergency.</p>
<p>White House officials do not see Clinton's convention speech as an answer to Dole's nearly hour-long address in San Diego but rather as a chance to offer his vision of the next four years leading up to the turn of the century.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to put forward a very concrete set of proposals, let the American people look at them and think about them, as the president makes the case of why four more years of his leadership will be good for the American people,&quot; said White House spokesman Mike McCurry.</p>
<p>White House officials are hoping Clinton's train ride to Chicago, which begins on Sunday in West Virginia, will generate interest in the convention. They plan to have Clinton announce new proposals at stops along the way.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
