<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5217" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed stays put, leaving economists pondering its next move.</title>
<headline>Fed stays put, leaving economists pondering its next move.</headline>
<byline>Chris Stetkiewicz</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The decision of the Federal Reserve's Federal Open Market Committee to leave interest rates unchanged has left economists and analysts pondering what the central bank might do next.</p>
<p>Some analysts said that while Fed policy-makers on Tuesday resisted pressures to raise short-term rates, economic data over the coming weeks may force them to raise rates later this year.</p>
<p>Other analysts -- and some former Federal Reserve officials -- said that mixed economic data and a touch of political pressure might be the recipe for steady monetary policy through the November presidential election.</p>
<p>Members of the Federal Open Market Committee are expected to be careful as they juggle upcoming data, such as the August employment report due Sept. 6, and the vicissitudes of the political race for the White House.</p>
<p>&quot;Every member of that FOMC is going to be very careful,&quot; said Preston Martin, a former Fed vice chairman who is now chairman of HomeVest Financial Services Inc. in San Francisco. &quot;That means that the odds build up about no action. No action is safer than some action.&quot;</p>
<p>The Fed has held its target for the federal funds rate -- the rate banks charge each other for overnight loans -- at 5.25 percent since January.</p>
<p>However, recent economic indicators suggest consumer spending and the labour market were heating up in August, although signs of a slowing manufacturing sector were seen as offsetting the growth signals.</p>
<p>&quot;Before the Fed can either raise or cut interest rates in an election year, they better have a solid economic justification for doing that,&quot; said Sung Won Sohn, chief economist at Norwest Corp. &quot;Without the justifications, they would rather wait,&quot; he said after Tuesday's decision.</p>
<p>Some analysts said the latest string of economic indicators painted a blurry economic outlook, meaning the Fed will probably stand pat until the picture clears.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they will stand still and await clarification on where the economy is going,&quot; said Lyle Gramley, a former Fed governor and currently an economist at the Mortgage Bankers Association of America.</p>
<p>How long could that take? &quot;Well, I think the Fed will move sometime later this year... It may well be until very late this year, possibly even December, before the Fed knows for sure whether it needs to move or not,&quot; Gramley added.</p>
<p>Gramley believes the U.S. economy is fundamentally strong but said &quot;some tightening will be necessary down the road.&quot;</p>
<p>Martin agreed that the Fed is likely to remain on hold, &quot;not just because of the election, but because this (current economic scene) is a central banker nirvana.&quot;</p>
<p>Martin cited a positive inflation outlook as one of the main reasons keeping the Fed on hold over the next few months.</p>
<p>But not everyone agrees with that scenario.</p>
<p>&quot;My guess is (a rate rise) is going to be right back on tap after the August data start coming out,&quot; said Salomon Brothers economist Brian Jones. &quot;There is a good chance they'll go (up) at the September 24 FOMC meeting.&quot;</p>
<p>Despite signs of strong economic growth, inflation remains quite low historically, and Fed leaders have refrained from raising rates in the absence of more troubling data. But upcoming employment data could change all that, analysts said.</p>
<p>Persistent job growth threatens to shatter the economy's recent low-inflation trend and the Fed will not stand idly and watch that happen, they said.</p>
<p>Critics initially blasted the Fed for failing to raise rates at its July FOMC meeting when a report just two days later showed 239,000 new jobs created in June.</p>
<p>But a month later the July report showed a decline to 193,000 in new non-farm payrolls and, perhaps more important, a slight drop in average hourly earnings.</p>
<p>Fed officials had predicted a slowdown in real gross domestic product from the robust 4.2 percent second-quarter clip. The dip in payroll growth suddenly made that forecast look brilliant, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;So far the Fed has done the right thing by keeping its powder dry,&quot; Schlossberg said. &quot;There is still a risk the Fed could fall behind the curve, but right now it looks like the economic slowdown is happening.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
