<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5220" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Novell Inc unveils intranet product.</title>
<headline>Novell Inc unveils intranet product.</headline>
<dateline>BURLINGAME, California 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Novell Inc. Tuesday unveiled its new IntranetWare software, intended to establish the computer networking company in the growing market for internal corporate networks known as intranets.</p>
<p>Novell has been a leader since 1983 in conventional networking software but has fallen behind Netscape Communications Corp and Microsoft Corp. in the competition for intranets, private networks which function like the Internet's Web.</p>
<p>&quot;With IntranetWare, Novell opens our product line and (our) 55 million customers to the future of networking,&quot; said Novell Chairman Robert Frankenberg. The company provides software for an estimated 1 million networks with 55 million users.</p>
<p>Orem, Utah-based Novell's IntranetWare is a full-service intranet and Internet access product for businesses of all sizes. It builds on the features of the company's Netware 4.11 network software.</p>
<p>The latest product offers a high-performance Web browser and server software -- the software needed to access and publish Web pages --  and is designed to take advantage of the latest standards for surfing the Internet and using far-flung corporate networks.</p>
<p>Novell did not give prices for the software, which it plans to release in the fall.</p>
<p>The company said IntranetWare is compatible with existing Novell network software and will allow companies to preserve previous investments in network software.</p>
<p>Novell said it will concentrate on IntranetWare in the future but will continue to sell and support NetWare 4 and NetWare 3.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BURLINGAME, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
