<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5223" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Times reported the following business stories on Wednesday:</p>
<p>* Venezuela is becoming Coca-Cola Co country as the company forms an alliance with PepsiCo Inc's longtime bottler there.</p>
<p>* Federal Reserve leaves interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>* Early call on AT&amp;T Corp management change shows the power of Wall Street analysts to roll stock.</p>
<p>* Westinghouse Electric Corp's CBS announces it will start a cable channel.</p>
<p>* U.S. trade deficit shrinks in June, but gap with China surges.</p>
<p>* The Dow Jones Industrial Average rises 21.82 to 5,721.26. The Nasdaq composite index falls 6.24 to 1,124.67.</p>
<p>* Leading retailers, including AnnTaylor Stores Corp, report gains in profits.</p>
<p>* President Bill Clinton signs legislation raising the minimum wage to $5.15 an hour from $4.25.</p>
<p>* Sprint Corp will start offering Internet services to its customers.  </p>
<p>* Shares in British Airways fall after a report that &quot;open sky&quot; talks between Britain and the United States were stalled.</p>
<p>* Thursday's meeting of Germany's Bundesbank on interest rates is being watched by politicians, business leaders and government officials across Europe.</p>
<p>* Wine lovers start comparing vintages over the Internet.</p>
<p>* Britain's  More O'Farrell advertising agency opens first office in the United States.</p>
<p>* Consumer Reports magazine says two sport utility vehicles, Isuzu Motors Ltd's Trooper and Acura SLX, can overturn during quick turns at low speed and demands a recall.</p>
<p>* New Jersey officials say organized crime has infiltrated the health-care industry.</p>
<p>* Sequana Therapeutics Inc and the Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center agree to form a joint venture to do cancer research.</p>
<p>-- New York newsroom, (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
