<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5232" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: SLOVAK FINMIN DENIES MULLING CAR DUTY BEFORE '97. [CORRECTED 15:50 gmt]</title>
<headline>SLOVAK FINMIN DENIES MULLING CAR DUTY BEFORE '97. [CORRECTED 15:50 gmt]</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Slovak Finance Ministry on Wednesday said it was not considering re-imposing customs duties on imports of new cars with engines of 1,500cc before next year.</p>
<p>Last September, Slovakia temporarily abolished its 19 percent customs duties on imports of new medium-sized cars, though officials said they would review the policy at the beginning of 1997.</p>
<p>Local media, however, have recently reported that the ministry was considering re-implementing the tariffs as a way to help stem the country's widening trade deficit.</p>
<p>&quot;The ministry has not so far prepared any proposal concerning re-imposing custom duties on import of medium-sized cars before the planned date, which is January 1, 1997,&quot; Daniela Zvoncakova of the ministry's press department said.</p>
<p>The abolition of the duties was an attempt to aid Slovaks looking to buy medium-sized cars and help eliminate the number of older cars from the road.</p>
<p>Economics Ministry spokesman Jozef Sucha told Reuters the country's trade balance would be the main criterion in considering any re-imposition of the duties at the end of 1996.</p>
<p>Slovakia posted a trade deficit of 26.975 billion crowns in the first half of the year, a dramatic reversal of the 1.8 billion crown surplus posted in 1995 (corrects from &quot;the first half of 1995&quot;).</p>
<p>Sucha said he did not expect the zero-level tariff to be maintained after January 1, but would not elaborate on the possible extent of its re-imposition in 1997.</p>
<p>No figures on total imports of new cars with 1,500cc engines for the first half of this year are available, but analysts said car imports comprise a large part of the country's overall imports.</p>
<p>Earlier this year the government decided to completely abolish a widely criticised import surcharge effective January 1, 1997 after heavy pressure from western economic organisations, such as the WTO, and the European Union.</p>
<p>-- Peter Laca, Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
