<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5242" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Ex-Nazi slaves protest at shareholders' meeting.</title>
<headline>Ex-Nazi slaves protest at shareholders' meeting.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former slave workers sold by the Nazis to chemical giant IG Farben over 50 years ago protested outside a shareholders' meeting on Wednesday to press for compensation from the firm's assets.</p>
<p>About 70 survivors and supporters said that IG Farben, which produced Zyklon B gas for the death camps, should complete its dissolution and give the former slave workers an ample share.</p>
<p>The shareholders' meeting was held by IG Farben in Abwicklung -- which means &quot;in liquidation&quot; -- a shell company set up in 1955 to dispose of remaining assets of the chemical giant broken up after Germany's defeat in World War Two.</p>
<p>The company decided last August to pay ex-slave labourers a share of any assets it reclaimed in east Germany.</p>
<p>But groups representing ex-slave labourers want it, as well as BASF, Hoechst and Bayer, which all took over parts of the IG Farben empire, to admit moral responsibility for the deaths of thousands of workers and to pay compensation.</p>
<p>&quot;I have a message to the shareholders...they should realise that their company was part of the murdering machine of the Third Reich,&quot; said Rudi Kennedy, 68, who survived IG Farben's slave labour camp in the Auschwitz concentration camp complex.</p>
<p>&quot;We were all 'people who were condemned to death' -- we were not forced labour. As long as we were able to work, we lived.' said Kennedy, a Jew from Wroclaw now in Poland, who was deported to Auschwitz aged 15 and recruited there to work.</p>
<p>Kennedy said he had returned to Germany for the first time since he emigrated to London in 1946 and that he had come expressly to call for the dissolution of IG Farben, which ran its own forced labour camp at Monowitz-Auschwitz.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to publicise the scandal that this IG Farben is allowed to exist...the more pressure we put on the company, the more likely the company's assets will be liquidated,&quot; Peter Gingold, a member of the Association of Victims of the Nazi Regime told Reuters Television in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Police officers formed a chain to stop the protestors from blocking the way for shareholders. Some survivors, who were sold by SS concentration camp guards, to IG Farben shouted &quot;SS&quot; at German police as they tried to hold them back.</p>
<p>Many German firms used slave labourers during the war but IG Farben, the world's fourth largest company until the end of the war, stood out by running its own concentration camp at Monowitz in Poland to ensure a regular supply of labour.</p>
<p>The liquidation has been taking so long because of the company's fight to reclaim assets seized at the end of the war. Its shares, or liquidation certificates, are still traded.</p>
<p>IG Farben in Abwicklung paid 30 million marks ($20 million) in compensation to the Jewish Claims Conference in 1957 but no compensation has been paid on an individual basis or to ex-slaves in Poland.</p>
<p>Survivors' groups say that was insufficient. IG Farben in Abwicklung paid its shareholders more than 100 million marks in dividends in 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
