<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5248" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Daimler,AT&amp;T to bid for German phone licence-report.</title>
<headline>Daimler,AT&amp;T to bid for German phone licence-report.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>AT&amp;T Corp and the Debis unit of Daimler-Benz AG are planning to form a consortium to bid for the E2 cellular phone licence in Germany, a weekly magazine said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>According to a report in the Wirtschafts Woche business magazine, Debis, AT&amp;T and its European partner Unisource NV are working together on a bid for the licence, which will be awarded next year.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T was not immediately available for comment and a spokesman for Debis called the report speculation.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not commment on speculation,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>The report was released ahead of publication on Friday.</p>
<p>Industry observers have long thought it likely that Debis would make a bold step into the telecoms arena ahead of liberalisation of the sector in 1998.</p>
<p>Although it does not operate a network of its own, Debis's Debitel unit is Germany's biggest mobile telephone service provider with some 700,000 customers under contract.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T and Unisource, an alliance of telecommunications companies from Sweden, Spain, Switzerland and the Netherlands, are also forming a fixed-wire network venture with Mannesmann .</p>
<p>They will jointly buy a stake in DBKom GmbH, the communications subsidiary of railway Deutsche Bahn AG.</p>
<p>The magazine report said the fact that AT&amp;T was teaming up with Daimler was bad news for utilities Viag AG and RWE AG.</p>
<p>Those companies are forming an alliance with British Telecom and hope to win the E2 licence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
