<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5250" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian bourse to slip independent of Buba move.</title>
<headline>Belgian bourse to slip independent of Buba move.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bel-20 share index  .BFX could face fresh selling pressure on Thursday independent of whether the Bundesbank cuts its 3.20 percent repo rate at Thursday's council meeting, dealers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Expectations of a cut were dealt a blow earlier on Wednesday when a German research institute issued a report showing strength in the German economy, reducing the need for the Bundesbank to ease credit to give economic activity a boost.</p>
<p>&quot;There was disappointment,&quot; said a trader. &quot;The majority now believes the Bundesbank will do nothing tomorrow.&quot; The pessimism helped push the Bel-20 down 0.35 percent to end at 1,753.92.</p>
<p>Weakness on Wall Street, and a dollar which lost ground on the mark as the views on a repo rate cut shifted, added further downside pressure, dealers said. The main fallout from the strong report was seen on the bond market, however.</p>
<p>One trader said both a rate cut and a lack of one would be negative for shares. &quot;In both cases investors will conclude that the rate-cutting cycle in Europe is over.&quot; European central banks as a rule closely follow Bundesbank decisions.</p>
<p>A lack of news and volume for a conclusive break upwards meant the Bel-20 would remain stuck below resistance at 1,760 and 1,770 points for now.</p>
<p>One trader recommended investors sell puts and calls in the current environment of weak price action.</p>
<p>Another said he was telling clients to stay in cash in anticipation of lower prices for quality shares such as steel and wire products share Bekaert.</p>
<p>A third said news of a pick-up in the German economy was not all bad. Germany is a major export market for Belgium. He noted inflation was still relatively low and that the bourse need not fear stable or even slightly higher interest rates.</p>
<p>He advised clients to shift into cyclicals.</p>
<p>Financials were hit hardest by the weakened rate cut hopes -- Fortis AG was down 0.3 percent, Generale Bank lost 1.1 percent. But Kredietbank was up 0.4 percent in a recovery from recent weakness. &quot;Financials did have a nice run in recent months,&quot; a trader observed.</p>
<p>Few shares stood out in the holiday-thinned morning session.</p>
<p>Glass maker Glaverbel shed 35 francs at 3,385 in a correction after rising from 3,100 on August 5.</p>
<p>Chemicals and drugs UCB firm continued a rally on solid half year results and bullish prospects, which began on July 24 at 54,100 and took it to 61,800 at today's close.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
