<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5261" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish shares dip in wake of company reports.</title>
<headline>Swedish shares dip in wake of company reports.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's sharemarket slipped in lively trade on Wednesday amid a barrage of mixed company results for the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>The general index closed 0.04 percent lower at 1951.98 after fairly strong turnover of 3.8 billion crowns.</p>
<p>The forestry index gained 0.57 percent after MoDo reported a better-than-expected half year profit of 1.66 billion crowns. MoDo closed two crowns higher at 183 crowns.</p>
<p>Swedish vehicle maker Volvo fell 1.5 crowns to 136.5 crowns despite a stronger-than-forecast result. It posted a pre-tax profit of 3.86 billion crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;The report was despite everything slightly positive,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>The banking sector slipped 0.47 percent and was one of the poorer performing sectors during the day.</p>
<p>Nordbanken rose 0.5 crowns to 137 crowns after posting a rise in first half operating profit to 3.8 billion crowns. Foreningsbanken reported an operating profit of 524 million and closed 0.10 crowns higher at 22.80 crowns.</p>
<p>Insurer Skandia did not fare as well after reporting a first half pre-tax profit of 1.54 billion crowns. It fell 6.5 crowns to 157.5 crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;The report showed that the result and operating margins were under heavy pressure,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>Drugs major Astra gained two crowns during the day to close at 277 crowns and fellow bluechip, telecoms group Ericsson, slipped 1.5 crowns to 148 crowns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
