<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5263" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bunds to fall whether Bundesbank cuts repo or not.</title>
<headline>Bunds to fall whether Bundesbank cuts repo or not.</headline>
<byline>David Crossland</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bunds face an initial sell-off whether the Bundesbank cuts its repo rate or not on Thursday, analysts and dealers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But there was disagreement over whether a cut in the repo -- the central bank's main money market rate -- would be better or worse for Bunds in the medium term than a &quot;rates unchanged&quot; announcement.</p>
<p>Some said an unchanged repo would keep hopes of a future easing intact and may weaken other currencies versus the mark, thereby stoking demand for German debt.</p>
<p>Others said a small cut, of five basis points or 0.05 percentage point, would signal that rates were headed lower and thereby keep investors interested in the German market.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be profit-taking whatever happens tomorrow,&quot; said Helmut Kaiser, global markets bond analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>If the Bundesbank cuts the repo rate, dealers will follow the maxim &quot;buy on the rumour, sell on the fact&quot;, Kaiser said. If it holds the rate steady, the resulting disappointment will also provoke selling, he added.</p>
<p>Kaiser said any sell-off would at most push September Bund futures as low as 96.90, a technical support line which was likely to hold. That would be equivalent to a rise in 10-year yields to 6.40 percent from the current level of 6.34 percent.</p>
<p>Peter Kerger, portfolio manager at Credit Suisse Capital Management in Frankfurt, said a decision to keep the repo unchanged could hurt the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Doing nothing may be interpreted as meaning that there will be no more rate cuts,&quot; Kerger said. &quot;A five basis point cut would be a little more helpful.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition, an easing now would help reduce currency market tensions, Kerger said. &quot;If the Bundesbank waits, it may be forced to act later to save other currencies.&quot;</p>
<p>Kerger said any initial Bund decline following a rates unchanged announcement would be limited to 20 or 30 basis points.</p>
<p>September Bunds fell sharply, and the mark appreciated, this morning in response to a stronger-than-expected rise in the Ifo institute's business climate index which undermined hopes of an imminent repo easing.</p>
<p>The index for west Germany rose to 94.1 in July from 90.4 in June. Economists had expected a figure of around 91.0.</p>
<p>September Bunds fell as low as 97.45 on the DTB futures exchange, down 0.61 from Tuesday's close, in response to the news.</p>
<p>Dealers said hopes for a slight repo rate cut had been dampened but not dashed.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll see a sell-off in both cases,&quot; said Heinz Gunasekera, bond analyst at UBS in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>&quot;But an unchanged rate may be a little bit better for Bunds. There's a chance of currency tension and Bunds would be in favour because of their safe haven status.&quot;</p>
<p>Some analysts said the initial sell-off could be quite large because Bunds had risen rapidly in recent weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of people are overweight in Bunds,&quot; Gunasekera said.</p>
<p>Lothar Hessler, bond analyst at Trinkaus &amp; Burkhardt, said a cut would depress the long end of the bond market.</p>
<p>&quot;We'd see a slight rise in yields but nothing serious because the environment for bonds remains favourable. There is no sign of inflation and the economic upturn is modest,&quot; Hessler said.</p>
<p>Hessler predicted 10-year German bond yields would rise to 6.50 percent by the end of the year as the economy gradually gained pace.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
