<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5274" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Skandia shows 64 pct jump in H1 pretax.</title>
<headline>Skandia shows 64 pct jump in H1 pretax.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish insurer Skandia on Wednesday posted a strong improvement in profits for the first half of 1996, saying it expected its unit-linked life assurance business to show good growth for the rest of the year.</p>
<p>Skandia reported a pre-tax profit of 1.54 billion crowns ($233.5 million) for the period, a 64 percent jump on the 940 million reported for the first half of last year.</p>
<p>With the profit from non-life insurance virtually unchanged at 1.55 billion crowns, much of the improvement came from an increase to 811 million crowns in the profit from the life assurance business.</p>
<p>But more importantly, profits from investment income showed a substantial increase on last year's levels.</p>
<p>Investment income from the non-life business came to 1.47 billion crowns, up from 663 million in the same period last year.</p>
<p>This, combined with a fall in joint group operating costs, meant a surge in the non-technical result to 1.08 billion crowns from 161 million crowns last year.</p>
<p>Premium income declined seven percent in the non-life business to 10.62 billion, but on the life side unit-linked insurance enjoyed a 37 percent gain in premiums to 15.01 billion crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;Naturally, the strong result for our investment operations during the first half is gratifying. The steady growth of our unit-linked business is expected to continue during the rest of the year,&quot; Skandia CEO Bjorn Wolrath said in a statement.</p>
<p>Earlier on Wednesday, rival Trygg-Hansa posted a 27 percent increase in pre-tax profits to 1.52 billion crowns. This, too, was largely the result of improved investment income. ($ = 6.595 Swedish Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
