<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5286" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek stocks continue advance, end higher.</title>
<headline>Greek stocks continue advance, end higher.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek equities resumed Tuesday's runup trading firmer to close with gains of 0.96 percent as players reappraised positioning and reacted favourably to early elections next month.</p>
<p>&quot;The market prefers a compressed pre-election period rather than a prolonged one, as planning for the public and private sectors will not have to deal with a short 12-month horizon but look longer term,&quot; said broker Dimitris Paparistidis at Kappa Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The runup in equities is starting from very low levels. Couple this with improved macroeconomic indicators as we get closer to the implementation phase of key infrastructure projects and you have three reasons for the rise,&quot; He said.</p>
<p>Greek Prime Minister Costas Simitis will decide this week whether to call early elections next month, government spokesman Dimitris Reppas told reporters on Monday.</p>
<p>Based on Greece's constitution, elections must be held within a month from the time they are announced.</p>
<p>The Athens general share index finished 0.96 percent, or 8.74 points higher at 916.66 from Tuesday's 907.92 close after opening at 912.78 points. Turnover was 9.49 billion drachmas on volume of 4.02 million shares.</p>
<p>Gainers led losers 120 to 88 with 30 issues unchanged on 238 traded. Banks gained 1.28 percent, industrials ended 1.52 percent higher with construction rising 0.04 percent. Small-caps ended with gains of 0.22 percent at 81.41 on the parallel market index.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
