<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5289" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German DAX pressured as Ifo shakes rate hopes.</title>
<headline>German DAX pressured as Ifo shakes rate hopes.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares dropped in bourse trade on Wednesday after the closely-watched Ifo business climate index jumped in July, undermining hopes for an imminent cut in Germany's securities repurchase rate.</p>
<p>The blue-chip DAX index ended floor dealings down 16.52 points, or 0.65 percent, at 2,543.74 points, just above the low of 2,539.29 points hit by the IBIS DAX in the pre-bourse electronic session.</p>
<p>Prices took an instant dip after the early morning Ifo index report showed a rise to 94.1 in July from June's 90.4, far exceeding expectations. Share market activity was livelier than it had been for several days, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;I could hardly believe what I was seeing on the screen when I came in,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>A slew of disappointing corporate earnings reports also hurt the market.</p>
<p>Construction group Philipp Holzmann AG slumped 3.2 percent to 360 marks after it reported an 11.8 percent drop in output for the first six months of the year and said it expected a negative operating result for 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;We had expected a flat output number,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Diversified utility group Viag AG drifted lower to end down six marks at 560.50 marks amid mild disappointment at its report Tuesday night of a 21 percent drop in first-half pre-tax profit -- the lower end of expectations.</p>
<p>Steel and engineering group Fried. Krupp AG Hoesch-Krupp also dropped nearly two percent to 215.90 marks after predicting a difficult second half, which dealers said was interpreted as a profit warning.</p>
<p>Despite the strong Ifo report, most dealers were still expecting the repo rate to be cut by five to 10 basis points when the Bundesbank council meets on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;A small cut will keep the hopes for more significant cuts alive and will boost market sentiment. The big question will be, will it be enough?,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
