<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5290" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Deutsche Telekom shares seen around 33 marks.</title>
<headline>Deutsche Telekom shares seen around 33 marks.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's state-owned telecommunications group Deutsche Telekom AG on Wednesday released figures related to its listing which analysts said implied that the shares could be offered to individual investors at 33 marks each.</p>
<p>Chief financial officer Joachim Kroeske said that a relationship could be seen between the limit Telekom plans to set for private investment in the issue and the number of shares each person can buy at a special price.</p>
<p>Kroeske told journalists at a briefing that private investors would be allowed to buy a maximum of 300 shares at a special reduced rate and could invest up to 10,000 marks in Telekom shares.</p>
<p>Kroeske declined to give a figure, but added that the 10,000 mark limit and 300 share limit &quot;are in line with one another.&quot;</p>
<p>Nicole Cousins, telecoms analyst with Bank Julius Baer in Frankfurt, said a figure of around 33 marks was more or less in line with what market players were expecting.</p>
<p>&quot;I was expecting around 30 or 31 marks, so 33 marks is around what we were anticipating,&quot; Cousins said.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
