<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5293" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Volvo Truck says order book 46 pct down.</title>
<headline>Volvo Truck says order book 46 pct down.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The truck unit of Swedish vehicle maker AB Volvo on Wednesday said its order book in the middle of 1996 was 46 percent lower than a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The order backlog at June 30, 1996, was 46 percent lower than on the same date a year earlier due primarily to weaker order bookings in North and South America,&quot; Volvo's chief executive Soren Gyll said in the company's half-year report.</p>
<p>For the first half of 1996 Volvo Truck posted an operating profit of 1.08 billion crowns against 2.94 billion crowns a year earlier. Sales slipped 10 percent to 23.11 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Volvo said the world market for heavy trucks declined in the first half compared wtih a year ago and the total market in North and South America weakened perceptibly.</p>
<p>Gyll said earnings in Europe, where the market as a whole strengthened, were satisfactory but lower than a year earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;Operations in North America resulted in a substantial loss due largely to a smaller volume of sales and pressure on margins,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;A restructuring programme is under way but a significant loss is also anticipated in the second half of the year.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
