<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5311" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norway Bergesen sees mixed outlook for rest of 1996.</title>
<headline>Norway Bergesen sees mixed outlook for rest of 1996.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norway's largest shipping company Bergesen d.y. ASA on Wednesday forecast a mixed outlook for its businesses for the rest of the year despite a more than two-fold rise in operating profits in the first six months.</p>
<p>The group booked operating profits of 253 million crowns ($39.3 million) in the period to June 30, compared with 102 million crowns a year ago. Profit before tax amounted to 153 million crowns versus 264 million crowns.</p>
<p>The results fell below expectations of around 215 million crowns for half-year pre-tax profits.</p>
<p>&quot;The operating profit showed an improvement during the first half of 1996, even though the results in the second quarter were weak,&quot; Bergesen said.</p>
<p>&quot;Tanker results improved but not sufficiently to make a profit, while dry bulk made a good profit. The largest gas carriers improved...,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Gas carriers showed an operating profit of 244 million crowns, a rise of almost 25 percent from 196 million crowns in the 1995 period.</p>
<p>Bergesen said the largest gas carriers were expected to show results in the second half 1996 in line with the first half. For other gas carrier segments, however, the relatively weak market was expected to continue into the third quarter and profits for the year would be somewhat weaker compared with 1995, it said.</p>
<p>Tankers recorded an operating loss of 29 million crowns versus a loss of 161 million crowns, while dry bulk operating profits rose slightly to 34 million crowns from 29 million crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;Tanker rates are expected to stay on a relatively high level throughout the third quarter, but the trend for the fourth quarter seems to be more uncertain.</p>
<p>&quot;Dry bulk profits for the second half of 1996 are expected to be weaker than during the first half-year, because of increased operating costs due to the drydocking of two vessels,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>It added that it would take a loss of about 19 million crowns in the second half due to the sale of the probo vessels and of the gas carrier Helikon.</p>
<p>($ = 6.434 Norwegian Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
