<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5314" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares hurt by Ifo report at opening.</title>
<headline>German shares hurt by Ifo report at opening.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares took an early dip on Wednesday after the closely-watched Ifo business climate index rose sharply in July, partly undermining hopes for an imminent cut in Germany's securities repurchase rate.</p>
<p>The blue-chip DAX index started down 13.10 points, or 0.5 percent, at 2,547.16 points, having dipped as low as 2,539.29 points in the pre-bourse session.</p>
<p>Disappointing corporate earnings also hurt prices.</p>
<p>Construction group Philipp Holzmann AG slumped 3.7 percent to 360 marks -- the biggest decline of the day -- after it reported an 11.8 percent drop in output for the first six months of the year and said it expected a negative operating result for 1996.</p>
<p>Diversified utility group Viag AG dropped 4.50 marks to 562 marks amid mild disappointment at its report of a 21 percent drop in first-half pre tax profit -- the lower end of expectations.</p>
<p>Steel and engineering group Fried. Krupp AG Hoesch-Krupp also dropped nearly three percent to 214 marks after predicting a difficult second half, which dealers said was interpreted as a profit warning.</p>
<p>The Krupp report also sent shares in steelmaker Thyssen AG down 1.20 marks to 262.30 marks.</p>
<p>Despite the strong Ifo report, dealers were still expecting the repo rate to be cut by  five to 10 basis points when the Bundesbank council meets on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;A small cut will keep the hopes for more significant cuts alive and will boost market sentiment. The big question will be, will it be enough?,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
