<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5317" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Chirac, Juppe to discuss tax reform - paper.</title>
<headline>Chirac, Juppe to discuss tax reform - paper.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe and President Jacques Chirac will meet this weekend in the south of France where they are expected to discuss plans for major tax reform, newspaper Les Echos reported on Wednesday, quoting government officials.</p>
<p>The meeting will take place at the presidential summer retreat in Bregancon on the Riviera.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, finance minister Jean Arthuis promised taxes would be eased &quot;substantially&quot; during the first phase of tax reform in 1997, another newspaper, Le Figaro said.</p>
<p>The tax overhaul would &quot;be noticable for everyone paying taxes and notably for the most modest (earners),&quot; Arthuis was quoted as telling a local radio.</p>
<p>The five-year tax reform plan is to be presented to parliament in September.</p>
<p>Le Figaro quoted a close aide to Juppe as saying taxes would be eased in 1997 by around 20 billion francs, the figure initially expected, not the 15 to 18 billion francs reported earlier this week in another newspaper.</p>
<p>It appeared likely that many of the recommendations by the tax reform commission headed by a former head of the tax office, Dominique de La Martiniere, would be followed, Le Figaro said.</p>
<p>It said the government was also looking at the possibility of extending a 20 percent tax allowance to all taxpayers, regardless of income. At the moment just salaried workers enjoy the allowance.</p>
<p>Juppe's centre-right government, aiming to combine austere spending plans with tax reductions to lift the economy, has pledged tax cuts from 1997 but has not said how much they would be.</p>
<p>He pledged in June that taxes would be lowered over the next five years but said the move would be conditional on the government's capacity to control spending.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
