<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5322" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German retail unions deny decisive tactical split.</title>
<headline>German retail unions deny decisive tactical split.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unions representing German retail workers in a four-month-old pay dispute on Wednesday denied they had split decisively over tactics in regional talks and said they expected to resume their co-operation soon.</p>
<p>A split had appeared to occur Tuesday evening when the HBV service sector union pulled out of negotiations with shopowners in the state of North Rhine-Westphalia while the white-collar DAG opted to continue talks.</p>
<p>Both unions had been jointly negotiating a wage and work hours deal for the region's 450,000 retail workers, one of several local deals being hammered out in advance of November's liberalisation of shop hours.</p>
<p>In a German radio interview, HBV head Margret Moenig-Raane described the occurence as a &quot;summer storm ... not a change in climate&quot; and said she was confident that both unions would return to the negotiating table.</p>
<p>DAG official Holger Grape told German radio he hoped the HBV might rejoin talks as early as next week.</p>
<p>However Heinz Trompeter, negotiator for the employer side, said shopowners were currently focusing their hopes for a settlement on the DAG.</p>
<p>The HBV pulled out of talks after employers refused to accept its unexpected demand for extra compensation for night work. The DAG distanced itself from this demand.</p>
<p>Unions are generally seeking a deal similar to one struck in Rhineland-Palatinate which called for workers to get a 1.85 percent wage rise plus 20 percent extra time in lieu per hour worked after 6:30 p.m. weekdays and 2:00 p.m. Saturdays.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
