<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5331" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Krupp sees difficulty in 1996 second half.</title>
<headline>Krupp sees difficulty in 1996 second half.</headline>
<dateline>ESSEN, Germany 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>German steel and engineering group Fried. Krupp AG Hoesch-Krupp on Wedensday predicted business in the second half of the year would be more difficult than previously expected.</p>
<p>After reporting a fall in pre-tax profit for the first half of the year, Krupp said it still expected to remain profitable for the full year and to pay what it called an appropriate dividend on 1996 results.</p>
<p>&quot;The second half of 1996 will be generally more difficult than previously expected,&quot; Krupp said in a statement.</p>
<p>The company said it would continue to optimise its industrial portfolio and to rationalise.</p>
<p>Earlier, Krupp said group pre-tax profit in the first half of 1996 fell to 185 million marks from 223 million marks the year before.</p>
<p>It said all six of its business divisions were profitable in the first half. It attributed the profit fall to the weak overall economy, which had a strong impact on the steel industry and related sectors.</p>
<p>Group sales in the period rose one percent to 11.7 billion marks and orders were up two percent at 12.7 billion marks.</p>
<p>Of total investment in the first half, 1.1 billion marks were spent on acquisitions and 400 million marks on investment in plant. As a result, Krupp said financial debt rose to correspond with business volume.</p>
<p>The group workforce totalled 72,000 employees at the end of June, up 3,000 from a year earlier largely because of the takeover of Italian steel maker Acciai Speciali Terni and other acquisitions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ESSEN, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
