<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5337" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India committee to consider foreign media entry.</title>
<headline>India committee to consider foreign media entry.</headline>
<byline>Arindam Nag</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indian government plans to appoint a committee to help it consider whether foreign newspapers should be allowed to publish in India, a senior official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>N. Mohanty, a top-level Industry Ministry official, told Reuters after a news conference on foreign investment that Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's cabinet has asked the Foreign Investment Promotion Board (FIPB) to prepare a status paper on all aspects of the media.</p>
<p>&quot;The panel will come up with concrete proposals for foreign investments in (India's) media,&quot; Mohanty said.</p>
<p>Last week India rejected a proposal by Britain's Pearson plc, publisher of the Financial Times, to acquire an equity stake in an Indian newspaper company.</p>
<p>The move was in line with India's long-standing practice of barring foreign journals from publishing in the country.</p>
<p>The decision to turn down Pearson was taken after pressure from a few publishers, while several editors, journalists and even a number of publishers supported the plan, Mohanty said.</p>
<p>Foreign newspapers and journals are freely imported into India, but they cannot publish Indian editions.</p>
<p>Asked if the committee would consider the entry of foreign investments in the print media, Mohanty said: &quot;Today, I can subscribe to foreign newspapers published abroad, so why can't we have them here?&quot;</p>
<p>The committee will have members from the FIPB and will study various investment options in both electronic media, including radio and television, and print media, he said.</p>
<p>Mohanty said he could not say when the committee would be set up.</p>
<p>Pearson's proposal to acquire a stake in India's Business Standard Ltd won the approval of the FIPB but was shot down by the Cabinet Committee on Foreign Investment (CCFI).</p>
<p>The FIPB approval has touched off a heated debate over foreign media entry in India. Communists in the 13-party United Front of Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda joined opposition Hindu nationalists in criticising the approval.</p>
<p>--New Delhi Newsroom +91-11-301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
