<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5340" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Rao's party suspends ex-minister after raids.</title>
<headline>Rao's party suspends ex-minister after raids.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's Congress party has suspended the membership of former communications minister Sukh Ram after police filed a corruption case against him, the United News of India (UNI) said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The ex-minister's whereabouts remained a mystery on Wednesday, five days after raids on his homes in the capital New Delhi and in the northern state of Himachal Pradesh uncovered more than $1 million in cash.</p>
<p>No formal charges have been laid by the Central Bureau of Investigation (CBI) against the ex-minister, who oversaw an ambitious programme to privatise India's telephone services.</p>
<p>&quot;The Congress president (former Prime Minister P.V. Narasimha Rao) has put Mr Sukh Ram under suspension with immediate effect,&quot;  UNI quoted Devendra Dwivedi, a close Rao aide, as saying. It did not give further details.</p>
<p>The former minister has denied allegations by opposition political parties that he favoured a little-known firm from his home state, Himachal Pradesh, in the tendering process.</p>
<p>Sukh Ram lost his portfolio when former prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao's Congress party was defeated in general elections which ended in May.</p>
<p>A senior Department of Telecommunications civil servant has been arrested in the case and police have seized large amounts of cash and jewellery from her home.</p>
<p>Indian officials said help has been sought from the United States to find Sukh Ram, who was abroad for medical treatment during the raids.</p>
<p>Indian newspapers have variously said he is in New York, London or Houston undergoing heart surgery.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
