<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5343" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Fund buying buoys Bombay shares, index up 2.7 pct.</title>
<headline>Fund buying buoys Bombay shares, index up 2.7 pct.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bombay shares held strong gains at close on Wednesday boosted by fresh buying by domestic institutions and foreign funds, brokers said.</p>
<p>The 30-share Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) index firmed 90.27 points, or 2.72 percent, to a provisional 3,406.33 -- the day's highest level -- at close.</p>
<p>The 50-stock NSE index gained 24.56 points, or 2.51 percent, to a provisional 1,001.56.</p>
<p>The 500-share CRISIL index rose 13.34 points, 2.0 percent, to a provisional 679.79.</p>
<p>Unit Trust of India, the country's biggest investment institution, was a keen buyer, traders said.</p>
<p>The decision on Tuesday by U.S. Federal Reserve to keep interest rates unchanged was a &quot;morale booster&quot;, they said. Some Japanese and Hongkong-based funds were also hectic buyers.</p>
<p>Foreign funds favoured power and heavy engineering stocks, the traders said.</p>
<p>Tata Power firmed 8.25 rupees to 153 and BSES 7.0 to 187.50 while L&amp;T rose 5.75 to 247.50.</p>
<p>Auto stocks TELCO rallied 18 rupees to 483 and M&amp;M 4.75 to 339, but Bajaj Auto slipped 1.75 to 988.25.</p>
<p>Shares of petrochemicals major Reliance jumped 14.75 rupees, or 7.34 percent, to 215.75.</p>
<p>Colgate said it set first interim dividend at 1.6 rupees per a 10-rupee face value share for fiscal 1996/97 (April-March). In the previous year, the firm paid three interims of 16 percent each. The Colgate stock gained 5.50 rupees to 251.</p>
<p>ACC rose 128 rupees to 2,152.50, HDFC 30.75 to 2,657.75, Asian Paints 11.75 to 365.75, Grasim 13.25 to 429.25, SBI 6.75 to 273, TISCO 9.25 to 193, ICICI 6.75 to 76.50 and ITC 5.50 to 291.50.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
