<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5344" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India says most pending foreign projects cleared.</title>
<headline>India says most pending foreign projects cleared.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's Industry Minister Murasoli Maran said on Wednesday the United Front government had cleared most of the foreign projects awaiting approval when it came to power in June.</p>
<p>Maran told reporters the Foreign Investment Promotion Board (FIPB) had cleared 332 projects out of 496 since July 12, covering investments worth 90 billion rupees.</p>
<p>Maran said 43 projects have been rejected while a decision on others have been deferred pending clarifications.</p>
<p>The FIPB, the main clearing agency for foreign projects, was revamped and brought under the wings of the industry ministry after the new government came to power. FIPB was earlier under the prime minister's office.</p>
<p>&quot;Earlier the FIPB took three to four months to clear the projects, today it takes three to four weeks,&quot; Maran said.</p>
<p>Among the projects cleared in 10 meetings of FIPB was a $700 million investment plan of Coca Cola and a venture of German car maker BMW AG.</p>
<p>A decision on most of these projects got stalled in February when India began preparing for general elections held in April/May.</p>
<p>-- New Delhi newsroom +91-11-301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
