<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5350" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: FEATURE - Nissan joins battle for Pakistani car market.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Nissan joins battle for Pakistani car market.</headline>
<byline>Ovais Subhani</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Nissan Motor Co Ltd, eyeing Pakistan's growth potential and its protective tariffs, has become the latest foreign car-maker to build an assembly plant here.</p>
<p>&quot;The market for the class of cars we are making is approximately 15,000 to 20,000 (a year),&quot; Humayun Mufti, chief executive of Ghandhara Nissan Ltd, told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite a slight slowdown in the economy, the market is showing a growth rate of 15-to-20 percent a year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>By December, the company will roll out the first locally made passenger car, a 1,400cc Nissan Sunny, and it hopes to capture 20-to-25 percent of the market in the next 18 months.</p>
<p>Ghandara Nissan will get technical assistance and completely knocked-down (CKD) vehicle kits from Nissan Motor Co Ltd. It plans to produce 6,000 vehicles a year at its $15.5 million plant being built near Port Qasim in Karachi, Mufti said.</p>
<p>Mufti said 31 percent of the spare parts for the vehicles would be manufactured locally at first. That figure would rise to 45 percent within three years as required by the government.</p>
<p>Initially the plant will produce 3,600 cars and later 2,400 light commercial vehicles a year. The company plans to gradually increase capacity and production.</p>
<p>Suzuki, Toyota, Honda and Korea's Kia Motors have already established manufacturing bases in Pakistan.</p>
<p>Stocks analysts predict double-digit earnings growth over the next two years for Pak Suzuki, with a production capacity of 50,000 vehicles a year, Honda Atlas with 10,000, and Indus Motors with 20,000 Totoya cars.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall earnings are expected to increase as more and more investors are realising there is a turn-around in the car industry,&quot; automobile analyst Raza Nensey of KASB &amp; Co said.</p>
<p>He attributed the change in outlook to a two-year-old ban on used cars and the drying up of a glut caused by the import in 1991 of 65,000 duty-free cars intended to be sold as taxis.</p>
<p>The scheme, launched by former premier Nawaz Sharif, was scrapped when Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto took power in 1993.</p>
<p>Nissan will compete with Toyota and Honda for sales of more up-market models with engines of 1,300cc and above. Suzuki and Kia have concentrated on low-priced economy cars and light commercial vehicles with engines of 1,000cc or below.</p>
<p>Analysts estimate vehicle sales at 100,000 a year, of which 30-to-35 percent are passenger cars. They expect annual sales of medium-sized cars alone to reach 60,000 within four years.</p>
<p>Pakistan, with a population of more than 130 million, has just 5.41 cars per 1,000 people, up from 4.9 in 1991.</p>
<p>&quot;Natural population pressure and increase in personal wealth are likely to spur domestic demand,&quot; said Mudassar Malik, an analyst at brokerage house BMA Capital Management Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;Less than one percent of the population in Pakistan are car owners, compared to 10 percent in Thailand, 16 percent in the Philippines, 47 percent in Malaysia, 18 percent in Indonesia, and two percent in China. So we are really very much at the low end of the car-ownership percentile,&quot; Malik said.</p>
<p>Apart from growth potential, Pakistan offers cheap labour and relatively low production costs.</p>
<p>It also has tariffs aimed at protecting the domestic car industry. Imports of used cars were banned in 1994 and a tariff of up to 160 percent is required to import a new 1,600cc car. CKD car kits, however, carry an import duty of only 30 percent.</p>
<p>Pakistan belongs to the World Trade Organisation (WTO), which wants to end trade protectionism. But car-makers say the tariffs are vital to shelter the local automobile industry.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the only way and the only model whereby the developed countries have been able to build up their engineering industry,&quot; Mufti said.</p>
<p>Mufti said the WTO agreement allowed countries with balance of payments problems -- such as Pakistan -- to legally protect infant industries with &quot;reasonable&quot; tariff barriers.</p>
<p>He said a growing domestic car industry was essential for the growth of Pakistan's overall engineering industry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
