<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5351" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: BOXING-BOUDOUANI UPSETS VASQUEZ TO TAKE WORLD TITLE.</title>
<headline>BOXING-BOUDOUANI UPSETS VASQUEZ TO TAKE WORLD TITLE.</headline>
<dateline>LE CANNET, France 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Laurent Boudouani of France took the World Boxing Association junior middleweight title in style by knocking out holder Julio Cesar Vasquez of Argentina on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Veteran Vasquez, 30, who had only suffered two losses in a professional career spanning over 10 years and featuring 56 wins, was floored by a fierce right uppercut early in the fifth round.</p>
<p>The Argentine showed plenty of courage to get up but a speedy left-right combination by the Frenchman knocked him out for good almost straight afterwards.</p>
<p>Boudouani, a silver medallist at the 1988 Seoul Olympics, was regarded by many as one of the most gifted fighters of his generation but he had lost against two-lightly-regarded opponents and some were questioning his stamina.</p>
<p>&quot;Since I was a kid, my goal has always been to become a world champion,&quot; he said. &quot;I know people were wondering if I would ever make it but I knew I could.&quot;</p>
<p>Boudouani, 29, stayed cool under pressure in the early rounds as the technically limited but powerful Vasquez kept going forward.</p>
<p>&quot;I knew I had to be careful because guys like him are always dangerous,&quot; said the Frenchman after recording his 33rd win. &quot;But I felt confident. I was prepared for a tough fight and everything went as planned.&quot;</p>
<p>Boudouani's coach Dominique Ramirez felt the win was a well deserved one. &quot;He has worked hard for this,&quot; he said. &quot;Things have not always been easy for him and I'm glad he made it. He's such a nice kid.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LE CANNET, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
