<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5355" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: HORSE RACING-FRENCH FAVOURITE FLOPS IN YORKSHIRE OAKS.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-FRENCH FAVOURITE FLOPS IN YORKSHIRE OAKS.</headline>
<dateline>YORK, England 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>French raider Shamadara, the 2-1 favourite, flopped in Wednesday's group one Yorkshire Oaks. The Aga Khan's filly could finish only fifth to Irish-trained Key Change, a 7-1 chance ridden by Johnny Murtagh.</p>
<p>Key Change was a place behind Shamadara in last month's Irish Oaks but she turned the tables emphatically to defeat Papering (8-1) by a length and three quarters.</p>
<p>Russian Snows battled into third place but was demoted to sixth after she was found to have interfered with Whitewater Affair when beginning her challenge.</p>
<p>Her jockey Frankie Dettori later received a four-day ban for irresponsible riding.</p>
<p>Winning trainer John Oxx said: &quot;I knew she was better today than before the Irish Oaks but I didn't really believe she would win. But she has won so well that we will have to consider the Irish St Leger or Prix Vermeille.&quot;</p>
<p>French Oaks winner Sil Sila was virtually pulled up by Ray Cochrane and finished last. Trainer Bryan Smart said: &quot;She might have pulled a muscle.&quot;  </p>
<p>Dettori, undeterred by his ban which starts next week, went on to win the group two Gimcrack Stakes on 4-1 chance Abou Zouz, trained by David Loder.</p>
<p>On Sunday, Dettori and Loder had teamed up to take the group one Prix Morny at Deauville on Bahamian Bounty.</p>
<p>Abou Zouz, who cost around $570,000 as a yearling, earned a 33-1 quote for next year's 2,000 Guineas after Wednesday's success.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="YORK, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
