<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5357" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-EASTBOURNE CLUB SAY BANNED GIDDINS CAN PLAY FOR THEM.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-EASTBOURNE CLUB SAY BANNED GIDDINS CAN PLAY FOR THEM.</headline>
<text>
<p>LONDON, Aug 21 (Retuer) - Ed Giddins, banned from playing first-class cricket for 19 months for using cocaine, would be welcome to play for Sussex League champions Eastbourne, the club said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The 25-year-old Sussex fast bowler was barred on Tuesday from playing any match under the jurisdiction of the Test and County Cricket Board (TCCB) until April 1, 1998.</p>
<p>The TCCB have cancelled his registration with Sussex but he is still able to play club cricket and benefit matches.</p>
<p>Giddins played for Eastbourne before joining Sussex six years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;We would be delighted to have Ed back provided he paid his membership like anyone else,&quot; said Eastbourne's chairman of selectors David Lockyer.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think anyone here would have a problem with it. He's got a lot of friends at Eastbourne and some of them will feel very sorry about what has happened.</p>
<p>&quot;But, providing he wants to play again, we would be delighted if he came to play with us.&quot;</p>
<p>Giddins, who toured Pakistan with England A last winter, tested positive after a county match against Kent in May. A second test also proved positive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
