<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5358" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-MARTINEZ SURVIVES, SABATINI ROLLS AT CLASSIC.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-MARTINEZ SURVIVES, SABATINI ROLLS AT CLASSIC.</headline>
<dateline>CARLSBAD, California 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Defending champion Conchita Martinez overcame a second-set letdown before easing past Naoko Sawamtsu 6-1 2-6 6-1 on Tuesday at the $450,000 Toshiba Tennis Classic.</p>
<p>Both Martinez and No. 3 Jana Novotna of the Czech Republic advanced into the third round. Novotna edged Linda Wild of the U.S. 7-6 (7-2) 7-6 (7-2).</p>
<p>In first round results involving seeded players, No. 5 Gabriela Sabatini of Argentina routed Lindsay Lee of the U.S. 6-0 6-0; No. 6 seed Karina Habsudova of Slovakia rallied past veteran Pam Shriver of the U.S. 5-7 6-3 6-4; and eighth-seeded Nathalie Tauziat of France whipped local favourite Marianne Werdel Witmeyer 6-2, 6-2.</p>
<p>Earlier in the day, Katarina Studenikova of Slovakia needed a break in the final game to eclipse 16-year-old U.S. high school sensation Venus Williams 6-4 3-6 7-5.</p>
<p>The second-seeded Martinez sailed through the opening set without difficulty but collapsed in the next set. The l994 Wimbledon champion regrouped, however, with her heavy topspin ground attack to reel off the final five games, punctuated with a pair of aces in the last game.</p>
<p>&quot;She started playing better, not making many unforced errors and I could't finish the point,&quot; said Martinez of the second-set collapse. &quot;But I started playing with more patience, more aggressive and I started to mix up my game a bit more.</p>
<p>Sabatini is playing in only her seventh tournament, including the Olympics, in a disappointing year in which the former Top-10 player sat out four months due to a severely pulled stomach muscle.</p>
<p>The Argentine, however, looked every bit the world class player who won the l990 U.S. Open, displaying her signature heavy topspin baseline game and effective serve for the easy win. &quot;I don't judge the score, I judge the way I played,&quot; said Sabatini, who has fallen to No. 14 in the world rankings. &quot;I'm very satisfied with how I'm playing.&quot;</p>
<p>Sabatini last turned in that identical score against Maria Jose Gaidano of Argentine in March of l995 at the Bausch and Lomb Championships at Amelia Island.</p>
<p>&quot;I won that easy because I played to win each point said Sabatini, who won 64-of-98 points against the worlds' No. 50 ranked player. &quot;I tried not to let her play her game because it could be tough. I tried take control of the match the while time.&quot;</p>
<p>After a 26-point service game in which Sabatini committed six of her eight double faults for a 2-0 lead, she never looked back in the one-hour roasting.</p>
<p>Sabatini was asked if she had an sympathy for her opponent. &quot;No mercy,&quot; she said. &quot;I try to win every point. I don't think about the whole picture. It's wrong to think like that.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARLSBAD, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
