<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5362" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-DALGLISH QUITS AS BLACKBURN'S DIRECTOR OF FOOTBALL.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-DALGLISH QUITS AS BLACKBURN'S DIRECTOR OF FOOTBALL.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Scotland international Kenny Dalglish has quit as Blackburn's director of football.</p>
<p>Robert Coar, chairman of the 1995 English premier league champions, announced Dalglish's departure at the press conference that followed Blackburn's 1-0 defeat at Aston Villa on Wednesday -- their second successive league defeat.</p>
<p>Coar said Ray Harford would continue as first-team coach and would have complete control of the footballing side of the club.</p>
<p>Dalglish, who left Liverpool unexpectedly after a successful six-year spell as manager, was elevated to director at Blackburn after their championship winning season.</p>
<p>He was appointed Blackburn manager in October 1991 and guided them to promotion to the premier league the following year.</p>
<p>Dalglish broke the British transfer record twice in two years, signing England striker Alan Shearer from Southampton for 3.3 million pounds ($5.3 million) in 1992 and Chris Sutton for five million pounds ($8 million) from Norwich in 1994.</p>
<p>The two formed a highly successful strike partnership, helping Blackburn to their first championship since 1914 in only their third season in the premier league.</p>
<p>Both players have since left the club. Shearer was sold to Newcastle for a world record fee of 15 million pounds ($22.2 million) before the start of the current season.  </p>
<p>Dalglish, an outstanding striker with both Glasgow Celtic and Liverpool, has been seen less and less at the club's Ewood Park ground after &quot;moving upstairs&quot; to become director of football.</p>
<p>His interest in the first team has waned and he has been largely involved in scouting and youth team activities.</p>
<p>He is currently on holiday in Spain.</p>
<p>Coar said: &quot;We appreciate what Kenny has done for Blackburn. He has had a change in role during the past year, which was of his choosing.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a situation that has just run its course. He has left by mutual agreement...We discussed the situation. It wasn't a particularly long conversation. It was `thanks' on both sides and `let's move on'.</p>
<p>Harford said said he had always had an excellent relationship with Dalglish and had a lot to thank him for. &quot;We came as a package and those four years have been among the best of my life without any doubt.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
