<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5364" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-SHEARER SCORES, UNITED BATTLE BACK AGAINST EVERTON.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SHEARER SCORES, UNITED BATTLE BACK AGAINST EVERTON.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alan Shearer, the world's most expensive player, scored with a brilliant free-kick on his home debut for Newcastle in a 2-0 win over Wimbledon in the English premier league on Wednesday. Big rivals Manchester United, staring their first home league defeat in 31 matches in the face, battled like the champions they are from 2-0 down to draw 2-2 with Everton.</p>
<p>In the night's other big match, featuring a dazzling galaxy of foreign imports, Chelsea beat Middlesbrough 1-0 thanks to a Roberto Di Matteo 30 metres strike four minutes from the end.</p>
<p>At Old Trafford, both the Everton goals came in the first half courtesy of big striker Duncan Ferguson on his 50th appearance for the Merseyside club. But Jordi Cruyff pulled one back for the champions with a fine header 20 minutes from time and with eight minutes left Everton's David Unsworth, attempting to clear, only succeeded in turning the ball over his own line.</p>
<p>At St James's Park, Newcastle were set on their way in the third minute by another costly ex-Blackburn player, David Batty, who chipped over Wimbledon keeper Neil Sullivan from 30 metres. Shearer finally got in on the act with just two minutes left. Fouled by Chris Perry, the Newcastle-born striker decided to take the free-kick himself and from 20 metres curled it into the corner of the net.</p>
<p>Shearer wheeled away in delight as Newcastle sealed their first victory of the season and went some way to forgetting the disappointment of Saturday's 2-0 defeat at Everton and the 4-0 Charity Shield drubbing by Manchester United.  </p>
<p>Serie A came to Chelsea, along with various other Europeans and Brazilians, with big things expected of Chelsea's Gianluca Vialli and Middlesbrough's Fabrizio Ravanelli, a hat-trick scorer against Liverpool on Saturday.</p>
<p>But it was midfielder Di Matteo, a costly close season signing from Lazio, who broke the deadlock to earn Ruud Gullit his first win as a manager.</p>
<p>Gareth Southgate, the man whose missed penalty sent England out of Euro 96, gave Aston Villa a 64th minute winner, but not from the penalty spot, at home to a dispirited Blackburn who could offer little in response as they went down 1-0.</p>
<p>After the game it was announced that Blackburn's director of football and ex-manager Kenny Dalglish was leaving the club by mutual agreement.</p>
<p>Sunderland found a rich vein of scoring form at Nottingham Forest with first half strikes from Michael Gray, Richard Ord and two goals from new signing Niall Quinn.</p>
<p>Alf-Inge Haaland provided the only consolation as the North East side went in 4-1 at the interval and that is how it stayed to cheer manager Peter Reid and the Sunderland faithful.</p>
<p>Teddy Sheringham presented Tottenham with a 34th minute lead at home to Derby, but the visitors, who earned a late draw at home to Leeds on Saturday, did the same again, thanks to Christian Dailly.</p>
<p>Leicester were indebted to promising youngster Emile Heskey who struck in the sixth and 42nd minutes against Southampton.</p>
<p>An otherwise quiet Matt le Tissier, in front of watching England manager Glenn Hoddle, gave his side hope from the penalty spot after 68 minutes, but Leicester held on for a 2-1 win with Southampton's Barry Venison sent off.</p>
<p>Gary McAllister showed Coventry the way forward after their dismal showing at home on Saturday when his 12th minute goal gave his new side the lead over West Ham.</p>
<p>But the Hammers surged back in the second half and deservedly levelled with a 74th minute equaliser from defender Marc Rieper.  </p>
<p>After two matches, Sheffield Wednesday, are the surprise premier league leaders with two victories from their first two games, including a 2-0 win at Leeds on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Manchester United and Sunderland come next, heading seven teams on four points. Blackburn and Wimbledon are bottom after two defeats.</p>
<p>Newcastle are in mid-table. Shearer, thrilled with his goal, said: &quot;I couldn't be more delighted but to be honest I'm more concerned with getting the three points than scoring.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a big bonus to get a goal. I don't really care about the pressure,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Shearer, who scored 31 premier league goals for Blackburn last season, said of his free-kick, &quot;It could have gone in the stand or in the top corner. Luckily for me it went in the top corner.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a shame we got off to a bad start against Everton (on Saturday) but there were more signs tonight we are getting it together.&quot;</p>
<p>Manchester United's satisfaction at fighting back against Everton was coloured by a late incident involving manager Alex Ferguson.</p>
<p>At the end of the match he had to be restrained by his assistant Brian Kidd and head of security at Old Trafford Ned Kelly as he moved towards match referee Graham Poll.</p>
<p>The Football Association is expected to call on Thursday for the referee's report into what happened.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
