<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5372" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-SCOTLAND NAME HASTIE AS NEW TEAM MANAGER.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-SCOTLAND NAME HASTIE AS NEW TEAM MANAGER.</headline>
<dateline>EDINBURGH 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Scotland on Wednesday appointed Arthur Hastie as team manager in succession to Jim Telfer who has stood down to concentrate on his duties as director of rugby.</p>
<p>The 61-year-old Hastie managed the Scotland tour to Zimbabwe last year and was the Scotland A manager for two seasons.</p>
<p>He was also Scotland's assistant manager on the 1993 South Seas tour and was in charge of Scotland's sevens squad in Hong Kong in 1994.</p>
<p>Hastie will chair the panel of four selectors which includes former Scotland flanker John Jeffrey.</p>
<p>The other selectors are coaches Richie Dixon and David Johnston, who have been appointed on a three-year contract up until the end of the 1999 World Cup, and Colin Fisher.</p>
<p>Scotland's convenor of rugby Duncan Paterson said: &quot;We are extremely glad to have a manager of Arthur's experience and talent to draw upon, and we are confident that the new management team will work extremely well together.</p>
<p>&quot;The coaches have established a winning record, based on open and fluid rugby, and John Jeffrey will also add a new perspective to selection.&quot;</p>
<p>Paterson also confirmed the Scottish Rugby Union had made Telfer available to take on the post as assistant coach of the British Lions for their tour to South Africa next May. </p>
<p>But he added: &quot;Any announcement concerning such an appointment will have to come from the Four Home Unions Committee.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EDINBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
