<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5373" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-PITCH INVASION AT YOUTH FINAL INCREASES SECURITY CONCERN.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-PITCH INVASION AT YOUTH FINAL INCREASES SECURITY CONCERN.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Security at English cricket grounds looks certain to be reviewed after two pitch invasions during the Lord's final of the first world under-15 tournament between India and Pakistan.</p>
<p>It was the worst violence of the season and comes soon after disturbances at Headingley during the second test between England and Pakistan.</p>
<p>Crowd trouble began midway through the Indian innings during Tuesday's final at Lord's when 50 supporters ran on to the ground after Pakistan were awarded an lbw decision. The invasion delayed play for a few minutes.</p>
<p>Later, with India on the brink of victory, about 500 Pakistani supporters ran on to the pitch, stealing the stumps and goading the Indian fans who responded by throwing plastic bottles and aluminium cans.</p>
<p>Players sheltered in the pavilion as police and security officials took several minutes to clear the playing area.</p>
<p>There were more ugly scenes after India's youngsters had completed a four-wicket win when both sets of supporters invaded the pitch as the umpires and players, some aged only 13, ran for the pavilion.</p>
<p>A large group of supporters gathered and when police attempted to move them back, a small number charged and two or three arrests were made.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
