<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5376" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-PRESSURE ON ENGLAND AS ILLINGWORTH BIDS FAREWELL.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-PRESSURE ON ENGLAND AS ILLINGWORTH BIDS FAREWELL.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kitson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>England will have to produce their best performance of the season in the final test against Pakistan starting on Thursday if they want to send outgoing chairman of selectors Ray Illingworth into a happy retirement.</p>
<p>Former England captain Illingworth's 30-month reign officially ends after the one-day series against Pakistan and the announcement of the touring squad headed for Zimbabwe and New Zealand later this year.</p>
<p>But the Oval test, with the confident visitors ahead 1-0 in the best-of-three series, represents Illingworth's last major engagement in an international career which dates back to his test debut as a player in 1958.</p>
<p>The 64-year-old Yorkshireman is not the sentimental type, but there are several good reasons why an English victory over a highly-talented Pakistan side would give him greater than average satisfaction.</p>
<p>England under Mike Atherton and Illingworth have endured dismal overseas series in Australia in 1994-95 and South Africa a year later, not to mention their abortive World Cup campaign on the sub-continent.</p>
<p>At home, though, they have proved a more resilient bunch during Illingworth's tenure and have not lost a domestic series in four attempts since returning to winning habits with a 1-0 success over New Zealand in 1994.</p>
<p>Critics, of which Illingworth has attracted many in the last two years, will point out that England have won only six of their 27 tests at home and abroad in the same time period and have selected 39 different players for test duty.</p>
<p>Yet even his worst enemies will acknowledge Illingworth's unswerving desire to boost English credibility, even after being found guilty of bringing the game into disrepute and being fined 2,000 pounds sterling ($3,100) by his employers this year.</p>
<p>The Test and County Cricket Board ruled he had made comments prejudicial to the interests of cricket in the wake of the row over the treatment of Devon Malcolm in South Africa, although his appeal is due to be heard next month.</p>
<p>In the meantime, Illingworth must hope his final gamble in charge will outflank Wasim Akram's tourists who warmed up in ominous fashion with a 271-run win over Essex this week.</p>
<p>Wicket-keeper Jack Russell has been dropped and Alec Stewart handed the gloves once again on his home ground to enable an extra bowler to be squeezed into the starting 11.</p>
<p>The switch comes just at the point when Stewart has re-established his opening partnership with Atherton, but if England bat second he is likely to drop down the order again with Nick Knight stepping up.</p>
<p>This time, though, England do not have Malcolm to blast through the opposition on the fastest pitch of the summer, preferring to keep faith with the seam attack which let Pakistan off the hook in favourable conditions on the first day at Headingley.</p>
<p>England coach David Lloyd described the pitch in terms that will please Pakistan's attack. &quot;It's white, it's rock hard, firm and bare. It will have some pace,&quot; Lloyd said. &quot;We have no jurisdiction over Test match wickets,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Pakistanis have promised to play attacking cricket to the end rather than sit back on their 1-0 lead and can again select from a position of strength.</p>
<p>An indication of their resources is the sight of teenage off-spinner Saqlain Mushtaq, unable to claim a test place, on top of the national averages with 29 wickets in his last four matches.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible we may go into the test with five recognised bowlers, but no decision will be made until we see the composition of the Oval pitch,&quot; said Pakistan manager Yawar Saeed.</p>
<p>Teams (from):</p>
<p>England - Michael Atherton (captain), Alec Stewart, Nasser Hussain, Graham Thorpe, John Crawley, Nick Knight, Dominic Cork, Chris Lewis, Ian Salisbury, Andy Caddick, Alan Mullally, Robert Croft.</p>
<p>Pakistan - Saeed Anwar, Aamir Sohail, Ijaz Ahmed, Inzamam-ul-Haq, Salim Malik, Asif Mujtaba, Shadab Kabir, Moin Khan, Wasim Akram (captain), Mushtaq Ahmed, Waqar Younis, Saqlain Mushtaq, Mohammed Akram, Ata-ur-Rehman.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
