<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5377" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: TENNIS-HENMAN SAVES MATCH POINT, BEATS HAARHUIS AT CANADIAN.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-HENMAN SAVES MATCH POINT, BEATS HAARHUIS AT CANADIAN.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tim Henman of Britain survived a match point on his way to a first-round victory over 14th-seeded Paul Haarhuis of the Netherlands on Tuesday at the $2 million Canadian Open.</p>
<p>Henman, the world's 37th-ranked player, who became the darling of the Wimbledon crowds by reaching the quarterfinals in July, recovered from a shaky second set to beat the 26th-ranked Haarhuis 6-2 2-6 7-6 (9-7).</p>
<p>In Tuesday's only second-round match, fifth-seeded Thomas Enqvist of Sweden defeated Spain's Javier Sanchez 6-3 6-4. Enqvist and the rest of the top-eight seeds were given first-round byes.</p>
<p>In an afternoon battle of up-and-coming 19-year-olds, Mark Philippoussis of Australia overpowered Sjeng Schlaken of the Netherlands 6-3 6-4.</p>
<p>Haarhuis was one of two seeded players to lose Tuesday. Sixth seeded Magnus Gustafsson of Sweden was beaten by American Alex O'Brien, ranked 76th, 6-3 7-6 (7-5). O'Brien, who won his first career tournament last week at New Haven, had the only service break of the match, in the eighth game of the first set.</p>
<p>The ninth seed, Cedric Pioline of France, had an easy time with Nicklas Kulti of Sweden, winning 6-4, 6-2.</p>
<p>After dropping five games in a row to lose the second set, Henman saved two break points on his serve in the opening game of the third, including one with a second-serve ace.</p>
<p>&quot;That was a big game because I was playing some pretty poor tennis at the end of the second set,&quot; Henman said. &quot;I was really struggling to keep the ball in play. If he'd broken me in that game things would have been very much in his favour.&quot;</p>
<p>Henman had five match points before finally winning the match on his sixth when Haarhuis hit a forehand long at 8-7 in the third-set tiebreaker. Haarhuis held his only match point at 6-5 in the tiebreak and failed to convert when he netted an easy forehand.</p>
<p>&quot;I had the easiest shot to win the match,&quot; said Haarhuis. &quot;It's better to lose a match 6-3 6-3 than to lose that way.&quot;</p>
<p>The Enqvist-Sanchez match was a closer affair than the score would suggest. One rally late in the match, with the 14th-ranked Swede serving for the match and down 15-30, lasted for more than 40 strokes. &quot;That was an unbelievable point. I thought I had won it a couple of times but he just kept getting it back,&quot; Enqvist said. &quot;He is a fighter and he never gives up.&quot;</p>
<p>Philippoussis, the 29th ranked player who caused a major shock by upsetting world number one Pete Sampras of the U.S. in the third round of this year's Australian Open, blasted 15 aces past Schalken, ranked 49th. Four of those aces came in one game, the eighth of the second set, and the Aussie wrapped up the match with three more aces in the final game.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
