<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5379" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: DEVELOPMENT-SPORTS TRUST APPOINTS BRUCE FORDYCE.</title>
<headline>DEVELOPMENT-SPORTS TRUST APPOINTS BRUCE FORDYCE.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Sports Trust said on Wednesday that Bruce Fordyce had accepted the position of executive director.</p>
<p>Fordyce, who has won nine gold medals in the Comrades marathon, will administer the day-to-day running of the trust, set up two years ago to provide funding from the public and private sectors to encourage sports development.</p>
<p>&quot;Sport has given me many things and the Sports Trust is in the position to change lives around the country in the way running changed mine,&quot; Fordyce told a news conference. &quot;Through sport South Africa can become healthier and wealthier and gain the confidence of the world.&quot;</p>
<p>Mthobi Tyamzashe, the director general of the Department of Sport and Recreation, told reporters a fulltime administrator was needed by the trust, which had allocated eight million rand to sport since its formation.</p>
<p>&quot;It has become clear that a dedicated fulltime professional is needed to make sure that future funds are correctly allocated. I can think of no-one better qualified to achieve this than Bruce Fordyce,&quot; Tyamzashe said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
