<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5381" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: RUGBY UNION-KRUGER STANDS BY TO REPLACE TEICHMANN.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-KRUGER STANDS BY TO REPLACE TEICHMANN.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Northern Transvaal flanker Ruben Kruger is likely to take over as South African captain on his home ground for the second test against New Zealand on Saturday if Gary Teichmann fails a late fitness test.</p>
<p>Number eight Teichmann, who badly bruised his left hip in the 23-19 defeat by the All Blacks last Saturday, was clearly struggling with the injury during a fitness test on Wednesday.</p>
<p>South African Rugby Football Union (SARFU) press officer Alex Broun said the 23-man squad would remain intact until Saturday morning when the Springbok test line-up would be picked.</p>
<p>If Teichmann fails his fitness test, his probable replacement would be Northern Transvaal loose forward Schutte Becker.</p>
<p>The only other likely change would see the return of outside centre Japie Mulder, who also has to pass a fitness test by Saturday after withdrawing from the Durban test with a back injury.</p>
<p>The Springbok management scotched rumours on Wednesday that Natal provincial players had been under particular pressure to retain their places in the test side.</p>
<p>South African team manager Morne du Plessis said: &quot;I know nothing about a Natal bias...we pick the team purely in terms of the green and gold.&quot;</p>
<p>On the subject of provincial bias, Springbok lock Mark Andrews said: &quot;Just look at our national team -- we've got a Natal captain.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
