<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5384" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SOCCER-NAMIBIA OUT TO ENHANCE REPUTATION.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-NAMIBIA OUT TO ENHANCE REPUTATION.</headline>
<byline>Mark Gleeson</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Namibia's soccer team, who took four years to win their first match, now seek to continue a long-standing run of unbeaten results in this weekend's African Nations Cup qualifying matches.</p>
<p>Namibia host Botswana in Windhoek on Saturday in one of four preliminary round, second leg matches ahead of the start of the group qualifiers for the 1998 finals in Burkina Faso.</p>
<p>In the other matches, Togo host Congo in Lome, Mauritania attempt to overcome a three-goal deficit at home to Benin in Nouakchott and the tiny Seychelles have a very real chance of an upset victory over Mauritius.</p>
<p>Namibia, who have been members of the international soccer community for only six years and are placed 109th in the FIFA rankings, forced a goalless draw in the first leg in Gaborone two weeks ago to stretch their unbeaten record to 15 months and seven matches.</p>
<p>Included in that run was a surprise World Cup win over Mozambique two months ago which has given the arrid southern African country a whole new footballing profile.</p>
<p>&quot;The team has really improved and is very dedicated,&quot; said midfielder Eliphas Shivute, who had to give up soccer for three years to earn a living as a miner.</p>
<p>Few of the youthful team, whose eldest member is 26, have regular employment and players earn less than $100 per appearance for the national team.</p>
<p>&quot;But the fact that most don't work and that most of them live in Windhoek means we can train twice a week. That has been one of our secrets,&quot; team manager Abraham So-oabeb told Reuters.</p>
<p>Namibia, who beat Botswana in a friendly in early 1994 to record the first international win in their history, will be playing only their 27th international since joining FIFA after independence in 1990.</p>
<p>But So-oabeb believes that despite the lack of experience and finance, Namibia can launch a strong bid at qualifying for the finals in Burkina Faso.</p>
<p>Should they beat Botswana, Namibia will be placed in group five of the qualifiers alongside Cameroon, Gabon and Kenya.</p>
<p>The Seychelles islands could provide the bigest shock of the weekend if they overcome a 0-1 deficit in their tie against fellow Indian Ocean islanders Mauritius.</p>
<p>The Seychelles is Africa's smallest country and they have only been intermittent competitors in 10 years of FIFA membership and are still without success in an official international match.</p>
<p>But they have a real chance to rewrite history in Mahe on Sunday against a Mauritian team who have beaten them in all nine of their previous encounters.</p>
<p>Togo and Congo, who both recorded surprise wins in the recent World Cup qualifiers, meet in Lome on Sunday after a goalless draw in the Congo earlier this month.</p>
<p>Mauritania host Benin on Friday but have their work cut out after suffering a 4-1 defeat away in the first leg.</p>
<p>The Central African Republic are already through to the group qualifiers after the disqualification of Burundi.</p>
<p>Burundi's team did not arrive for their scheduled preliminary round, first leg match in Bangui two weeks ago, unable to leave the trouble east African country because of an air ban imposed in a recent set of internationally-sponsored sanctions.</p>
<p>The Central African Republic go through on a walkover to play in group four with Guinea, Sierra Leone and Tunisia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NAMIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UPVOLA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
