<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5390" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: SOCCER-ZAGALLO NAMES MAKESHIFT SQUAD FOR BRIEF EUROPEAN TOUR.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ZAGALLO NAMES MAKESHIFT SQUAD FOR BRIEF EUROPEAN TOUR.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil coach Mario Zagallo admitted on Wednesday he had been forced to name a makeshift squad for a brief European tour at the end of this month.</p>
<p>Zagallo said he had stood by a policy of not picking more than one player from each team to avoid upsetting Brazilian clubs. The only exception made was Palmeiras who contributed full-back Cafu and midfielder Flavio Conceicao.</p>
<p>&quot;We try not to upset the clubs but as a result the national team ends up suffering instead and is still always expected to win,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Brazil play friendlies away to Russia on August 28 and Netherlands three days later.</p>
<p>Unlike many countries, where the domestic programme is suspended on the weekend before a major international, Brazilian football carries on regardless.</p>
<p>The tour is seen as the first step towards forming the team which the world champions will send to the 1998 World Cup in France. As holders, Brazil do not have to play in the qualifying competition.</p>
<p>Zagallo included 32-year-old striker Bebeto and Barcelona's Ronaldo in the squad, despite a much-publicised row between them following the Olympic team's semifinal defeat by Nigeria at the Atlanta Games.</p>
<p>Brazil had used most of their friendlies in the past year as warm-up matches for the Olympics, restricting Zagallo to players under 23.</p>
<p>Bad results on the tour could put Zagallo's job in jeopardy following the failure to win the gold medal in Atlanta.</p>
<p>The only uncapped player in the squad is central defender Goncalves who plays for Brazilian champions Botafogo.</p>
<p>Squad:</p>
<p>Goalkeepers - Carlos Germano (Vasco da Gama), Dida (Cruzeiro)</p>
<p>Defenders - Ze Maria (Parma), Ze Roberto (Portuguesa), Andre Luis (Sao Paulo), Cafu (Palmeiras), Goncalves (Botafogo), Narciso (Santos), Ronaldo Guiaro (Atletico Mineiro), Andre Cruz (Napoli)</p>
<p>Midfielders - Flavio Conceicao (Palmeiras), Ze Elias (Bayer Leverkusen), Amaral (Parma), Beto (Napoli), Giovanni (Barcelona), Leonardo (Paris St Germain), Mauro Silva (Deportivo Coruna), Sergio Manoel (Cerezo Osaka)</p>
<p>Strikers - Bebeto (Flamengo), Donizete (Benfica), Jardel (Porto), Ronaldo (Barcelona)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
