<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5392" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RUGBY UNION-AUSTRALIA TO PLAY ENGLAND TWICE A YEAR.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-AUSTRALIA TO PLAY ENGLAND TWICE A YEAR.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia and England are to play two tests each year from 1997 until at least 2003, one home and the other away, the Australian Rugby Union (ARU) said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>England will play one test in Australia each July, with the Wallabies travelling to Twickenham for the return fixture in November, said ARU chief executive officer John O'Neill.</p>
<p>&quot;This agreement is in place until 2003,&quot; O'Neill said.</p>
<p>The ARU also agreed to add a one-off test against Wales to Australia's European tour later this year.</p>
<p>O'Neill said plans to approach England about playing a one-off test at Twickenham at the end of tour in December had been dropped.</p>
<p>&quot;The Board considered this is not achievable due to the long-standing commitment to play the Barbarians at Twickenham on December 7,&quot; O'Neill said.</p>
<p>Australia are already scheduled to play Italy, Ireland and Scotland during the eight-week tour, starting in Italy in October.</p>
<p>The match against Wales is subject to an agreement with the Irish to change dates for the one-off test in Dublin, originally scheduled for November 30.</p>
<p>&quot;The ARU will ask that the Ireland test be brought forward to November 23 and the Wales test be played on November 30,&quot; O'Neill said in a statement.</p>
<p>Australia are also seeking a satisfactory financial agreement with the Welsh to take part in the match.  </p>
<p>In England, Rugby Football Union (RFU) president John Richardson welcomed the agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;England has sought fixtures with Australia and is therefore delighted that the Australian Rugby Union has agreed to home and away fixtures each year from 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is consistent with the RFU policy of playing regularly against the challenge of the southern hemisphere countries.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
