<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5393" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: TENNIS-AUSTRALIA RECALL PHILIPPOUSSIS FOR DAVIS CUP TIE.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-AUSTRALIA RECALL PHILIPPOUSSIS FOR DAVIS CUP TIE.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia on Wednesday recalled teenager Mark Philippoussis for next month's Davis Cup tie against Croatia, signalling a thaw in relations with team captain John Newcombe.</p>
<p>Wimbledon semifinalist Jason Stoltenberg, Patrick Rafter, and Olympic doubles champions Todd Woodbridge and Mark Woodforde complete Australia's squad for the world group qualifying tie in Split from September 20-22.</p>
<p>Newcombe criticised big-serving Philippoussis in March when he withdrew from the Davis Cup zonal tie against Japan to give himself more time to practice for a tournament.</p>
<p>At the time, Newcombe hinted that Philippoussis's decision to put practice ahead of playing for his country could affect his future Davis Cup selection.</p>
<p>But the 19-year-old earned an immediate recall after beating former world number one Jim Courier on his way to the semifinal of last week's hardcourt tournament in Connecticut.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously Stoltenberg is in fine form after doing so well at Wimbledon and the 'Woodies' are dominating in doubles,&quot; Newcombe said in a statement released by Tennis Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;Philippoussis seems to be regaining form and Rafter is on an upward swing in the rebuilding of his game,&quot; Newcombe said.</p>
<p>Newcombe predicted the tie would be one of the hardest Australia has played in the past two years, predicting that world number six Goran Ivanisevic would lead the Croatians and be almost impossible to beat in his two singles matches.</p>
<p>&quot;He is obviously going to be very hard to beat in his home town, so we are going to have to win the other two singles and doubles,&quot; Newcombe said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
