<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5394" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: ATHLETICS-ATHLETES TO EARN BONUS FOR WORLD RECORDS.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-ATHLETES TO EARN BONUS FOR WORLD RECORDS.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Athletes who break world records at next year's world championships in Athens will be paid a US$100,000 bonus, International Amateur Athletics Federation president Primo Nebiolo said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've already made an agreement with a great sponsor that will give $100,000 for each new world record -- this will be the case for 1997 and 1999,&quot; Nebiolo said in an interview published on Wednesday in Sydney's Daily Telegraph newspaper.</p>
<p>He did not identify the sponsor.</p>
<p>Nebiolo said the federation hoped to expand the scheme to other major meetings.</p>
<p>&quot;Our idea is that we want to find a sponsor giving us special money for a new world record for the indoor world championships, the outdoor world championships, the World Cup and Grand Prix Final,&quot; Nebiolo said.</p>
<p>As it stands, the most lucrative event in the sport in prize money terms is the privately-backed Zurich grand prix meeting, which has a $6.0 million budget, including a $50,000 bonus for world records.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not doing this to go in competition for Zurich...We are not in competition with our private organisers,&quot; said Nebiolo, who made his comments during a visit to Sydney for the world junior championships, which began on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Increasing cash rewards in the sport have led to speculation that athletes might time their world record attempts depending on the rewards available.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
