<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5397" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-CUBS' SOSA OUT 4-TO-6 WEEKS WITH BROKEN HAND.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-CUBS' SOSA OUT 4-TO-6 WEEKS WITH BROKEN HAND.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chicago Cubs rightfielder Sammy Sosa, one of the leading candidates for Most Valuable Player in the National League, will miss the next four to six weeks with a broken hand.</p>
<p>Sosa, who leads the league in homers with 40, suffered the injury during the Cubs' 8-1 win over the Florida Marlins on Tuesday when he was hit by a pitch from Mark Hutton in the first inning.</p>
<p>Sosa, who remained in the game until the fifth inning, recorded his 100th RBI of the season when was hit by the Hutton pitch with the bases loaded.</p>
<p>The injury snapped Sosa's streak of 304 consecutive games played, the third longest active streak in the majors behind Baltimore's Cal Ripken Jr and San Francisco's Barry Bonds.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very disappointing to get an injury like this, particularly now when we are making a move in the division,&quot; Sosa told WMVP Radio in Chicago. &quot;The doctor told me it's going to be closer to the six weeks than four.&quot;</p>
<p>The loss of Sosa could be a huge blow to the Cubs' playoff hopes. Chicago is five games behind Houston in the National League Central and five games behind Montreal in the wildcard race.</p>
<p>The 27-year-old Sosa had been struggling at the plate recently with just seven hits in his last 42 at-bats, but was still on a pace to hit 52 homers and drive in 131 runs, surpassing his career high of 119 set last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
