<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5398" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-ANGELS' MANAGER MCNAMARA HOSPITALIZED WITH BLOOD CLOT.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-ANGELS' MANAGER MCNAMARA HOSPITALIZED WITH BLOOD CLOT.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>California Angels interim manager John McNamara was admitted to Columbia Presbyterian Hospital on Wednesday with a blood clot in his right calf.</p>
<p>McNamara is expected to remain in the hospital for the next four or five days. The 64-year-old McNamara had watched several games from inside the clubhouse because of the injury.</p>
<p>Bench coach Joe Maddon is running the club during McNamara's absence.</p>
<p>The Angels continue on to Baltimore on Friday and complete their 10-game road trip there Sunday before returning home for an eight-game homestand beginning Monday.</p>
<p>McNamara had taken over as interim manager on August 6 after Marcel Lachemann stepped down. At the time, California was 52-59 and in last place in the American League West. Since then the Angels have gone 7-9.</p>
<p>A veteran of 18 seasons as a major league manager, McNamara was in his fifth season as a minor-league catching instructor in the Angels organisation when he was named interim manager.</p>
<p>McNamara has a lifetime managerial record of 1,150-1,215 with Oakland, Cincinnati, San Diego, California, Boston and Cleveland. He took Boston to the World Series in 1986.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
