<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5400" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-SAMPRAS TO OPEN OPEN AGAINST RIKL, PHILIPPOUSSIS LOOMS.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-SAMPRAS TO OPEN OPEN AGAINST RIKL, PHILIPPOUSSIS LOOMS.</headline>
<byline>Bill Berkrot</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>World number one Pete Sampras, seeking his first Grand Slam title of the year, and women's top seed Steffi Graf, aiming for her third, should be able to ease into the year's final major, which begins on Monday.</p>
<p>Sampras opens defence of his U.S. Open crown against David Rikl of the Czech Republic, while top-ranked Graf begins her title defence against Yayuk Basuki of Indonesia.</p>
<p>Wednesday's U.S. Open draw ceremony revealed that both title holders should run into their first serious opposition in the third round.</p>
<p>Looming in Sampras's future is a likely third-round date with recent nemesis Mark Philippoussis, the rising Australian who took out Sampras in the third round of the Australian Open in January.</p>
<p>Sampras avenged that defeat with a straight sets win over the 19-year-old power hitter in the second round at Wimbledon and their rubber match in New York could provide some first-week fireworks.</p>
<p>While only a stunning upset will keep Graf from sailing through to a predictable semifinal showdown with third seed Arantxa Sanchez Vicario, the German star could also be tested in the third round where she will probably face 28th-ranked veteran Natasha Zvereva of Belarus.</p>
<p>There will be no repeat of last year's men's final with eighth-ranked Andre Agassi landing in Sampras's half of the draw. Bumping Agassi up to the sixth seeding avoided the possibility that he would run into Sampras as early as the quarter-finals, but they could lock horns in the semis.</p>
<p>Olympic champion Agassi meets Karim Alami of Marocco in the first round.</p>
<p>Surprise second seed Michael Chang, ranked third in the world, opens against Czech Daniel Vacek, while women's second seed Monica Seles drew American Anne Miller as her first victim.</p>
<p>Second-ranked Austrian Thomas Muster, who was seeded third, did not have the luck of the draw with him. In the first round Muster faces American Richey Reneberg, who has been playing some of the best tennis of his career of late.</p>
<p>If he survives, Muster is seeded to run into either fifth-seeded Wimbledon champion Richard Krajicek of the Netherlands or 12th-seeded American Todd Martin in the quarter-finals in Chang's half of the draw.</p>
<p>Perhaps the best, yet most unfortunate, first-round matchup of the men's competition pits eighth seed Jim Courier against retiring star Stefan Edberg.</p>
<p>The popular Swede is playing his final major tournament next week and the two-time champion's Grand Slam farewell could well be a one-match affair.</p>
<p>With the exception of a Philippoussis showdown, Sampras looks to have landed in a comfortable quarter of the draw with the likes of Frenchman Cedric Pioline and ailing French Open champion Yevgeny Kafelnikov, who is nursing a rib injury, in his path.</p>
<p>Seles, runner-up to Graf last year, is seeded to run into fifth-ranked German Anke Huber in the quarter-finals with fourth seed Conchita Martinez or eighth-seeded Olympic champion Lindsay Davenport looking like her most likely semifinal opponents.</p>
<p>But Huber will be tested immediately with a first-round encounter against dangerous 18th-ranked South African Amanda Coetzer.</p>
<p>Sanchez Vicario, runner-up to Graf at the French Open and Wimbledon, begins play against a qualifier in a quarter of the draw that includes young talent Martina Hingis, the 16th seed, before a probable quarter-final clash with seventh-seeded veteran Jana Novotna.</p>
<p>Martinez begins play against Ruxandra Dragomir of Romania.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
