<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5401" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-USTA DEVIATES FROM RANKINGS FOR U.S. OPEN SEEDINGS.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-USTA DEVIATES FROM RANKINGS FOR U.S. OPEN SEEDINGS.</headline>
<byline>Bill Berkrot</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Tennis Association broke with its own longstanding tradition and took a page out of the Wimbledon handbook on Wednesday by deviating from the ATP Tour rankings in formulating men's seedings for the U.S. Open Tennis Championships.</p>
<p>Unlike Wimbledon officials, the usually conservative association has for many years seeded players at the Open strictly according to world rankings.</p>
<p>USTA President and Tournament Chairman Les Snyder decided to do things a little differently this year, withholding the list of men's seeds until just prior to Wednesday's draw ceremony with the promise of a few surprises.</p>
<p>Most notable was the bumping of red-hot Michael Chang, currenly ranked a career-high third in the world, to the second seed, right behind world number one Pete Sampras.</p>
<p>That dropped second-ranked Thomas Muster of Austria, who has achieved nearly all of his success on clay, to the third spot for the tournament which begins on Monday.</p>
<p>Snyder said tournament officials wanted the seedings to be a more accurate predictor of the event rather than a reflection of the rankings computer.</p>
<p>He said a player's showing in the other Grand Slams, recent performance and record on hard courts were all taken into consideration in making the seeding decisions. He insisted the popularity of a player was not a factor.</p>
<p>&quot;Just like any sport, players can get on a hot streak and I think that should be taken into account,&quot; Snyder said.</p>
<p>Chang holds a 15-1 match record during the summer hardcourt season after winning titles in Washington and Los Angeles and reaching the final in Cincinnati.</p>
<p>In other moves, eighth-ranked Andre Agassi, coming off victories in the Olympics and at Cincinnati, was seeded sixth, and seventh-ranked Wimbledon champion Richard Krajicek was seeded fifth.</p>
<p>Despite a history of disappointing showings at Flushing Meadow, sixth-ranked Croatian Goran Ivanisevic was seeded fourth, while fourth-ranked French Open champion Yevgeny Kafelnikov was seeded only seventh.</p>
<p>Sixteenth-ranked Spaniard Felix Mantilla, who would have been awarded the final seeding under the usual U.S. Open format, was left unseeded, allowing Frenchman Cedric Pioline to join the seeded ranks in the men's draw.</p>
<p>Asked how he hoped it would all pan out on the final Sunday, Snyder said: &quot;I'd like to have what we had last year, women one and two, and men one and two.&quot;</p>
<p>The following is the list of men's seeds for the U.S. Open with their world ranking in parenthesis. Several of the players were moved up one place by the withdrawal of fifth-ranked Boris Becker, who pulled out with a wrist injury.</p>
<p>1. Pete Sampras (U.S.) (1)</p>
<p>2. Michael Chang (U.S.) (3)</p>
<p>3. Thomas Muster (Austria) (2)</p>
<p>4. Goran Ivanisevic (Croatia) (6)</p>
<p>5. Richard Krajicek (Netherlands) (7)</p>
<p>6. Andre Agassi (U.S.) (8)</p>
<p>7. Yevgeny Kafelnikov (Russia) (4)</p>
<p>8. Jim Courier (U.S.) (9)</p>
<p>9. Wayne Ferreira (South Africa) (10)</p>
<p>10. Marcelo Rios (Chile) (11)</p>
<p>11. MaliVai Washington (U.S.) (12)</p>
<p>12. Todd Martin (U.S.) (13)</p>
<p>13. Thomas Enqvist (Sweden) (14)</p>
<p>14. Alberto Costa (Spain) (15)</p>
<p>15. Marc Rosset (Switzerland) (17)</p>
<p>16. Cedric Pioline (France) (18)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
