<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5404" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-RANGERS ERRORLESS STREAK ENDS IN LOSS TO TRIBE.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-RANGERS ERRORLESS STREAK ENDS IN LOSS TO TRIBE.</headline>
<dateline>CLEVELAND 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>To err had been been unlike the Texas Rangers -- until Tuesday.</p>
<p>Shortstop Kevin Elster made the club's first error in 16 games, leaving the Rangers one game short of the all-time major-league mark, and Manny Ramirez hit his third grand slam of the season as the Cleveland Indians pounded out a 10-4 victory over the Rangers in a battle of division leaders.</p>
<p>Elster, who played errorless ball for 45 straight games, mishandled a throw to second by second baseman Mark McLemore, ending the streak in the fourth inning. The St. Louis Cardinals played errorless ball for 16 straight games in 1992.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm more diasappointed with the loss than the streak,&quot; McLemore said. &quot;It's a pretty impressive streak. I think he (Elster) kind of looked down at the bag.&quot;</p>
<p>Omar Vizquel walked to lead off the fifth and Jim Thome hit his 28th homer to give Cleveland the lead for good, 5-4.</p>
<p>Albert Belle added his 41st homer in the eighth.</p>
<p>Albie Lopez (3-4) allowed four runs and nine hits with two walks and a pair of strikeouts in five innings.</p>
<p>Bobby Witt (12-9) was tagged for five runs and six hits with six walks and no strikeouts in 4 1/3 innings.</p>
<p>Juan Gonzalez drove in three runs for Texas.</p>
<p>In Boston, Mo Vaughn's 36th homer, a three-run shot in the eighth inning against reliever Mike Mohler (4-2), lifted the Red Sox past the Oakland Athletics 4-3.</p>
<p>Rich Garces (3-1), recalled earlier in the day from the minors, pitched a scoreless eighth inning to pick up the win for Boston, which has won 13 of its last 17 games. Heathcliff Slocumb pitched a 1-2-3 ninth for his 21st save.</p>
<p>An inning earlier, Mike Bordick had given Oakland a 3-1 lead with a two-run homer off Sox starter Mike Maddux.</p>
<p>Maddux allowed three runs and six hits in seven innings with four walks and two strikeouts.</p>
<p>In Baltimore, Mike Mussina allowed two hits over seven innings for his 16th win of the season and B.J. Surhoff and Cal Ripken each knocked in a run in a three-run fourth, as the Orioles downed the Seattle Mariners 4-1.</p>
<p>Mussina (16-8) walked four and struck out eight to join New York's Andy Pettitte as the A.L.'s only 16-game winners.</p>
<p>Randy Myers struck out two in the ninth for his 24th save.</p>
<p>Mark Whiten homered to give Seattle a 1-0 lead in the third, but the Orioles scored three runs off rookie starter Matt Wagner (3-4), who was recalled from the minors earlier in the day.</p>
<p>In New York, Jim Leyritz's two-run homered highlighted a six-run fourth-inning rally and Brian Boehringer pitched 5 1/3 innings of scoreless relief for his first major-league win as the Yankees bombed the California Angels 17-6.</p>
<p>Leyritz tied a career high with five RBI as New York's 7,8 and 9 hitters went a combined 9-for-13 with 10 RBI.</p>
<p>The Angels scored five first-inning runs against Yankees starter David Weathers. Garret Anderson and Jorge Fabregas had two-run singles and Rex Hudler added an RBI double.</p>
<p>Paul O'Neill and Mariano Duncan added homers for New York, which batted around twice in the contest.</p>
<p>At Minnesota, Marty Cordova homered twice and drove in four runs as the Twins used a season-high 20-hit attack to defeat the Milwaukee Brewers 12-7.</p>
<p>Dave Nilsson's first of two homers had given Milwaukee a 3-0 leadin the first, but Scott Stahoviak led off the second with his 10th homer off Ricky Bones (7-14). Six pitches later, Cordova cracked his 11th homer.</p>
<p>Ron Coomer also homered for the Twins.</p>
<p>Jose Parra (5-3) pitched three innings in relief of starter Scott Klingenbeck, giving up two hits and two walks with a pair of strikeouts for his fourth straight win.</p>
<p>At Kansas City, Alex Gonzalez's leadoff homer in the 14th inning off Rick Huisman provided the go-ahead run and Mike Timlin won for the first time in exactly a year as the Toronto Blue Jays outlasted the Royals 6-5.</p>
<p>The teams traded runs in the 13th. Carlos Delgado hit a two-out home run, his 20th, off Huisman to give Toronto a 5-4 lead, but Craig Paquette tied the game with a one-out single off Timlin.</p>
<p>Domingo Cedeno had tied the game when he led off the ninth with a home run off Royals closer Jeff Montgomery.</p>
<p>Paquette and Kevin Young hit solo homers for K.C.</p>
<p>In Detroit, Melvin Nieves homered from both sides of the plate and drove in a career-high five runs as the Tigers snapped an eight-game losing streak with a 16-11 pounding of the Chicago White Sox.</p>
<p>Bob Higginson and Andujar Cedeno hit fourth-inning homers for the Tigers. Mark Lewis had three hits and scored two runs and Kimera Bartee added three hits and two RBI.</p>
<p>Frank Thomas, Robin Ventura, Tony Phillips and Danny Tartabull homered for the White Sox.</p>
<p>White Sox starter Kevin Tapani (11-8) was the loser, giving up nine runs and eight hits in four innings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CLEVELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
