<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5405" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-BRAVES ERRUPT FOR THREE HOMERS ON SIX PITCHES.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-BRAVES ERRUPT FOR THREE HOMERS ON SIX PITCHES.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Atlanta Braves made Cincinnati Reds pitcher Dave Burba feel black and blue on Tuesday night, exploding for three homers in six pitches during the third inning.</p>
<p>Terry Pendleton, Chipper Jones and Ryan Klesko all took Burba (7-12) downtown and Tom Glavine snapped a personal two-game losing streak as the Braves beat the Reds 4-1 for their fifth straight win.</p>
<p>With the score tied 1-1, Pendleton led off with his eighth homer. Three pitches later, Jones hit his 26th, extending his hitting streak to 14 games. After Fred McGriff popped out on the next pitch, Klesko belted the first pitch he saw for his team-high 30th homer to cap the scoring.</p>
<p>&quot;Burba made some mistakes,&quot; said Jones. &quot;Pendleton hit a good pitch, but he was down the middle to Ryan and me. Three runs on three pitches really picks you up.&quot;</p>
<p>Glavine (13-7) allowed five hits -- including a solo homer by Bret Boone -- over eight innings.  He walked three and struck out five.</p>
<p>Mark Wohlers pitched a perfect ninth inning for his 31st save.</p>
<p>In Chicago, Kevin Foster (4-2), recalled from the minors earlier in the day, allowed a run in five innings and keyed an eight-run first with a two-run triple, leading the Cubs to an 8-1 victory over the Florida Marlins.</p>
<p>Foster allowed two hits and a walk with a pair of strikeouts before giving way to Terry Adams, who hurled three perfect innings, and Turk Wendell, who added a 1-2-3 ninth.</p>
<p>Astro starter Mark Hutton (1-1) did not retire a batter, hitting Sammy Sosa and walking Luis Gonzalez to force in runs.</p>
<p>Chicago's Mark Grace singled in a run and extended his hit streak to 14 games.</p>
<p>In San Francisco, Bobby Jones allowed four hits and struck out a career-high 10 over seven innings and an obstruction call in a four-run eighth inning snapped a tie and helped the New York Mets to a 7-3 victory over the Giants.</p>
<p>Jones (11-7) allowed three runs, including homers to Rick Wilkins and Glenallen Hill, and walked one.</p>
<p>With the score tied at 3-3 in the eighth, pinch-hitter Carl Everett bounced a single into right field. As Alex Ochoa rounded third, Giants third baseman Bill Mueller cut into his path and was called for interference by umpire Gary Darling.</p>
<p>Todd Hundley hit his 37th homer for the Mets.</p>
<p>In San Diego, Greg Vaughn homered and Bob Tewksbury and two relievers combined on a three-hitter to lead the Padres to a 3-0 victory over the Montreal Expos.</p>
<p>In the sixth inning, Vaughn hit a 3-0 pitch from Rheal Cormier (7-9) over the left-field fence for a 1-0 lead.</p>
<p>Tewksbury (10-8) allowed three hits, walked one and struck out three over 7 2/3 innings. He retired 19 straight batters until Rondell White singled with two out in the eighth.</p>
<p>Doug Bochtler replaced Tewksbury in the eighth and Trevor Hoffman struck out one in a perfect ninth inning for his 30th save.</p>
<p>In Houston, Jeff Bagwell homered and drove in three runs and John Cangelosi had four hits as the Astros raced to a seven-run lead and beat the the Pittsburgh Pirates 9-4.</p>
<p>The Astros scored three times in the first inning against starter Dan Miceli (2-9), who gave up seven runs and nine hits over four innings as the Pirates lost their fifth straight.</p>
<p>Donne Wall (7-4) allowed three runs and seven hits through seven-plus innings as the Astros won for the eighth time in 12 games.  He walked one and struck out four.  Xavier Hernandez allowed one hit and struck out three in 1 2/3 innings for his third save.</p>
<p>In Los Angeles, pinch hitter Ruben Amaro's two-run homer with two out in the top of the ninth snapped a tie and centre fielder Wendell Magee's leaping catch at the wall for the final out preserved the lead as the Philadelphia Phillies defeated the Dodgers 3-1.</p>
<p>With two out in the ninth, Kevin Stocker doubled off Antonio Osuna (8-5). Amaro, pinch-hitting for winning pitcher Ricardo Jordan, hit the first pitch over the wall.</p>
<p>Eric Karros singled with one out off closer Ricky Bottalico in the ninth and Tim Wallach hit a ball that Magee reached over the fence and snared for the final out.</p>
<p>At Colorado, Dante Bichette's second homer of the game, a two-run blast with one out in the bottom of the 13th inning, lifted the Rockies past the St. Louis Cardinals, 5-4.</p>
<p>T.J. Mathews (2-5) gave up a bloop single to Andres Galarraga before Bichette drilled Mathews' first pitch.</p>
<p>Mike Munoz (1-2) recorded the win, despite giving up a run in the 13th when Brian Jordan singled in Ron Gant.</p>
<p>Galarraga also hit his 35th home run of the year.</p>
<p>The Cards nearly took the lead in the 12th off Marvin Freeman. Tom Pagnozzi walked with one out and Alicea doubled to deep right but Pagnozzi was thrown out at home.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
