<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5409" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-TEMPERS FLARE IN MILAN-JUVENTUS FRIENDLY.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-TEMPERS FLARE IN MILAN-JUVENTUS FRIENDLY.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian champions Milan beat European Cup holders Juventus 1-0 in a bad-tempered soccer friendly on Wednesday with each team having a man sent off in the second half.</p>
<p>Milan's Yugoslav striker Dejan Savicevic and Juventus midfielder Antonio Conte were sent off in the 59th minute after a scuffle on the pitch.</p>
<p>The home team's new Dutch signing Edgar Davids and Juventus midfielder Angelo Di Livio were fortunate not to join them after also trading blows out of sight of the referee two minutes from time.</p>
<p>Stefano Eranio scored the winning goal in the 84th minute, picking up a rebound from close range after Juventus goalkeeper Angelo Peruzzi parried a shot from Marco Simone, to secure the Luigi Berlusconi trophy.</p>
<p>The match was the first between the two old serie A rivals since last season's Milan coach Fabio Capello departed for Spain's Real Madrid and Juventus strikers Gianluca Vialli and Fabrizio Ravanelli moved to England's premier league.</p>
<p>Milan were without striker George Weah and former Italian international Roberto Baggio.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
