<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5411" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: ATHLETICS-DEVERS RUNS THIRD-FASTEST TIME OF THE SEASON.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-DEVERS RUNS THIRD-FASTEST TIME OF THE SEASON.</headline>
<dateline>LINZ, Austria 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Olympic champion Gail Devers ran the third-fastest time of the season to win the women's 100 metres at the Linz Grand Prix athletics meeting on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The American clocked 10.92 seconds for her first victory since her triumph in Atlanta, leaving Chandra Sturrup of the Bahamas well behind in second place with 11.16.</p>
<p>In the men's sprint, American Dennis Mitchell, who beat Olympic champion Donovan Bailey in Zurich last week, finished five hundredths of a second behind Nigerian Davidson Ezinwa who won in 10.01 seconds.</p>
<p>Ezinwa's twin brother Osmond was third in 10.09.</p>
<p>&quot;(At the start) I had too little time...the race was then a matter of catching up. I've got more in me than the 10.06,&quot; Mitchell said.</p>
<p>Allen Johnson repeated his Olympic triumph with victory in the 110 metres hurdles. The American finished in 13.25 seconds, four-hundredths ahead of Emilio Valle of Cuba.</p>
<p>Other Atlanta gold medallists also came up trumps.</p>
<p>Germany's Ilke Wyludda outclassed her rivals with a throw of 67.28 metres in the women's discus and Nigeria's long jump champion Chioma Ajunwa outjumped Austrian Ludmila Ninova and Heike Drechsler of Germany with 6.85 metres.</p>
<p>Olympic javelin gold medallist Jan Zelezny of the Czech Republic won his event by more than three metres with a throw of 89.24 metres.</p>
<p>But Randy Barnes of the U.S. failed to repeat his Olympic triumph in the shot, finishing third behind Italy's Paulo Dal Soglio and Ukraine's Aleksandr Bagach.</p>
<p>Theresia Kiesl, who won Austria's first ever track medal in Atlanta -- a bronze -- disappointed her home crowd when she finished second to Amy Wickus of the United States in the women's 1,500 metres.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LINZ, Austria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
