<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5414" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER-DORTMUND BOUNCE BACK TO THRASH DUESSELDORF 4-0.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-DORTMUND BOUNCE BACK TO THRASH DUESSELDORF 4-0.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bundesliga champions Borussia Dortmund bounced back from their opening-day defeat to thrash Fortuna Duesseldorf 4-0 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Skipper Michael Zorc set Dortmund on their way to a comfortable win with a goal in the 35th minute. He finally got the better of Georg Koch after the Duesseldorf goalkeeper had denied him three times early in the half.</p>
<p>Swiss international Stephane Chapuisat added the second six minutes later.</p>
<p>Substitute Karl Heinz Riedle scored twice in the second half, his second set up by new arrival Paulo Sousa.</p>
<p>Bayer Leverkusen, who beat Dortmund 4-2 on Saturday, carried on in a similar vein against Duisburg, a hat-trick by Ulf Kirsten powering them to a 3-1 win.</p>
<p>Kirsten struck in the 65th, 71st and 82nd minutes after Markus Marin had put Duisburg ahead with a penalty in the 54th minute.</p>
<p>Bayern Munich fared less well, drawing 1-1 with Bochum at home. They were booed by their fans and criticised by club president Franz Beckenbauer.</p>
<p>&quot;The players thought this would be easy. They thought they could win by playing at half strength,&quot; said Beckenbauer. &quot;But 50 percent is too little against this opposition.&quot;</p>
<p>Ruggiero Rizzitelli put Bayern ahead in the 52nd minute. Peter Peschel equalised after 73 minutes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
