<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5422" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: THE SPORT SIDE - DUTCH CHAMPS AJAX OUT OF SORTS.</title>
<headline>THE SPORT SIDE - DUTCH CHAMPS AJAX OUT OF SORTS.</headline>
<byline>Ian Geoghegan</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>On the eve of the new Dutch soccer season, Ajax Amsterdam, European champions in 1995 and runners-up in 1996, are looking out of sorts.</p>
<p>In their last five pre-season games the Dutch champions have conceded 16 goals without themselves finding the net once.</p>
<p>Racked by injury and bedevilled by waning confidence, the world club champions look a pale shadow of the side that in recent years has rivalled Blackbeard the pirate in capturing silverware.</p>
<p>The latest setback, Sunday's 3-0 defeat by a strong, fluent PSV Eindhoven in the Johan Cruyff Shield, the traditional season curtain-raiser, exposed alarming deficiencies in an Ajax machine that is used to sweeping all before it.</p>
<p>Coming hard on the heels of drubbings by AC Milan, Juventus and Spain's Deportivo La Coruna, as well as defeat against Ruud Gullit's Chelsea, the extent of PSV's superiority in all departments will worry Ajax coach Louis van Gaal.</p>
<p>PSV, European champions in 1988 and now led by former Dutch coach Dick Advocaat, have fired a serious warning at Ajax -- it was their first win in Amsterdam for almost four years -- and they look a good bet to usurp the Dutch crown.</p>
<p>But it would be unwise to write off Ajax, bidding for their fourth consecutive Dutch title and 27th in total, before the season kicks off in earnest.</p>
<p>Van Gaal sees no reason to panic, preferring to blame a lengthy list of players injured or recovering, including internationals Marc Overmars, Patrick Kluivert, Winston Bogarde and Peter Hoekstra.</p>
<p>Defections, not helped by the Bosman ruling which made stars like Edgar Davids and Michael Reiziger give-away bargains for AC Milan, have also forced Van Gaal to chop, change and improvise his line-up.</p>
<p>&quot;I have to protect the players from themselves. Many of them just aren't yet fit enough for big games. Only the Boer brothers (Frank and Ronald) and (Edwin) van der Saar are really fit.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I can't really change anything. Some players need time to get into a rhythm. We usually use the pre-season to get the team to build up a head of steam, but we'll have to make the most of the next games just to limit the damage,&quot; Van Gaal said.</p>
<p>Dutch media have also speculated that Ajax's move to a new home, the towering multi-billion dollar Arena, has eroded the club's previous air of invincibility at the cramped de Meer stadium.</p>
<p>&quot;The recent defeats hurt, they have damaged our confidence and will have given other opponents heart,&quot; Van Gaal said.</p>
<p>&quot;Other teams will have been watching and will come here with more confidence. At the Meer we built up a fearsome reputation which we don't yet have at the Arena. We're going to have to work on that.&quot;</p>
<p>Van Gaal insists he has bought wisely over the summer, replacing Davids and Reiziger, as well as the Nigerian pair Finidi George and Nwankwo Kanu.</p>
<p>But Richard Witschge, who caught the eye during the European championships, is no Davids. His languid style, deft touch and superb passing will help when Ajax go forward. But Davids's strength was as ball-winner when the team were under pressure.</p>
<p>Mariano Juan, the young Argentine who cannot yet communicate with his team mates, is no replacement for Bogarde, another who emerged from Dutch disappointment at Euro 96 with his reputation enhanced, while Kluivert's slow recuperation may force Van Gaal to shop around for a stand-in goalscorer.</p>
<p>Babangida, signed from Roda to replace his fellow countryman Finidi, has looked sluggish, while both Peter Hoekstra and Finn Jari Litmanen are struggling to find form and confidence.</p>
<p>PSV's emergence from a summer of canny buying as serious title contenders has whetted the appetite of Dutch soccer fans and may spell an end to Ajax's recent hegemony.</p>
<p>The champions begin the defence of their title against NAC of Breda on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
