<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5423" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: CRICKET-AUSTRALIA READY TO PLAY DESPITE SECURITY WORRIES.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-AUSTRALIA READY TO PLAY DESPITE SECURITY WORRIES.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The usually combative Australian wicketkeeper and stand-in captain Ian Healy said on Wednesday he was willing to play diplomat to mend the strained relations with Sri Lanka's cricketers.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, I think I can do that without much difficulty,&quot; Healy told a news conference after being asked if he should now be a diplomat.</p>
<p>Australia, making their first visit to Sri Lanka since boycotting a World Cup fixture in February, arrived in Colombo on Tuesday night for a limited overs tournament which also includes India and Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>Healy is leading the side in place of injured captain Mark Taylor. Leg-spinner Shane Warne is also missing because of injury.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got sufficient replacements, but whether they got sufficient experience to fill their hole is to be seen,&quot; Healy said. &quot;You can't replace these fellows overnight.&quot;</p>
<p>Healy said the 13-man squad still had reservations about playing in Sri Lanka, which has been fighting a civil war with separatist Tamil guerrillas for the past 13 years.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd be lying if I said there are no worries,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Colombo's police chief has said he would deploy commandoes, sniffer dogs and plainclothed policemen in a massive security operation to ensure the tournament was trouble-free.</p>
<p>Relations between the sides were badly strained last year when the Sri Lankans were first found guilty and then cleared of ball tampering, and spinner Muttiah Muralitharan was called for throwing during a controversial test series in Australia.</p>
<p>Many Sri Lankans believe the Australians forfeited their World Cup opener in Colombo not due to security fears but due to fears of hostile local crowds.</p>
<p>&quot;The reception we got has dispelled fears,&quot; Healy said.</p>
<p>Tour manager Cam Battersby said the team had been well received.</p>
<p>&quot;We've already experienced what we've experienced in the past -- that marvellous Sri Lankan hospitality,&quot; Battersby said.</p>
<p>He said Australia were keen to avenge their defeat by Sri Lanka in the final of the World Cup in Lahore in March.</p>
<p>The two-week, four-nation Singer World Series begins on August 26.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
