<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5425" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: GOLD FIELDS, UNIONS AGREE VIOLENCE MUST END.</title>
<headline>GOLD FIELDS, UNIONS AGREE VIOLENCE MUST END.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>In the wake of severe labour unrest, which claimed at least 17 lives, mine management and unions agreed on Wednesday that violence should cease, Gold Fields of South Africa Ltd chief executive Alan Wright said.</p>
<p>Speaking at a presentation of the group's year results, Wright said labour issues were critical at Gold Fields' mines and management was facing a &quot;fairly severe dilemma&quot;.</p>
<p>In the past two weeks violent union action, hinting at ethnic conflict, killed at least 17 miners at Gold Fields' Kloof Gold Mining Co and Driefontein Consolidated .</p>
<p>&quot;We've had a number of tragedies at our mines in the past couple of weeks... management have a fairly severe dilemma on their hands. </p>
<p>&quot;We had talks this morning (Wednesday) and consensus was reached on the basis that all of us feel there should be no more violence. No more tragedies,&quot; Wright said.</p>
<p>He urged the safe return to work for all employees who wished to and warned that those who did not stood the risk of losing their jobs.</p>
<p>Hesitant to say the conflict was ethnically based, Wright did emphasise that the National Union of Mineworkers (NUM) had a traditional Xhosa membership, while the United Workers of South Africa (Uwusa) drew mostly Zulus.</p>
<p>&quot;It is hard to say whether it is a straight ethnic fight but if it is, then it can still be interpreted as unions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>NUM is aligned to the African National Congress, while the smaller Uwusa is linked to Chief Mangosuthu Buthelezi's Inkatha Freedom Party. </p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
