<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5426" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: GOLD FIELDS URGES MORE MINE SHIFTS WORKED.</title>
<headline>GOLD FIELDS URGES MORE MINE SHIFTS WORKED.</headline>
<byline>Melanie Cheary</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Miners must work more shifts if the South African mining industry is to survive, Gold Fields of South Africa chief executive Alan Wright said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Speaking at a presentation of Gold Fields' year results, he criticised rising working costs at the group's mines and the slow progress being made on full calendar operations (FULCO).</p>
<p>&quot;The costs on our mines are increasing at a rate equivalent to the price of the product we are selling,&quot; Wright said.</p>
<p>&quot;We reached agreement in priniciple with all unions but I don't believe we are any further down the path to FULCO operations than we were a year ago. If we don't change to FULCO we're going to lose our industry in South Africa.&quot;</p>
<p>Gold Fields posted earnings per share for the year ended June 30 of 393 cents from 417 cents previously. It declared a steady dividend of 220 cents per share.</p>
<p>In the same period unit working costs rose to 34,000 rand per kg of gold produced from 28,000 rand.</p>
<p>&quot;Unit working costs were up 21 percent year-on-year. As we go deeper it costs more... we are also being pushed into higher wage agreements,&quot; Wright said.</p>
<p>Gold Fields, a member of the Chamber of Mines employer negotiating body, has yet to sign a wage agreement with the unions on 1996/97 wages and working conditions.</p>
<p>Wright urged the industry to reach rapid agreement on FULCO in order to compete successfully with global mining companies.</p>
<p>&quot;We are competing where major global companies work a 20 out of a possibe 21 shifts (per week)... We work 11 shifts every fortnight. I hope for the benefit of the entire industry that very quickly we can move to working seven days a week.&quot;</p>
<p>Looking to the future, he said that Gold Fields would focus on mining -- particularly gold -- and aggressive exploration.</p>
<p>&quot;Mining will remain the core business of Gold Fields, focused on exploration, mining and mineral beneficiation.</p>
<p>&quot;(We plan to) progressively expand through exploration and investments in new selected geological and geographical areas.&quot;</p>
<p>The group's ultimate cocnentration would be on gold to build maximum shareholder wealth, Wright said.</p>
<p>The short to medium term would see the group capitalising on its existing &quot;super mine&quot; asses -- Driefontein Consolidated Ltd and Kloof Gold Mining Co Ltd .</p>
<p>Wright said the group had budgeted 86 million rand for exploration capital spending this financial year -- 36 million of which would be spent on exploration in South Africa. Gold exploration would win 54 million of the 86 million rand.</p>
<p>Underground fires at Kloof and Dries' east and west mines in May and JUne had knocked the group's gold production -- losing it 1.5 tonnes of gold valued at 82 million rand, Wright said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
