<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5429" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOTSWANA: PRESS DIGEST - BOTSWANA - AUG 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - BOTSWANA - AUG 21.</headline>
<dateline>GABORONE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in Botswana's independent midweek newspapers The Sun and The Gazette on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE SUN</p>
<p>- Debswana, the 50/50 partnership between De Beers Centenary and the Botswana government, is to spend one billion pula to double treatment capacity at the Orapa diamond mine. This will increase Botwana's annual diamond production from 17 million carats to 23 million.</p>
<p>- The former general manager of the Botswana Housing Corporation, Gaolekwe abana, having successfuly fought a case against wrongful dismissal and been awarded payment 400,000 pula, is now charged with corruption involving the award of building contracts to a building firm.</p>
<p>- A freelance journalist has been charged by the Directorate of Corruption and Economic Crime (DCEC) for revealing the name of a person under investigation by the department, contrary to the Ant-Corruption Act.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE GAZETTE</p>
<p>- The government announced a nine-member Vision 2020 task group to define and shape the long term vision of the country. Members of the public are invited to make submisions to the group as to how they see Botswana's future social and economic development.</p>
<p>- Gaborone newsroom (+267) 347182</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GABORONE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOTSWANA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
