<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5431" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: BARLOWS TO LIST ON NAMIBIAN STOCK EXCHANGE.</title>
<headline>BARLOWS TO LIST ON NAMIBIAN STOCK EXCHANGE.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African group Barlow Ltd said on Wednesday it would list its ordinary shares on the Namibian Stock Exchange (NSE) on September 11.</p>
<p>The shares will have full Namibian asset status.</p>
<p>Barlows chairman Warren Clewlow said the move reflected the company's faith in the Namibian economy and the success of the NSE, which was proving an increasingly attractive institution for local and foreign investors.</p>
<p>&quot;For this reason, we think it appropriate that our Namibian-based investors should have the opportunity to deal in Barlow shares through their own stock market.&quot;</p>
<p>Barlows has a significant presence in Namibia through its Windhoek-based Sonnex subsidiary, which employs around 360 people.</p>
<p>Activities include the distribution of Caterpillar and Hyster equipment, the manufacture of Plascon paints and the production of building materials. </p>
<p>From September 1, Sonnex will also be countrywide franchise holder for BMW and Landrover, except for Landrover in Walvis Bay and Swakopmund.</p>
<p>The NSE, founded four years ago, currently has 26 listed companies.  </p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NAMIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
