<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5438" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - SOUTH AFRICA - AUG 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - SOUTH AFRICA - AUG 21.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- Government has released a consolidated, country-by-country breakdown of South Africa's trade which shows its growing reliance on exports to African countries.</p>
<p>- The rand would renew its assault on the 4.60 level against the dollar, which could signal the turning point for the currency, traders predicted.</p>
<p>- Government's low-cost housing programme has received a major boost with private sector participation materialising in Gauteng province, where 20,000 houses will be built over three years in a one billion rand deal.</p>
<p>- Gold Fields' Leeudoorn gold mine was tense last night as management and union officials met to stabilise the situation after clashes which left four miners dead.</p>
<p>- Packaging and rubber group Consol increased earnings before exceptional items by 17 percent, overcoming a weaker second half performance induced by a decline in the economy.</p>
<p>- Food group Kolosus has quietly striped Silveroak Industries of assets and sold it after the subsidiary was landed with a $100 million damages claim from its former U.S. partner.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- The government will look for ways to lower taxes on low-income earners in next year's budget, Gill Marcus, deputy minister of finance, said.</p>
<p>- The International Monetary Fund has proposed scrapping the special tax regime for mining companies in South Africa and the imposition of a levy on them for developing minerals.</p>
<p>- A top-level meeting last night to settle conditions for the purchase of Anglo American's 48 percent stake in Johnnies Industrial Corp by New African Investment Ltd and the National Empowerment Consortium failed after Anglo raised the issue of an editorial charter for its newspaper interests.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- German businessmen have issued a stern warning to the government to curb escalating crime or face future disinvestment.</p>
<p>- Two policemen have been quizzed in connection with South Africa's biggest armed robbery, the 31 million rand heist at Pinetown, near Durban, earlier this month.</p>
<p>- Johannesburg's Kippies jazz club, one of the city's best known venues, is to close after receiving an eviction notice from the property owners.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
