<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5439" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: PRESS DIGEST - CENTRAL/EAST EUROPE - AUG 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - CENTRAL/EAST EUROPE - AUG 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>ALBANIA</p>
<p>KOHA JONE</p>
<p>- An editorial said Albania could not expect European Union membership unless democracy was fully respected.</p>
<p>- At an upcoming party convention, the opposition Socialist Party is due to announce its complete separation from the former communist party and the late dictator Enver Hoxha, the party presidency decided at its last meeting.</p>
<p>GAZETA SHQIPTARE</p>
<p>- Fires have destroyed thousands of hectares of forest in southern Albania.</p>
<p>AUSTRIA</p>
<p>DIE PRESSE</p>
<p>- Johannes Ditz, finance chief of the national postal system, said he doubted the 1999 deadline for privatisation could be met. He said it was only possible &quot;under optimal conditions&quot;.</p>
<p>- Austria has the fourth highest wage costs world-wide.</p>
<p>- Austria's industry is not expected to pick up until 1997, chamber of economy expert Joachim Lamel said.</p>
<p>- OMV is investing seven billion schillings in a new expansion drive this year, almost twice as much as last year. The company plans to build 100 petrol stations abroad by 1998 and cut the number of stations in Austria.</p>
<p>DER STANDARD</p>
<p>- Tyre-maker Semperit AG will be split into two limited liability companies directly subordinate to the German group Continental. The two units will handle sales and production seperately.</p>
<p>KURIER</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Viktor Klima said the state would have to consider a tax reform in 1999 or 2000 &quot;at the latest&quot;. He said loopholes would be eliminated and tax rates cut.</p>
<p>- Raiffeisen Zentralbank said it was expanding its eastern European activities, moving into investment banking in Croatia and Russia. The company expects both sectors to break even within two years.</p>
<p>CROATIA</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- Citizens express great interest in moving to areas of special state interest.</p>
<p>- Croatian-Yugoslav talks on the missing and captured: Croatia looking for 2,605 people, while Yugoslavia's request stands at 999 people.</p>
<p>- Is the end of 1996 to see some 300,000 people out of work?</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- Just 4 more months until the new value added tax (PDV) takes effect: entrepreneurs are getting acquainted with the new tax system.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- Has mutual recognition between Croatia and Yugoslavia run into problems due to Prevlaka?</p>
<p>- We'll be introducting drastic measures in an attempt to quash the labour black market, says in an interview the deputy minister for labour and social welfare Vera Stanic. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
<p>CZECH REPUBLIC</p>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - The Czech Airplane industry could take part in the manufacturing of F/A-18 fighter planes if the Czech Air Force chooses this type of plane, Gary E. Mitchell from McDonnell Douglas told reporters yesterday.</p>
<p>- The government is prepared to protect consumers from rising food prices by preventing farmers from raising the prices of their crops after this year's harvest according to the head of the Prime Minister's advisors.</p>
<p>- By the year 2000, nuclear energy should account for 44 percent of all energy produced in the country, compared with last year's 26 percent, Coal-based energy should decrease from 70 percent to 53 percent by the end of the millenium according to Ladislav Kriz from electrical utility CEZ.</p>
<p>- The export of Czech electronics to the European Union increased by more than 40 percent to 912 million ECU in 1995 compared with 1994 levels.</p>
<p>- Czech engineering conrecn Skoda denied it is obtaining shares in Omnipol, the largest Czech weapons manufacturer, through Cimex Holding.  Skoda Praha is currently not involved in any weapons production and is not interested in purchasing shares of companies which produce weapons, Jaroslav Hudec, Skoda Plzen's press agent, stated yesterday.</p>
<p>- The quality of hops from this year's harvest will be above average with an average of a tonne of hops per hectare expected.</p>
<p>- The general manager of Kladno's Poldi Ocel steel plant, Vladimir Stehlik, has called the company's employees to work starting with the morning shift on Monday, August 26. According to the company's former general director, at least seven weeks will be necessary to get the plant back to full capacity.</p>
<p>PRAVO - Computers from the american company Apple computers will continue to be sold on the Czech market in spite of the fact that TIS, a local computer company, broke its exclusive contract with Apple Computers on August 7th.</p>
<p>- According to Agriculture Minister Josef Lux, the Czech government has recommended the sale of a minority, 11-percent share in steel makers Vitkovice and Nova Hut, a group of foundery's located in Northern Moravia, to the foundry's management. -- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
<p>LATVIA</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- The government dismissed the chief of the state revenue service Imants Grikis and appointed Andrejs Sonchiks to replace him. The official explanation is that he was replaced in connection with an overall reorganisation of the service, the unofficial reason is that he failed to solve a dispute with market workers who did not want electronic cash registers.</p>
<p>- The deputy chairman of the parliament education committee Juris Celmins said plans by Prime Minister Andris Shkele to reform the system of paying wages to teachers is contrary to the law on education and the law on the state budget.</p>
<p>- Foreign ministers of the three Baltic States and five Nordic Countries met in Riga. They discussed the abolition of visa regulations, security problems and integration with the EU.</p>
<p>- The government approved a package of draft laws needed to reform the border troop service by giving them over to the ministry of the interior.</p>
<p>- The parliament defence committee prepared the draft law on compulsory military service for its second reading. To pass the law, Shkele may ask parliament to convoke an extraordinary session this Friday.</p>
<p>- A Riga city council committee has revealed several transgressions of the law by the administration of the Riga central district in restoring the right of ownership to several houses in the district.</p>
<p>- In Vilnius, the newly appointed Latvian ambassador to Lithuania, Atis Sjanitis, presented his credentials to Lithuanian President Algirdas Brazauskas.</p>
<p>DIENA</p>
<p>- The privatisation of enterprises by liquidating them may lead to an increase in the level of unemployment in Latvia, which was at 7.1 percent in July.</p>
<p>NEATKARIGA RITA AVIZE</p>
<p>- Lithuania's parliament called on Latvian deputies not to ratify the licence agreement between Latvia and Amoco , which, the Lithuanians believe, may harm relations between the two countries.</p>
<p>BIZNESS &amp; BALTIYA</p>
<p>- According to statistical data, in the first half of 1996 cargo turnover in Latvian ports increased by 15 percent.</p>
<p>DIENAS BIZNESS</p>
<p>- Latvian van maker RAF is going to offer ambulance vehicles made on the basis of the Chevrolet Astrovan.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
<p>SLOVAKIA</p>
<p>NARODNA OBRODA - Some 92,729 orders to sell privatisation bonds have been registered on the over-the-counter RMS since beginning of trading two weeks ago. No anonymous trades, however, have been concluded so far.</p>
<p>- Gear box producer Sachs Trnava, a 100-percent subsidiary of German Fichtel und Sach A.G., plans turnover of 500 million crowns this year, up from 370 million in 1995. The company, exporting 80 percent of its production to Germany and the Czech Republic, plans to increase turnover to one billion crowns by the year 2001.</p>
<p>- The Slovak Association of Agricultural Companies (ZPD) said it would propose exports of grain if this year's harvest exceeds the country's consumption needs. The agriculture ministry had said it would not grant any export licences this year.</p>
<p>- The National Property Fund, which issued privatisation bonds, registered 88 entities entitled to purchase the bonds.</p>
<p>SME - Today is the 28th anniversary of invasion of the former Warsaw Pact armies into then Czechoslovakia.</p>
<p>- The finance ministry said revenues from sale of privatisation bonds would be tax-free.</p>
<p>PRACA - The ZPD demands the state fund of market regulation to increase prices of grain to 4,000 crowns per tonne, from the proposed maximum price of 3,700 crowns.</p>
<p>- ZPD warns that if government does not solve the current problems of Slovak agriculture domestic production will radically decrease within two years, resulting in significant increase of food prices as most of the food will have to be imported.</p>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - Volkswagen A.G. plans to invest about 41.8 million marks in its Slovak subsidiary, located in the capital Bratislava, next year.</p>
<p>- Completion of the highway connecting the northern Slovak town of Zilina with the Polish borders is expected to cost about 18 billion crowns.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
