<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5447" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: SLOVAK C.BANK SAYS BILL RATE HIKE SIGNAL TO MKT.</title>
<headline>SLOVAK C.BANK SAYS BILL RATE HIKE SIGNAL TO MKT.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Bank of Slovakia (NBS) on Wednesday said it raised the yield of its three-month liquidity bills as part of its attempts to ease inflationary pressures building from a burgeoning money supply.</p>
<p>&quot;We set the yield higher to signal the central bank is willing to drain the liquidity surplus at a rate appropriate to the current interbank money market level,&quot; Peter Andresic, NBS chief-dealer, told Reuters.</p>
<p>He declined to comment on the issue further.</p>
<p>Yield on the NBS bills auctioned on Wednesday hit 9.3 percent, up from 8.99 percent in the last successful auction of similar bills on June 26.</p>
<p>The market and the NBS have been waging a war of words recently over the yield of central bank bills, which dealers said was too low. As a result, several central bank auctions have failed over the past two months.</p>
<p>Slovak interbank money market rates held steady after the rise but dealers said the hike would not stem the recent downtrend of interbank rates to the current bid range of 12.0-12.9 percent on all terms.</p>
<p>&quot;The yield is nothing compared to the nine percent coupon on one-year state bonds to be issued tommorow,&quot; said Dalibor Cernicka of Istrobanka.</p>
<p>&quot;This also hardens the NBS position, as it has created a great arbitrage opportunity, pushing for bill repurchase rate hike, as opposed the expected cut,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The NBS repo and reverse repo rates, generally accepted as the key price determining factor on the market, currently stand at 8.2 and 7.4 percent respectively.</p>
<p>-- Tatiana Vacova, Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
