<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5449" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: CZECH FINMIN SEES SPEND CUTS ACROSS ALL MINISTRIES.</title>
<headline>CZECH FINMIN SEES SPEND CUTS ACROSS ALL MINISTRIES.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech Finance Ministry is seeking cuts of roughly more than one percent from the 1996 budgets of every ministry in order to balance the state budget by the year's end, a senior ministry official said.</p>
<p>&quot;The total we need to cut is roughly 9.3 billion crowns,&quot; Deputy Finance Minister Miroslav Havel told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Earlier, Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus told a news conference after a cabinet meeting that a finance ministry plan to balance the budget would be on the agenda of next week's cabinet meeting.</p>
<p>Havel said the cuts, needed because of a projected 6.6 billion crown revenue shortfall and a 2.7 billion over-expenditure from the originally approved balanced budget, would not affect pensions or civil service wages.</p>
<p>&quot;(The cuts) will touch every ministry and in the same level -- the same percentage of reduction of several non-investment outlays. Certainly we're not cutting pensions or wages,&quot; sadi Havel, who directs budget planning for the ministry.</p>
<p>&quot;But we are reducing such expenditures on materials and other things,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>The budget cuts, if passed, would reduce the entire 1996 state budget to 291 billion crowns from the plan passed by parliament last December.</p>
<p>He said the revenue gap was mostly due to Russia's failure to pay about five billion crowns on loans owed to the country.</p>
<p>The largest component of the over-expenditure was subsidies for heating because of the longer than expected winter and other social aid payments, he said.</p>
<p>A sampling of the proposed cuts were presented to a council of economic ministers on Tuesday. Havel said although most were not happy to make the reductions in their own budgets, there was a larger macroeconomic question at stake.</p>
<p>&quot;You know (the ministers) don't like cutting their budgets. But we're doing it because of the total macroeconomic situation,&quot; Havel said.</p>
<p>Annual inflation has remained stubbornly around nine percent this year, and the central bank has been seeking ways to reduce demand on the money supply.</p>
<p>&quot;Because inflation this year in certain ways has shifted and will be probably higher than we expected...if the budget ended in deficit, it would mean a further increase in demand on the money supply,&quot; Havel said.</p>
<p>-- John Mastrini, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
