<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5450" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: ROMANIA OFFERS FRESH STATE COMPANIES FOR SALE.</title>
<headline>ROMANIA OFFERS FRESH STATE COMPANIES FOR SALE.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's State Ownership Fund (FPS), which is managing the country's privatisation programme, has added another 40 companies to the list of firms on offer in a cumbersome mass selloff scheme.</p>
<p>Stakes of up to 51 percent in the companies can now be purchased for cash. This year the FPS has offered large holdings in 625 companies and says it has found buyers for stakes in 341 firms.</p>
<p>But the FPS cannot yet say how much it has raised or the size of the stakes purchased.</p>
<p>The FPS is now awaiting letters of intent from local and foreign individual and corporate investors willing to buy stakes of 40 or 51 percent in the 40 new offerings, a FPS official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Romania's mass selloff programme offered up to 60 percent of 3,905 companies to adult Romanians in exchange for free vouchers and coupons. The remaining stakes -- of at least 40 percent -- were scheduled for cash sales.</p>
<p>The 40 companies are in sectors including construction, transport, trade, metal and light industries, agriculture and services, the FPS said, and are various sizes.</p>
<p>The FPS said it would work out starting prices for the stakes when it receives the letters of intent. The nominal value of the shares of the 40 companies is 25,000 lei each.</p>
<p>In a separate scheme, the FPS has privatised around 2,300 state enterprises so far, mostly through worker-management buyouts.</p>
<p>Local economists say lack of domestic capital, bureaucracy, a corrupt business environment and inadequate laws are to blame for low foreign investor interest which has meant the bulk of the Romanian economy is still in state hands.</p>
<p>Faster privatisation, as well as restructuring of communist-era industrial giants are targets Romania must meet under loan accords with international lenders. ($=3,156 lei) -- Luli Popescu, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
