<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5454" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: SLD WANTS TREASURY MINISTRY, ECONOMY MIN. FOR PSL.</title>
<headline>SLD WANTS TREASURY MINISTRY, ECONOMY MIN. FOR PSL.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The co-ruling Democratic Left Alliance (SLD) should control the powerful treasury portfolio, which is to be created under the coming reconstruction of the ministries, a SLD official was quoted as saying on Wednesday.</p>
<p>PAP news agency quoted Jerzy Szmajdzinski, the head of SLD's parliamentary caucus as saying that the coalition's smaller partner, the Polish Peasant Party (PSL), should be in charge of the new economy ministry.</p>
<p>The two parties are scheduled to begin discussion on the cabinet reshuffle on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>The treasury ministry -- due to be created in October -- would encompass the current privatisation ministry and take charge of of all state assets controlled by the central government.</p>
<p>The ministry would be put in charge of those state-owned companies which are now supervised by the finance, privatisation, telecommunications and industry ministries.</p>
<p>It is logical that SLD should appoint its candidate to the treasury ministry because its member Wieslaw Kaczmarek is now privatisation minister, Szmajdzinski was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>It was also logical that a PSL candidate should head the economy ministry since it would emerge from the current industry and foreign trade ministries, controlled by the Peasants, he was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>PSL officials earlier said that putting SLD's candidates in charge of the treasury and finance ministries would give the party too much influence in the government.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
