<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5456" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: SECTOR GROWTH POTENTIAL PRICED IN TVK - BAGC.</title>
<headline>SECTOR GROWTH POTENTIAL PRICED IN TVK - BAGC.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank Austria-GiroCredit Befektetesi Rt rated the shares of Hungary's chemical giant TVK as &quot;hold&quot; saying the sector's growth potential was already built into its price.</p>
<p>&quot;The sector is set for strong growth and we believe this is already reflected in TVK'sprice,&quot; analysts Anthony Vago and Rupert Foster said in a company update.</p>
<p>&quot;We therefore only recommend the stock as a hold, even though its current price/earnings ratio is at a 14.2 percent discount to that of (chemical firm) Borsodchem which in our opinion is a stock with better growth prospects and less risk.&quot;</p>
<p>TVK, Hungary's largest chemical firm, produces olefins and polyolefins and processes plastics goods.</p>
<p>The growth in demand for polyolefins in Central and Eastern Europe should be high for the next decade and should even exceed those in Western Europe due to relatively higher economic growth within the region, the analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;However, the company is already operating at nearly full capacity which means that without a large investment in a new plant it will be unable to take advantage of the growth opportunity,&quot; they said.</p>
<p>The analysts said they believed the prices of polyolefins peaked in the first half of 1996 and they saw the cycle to enter a major downturn towards the end of 1997 as supply on the market increases.</p>
<p>Furthermore, they added, whilst the prices of oil based inputs are expected to fall, this will only be temporary and prices should rise towards the end of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Thus the company's margins will be reduced as there is downward pressure on sales prices and rising input prices,&quot; the analysts said.</p>
<p>On the Budapest Stock Exchange TVK shares closed unchanged at 1,345 forints.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
