<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5465" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: PRESS DIGEST - SWITZERLAND - AUG 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - SWITZERLAND - AUG 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>NEUE ZUERCHER ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- The Swiss farmers association demanded massive intervention form the government with regard to the Swiss meat market. The farmers hope to raise meat prices to an acceptable level.</p>
<p>- Swiss Economic forecasting institute BAK said it expected Switzerland's real gross domestic product (GDP) to decline by 0.4 percent in 1996 compared to the previous year. In spring, BAK predicted a 0.9 increase in GDP.</p>
<p>- The Swiss government said in an answer to a parlamentary request that it did not want to conduct referendums via the internet, claiming results could be manipulated.</p>
<p>TAGES ANZEIGER</p>
<p>- Swiss sports equipment market be concentrated as Intersport Schweiz AG and PSC Power Sport Corporation with its subsidies Camaro Sport AG and Zentralsport announced plans to merge.</p>
<p>- The Swiss government might postpone the referendum over the new labour law from December 1, 1996 to March 2, 1997. Swiss labour unions said the desision to postpone the referendum could have been initiated by employers associations, who first wanted to push through wage cuts at the end of the year before tackling the debate of the new labour law.</p>
<p>JOURNAL DE GENEVE</p>
<p>- ABB Switzerland reported a seven percent drop in net profit to 139 million Swiss francs for the 1996 first half. Sales rose by nine percent to 2,594 million francs in the same period. REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
