<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5471" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: S&amp;P SAYS MERITA ASSETS IMPROVING.</title>
<headline>S&amp;P SAYS MERITA ASSETS IMPROVING.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's said in a statement received here on Wednesday its upgrading to BBB plus from BBB of Merita Oy's unsecured long-term debt reflected the banking group's strong funding and improving asset quality.</p>
<p>&quot;The rating action reflects the dominant position that Merita holds in the Finnish banking industry, its strong funding, and improving asset quality,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>Attaching a stable outlook to its new rating, S&amp;P, however, said Merita's &quot;ability to improve profitability is restrained by an economy that continues to be characterised by high structural unemployment and slack credit and consumer demand.&quot;</p>
<p>The bank's ability to &quot;diversify ... income streams, while aggressively reducing a high cost base will be an important factor in improving the financial strength of Merita in the future,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>Many of the Finnish banking sector's problems of the early 1990s had now been resolved. &quot;Asset-quality indicators are likely to continue to improve in the short term,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>But Merita would remain vulnerable to economic downturns, and S&amp;P also said a &quot;very competitive operating environment&quot; would place downward pressure on margins. This would suppress efforts to strengthen profitability and capitalisation.</p>
<p>&quot;Standard &amp; Poor's continues to have concerns regarding asset concentration in the domestic economy,&quot; the credit rating institute said.</p>
<p>But as Merita was &quot;very important to the ongoing payments system in Finland&quot; the government would have a &quot;strong incentive ... to stand behind the bank if a financial crisis occurred in the future,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>In its June 1996 KreditGuide report covering the Nordic countries, S&amp;P said the outlook for Merita was stable.</p>
<p>&quot;Although asset quality indicators have improved lately as the economy benefits from an export-led recovery, the amelioration in the creditworthiness of the new bank will likely proceed at a slower pace,&quot; the June report said.</p>
<p>--Helsinki Newsroom  +358 - 0 - 680 50 245</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
