<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5477" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: NOKIA NEW PLANT TERMINAL CAPACITY 1 MLN/YR.</title>
<headline>NOKIA NEW PLANT TERMINAL CAPACITY 1 MLN/YR.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish telecommunications group Nokia Oy said in a statement on Wednesday the multimedia terminal output capacity of its new factory in Sweden would be about one million units per year.</p>
<p>&quot;Nokia Multimedia Network Terminal's new factory will employ a staff of 300. The production capacity will be approximately one million 'd-boxes' per year and the factory will have space for further expansion,&quot; Nokia said.</p>
<p>The so called 'd-box' developed by Nokia is a device which turns a normal televisin set into a personal computer.  </p>
<p>&quot;The TV can thus be used for receiving the growing number of digital satellite-TV programs as well as interactive services like home shopping, dataprograms, CD-ROM-services as sell as e-mail and telefax. The walls between entertainment, data-services and telecommunication have thus disappeared,&quot; Nokia said.</p>
<p>The new factory was opened on Wednesday in Motala, Sweden, Nokia said.</p>
<p>&quot;The future global market for digital multimedia terminals is predicted to have an enormous growth potential where European technology will play a leading role,&quot; Nokia said.</p>
<p>An order won by Nokia last year for one million multimedia terminals to Beta-Technik, part of the German Kirch media group, was the largest single order so far for multimedia terminals in Europe, it said.</p>
<p>---Helsinki Newsroom +358-0-680 50 248</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
