<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5478" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU'S EASTERN APPLICANTS MAY FACE LONG WAIT.</title>
<headline>EU'S EASTERN APPLICANTS MAY FACE LONG WAIT.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Clayton</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Like eager students looking for careers, countries from central and eastern Europe hoping to win admission into the European Union have filled in the application papers on time.</p>
<p>Now, they face a long -- and, for many, an agonising -- wait while Brussels bureaucrats weigh up their suitability to join a club which officially wants them in, but privately is terrified of the effects the newcomers may have on the existing set-up.</p>
<p>&quot;Recently, hard facts have dawned on both sides -- enlargement is not for tomorrow. It is going to be a long, hard process, but that is not to say we are no longer committed to it,&quot; said one senior EU official.</p>
<p>Ten countries from former communist Europe -- Poland, Hungary, the Czech Republic, Slovakia, Bulgaria, Romania, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, and Slovenia -- are all waiting outside the most successful political and trade group ever seen in Europe.</p>
<p>In the euphoria that greeted the fall of communism on the continent seven years ago, the EU's existing member states -- most also members of the NATO military alliance that won the Cold War -- held out the prospect of quick membership.</p>
<p>All the new democracies had to do, they suggested, was embrace pluralism, adopt market reforms, and impose political control of their once-dominant military.</p>
<p>The reward would be a single market with a free flow of goods, people, capital and services stretching from the Baltic to the Black Sea -- a global show-case for successful free-market democracy.</p>
<p>But as so often in EU affairs, diplomats say harsh realities are now acting as a brake on lofty idealism.</p>
<p>Pessimists fear the whole project could be delayed for years, and even the optimists no longer believe in a turn-of-the-century target date.</p>
<p>At the root of the problem is money, most often the cause of EU woes.</p>
<p>The prospective new members are poorer than even the EU's poorest countries -- Greece, Ireland and Portugal -- and much poorer than those countries were when they joined.</p>
<p>Worse still, the applicant states are still overwhelmingly agrarian economies which could torpedo attempts to keep the EU's $52-billion farm budget under control.</p>
<p>Unless the EU's system of payments to poor regions and subsidies to farmers is reformed, enlargement could force an unacceptably large increase on the budget -- some estimates have suggested as high as 60 percent.</p>
<p>With internal EU relations already strained by moves to create a single currency by 1999, diplomats and analysts say a new bout of reform negotiations could take months to bear fruit.</p>
<p>EU member states have already begun an inter-governmental conference (IGC) to plot the shape of a union that could one day include 30 states. Cyprus and Malta are also waiting in the wings and even Turkey has not yet lost all hope of membership.</p>
<p>&quot;The IGC could last months and membership negotiations years even before the laborious ratification process gets underway,&quot; said one EU diplomat who follows the enlargement issue.</p>
<p>Officials say even the most ardent supporters now accept the most likely batch of new members -- Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic -- are unlikely to gain admission before 2002.</p>
<p>When Brussels' officials return from their summer break, the issue is likely to dominate EU politics.</p>
<p>The first job will be to analyse boxes and boxes of replies to questions submitted to all 10 governments earlier this year by the European Commission to try to gauge each country's ability to meet the rights and obligations of membership.</p>
<p>When that process is complete, the Commission will submit &quot;opinions&quot; to the current 15 EU states on which applicants are most likely to be able to make the grade and a recommendation on whether to open negotiations. 190839 GMT aug 96</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
