<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5480" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: PRESS DIGEST - FRANCE - AUG 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - FRANCE - AUG 21.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are leading stories in this morning's Paris newspapers.</p>
<p>LES ECHOS</p>
<p>-- Markets betting on German interest rate cut as Paris Bourse closes up 1.66 percent.</p>
<p>-- CGT unionists say shoemaker Bally is about to close down French unit which employs 1,200 people.</p>
<p>-- MATIF and Societe des Bourses Francaises exploring closer links.</p>
<p>LA TRIBUNE DESFOSSES</p>
<p>-- Government considering either abolishing 20 percent general deduction on taxable income or extending it to all taxpayers. Either way, property owners stand to benefit as wage earners lose out and the move conflicts with President Jacques Chirac's election promises.</p>
<p>-- CAC 40 index back up past 2,000 mark on Tuesday.</p>
<p>L'AGEFI</p>
<p>-- Lower German M3 money supply points to Bundesbank rate cut.</p>
<p>-- Switch to euro will force utility supplier EDF to upgrade investor relations services, says top executive Bruno Lescoeur.</p>
<p>-- No discussions opened yet on takeover of Credit Foncier by rival Credit Immobilier de France and many questions still unanswered.</p>
<p>LIBERATION</p>
<p>-- African hunger strikers split conservative parties.</p>
<p>LIBERATION (Economic section)</p>
<p>-- Finance ministry critical of Credit Lyonnais chairman Jean Peyrelevade for insufficient cover of 135 billion franc loan to CDR holding company with swap agreements.</p>
<p>LE FIGARO</p>
<p>-- Africans start 48th day of hunger strike in Paris church to renew or obtain work and residence rights.</p>
<p>LE FIGARO-ECONOMIE</p>
<p>-- Finance minister Jean Arthuis repeats everyone will feel the impact of substantial tax cuts, especially the lowest wage earners.</p>
<p>-- French government expects about 2.5 percent GDP growth for 1997 but doesn't explain how.</p>
<p>-- Pechiney may lay off 3,000 to 3,500 workers.</p>
<p>LE PARISIEN</p>
<p>-- Morocco's King Hassan II announces referendum on creation of second house of parliament for wage earners, professional associations and municipal representatives.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5381</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
