<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5481" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREECE - AUG 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREECE - AUG 21.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek financial press:</p>
<p>EXPRESS</p>
<p>--Capital markets vote for early elections. Despite the uncertainty there was no capital flight or downside speculation. The Athens bourse gained 2.30 percent piercing resistance at 900 points</p>
<p>--Bank of Attica valuation is set at 18.5 billion drachmas</p>
<p>--Despite the certainty of early elections next month the government wants to show it is maintaining pace. It seeks to be profiled as a political party of European orientation aiming to modernise the economy</p>
<p>KERDOS</p>
<p>--EU Commissioner Jacques Santer sends tough message to Ankara on recent violence in Cyprus</p>
<p>--International fair in Thessaloniki which starts September 7 will provide the podium for political arguments by the parties ahead of early elections</p>
<p>--Limiting the wasteful state becomes a pre-election campaign promise for the ruling socialists</p>
<p>--Early elections will temporarily halt rate easing in state debt paper</p>
<p>IMERISIA</p>
<p>--September 22 is the most likely date for going to the polls again</p>
<p>--Pre-election euphoria led by shares of OTE telecom and National Bank help benchmark share index break 900 points</p>
<p>--The economy is the key issue: elections now will clear the way for tough economic measures ahead. Finance ministers are proposing state spending cuts of 850 billion drachmas in 1997</p>
<p>--Stavros-Elefsina highway project passes parliament as deputies voted in principle in favour of the contract with building consortium Attiki Odos</p>
<p>FINANCIAL KATHIMERINI</p>
<p>--Athens stock exchange votes in favour of early elections, market reacts warmly</p>
<p>--OTE telecom expects earnings growth of 27 percent this year with profits reaching 259 billion drachmas</p>
<p>NAFTEMBORIKI</p>
<p>--The untouchables, an expert I.R.S. team from the US, is coming to help the fight against money laundering</p>
<p>--Government spokesman gives clear hint of early polls amid a favourable climate in the financial markets --George Georgiopoulos, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
