<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5485" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Rate worries weigh on dlr, Eurobourses down.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Rate worries weigh on dlr, Eurobourses down.</headline>
<byline>Peter Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar slid against the mark on Wednesday and European shares fell back after a respected business climate survey dampened expectations that Germany would ease credit this week.</p>
<p>Financial markets' hopes that the German Bundesbank was about to serve up a long-awaited cut in its main money market rate took a blow when the key confidence barometer issued by the Ifo economic institute emerged much stronger than expected.</p>
<p>Its survey of business conditions in the economy jumped to an eight-month high of 94.1 in July, a sharp rise from a three-month low of 90.4 in June.</p>
<p>Economists had predicted a figure of around 91 for July and were caught off-guard by the apparent sudden surge of confidence in Germany's economic recovery.</p>
<p>The news boosted the mark against the dollar and stengthened it against other European currencies. By mid-afternoon the dollar had drifted down below 1.4820 marks, having earlier nudged the 1.49 level.</p>
<p>German bonds and shares fell as traders took the view that the Bundesbank would no longer feel under any pressure at Thursday's meeting of its policy-making council to trim its securities repurchase rate, or repo, to boost the economy.</p>
<p>The main Frankfurt DAX share index closed floor trading 16.5 points down and extended its losses in post-bourse electronic trade.</p>
<p>London, Europe's largest bourse, which closed on Tuesday at a record high, was boosted in the morning after British retail trade figures provided Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke with further ammunition if he wants to cut lending rates again on September 4, when British monetary authorities next meet.</p>
<p>Retail sales suffered a surprise 0.6 percent drop in July, providing evidence that while shops are busy, there is no danger of a runaway spending boom.</p>
<p>But by mid-afternoon the blue chip FTSE 100 index, which ended at a record close of 3,883.2 points on Tuesday, had reversed itself and dropped well into negative territory under the influence of Wall Street.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average opened lower and then continued to lose more than half a percent, pressured by profit-taking, softer bonds and brokerage downgrades of some technology issues.</p>
<p>London traders said a modest correction was in order, as the FTSE -- up almost five percent so far this month -- had settled higher for six of the last seven trading sessions.</p>
<p>French shares fell more than one percentage point to below the 2,000 level on the CAC-40 index on the back of profit-taking after Tuesday's 1.66 percent rise and after the stronger-than-expected Ifo survey.</p>
<p>Weaker expectations of a German rate cut dimmed prospects that the Bank of France would trim its own rates, particularly in view of recent French franc weakness.</p>
<p>&quot;The franc is still relatively weak. Even if the Bundesbank does something on Thursday, the Bank of France will wait,&quot; said economist Philippe Brossard of ABN-AMRO in Paris.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1430 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.4815 marks and 108.20 yen, compared with 1.4884 marks and 108.28 yen at the London close on Tuesday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1430 GMT</p>
<p>The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares was down 12.6 points at 3,870.6.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index dropped 22.55 to 1997.51.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt closed down 16.52 at 2,54.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold fixed at $386.80 an ounce in the afternoon, compared with $387.45 in the morning and $387.55 at its close in London on Tuesday. Silver was easier at $5.20.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
