<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5487" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Swiss franc grows accustomed to Yeltsin worries.</title>
<headline>Swiss franc grows accustomed to Yeltsin worries.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Reierson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Renewed question marks over the health of Russian President Boris Yeltsin and rumours of fierce political infighting in the Kremlin have provided support for the Swiss franc, a traditional safe-haven currency.</p>
<p>But the overall reaction has been muted as currency markets become hardened to yet another chapter in the long-running Russian leadership saga.</p>
<p>&quot;The concerns (over Yeltsin's health) have been outweighed by the stronger-than-anticipated German data that we saw come out this morning,&quot; said James Mckay, economist at PaineWebber.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen many health scares now and quite a few turbulent events and they have all passed without many long-term problems developing.&quot;</p>
<p>The IFO research institute released stronger than expected figures for German business confidence on Wednesday. And analysts said the market was unwilling to get too sidetracked by the Yeltsin rumours ahead of Thursday's council meeting of the German Bundesbank.</p>
<p>Yeltsin has not been seen in public since his August 9 inauguration and is said to be on holiday. Russia's Interfax news agency said Yeltsin would return to the Moscow area on Wednesday but a Kremlin spokesman said this could not be confirmed.</p>
<p>Yeltsin aides have denied vigourously rumours that he is ill or has already undergone surgery for heart problems.</p>
<p>During previous bouts of Russian turbulence, the Swiss franc has been boosted by its safe-haven status. This is often at the expense of the mark with Germany's proximity and links with Eastern Europe and Russia seen as a negative for the currency in times of crisis.</p>
<p>The Swiss franc was trading at 80.94 centimes per mark in afternoon dealings in Europe after a session low of 81.05 earlier in the day and late Tuesday's 81.12/13.</p>
<p>Analysts said any negative news on Yeltsin's health would have an impact on the market but this was likely to be shortlived as more attention is paid to the moribund Swiss economy.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem now is that the Swiss economy is flat on its back,&quot; said Keld Holm, international economist at Lehman Brothers. &quot;This is coming to bear and the strain will show at some stage.&quot;</p>
<p>Longer-term, Holm sees this economic weakness leading to a Swiss franc level of 84-85 centimes per mark.</p>
<p>However, other analysts said the franc was still well supported by Switzerland's massive current account surplus and potentially huge German capital inflows ahead of 1999, the start date for European economic and monetary union.</p>
<p>In any case, the Swiss franc's strength or weakness is becoming less reliant on the ebbs and flows of Russian politics.</p>
<p>&quot;It's always been a feature of Russian political life that the health of the leaders is in question,&quot; said Holm.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets are learning that the volatility created by Russian uncertainties is fading. Once it was a big deal, now it's only a blip.&quot; -- London Newsroom +44 171 542 6745</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
