<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5492" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMF agrees to release $330 million for Russia.</title>
<headline>IMF agrees to release $330 million for Russia.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Monetary Fund executive board agreed on Wednesday to release $330 million for Russia, saying the country's reform programme was on target and the money would no longer be held up.</p>
<p>The new funding, part of a $10.2 billion, three-year loan approved in February, had been delayed because of problems in the Moscow government's efforts to collect taxes that raised questions about overall economic reform.  </p>
<p>&quot;Executive directors were satisfied that the Russian government and central bank met their July targets, and are pursuing policies consistent with the attainment of macro-economic objectives of the program,&quot; the IMF said in a statement.</p>
<p>The lending agency has been reviewing the program on a month-by-month basis and dispensing additional funding as long as Russia met the program targets. The IMF said that a further disbursement could become available next month if current talks in Moscow show Russia is sticking to the program.</p>
<p>Russia ran into revenue problems during the presidential election campaign this spring when the government apparently slacked off on tax collection enforcement to win support.</p>
<p>In its statement, the IMF board said it particularly welcomed steps taken to improve revenue collection, which caused the delay in the loan tranche.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
