<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5493" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: FOCUS-Swedish insurers reap investment gains.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Swedish insurers reap investment gains.</headline>
<byline>Trevor Datson</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish insurers Skandia and Trygg-Hansa on Wednesday reported sharply higher earnings for the first half of the year as return on financial investments bolstered less impressive insurance profits.</p>
<p>Trygg-Hansa's pre-tax profit increased to 1.52 billion crowns ($230.5 million), a 27 percent improvement on the 1.20 billion crowns posted in the corresponding period last year.</p>
<p>The increase was bolstered by a 29 percent jump in profits from the non-life insurance business, and by a sharply improved return on the group's asset portfolio.</p>
<p>Capital gains and unrealised changes in value in the bond and share portfolio improved to 1.19 billion crowns from 848 million in the same 1995 period.</p>
<p>Trygg-Hansa has initiated a business process re-engineering programme that it says will cut costs in its claims department alone by 200 million crowns a year.</p>
<p>Total operating costs for the period declined to 582 million crowns from 684 million in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;It is with great satisfaction that I note that the thorough process of change that Trygg-Hansa is going through has begun to have results,&quot; group CEO Lars Thunell said in the company's interim results statement.</p>
<p>Although the positive trend in financial investments would continue for the rest of the year, chief financial officer Zaid Pedersen said shareholders should not expect a similar return in the second half.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of these are one-off gains here influenced by market developments. You can't multiply this result by two for the year, that would be too good, I guess,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rival Skandia also posted a strong improvement in profits for the first half.</p>
<p>Skandia's pre-tax profit of 1.54 billion crowns ($233.5 million) for the period was a 64 percent jump on the 940 million reported for the first half of last year.</p>
<p>With the profit from non-life insurance virtually unchanged at 1.55 billion crowns, much of the improvement came from an increase to 811 million crowns in the profit from the life assurance business.</p>
<p>But, more importantly, profits from investment income showed a substantial increase on last year's levels.</p>
<p>Investment income from the non-life business came to 1.47 billion crowns, up from 641 million in the same time last year.</p>
<p>This, combined with a fall in joint group operating costs, meant a surge in the non-technical result to 1.08 billion crowns from 161 million crowns last year.</p>
<p>Premium income declined seven percent in the non-life business to 10.62 billion, but on the life side unit-linked insurance enjoyed a 37 percent gain in premiums to 15.01 billion crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;Naturally, the strong result for our investment operations during the first half is gratifying. The steady growth of our unit-linked business is expected to continue during the rest of the year,&quot; Skandia CEO Bjorn Wolrath said in a statement.</p>
<p>Earlier on Wednesday, rival Trygg-Hansa posted a 27 percent increase in pre-tax profits to 1.52 billion crowns. This, too, was largely the result of improved investment income. ($ = 6.595 Swedish Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
