<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5494" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS - W.German Ifo climate index jumps in July.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - W.German Ifo climate index jumps in July.</headline>
<byline>Janet Northcote</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's respected Ifo institute said on Wednesday its business climate index for July jumped to 94.1 from 90.4 in June, far exceeding economists' expectations for a figure of around 91.0.</p>
<p>The index had been hotly awaited in financial markets, with many players looking for a weak figure, which would make it more likely that the German Bundesbank would cut its main money market interest rate, the securities repurchase rate or repo, this Thursday.</p>
<p>Economists had expected at best a slight improvement in the index from June's level, which was a three-month low.</p>
<p>German government bonds or bunds, which had fallen in early trading in anticipation of a weak figure, extended their losses on the news. The September bund future hit a day's low of 97.73, before recovering to trade 0.25 point down at 97.81.</p>
<p>German shares also weakened on the news, with players concerned that the figure reduced the chances for a lowering of the 3.30 percent repo rate on Thursday.</p>
<p>But economists contacted after the announcement said the figure did not change their expectations for the Bundesbank meeting.</p>
<p>A Reuter poll issued on Tuesday had showed eight out of 10 economists polled expected the repo rate to be cut by up to 20 basis points (0.20 percentage point) this week, with most seeing a smaller move.</p>
<p>Gernot Nerb, economist at Salomon Brothers and the former chief economist at Ifo itself, said in response to the figures, &quot;The Bundesbank has to be aware that the recovery is happening, but also that investment is still weak. Especially in mechanical engineering there was hardly any improvement (in expectations).&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank should not be worried by the jump and I would recommend a cut (in the repo) by 10-15 basis points.&quot;</p>
<p>Armin Kayser at Swiss Bank Corp, who was one of the two in this week's poll who did not expect an easing, said that he did not believe recent Ifo data had truly reflected the economic situation.</p>
<p>&quot;I still don't expect any move tomorrow. My view has not changed because of this data,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Referring to a second figure released on Wednesday -- an upward revision in the index of west German industry orders to 98.3 in June from a provisional 97.7, Kayser said, &quot;The upward revision of new orders data and the improvement in the Ifo data do not favour a rate cut. There is no strong reason for the Bundesbank to stimulate the economy.&quot;</p>
<p>Karen Kricks-Brunnlieb, economist at Trinkaus &amp; Burkhardt, agreed, &quot;The figure is much higher than expected, but it doesn't change our expectations because we do not expect a repo rate cut.&quot;</p>
<p>Rainer Veit at DB Research in Frankfurt was also concerned about the reliability of the data as a guide to the economic situation, but said he continued to expect a repo easing.</p>
<p>&quot;This is very difficult to assess. June was a very difficult figure and I saw it as an aberration to the trend. The July figure is again somewhat of an aberration,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We still see a 60 percent probability of a repo rate cut tomorrow, of about five to 10 basis points. It would keep the interest rate hopes alive,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
