<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5496" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Maxus hopes for amicable Ecuador resolve. [CORRECTED 22/8/96]</title>
<headline>Maxus hopes for amicable Ecuador resolve. [CORRECTED 22/8/96]</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Maxus Energy Corp, whose Ecuadorian exploration and production operations were halted by the government there Tuesday, hopes to  have something to say about its difficulties with state oil company  Petroecuador in the next couple of days (Corrects to clarify that the  company does not yet know when problems will be resolved), a senior  company official said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have people working with the (energy) ministry down there and we hope to have something to say in the next couple of days,&quot; said Mark Miller, executive vice president of Maxus, a unit of Argentina's largest energy concern YPF SA. </p>
<p>Late Tuesday in Quito the country's energy and mines minister Alfredo Adoum ordered the halting of Maxus oil production in the country.</p>
<p>Maxus, which has been operating fields near the Colombian border for the past nine years, is the only one of the 10 or so foreign oil companies producing Ecuadorian oil which does not have a production-sharing agreement with the government. Maxus has been engaged in negotiations over new contract terms. </p>
<p>Asked if Maxus is optimistic it can reach an amicable resolution to its problems with the Ecuadorian government, Miller said: &quot;Yes, we are.&quot;</p>
<p>However, he wouldn't comment on the implications of the government's actions for Maxus or for foreign oil companies operating in Ecuador.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very early and we are just now assessing the statement and responding to it, but it is premature to be commenting until we have had time to work with the minister,&quot; Miller said.</p>
<p>Among the other foreign oil companies operating in Ecuador are France's Elf Aquitaine and Repsol of Spain and ARCO (Atlantic Richfield Co ) of the U.S..</p>
<p>Maxus Ecuadorian estimated reserves were 228 million barrels in 1992, ranking second only to Petroecuador. It began producing heavy oil in 1994 at a rate of 14,000 barrels a day.</p>
<p>-- Tony McAuley, New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
