<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5510" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada union to strike GM, if target or not.</title>
<headline>Canada union to strike GM, if target or not.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Canadian Auto Workers (CAW) union president Buzz Hargrove said the union will likely hit the Canadian unit of General Motors Corp with strikes whether or not it is chosen as the CAW's strike target next week.</p>
<p>Hargrove said he suggested a plan to the union's bargaining committee to begin striking at GM plant by plant, while seeking a master agreement with the Canadian subsidiaries of either Ford Motor Co or Chrysler Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;If we were to select GM as the target, then we could follow this strategy of hitting GM while we moved over to one of the other companies,&quot; Hargrove told Reuters on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Hargrove said that even if the union chooses Ford or Chrysler as its target for a September 14 strike deadline he anticipates strikes will also be necessary at GM for the union to win concessions over the thorny issue of outsourcing.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether or not they are the target, if they are first second or third we have a different problem at GM than we do at Ford or Chrysler, Hargrove told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the union is exploring a range of possibilities, but will not set a plan of attack before the United Auto Workers (UAW) union announces its strike target on Thursday. The CAW usually chooses a different target from the UAW.  </p>
<p>Rhetoric from Hargrove over the issue of contracting out at General Motors Canada has risen sharply over the past year and led to a demonstration outside the company's headquarters after it released its first quarter results this year. The UAW shut down GM entirely in the first quarter of 1996 with a 17-day strike at its Dayton, Ohio brake plant, forcing a US$900 million loss in revenues.</p>
<p>A CAW spokeswoman said the union will hold a press conference on Thursday after the U.S. strike target is announced and will release the results of the voting on the strike mandates from its members on Sunday.  </p>
<p>Next week, the CAW is expected to announce its choice for a strike target ahead of the Labor Day long weekend holiday which begins on Friday August 30.</p>
<p>-- Paul Casciato (416) 941-8100, or e-mail: paul.casciato@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
