<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5514" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada drops entry ban against Hong Kong tycoon.</title>
<headline>Canada drops entry ban against Hong Kong tycoon.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER, British Columbia 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Canadian appeals court has overturned a deportation order against a Hong Kong billionaire convicted of bribery in the British colony, his lawyer said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Ronald Li, one of Hong Kong's richest businessmen and former head of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, left Canada in 1994 but fought to overturn the deportation order so he would be free to travel here.</p>
<p>&quot;The deportation order against Mr. Li has been quashed. He is admissible in Canada,&quot; Toronto lawyer Lorne Waldman said. Li's whereabouts were unknown and it was not clear whether he planned to return to Canada as a result of the ruling.</p>
<p>Waldman said Canada's federal Court of Appeal ruled this month that the deportation order should not stand because the statute under which Li was convicted in Hong Kong was broader than equivalent law in Canada.</p>
<p>Under Canadian immigration law, he could be denied entry only if the crime for which he was convicted in Hong Kong was equivalent to an offense in Canada. He was jailed in Hong Kong in 1990 after being convicted on corruption charges after acquiring shares in two companies in return for supporting their listing on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>His downfall followed a scandal over his closure of the exchange after the global share market crash in October 1987 and a government report that said he ran the exchange like a private club. He was released from jail in 1993.</p>
<p>Li invested in Canada and before the case erupted was granted honorary citizenship of Toronto and Calgary for his contributions to community life. Despite the deportation order, he has continued to invest in Canada and support charities here.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER, British Columbia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
