<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5515" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Westcoast to restructure divisions.</title>
<headline>Westcoast to restructure divisions.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Westcoast Energy Inc said Wednesday it will restructure its pipeline and field services divisions in an effort to lower costs and improve its natural gas delivery service to customers.</p>
<p>The gas pipeline and processing company said the move would result in about 300 job losses, roughly one quarter of the divisions' workforce, over the next year.</p>
<p>Westcoast said its gas producer customers face lower than expected sales prices which are forcing cost cuts at Westcoast.  </p>
<p>The company has applied to the National Energy Board for a deferral account in which to record costs of the restructuring. It did not specify the amount of the costs.  The affected operations are in British Columbia and Alberta.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to be positioned to be able to compete vigorously for new business. We remain confident in the future development of untapped gas reserves in northeast British Columbia but we will have to manage any growth in the context of increasingly cyclical commodity pricing,&quot; said Westcoast president Michael Phelps.</p>
<p>A Westcoast spokeswoman said later that the company expects no &quot;near-term financial impact&quot; but there will be costs associated with the restructuring. The bulk of the layoffs will occur in September but it is not yet clear what the final amount of the related costs will be, she said.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
