<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5516" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: C-MAC won't amend Circo Craft bid.</title>
<headline>C-MAC won't amend Circo Craft bid.</headline>
<dateline>SHERBROKE, Quebec 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>C-MAC Industries said on Wednesday it has sent a letter to shareholders of Circo Craft Co Inc advising it would not amend its C$9.50 per share takeover offer for the company.</p>
<p>C-MAC, a make of advanced electronic components said in the letter that as Circo Craft's recent earnings did not show an increase it believed the offer was adequate.</p>
<p>C-MAC also said the offer represents a premium of 38 percent over Circo's market value at the time of the offer.  </p>
<p>Circo, a maker of circuit boards, was trading under C$7 before the bid was announced by C-MAC on August 1. After the bid, the stock jumped on hopes of a bidding war or a sweetened offer by C-MAC.</p>
<p>Circo was off C$0.05 at C$10.10 while C-MAC was down C$0.35 at C$6.50 in early afternoon trading on the Toronto Stock Exchange on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Circo Craft's board of directors recommended on August 19 that shareholders reject the bid and also disclosed that several other companies had entered into confidentiality agreements to review Circo's operations.</p>
<p>But C-MAC said its shareholders' letter that it was &quot;surprised&quot; at certain statements by Circo's board when itrejected the offer, including:</p>
<p>- CIBC Wood Gundy Securities Inc would recieve additional compensation if a superior offer was forthcoming.</p>
<p>- that the company would risk the long term value of Circo Craft by opening its books to other interested parties.</p>
<p>C-MAC said the offer will expire, as previously announced, on August 30.</p>
<p>Circo earlier reported that its earnings fell to C$0.16 per share, or to C$2,438,000 in the second quarter from C$0.15 per share, or C$2,400,000 in the year ago period.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto bureau 416-941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHERBROKE, Quebec"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
