<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5518" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: CBRS removes Inco debt from credit watch.</title>
<headline>CBRS removes Inco debt from credit watch.</headline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian Bond Rating Service said on Wednesday that it removed Inco Ltd from its credit watch list, restoring previously assigned ratings.</p>
<p>CBRS also said it assigned a rating of P-3 to Inco's newly issued Series E Preferred Shares. The ratings are being reinstated at B++(High) and B++ for the outstanding senior unsecured debentures and term notes and convertible debentures of Inco, respectively, it said. CBRS's review had focused on Inco financing in its C$4.3 billion acquisition of Diamond Fields Resources Inc and capital structure in respect of developing a nickel property at Voisey's Bay, Newfoundland.  </p>
<p>CBRS said the ratings outlook for Inco is stable. The agency said it recognizes the versatility of the financing methodology employed by Inco in the Diamond Fields acquisition, which was scheduled to close Wednesday.</p>
<p>The reinstatement of medium quality ratings for Inco reflects the maintenance of financial flexibility, the long life reserves position and expected continuation of favourable operating leverage for many years, CBRS said.  </p>
<p>The agency said there is no deterioration in the credit quality of outstanding securities at this stage and there will likely be no discernible impact on the credit quality in the intermediate term, as long as the costs of developing Voisey's Bay are held within budget and expectations on production costs and by-product credits are realized.</p>
<p>Proforma debt leverage is reduced to 20 percent from 34 percent at June 30, 1996 and will likely increase to 30-35 percent with the start of the project construction, but falls within the benchmarks deemed safe for the medium quality rating, CBRS said.</p>
<p>Inco's new Class E preferred shares are rated P-3 by CBRS, reflecting the expected stability of cash dividends payable at a rate of 5.5 percent a year for at least five years and other attractive equity-linked features, the agency said.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Montreal bureau (514) 985-2434</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
