<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5532" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Adviser urges Quest to seek merger partner.</title>
<headline>Adviser urges Quest to seek merger partner.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cypress Asset Management Inc, a Houston-based investment adviser, said Wednesday it urged the board of Quest Medical Inc to seek a suitable merger partner.</p>
<p>Cypress, which currently holds a 6.5 percent stake in the Dallas-based health-care products manufacturer, said it made the recommendation in a letter to the company on August 20.</p>
<p>In a filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission, Cypress said it initially believed Quest's stock to be a good value, despite a June 25 announcement that the company projected significantly lower earnings for the second quarter.  </p>
<p>While the stock fell to $6 from $10.75 after the forecast was made, Cypress said it bought additional common shares until its stake reached 7.0 percent or 578,089.</p>
<p>It said it planned to file a &quot;passive&quot; disclosure report about the purchases to the SEC by January 1997, but changed its mind and filed Wednesday's  13D report after Quest's stock price remained low for quite some time.</p>
<p>Cypress said it now holds 537,314 shares of Quest. It said its latest transactions on Quest include the sale of 30,600 shares between July 10 and 17 at prices ranging from $7.375 to $8.75 a share.  </p>
<p>Cypress said that it became apparent that even the recent replacement of Quest's chairman &quot;was not sufficient to improve returns to stockholders.&quot;</p>
<p>It said it then began further investigation and found that Quest suffered from &quot;significant weaknesses&quot; in several key areas and &quot;drastic measures&quot; were necessary to enhance stockholder value.</p>
<p>Cypress said it believed the best course for Quest would be to seek a strategic partner either in the form of a merger or sale of the company to such partner.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
