<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5546" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton calls parts of welfare bill &quot;plain wrong&quot;.</title>
<headline>Clinton calls parts of welfare bill &quot;plain wrong&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Steve Holland</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton says in a new book that parts of the welfare reform legislation he will sign Thursday &quot;are just plain wrong.&quot;</p>
<p>The book, &quot;Between Hope and History: Meeting America's Challenges for the 21st Century,&quot; reaches stores this week, just in time for Clinton's fall re-election campaign.</p>
<p>The 178-page campaign manifesto presents Clinton's reasons for thinking he deserves a second four-year term and the Republicans are on the wrong path.</p>
<p>Selling for $16.95, the book is essentially culled from Clinton's frequent speeches. He wrote it secretly in his spare time with much help from Seattle writer William Nothdurft.</p>
<p>A first printing of 400,000 copies was ordered by the publisher, Times Books, a division of Random House.</p>
<p>Clinton Thursday signs welfare reform legislation passed by the Republican-controlled Congress. It will end the 61-year-old federal guarantee of aid to the poor and delegate broad power to states to design their own welfare programs.</p>
<p>Liberal Democrats are outraged, saying it would hurt poor children and throw hundreds of thousands of people into poverty. But Clinton wants to sign it to make a start toward overhauling the moribund U.S. welfare system and meet his 1992 campaign pledge to &quot;end welfare as we know it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There are parts of the legislation that are just plain wrong,&quot; Clinton says in the book. &quot;We must work hard in the coming months and years to make them right.&quot;</p>
<p>Particularly offensive to the president are new cuts in child nutrition assistance that will hit working families and the cutting off of assistance to legal immigrants.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be refining this reform for some time to come,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>At a time when Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole is going to great lengths to have his personal story told, Clinton's book largely sticks to policy. The most personal section concerns race and riding the city bus to school in segregated Arkansas.</p>
<p>&quot;My friends and I liked to sit at the back of the bus. When the bus was crowded, it was pointed out to us that black folks were supposed to sit in the back of the bus. I didn't know any better. Discrimination doesn't come naturally; it has to be taught,&quot; he says.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
