<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5552" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NASD penalizes Citicorp unit $325,000.</title>
<headline>NASD penalizes Citicorp unit $325,000.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>NASD Regulation Inc said on Wednesday that it censured and fined Citicorp Securities Corp $25,000 and ordered it return $300,000 for allegedly allowing 19 brokers to work, despite failure to complete a required training on securities regulations.</p>
<p>In imposing the sanctions, NASDR said it found that for certain periods between November 1995 and May 1996, Citicorp unit Citicorp Securities failed to insure employees finished the course on time. As a result, employee registrations were deemed inactive. The course began to be required by the SEC on July 1, 1995.  </p>
<p>The course is intended to make sure that brokers stay current on products, markets and rules that govern the securities industry.</p>
<p>The amount ordered to be returned represents money improperly paid to the 19 individuals during the time that their registrations were inactive, NASDR said. The amount will be paid to NASDR, it said.</p>
<p>NASDR President Mary Schapiro said her office was committed to closely monitoring members' compliance with the essential rules.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue to pursue disciplinary actions against those members, large or small, who fail to comply,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>NASDR is the regulatory arm of the National Association of Securities Dealers, which is runs the Nasdaq stock market as a separate unit.</p>
<p>NASD is a self-regulatory organization under SEC oversight.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
