<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5557" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. crudes drift lower, Sep/Oct roll gains late.</title>
<headline>U.S. crudes drift lower, Sep/Oct roll gains late.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. crudes drifted lower in sympathy with declining spot values, though grades gained some strength to the close, traders said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Business was subdued, however, as September business was in the process of being cleared up, leaving many to take to the sidelines ahead of more serious October supplies.</p>
<p>The September/October West Texas Intermediate roll widened in the afternoon, gaining around 15-20 cents to end in a 40-45 cents range, lifting Postings Plus to $2.10-$2.20.</p>
<p>Sep WTI/Cushing ended the session weaker at $22.10-$22.20, and Oct WTI/Cushing at $21.75-$21.80.  </p>
<p>Outright crude prices were pushed some 30-40 cents lower on the day due to pressure from morning stock data, which showed a higher crude build in U.S. government numbers than  the weekly American Petroleum Institute (API) report Tuesday.</p>
<p>Support for prices was seen when Mexican state oil company PEMEX said it shut all three ports in the Gulf of Mexico as a precaution against Tropical Storm Dolly.</p>
<p>More than 800,000 barrels a day (bpd) of crude oil exports to the U.S. stand to be delayed, traders said.</p>
<p>Grades firmed, however, as the session dragged on, but overall the prices were steady to slightly off from Tuesday.</p>
<p>Light Louisiana Sweet/St. James saw late trades at 16 and 17 cents over WTI/Cushing, then fell back by the close.</p>
<p>Midland/WTI was around the even level to WTI/Cushing, with Heavy Louisiana Sweet/Empire also hovering at that mark.</p>
<p>Sour grades saw deals for West Texas Sour/Midland at minus $1.50 to WTI/Cushing, and was talked at minus $1.55-$1.45.</p>
<p>Late deals in the Brent aftermarket saw two full cargoes exchanged at $20.30 for October paper, 9 cents above the IPE Brent close. The Sep/Oct Brent spreads were sold at 50 cents.</p>
<p>Foreign crude business into the U.S. was quiet. Brent cargoes remained in an unfavorable light under current arbitrage conditions, traders said.</p>
<p>--Patrick Connole, New York Energy Desk, +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
