<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5581" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries end lower in subdued trade.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries end lower in subdued trade.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries ended lower on Wednesday when no buyers emerged to counter early weakness.</p>
<p>Prices had slipped in Europe in sympathy with a falling dollar/mark, dealers said. A report from the German Ifo economic group showing surprising German economic strength cast doubt on forecasts for lower official interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The market opened lower in New York in line with overseas and there was no inclination in the U.S. to reverse that trade,&quot; said Steve Ricchuito, chief financial economist at Barclays de Zoete Wedd Government Securities Inc.  </p>
<p>&quot;You just didn't see any enthusiasm today,&quot; said Kim Rupert, senior economist at MMS International.</p>
<p>The benchmark 6-3/4 percent 30-year bond ended at 98-29/32, down 15/32 to yield 6.84 percent.</p>
<p>The market had scant news to digest.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, prices did not react to the government's report that the U.S. budget had a $27.1 billion deficit in July, after a $34.1 billion surplus in June.</p>
<p>Also as anticipated, the Treasury announced the terms of its monthly two- and five-year note auctions next week.  </p>
<p>The Department said it would sell $18.75 billion in two-year notes on Tuesday and $12.5 billion in five-year notes on Wednesday. The auctions will settle on September 3.</p>
<p>The market took the announcement in stride.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone's accustomed to the two's and five's,&quot; said Ricchuito. &quot;There was no increase in the auction size and while they'll raise ($3.45 billion in) new cash, a lot of it is rollover,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Economists said the market would pay close attention to Thursday's weekly jobless claims data.  </p>
<p>Last week, the four-week moving average for new jobless claims dipped to a seven-year low.</p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters estimated, on average, that new jobless claims rose to 331,000 in the week ended August 17, from 321,000 a week earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;There may be a little concern that if the claims numbers don't rise in the next couple of weeks, August economic data might be stronger than expected,&quot; said Joshua Feinman, vice president and global markets economist at Bankers Trust.</p>
<p>&quot;If claims stay (near 320,000), it's a cinch that the August data will be stronger than expected,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Rupert said a low jobless claims number could suggest a healthy (August monthly) U.S. payrolls number.</p>
<p>Current estimates for August non-farm payroll growth center in the area of 225,000 to 275,000 new jobs.</p>
<p>For the time being, investors seem content to let the market trade in its current range.</p>
<p>Rupert defined that range as being between 6.75 percent and 6.875 percent on the long bond yield.</p>
<p>&quot;We still bouncing around in a range,&quot; Feiman concurred. &quot;People are not ready to push the market higher from here.&quot;  </p>
<p>At the short end of the maturity range, three- and six-month bill rates each fell two basis points to 5.01 percent and 5.08 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>The 6-1/4 percent two-year note slipped 2/32 to 100-15/32, ending with a 5.99 percent yield.</p>
<p>The five-year note fell 5/32 to 101-3/32, yielding 6.36 percent.</p>
<p>The 10-year note traded down 10/32 at 102-24/32, for a yield of 6.62 percent.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1679</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
