<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5585" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Greater China to merge with Xinhua unit.</title>
<headline>Greater China to merge with Xinhua unit.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greater China Corp said on Wednesday it had agreed to merge with Beijing's Newsdata Network Systems Co Ltd, a supplier of wireless data communications and networking systems that is partially owned by China's official Xinhua News Agency.</p>
<p>The merger, in which both parties would be equal partners, is expected to be completed on or before September 15, 1996, the company said.</p>
<p>Financial terms were not immediately available.  </p>
<p>The merger will make Greater China the first international publicly traded company in the information service business in China, Greater China said.</p>
<p>Newsdata Network holds a twenty-year license for two government authorized wireless transmission frequencies available for use throughout China and holds patents on wireless technology, Greater China said.</p>
<p>Newsdata Network supplies live stock quotes from the Shanghai and Shenzhen Exchanges as well as other pertinent trading reports and business information, Greater China said.</p>
<p>Newsdata Network has the capability of delivering over 160 channels of information and also provides an e-mail package, Greater China said.  </p>
<p>Greater China chief executive officer John Allen said the company will be owned 50 percent by Newsdata Network and 50 percent held by Greater China's shareholders.</p>
<p>Greater China's shares are presently listed on the NASD Bulletin Board, but Allen said the company aims to be listed on the New York Stock Exchange. He did not give a time line for the listing.</p>
<p>The company's shares will not be traded in China at the present time, Allen said.</p>
<p>Newsdata Network has about $3.5 million in revenues and the company is profitable, Allen said.</p>
<p>Greater China's sales are about $3.5 million for 1995 and had a loss of $695,000, including charges from closing some operations, Greater China said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
