<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5586" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US corp bonds off, Stratosphere rides rollercoaster.</title>
<headline>US corp bonds off, Stratosphere rides rollercoaster.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. corporate bonds closed significantly lower while the debt of casino and rollercoaster operator Stratosphere went for a wild ride only to end Wednesday's session unchanged, dealers said.</p>
<p>Stratosphere's 14.25 percent first mortgage notes shot up to an 87 bid from 81 at the open after the company announced it hired investment firm Donaldson, Lufkin &amp; Jenrette (DLJ) as advisor in a bid to maximize shareholder value.</p>
<p>But the debt gradually pared gains to close unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;It went up because of the news and down after people said 'So what?',&quot; one high-yield dealer said.  </p>
<p>Some dealers said the firm's announcement was old news.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch high-yield research said it was first disclosed on August 16 that the independent directors of Stratosphere had appointed DLJ to negotiate on behalf of the company.</p>
<p>Another key gainer was Kmart Corp debt, which rose 1/2 to one point, depending on maturity, on news earnings improved in the second quarter compared to the same period last year.</p>
<p>Kmart's 7.95 percent debentures due 2023 gained one point to close at a 73-1/2 bid.  </p>
<p>The retailer said earnings in its second quarter ended July 31 rose to $0.07, matching retail analyts' expectations.</p>
<p>Kmart earned $0.05 per share in the quarter last year.</p>
<p>ValuJet Inc's 10.25 percent notes dropped about 1/2 point in light trading following news it will not receive federal approval to resume flight service by Friday as planned. The notes closed at 84 bid, 84-1/2 offer compared 84-1/2 bid, 85-1/4 offer late Tuesday.</p>
<p>Sprint Spectrum's $523 million (proceeds) zero-coupon/cash pay deal, which priced on Tuesday, bucked the overall soft market to end slightly higher, dealers said.  </p>
<p>The first tranche of $250 million in 10-year senior notes traded ended 100-7/8 bid, 101-1/8 offer market, traders said. The notes were priced at par with an 11 percent coupon, and were quoted at 101-1/4 bid, 102 offer late Tuesday.</p>
<p>The second tranche of $273 million (proceeds) of 10-year senior discount notes, priced with a five-year zero coupon, also traded up to 55.375 bid, 55.625 offer. The notes were originally priced at 54.687 to yield 12.50 percent and rose to a 54.875 bid, 55.000 offer by Tuesday's close.</p>
<p>The entire issue is rated B2/B-plus.  </p>
<p>Junk bonds overall closed off 1/8 as falling Treasuries and a weak equity market depressed prices.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year long bond closed down 15/32 to 98-29/32 to yield 6.84 percent in late trade. The Dow Jones Industrial Average closed off 31.44 at 5689.82.</p>
<p>Only one new issue priced today. The Province of British Columbia issued a $300 million 40-year Yankee bond, said lead manager Lehman Brothers.</p>
<p>The AA2/AA+ issue priced at 99.225 to yield 7.31 percent or 44 basis points over the 6.0 percent Treasury due 2026.</p>
<p>--Roanne Daniels, 212-859-1677</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
