<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5588" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dlr/mark ends flat in US, Buba rate cut hopes fade.</title>
<headline>Dlr/mark ends flat in US, Buba rate cut hopes fade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar ended nearly unchanged against the mark in cautious trade after new German economic data dimmed hopes for a repo rate cut at the Bundesbank council meeting on Thursday, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Ifo Institute for Economic Research reported its west German business confidence index jumped to 94.1 in July from 90.4 in June. This exceeded the average forecast of economists polled by Reuters who expected an increase to 91 in July.</p>
<p>&quot;The Ifo survey cast last minute doubt on the probability of a rate cut,&quot; said Brian McCarthy, market analyst at Ruesch International. &quot;If they do cut, the dollar should recover.&quot;  </p>
<p>The dollar closed at 1.4821/31 marks, little changed from 1.4820/30 at the open. Traders pegged support for the dollar near 1.4810/15 amid talk of good buying interest in that area.</p>
<p>Further signs that the German economy might not need stimulation from lower rates emerged in reports showing West German industrial orders for July were revised higher and production of motor vehicles in Germany picked-up from January to July compared with the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>The stronger-than-expected business sentiment data and other figures came one day after a report of slower German M3 money supply growth had raised hopes for a repo rate cut.  </p>
<p>&quot;You think with M3 ... you're going to get the cut, and all of a sudden the next day, other financial news comes out saying maybe they won't cut,&quot; said Robert Gilmartin, a vice president of foreign exchange at First Union National Bank. &quot;But the proof will be in the pudding tomorrow morning.&quot;</p>
<p>Both the dollar and the mark gained against the yen after prospects for continued low interest rates in Japan improved after consumer finance firm Minami Kyushu Credit Co Ltd announced it filed for bankruptcy.</p>
<p>The dollar closed at 108.44/51 yen, up from 108.25/35 at the open.  </p>
<p>The dollar ended near session highs against the yen as traders said there was talk that a major Wall Street investment firm purchased the U.S. unit.</p>
<p>The mark traded around 73.16/19 yen late in the New York session, up from 72.99 earlier in the day.</p>
<p>Traders had pegged mark/yen resistance near 73.15 amid rumored offers from large hedge funds near that level.</p>
<p>The Bank of Japan has kept official interest rates at rockbottom levels to boost economic growth and help restore Japan's debt ladden financial sector.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't think they're nearly ready to raise rates yet, quite frankly, and certainly not with another financial institution going belly up,&quot; said Ben Strauss, an assistant vice president at Bank Julius Baer and Co. &quot;It's another reason to sell yen.&quot;</p>
<p>In other trade, the dollar finished at 1.2001/09 Swiss francs, up from 1.1990/00 at the open.</p>
<p>Sterling rose to US$1.5498/05 from US$1.5490/97.</p>
<p>The dollar closed at Canadian $1.3739/44, barely changed from C$1.3738/43. The Australian dollar closed at $0.7911/16.</p>
<p>-- Donna Sells 212-859-1668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
