<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5589" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American supports USAir's Heathrow bid.</title>
<headline>American supports USAir's Heathrow bid.</headline>
<dateline>FORT WORTH, Texas 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>American Airlines said on Wednesday it supported USAir Group bid to serve London Heathrow's Airport, saying it was consistent with the &quot;open skies&quot; aviation agreement being discussed by the United States and Britain.  </p>
<p>USAir filed with the U.S. Department of Transportation to serve London's Heathrow Airport from Boston, Charlotte, Philadelphia and Pittsburgh.</p>
<p>The carrier cited the need for competition in the U.S.-U.K. market in view of the proposed alliance between British Airways Plc and AMR Corp's American Airlines.</p>
<p>USAir, British Airway's existing trans-Atlantic partner, previously filed a lawsuit against the proposed alliance, alleging the deal would monopolize air travel between the U.S. and Britain and undermine USAir's own agreement with BA.  </p>
<p>BA holds a 24.6 percent stake in USAir.</p>
<p>USAir cannot serve Heathrow until the current Anglo-U.S. aviation treaty is liberalized.</p>
<p>American said it remains optimistic that a new &quot;open skies&quot; agreement will be reached, which will make possible new services such as those proposed by USAir.</p>
<p>American Airlines said it expects some Heathrow slots will be available to U.S. carriers under a the new aviation pact, but there may be costs involved.</p>
<p>In 1991, American said it was required to invest more than $440 million to secure limited access to Heathrow.</p>
<p>&quot;While we agree that additional U.S. carriers should be authorized to serve Heathrow, those who seek to fly there must recognize that realization of their aspirations will inevitably be a function of the costs and practicalities with which we and others have had to contend,&quot; said Arnold Grossman, American's vice president of international affairs.</p>
<p>The &quot;open skies&quot; aviation talks are set to resume next week in Washington.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FORT WORTH, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
