<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5592" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natgas futures end lower, AGAs pressure ACCESS.</title>
<headline>Natgas futures end lower, AGAs pressure ACCESS.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures, pressured by softer cash, ended lower across the board Wednesday in moderate trade, then fell further on ACCESS after an unexpectedly-large weekly AGA stock build.</p>
<p>September fell 2.3 cents to close at $2.03 per million British thermal units, then slipped to the $1.99-2.00 area on ACCESS. October settled 3.1 cents lower at $2.093.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the AGA build) was a pretty bearish number. It could be bombs away,&quot; said one Houston-based trader, noting weaker cash prices this morning helped undermine futures during the day session.  </p>
<p>AGA said Wednesday that U.S. gas stocks rose last week by 93 bcf to 62 percent of capacity, with the East gaining 67 bcf. The overall build was above-expectations in the 75-85 bcf range. Stocks are still 402 bcf, or 17 percent, below year-ago levels.</p>
<p>With injections continuing at a healthy pace and more mild weather ahead, most expected the market to remain on the defensive near-term.</p>
<p>But technically, prices were still range bound, with September support still at the $1.975 August 7 low and resistance at the recent $2.215 high.</p>
<p>Cash quotes at the U.S. Gulf Coast were off more than five cents Wednesday to the $2.00-2.05 area, almost 25 cents below August indices. Midcon pipes fell a similar amount to the mid-$1.80s, more than 25 cents below August 1 levels.</p>
<p>The 12-month strip slipped 1.4 cents to $2.119. NYMEX said 29,834 Henry Hub contracts traded, down from Tuesday's revised tally of 33,766.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Henry Hub natgas futures expire Monday, August 26.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Permian natgas closed seven cents lower at $1.75, while deferreds settled down by four cents but again were untraded. NYMEX said 63 Permian contracts traded, down from Tuesday's total of 30.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Permian natgas futures expire Wednesday August 28.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, September finished down by seven cents at $1.88, while deferreds ended one to six cents lower. The East/West spread widened by 1.7 cents to 19.0 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>KCBT September natgas futures expire Tuesday, August 27.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
