<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5596" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. crude imports stalled as Sep business ends.</title>
<headline>U.S. crude imports stalled as Sep business ends.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign crude activity into the U.S. was quiet again Wednesday, remaining aloof while end-September business worked its way out, traders said.</p>
<p>Barrels from Latin American were only at talking levels, since there seemed to be no interest for doing trades.</p>
<p>Crude brokers said Cano Limon was talked at a $1.65-$1.75 discount to October West Texas Intermediate/Cushing, while Cusiana offers firmed to talk at parity to October WTI.</p>
<p>October WTI/Cushing was around $21.70-$21.75 by the close, off around 35 cents from Tuesday's closing ranges.</p>
<p>Players were watching developments off the Mexican coast, as Tropical Storm Dolly forced closure of three large ports.</p>
<p>State oil company Petroleos Mexicanos (Pemex) said it was forced to shut Pajaritos, Dos Bocas and Cayo Arcas ports on the Gulf of Mexico in preparation for possible damage.</p>
<p>A decision by the Ecuadorean government to revise all contracts with foreign companies with operations in the country, has had no impact on the market, traders said.</p>
<p>The head of the state oil company Petroecuador said each firm's contract would be revised for the benefit of the sate.</p>
<p>On the spot Brent market for the U.S., there remained only one cargo seen heading west for September. Traders said talk was quiet by the lack of arbitrage opportunities.</p>
<p>-Patrick Connole, New York Energy Desk, +1 212 859 1828</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
