<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5597" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX crude ends lower as profit taking continues.</title>
<headline>NYMEX crude ends lower as profit taking continues.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX crude oil ended lower as recent profit taking continued in the wake of inventory reports that turned out to more bearish than than the market had expected, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Technical indicators are looking toppy. We are seeing a healthy correction,&quot; said Gerald Samuels, managing director of ARB Oil, adding however he thought the market still had good upside potential.</p>
<p>October crude settled 39 cents lower at $21.72 a barrel after the U.S. Energy Information Administration said crude stocks rose by 1.8 million barrels to 308.1 million.  </p>
<p>Some sources said they expected October crude to test support in the $21.40 to $21.50 a barrel range, with the first resistance pegged at $22.00. Longer-term resistance on spot continuation charts was pegged at $22.60, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Crude prices are moving way ahead of themselves,&quot; said Nizam Sharief, analyst at Hornsby and Co in Houston.</p>
<p>Heating oil was the strongest of the weakest in the oil complex, with widening heat-to crude crack spreads to show for it. September heat fell 0.69 cent to 60.98 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>September gasoline, which barely finished stronger than crude, settled 0.89 cent lower at 63.12 cents a gallon.  </p>
<p>The October heat-to-crude crack spread widened by a modest nine cents to $3.89 a barrel.</p>
<p>On the news front, closure of three Mexican ports in the Bay of Campeche in the south of the Gulf of Mexico due to tropical depression Dolly was seen bullish, but only remotely so.</p>
<p>Forecasters say the storm is likely to strengthen once it enters the Bay of Campeche and makes landfall in northern Mexico or southern Texas.</p>
<p>-- Oliver Ludwig, New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1633</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
