<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5599" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USWC prods prices flatten on neutral inventories.</title>
<headline>USWC prods prices flatten on neutral inventories.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast product prices were steady early Wednesday, held in check by neutral inventory reports and a drop in refinery buying after after last week's disruption in output.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is going sideways,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>While API data showed a 1.21 million barrel fall in total West Coast gasoline, supply remained 764,000 barrels over year ago levels.</p>
<p>And though PADD 5 reformulated stocks shrank by 780,000 barrels last week they also stayed well above the same period last year -- 4.9 million barrels above August 16, 1995.  </p>
<p>Conventional-grade gasoline in Los Angeles rose one cent from midday to 65/65.50 cents a gallon, with premium quality seven cents higher.</p>
<p>But CARB-grade gasoline slipped a half cent to 68/68.50 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>Wednesday's EIA report showed U.S. distillate stocks up 1.1 million barrels for the week ending August 16, compared to the larger 1.83 million barrel rise estimated by the trade group American Petroleum Institutre.</p>
<p>Low sulphur diesel in L.A. slipped a half cent to 68.50/69.50 cents on the supply builds.</p>
<p>And with supply returning after last week's refinery problems, low sulphur was seen falling to its usual five-cent discount to CARB diesel, traders said.</p>
<p>Jet fuel was unchanged at 69.50/70 cents.</p>
<p>And business shifted from August to September after two quiet sessions when traders attended a golf tournament.</p>
<p>August gasolines were seen 1.50 below September.</p>
<p>-- David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles Bureau 213 380-2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
