<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5603" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole economic plan criticized as too optimistic.</title>
<headline>Dole economic plan criticized as too optimistic.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Rich Miller, Economics Correspondent</p>
<p>Republican presidential hopeful Bob Dole has called himself the most optimistic man in America and critics charged on Wednesday that is exactly what is wrong with his plan to slash taxes and balance the budget.</p>
<p>They accused the former Kansas lawmaker of over-estimating both the amount of revenue he can count on and the spending cuts he will be able to deliver to make the plan work.</p>
<p>&quot;The revenue estimates are optimistic and the spending cuts problematic,&quot; Richard Kogan of the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities said. &quot;There is considerable risk that the (budget) deficit targets in the Dole plan will be missed by substantial amounts.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole, who last week was anointed his party's standard bearer to run against President Clinton in the November 5 election, has scoffed at the critics, saying that he can deliver on his plan if Republicans retain control of Congress.</p>
<p>The centerpiece of the program is $548 billion in tax cuts over six years, including a 15 percent cut in individual income tax rates and a halving of the maximum capital gains tax.  </p>
<p>Robert Reischauer, former head of the Congressional Budget Office, agreed that Dole and a Republican Congress could push through the plan, but he doubted they would stick with it.</p>
<p>&quot;Initially this is really quite doable,&quot; Reischauer told a symposium sponsored by the Center for National Policy.</p>
<p>&quot;The question is, is it sustainable?,&quot; he asked. &quot;The answer is no. The spending reductions would be unacceptable to our political system.&quot;</p>
<p>The program builds on $393 billion in spending cuts already proposed by Congressional Republicans for the next six year and adds $217 billion on top on that.</p>
<p>Dole has ruled out any further cuts in Medicare health care spending for the elderly, the Social Security pension fund and military outlays to help pay for his program. He also said on Tuesday that military veterans would not be hurt by the plan.</p>
<p>&quot;It's mind-boggling when you think of how much Dole has taken off the table,&quot; said Martha Phillips, Executive Director of the Concord Coalition anti-deficit group.</p>
<p>She said that Dole has ruled out further cuts in more than two thirds of the budget and questioned whether he could find the needed savings in the portion that remains.  </p>
<p>Robert Greenstein, Executive Director of the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities, said the Dole plan would lead to deep cuts in discretionary spending. &quot;There will be fewer teachers, there will be fewer border guards,' he said.</p>
<p>However, Dole supporter and former budget official John Cogan argued that the spending cuts were doable and that critics had exaggerated their size.</p>
<p>The $217 billion in extra spending reductions proposed by Dole amounts to a just over a six percent cut in the various programs not ruled off limits by the candidate, Cogan said.</p>
<p>The Dole plan has also come under fire for its allegedly rosy scenario for government revenue.</p>
<p>Much of the criticism has been focussed on the program's dependance on faster economic growth to generate some  of the tax revenues that would be needed to close the deficit -- a reprise of the supply-side arguments of the 1980's.</p>
<p>According to the Dole proposal, faster growth and reduced tax avoidance would help boost government revenues by $147 billion over six years, paying for 27 percent of the scheduled $548 billion in tax cuts.  </p>
<p>Reischauer said the consensus among economists for the expected revenue feed-back from faster growth from supply-side tax cuts was more on the order of 10 to 20 percent.</p>
<p>But he conceded that estimate does not include any extra revenues that might be generated from reduced tax avoidance. Nor does it include any calculation of the economic impact of Dole's proposal to cut back on government regulation.</p>
<p>Reischauer said he believed the CBO would give Dole credit for some revenue feed-back if it judged his plan credible. But the feedback would likely be much smaller than calculated by Dole.</p>
<p>&quot;You might have to take your electron microscope to detect it,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
