<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5610" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. stock index futures end mixed, Sept S&amp;P down.</title>
<headline>U.S. stock index futures end mixed, Sept S&amp;P down.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. stock index futures finished mixed after cutting losses in late trading, but September Standard and Poor's 500 futures never fully recovered from a weak tone set early.</p>
<p>Buyers emerged late in September S&amp;Ps, triggering buystops at 665.50 and 666.30.</p>
<p>&quot;Local buying hit stops at 665.50 and then they just kept on going and pushed through the daily high and pushed them through more stops,&quot; an S&amp;P trader said.</p>
<p>September ended in the middle of its daily range and still locked into the recent 660.00 to 670.00 zone.  </p>
<p>Traders noted that the late buying could not rescue September from negative territory, and said the overall mien of the market this week continued to be sluggish.</p>
<p>Early in the session, September S&amp;Ps dropped to support at 665.00, quickly extended losses, then stabilized. Between the early sell-off and the late rebound from the lows, trading was lackluster and consolidative.</p>
<p>In view of the overall slow trade, players' attention was turned as far ahead as September 6, when the August employment report will be released.  </p>
<p>One trader cited the possibility of interest from the July durable goods report on Friday or consumer confidence next Tuesday. The latest weekly jobless claims will be released Thursday at 0730 CDT/1230 GMT and were forecast to rise to 331,000 in the week ended August 17 from 321,000 the previous week.</p>
<p>An early smattering of U.S. data had little impact on the slumbering market.</p>
<p>U.S. July import prices fell 0.2 percent after a revised June decline of 1.1 percent. July export prices fell 0.5 percent after a revised June drop of 0.2 percent.  </p>
<p>September S&amp;P 500 futures settled down 1.95 points at 666.00, Midcap 400 ended up 0.65 at 231.85, Value Line finished down 0.45 points at 619.45, NYSE Composite fell 0.75 to 356.70, and Nikkei 225 rose 50.0 points to 21,255.0 -Derivatives desk(312)408-8750 E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
