<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5618" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chicago cancelling ValuJet Midway lease.</title>
<headline>Chicago cancelling ValuJet Midway lease.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The city of Chicago is canceling ValuJet Inc's lease at Midway Airport because the discount airline has been inactive, a city spokesman said.</p>
<p>The cancellation will take effect on Friday, said Barrett Murphy, Chicago Department of Aviation director of marketing.</p>
<p>&quot;We sent them (ValuJet) formal notice and they haven't gotten back to us&quot; about the cancellation, Murphy said.</p>
<p>ValuJet had only one of Midway's 30 gates under lease. Airport rules require that an airline run at least six arrivals and departures per day to keep its lease.  </p>
<p>ValuJet suspended service in June under U.S. Federal Aviation Administration orders after a May airliner crash in Florida that killed all 110 passengers.</p>
<p>&quot;Because they have been inactive, they have not met our threshold, so we notified them we were taking back the gate ... If they want to come back tomorrow, we can lease them partial gates. We hope they do come back,&quot; Murphy said.</p>
<p>The airline said Wednesday it will not be able to resume operations by its target date of Friday. The U.S. Department of Transportation declined comment on when ValuJet might be granted federal permission to fly again.</p>
<p>The city of Chicago owns both Midway and the much larger O'Hare Airport, which has 150 gates.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
