<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5625" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US CREDIT OUTLOOK - Jobless claims to set the tone.</title>
<headline>US CREDIT OUTLOOK - Jobless claims to set the tone.</headline>
<byline>Jose Paulo Vicente</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. credit markets will focus on the release of fresh jobless claims data on Thursday as players struggle to find economic evidence to push the market out of its current doldrums, analysts said.</p>
<p>Players will scrutinize the jobless report for a reason to take the market out of its current trading range, which has kept the 30-year Treasury bond yield confined between 6.75 and 6.85 percent for the last six session.  </p>
<p>In a Reuters survey, economists believe on average jobless claims were up to 331,000 in the week ended August 17 against 321,000 claims in the prior seven-day period.</p>
<p>&quot;If the numbers come in close to the consensus, we'll be looking at it as a continuation of the range trade,&quot; said Patrick Dimick, economist at C.S. First Boston.</p>
<p>&quot;We're now at the cheap end of the range and you'll see some people try to buy it tomorrow if the claims data allow (them to),&quot; Dimick said. &quot;I think there is a lot of people who still want to buy bonds in the 6.80's,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>The 6-3/4 percent benchmark 30-year U.S. Treasury bond was quoted down 15/32 at 98-29/32 in late trade on Wednesday to yield 6.84 percent. Fresh claims data are due out on Thursday at 0830 EDT/1230 GTM.</p>
<p>The Labor Department's jobless claims report gained momentum over the last few trading sessions after the indicator's four-week moving average posted a seven-year low at 313,000 claims in the week ended August 10.</p>
<p>The surprising drop prompted many economists to revise up their estimates for the August employment report, which will be issued on September 6.  </p>
<p>Analysts called the August non-farm payrolls a key indicator for members of the Federal Reserve's Open Market Committee at their September 24 meeting. The FOMC is the central bank's policy-setting arm.</p>
<p>&quot;The jury is still out whether the economy is slowing. And if it is, people wonder whether it's enough to keep the Fed at bay,&quot; said Raphael Marrone, senior analyst at Deustche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>Analysts said the market will also be gearing up for the July durable goods report, which is slated for release on Friday (August 23) at 0830 EDT/1230 GMT.  </p>
<p>Analysts said portfolio managers have been mostly out of the market lately as they wait for new economic indicators.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is now living through this post-FOMC period in which everyone is looking for new data,&quot; said a trader at a U.S. investment bank.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the Federal Reserve decided to leave short-term rates unchanged, keeping its target for the federal funds at 5.25 percent.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the central bank refrained from open market operations. Federal funds are seen opening at 5.19 percent on Thursday, analysts said. -- (212) 859-1676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
