<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5632" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. debt futures end lower in sluggish activity.</title>
<headline>U.S. debt futures end lower in sluggish activity.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. debt futures ended lower, as weakness in the German bund market overnight weighed on a directionless, sluggish U.S. market, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's amazing how the Ifo and the selling of bunds really took hold,&quot; one cash bond analyst said, referring to the stronger than expected Ifo West German business climate index.</p>
<p>The index rose to 94.1 in July, versus 90.4 in June and the average market forecast of 91.0, and raised expectations the German central bank would cut rates. Talk that the index would be 94.1 circulated late, but still managed to weigh on bunds and pressured U.S. Treasury bonds at the opening, he said.  </p>
<p>He said expectations grew throughout the day that the Bundesbank would lower the German repo rate.</p>
<p>However, the analyst also conceded that the U.S. markets lacked much else to react to now that the Federal Open Market Committee decided not to tighten rates at its much-anticipated meeting on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is in a malaised environment,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Even signs that U.S. price pressures remained subdued failed to prop the market higher. Both oil and grain prices were mostly lower, with the Commodity Research Bureau's index down slightly.  </p>
<p>In addition, both U.S. July import and export prices fell 0.2 percent and 0.5 percent, respectively. Some traders, however, did express some concern about the non-petroleum import prices, which were up 1.5 percent.</p>
<p>On Thursday at 0830 EDT/1230 GMT, jobless claims for the week ended August 17 are expected to rise to 331,000, from 321,000.</p>
<p>Some traders believe September bonds will trade slightly lower due to short-term technical factors. The contract closed below 110-24/32, which could lead Septmber to 109-24/32.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think it will be constructive if we hold above there on an intraweek basis,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>At the end of pit trade, September T-bonds were down 08/32 to 110-20/32, 10-year notes were off 05/32 at 108-14/32, munibonds fell 02/32 to 115-07/32, December Eurodollars were unchanged at 94.21 and March Eurodollars were down one basis point at 94.10, while March T-bills were also down one basis point at 94.68. Derivatives Desk 312-408-8750;E-mail derivatives@reuter.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
