<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5634" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. West next-day power rises, back-months steady.</title>
<headline>U.S. West next-day power rises, back-months steady.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot electricity prices in the western U.S. were steady to higher Wednesday, bolstering by forecasts of extended hot weather and higher daily Bonneville Power Administration (BPA) prices, market sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just a little hotter weather that's pushing it up,&quot; said one East Coast-based trader. &quot;It's getting a bit hotter in Nevada.&quot;</p>
<p>Next-day prices were hoisted amid a BPA reported hike of its posting for 16-hour power blocks for Thursday by 40 cents to $17.90 per megawatt hour (MWh). Values for other BPA daily products were heard flat to up one dollar from Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Deferred-month prices were sharply lower in early trading, but trimmed most of their losses toward unchanged from Tuesday's ranges, brokers and traders said.</p>
<p>In today's physical market, California-Oregon Border (COB) prices for firm, peak delivery were quoted at $17.00-$17.90 per MWh, up from Tuesday's $16.00-$17.00 range.</p>
<p>September COB power for firm, peak delivery was assessed at $17.50-$18.25, up from Tuesday's $17.10-$17.90.  </p>
<p>October COB, with similar delivery terms, was pegged at $15.75-$16.25, compared with $15.50-$15.90 on Tuesday, and firm, peak COB for the 1996 fourth-quarter was valued at $16.25-$16.75, down from Tuesday's $16.90-$17.25 range.</p>
<p>Further north at the Mid-Columbia (Mid-C) delivery point in Washington, firm, peak electricity prices for next-day delivery were quoted at $15.50-$16.50 per MWh, up from $15.00-$15.50 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>September Mid-C electricity was pegged at $17.25-$17.75, up from Tuesday's $16.50-$17.10. October Mid-C was quoted in the $15.50 area.  </p>
<p>Down at the Palo Verde (PV) switchyard close to Phoenix, Ariz., next-day electricity for peak, firm delivery was valued at $22.00-$22.50 per MWh, up from Tuesday's $21.00-$22.00.</p>
<p>September firm, peak PV prices were quoted at $20.70-$21.25, compared with $20.75-$21.25 on Tuesday. October PV electricity, with similar delivery terms, was assessed at $15.75-$16.50, compared with Tuesday's range of $15.90-$16.10.</p>
<p>Fourth-quarter 1996 PV prices were quoted at $16.20-$16.50, down slightly from $16.30-$16.70 on Tuesday. Several deals were heard done at $16.30 and $16.40.</p>
<p>Firmer natural gas prices in the West provided support for PV electricity, traders said. Natgas prices for September delivery to San Juan, N.M., ended today in the high $1.50-range, up eight to nine cents from earlier trading.</p>
<p>Pacific Gas &amp; Electric Co said its 2,160 MW Diablo Canyon nuclear plant in central California resumed full output today after production was reduced for a couple of days because of a nearby wildfire.</p>
<p>--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
