<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5644" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Canadian spot natgas up slightly on pipeline work.</title>
<headline>Canadian spot natgas up slightly on pipeline work.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot natural gas prices gained a few cents from last week as NOVA performed scheduled maintenance on its pipeline and a plant outage in British Columbia was extended for two days, traders said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Gas for August delivery at the AECO storage hub in Alberta was talked in the C$1.17/1.18 per gigajoule range, up from C$1.15/1.16 last week. September AECO gas was quoted around $1.15 per GJ, up about one cent.</p>
<p>A 24-hour outage on NOVA's system is affecting about 100 million cubic feet per day of throughput, out of a total of about 12 billion cubic feet per day, a company spokesman said.  </p>
<p>Westcoast Energy's 700 million cubic feet per day McMahon gas plant returned to partial service Tuesday and is expected to be back in full operation at 0800 MDT Thursday.</p>
<p>A company spokesman said the plant was completely down from August 15 through August 19, but the outage had to be extended partially for two more days to complete the work.</p>
<p>Gas for September export at Sumas, Wash., eased by about one cent from last week to the US$0.96/1.00 per million British thermal units range as California buyers became more sparse due to the brief respite of cool weather to the region.</p>
<p>However, temperatures are expected to return to above-normal levels this weekend in the Northwest, which should boost demand and prices.</p>
<p>Spot prices in eastern Canada were discussed well above last week's levels but the market had eased from earlier in the week. Gas at Niagara and Parkway was talked in the US$2.22/2.27 per mmBtu area, up more than five cents on the week. On Tuesday, prices were in the $2.30s.</p>
<p>--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
