<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5645" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TWA financial chief seen adding stability.</title>
<headline>TWA financial chief seen adding stability.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trans World Airlines Inc's naming of a new chief financial officer (CFO) will give the airline, still dealing with last month's plane crash, some much-needed stability, securities analysts said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;In what is already a difficult time, I think it's good they're bringing some stability to the organization,&quot; said James Higgins, analyst for Donaldson Lufkin &amp; Jenrette. &quot;I think the fact they moved quickly on this is a plus.&quot;</p>
<p>St. Louis-based TWA said Wednesday it named Edward Soule to the position of executive vice president and chief financial officer.  </p>
<p>Most recently, Soule served as chief financial officer for the brokerage firm Edward D. Jones &amp; Co. He left the company in 1995 to study philosophy at Washington University, but remained a partner in the firm and worked as a consultant.</p>
<p>&quot;He was a very innovative guy for CFO. He was able to craft things like credit facilities that gave banks great comfort but us great flexibility,&quot; said John Bachmann, the Jones' managing principal and a TWA director.</p>
<p>&quot;We were very sorry to lose him when we lost him,&quot; Bachmann said. &quot;We're excited for him.&quot;  </p>
<p>Soule replaced Robert Peiser, who left the company in June over differences in management direction, a TWA spokesman said. The senior vice president of marketing, Mark Coleman, also left, and his position is occupied by acting vice president Marilyn Hoppe as an external search to replace Coleman continues.</p>
<p>&quot;When the CFO left, that really started the stock slide,&quot; said one analyst who asked not to be named. He said TWA shares fell from the low $20s to the mid teens amid rumors of management instability.</p>
<p>&quot;Then of course there was the crash. At least they have solved one of these problems,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>On July 17, TWA Flight 800 exploded over the Atlantic Ocean, killing all 230 people on board.</p>
<p>TWA shares traded unchanged at 10-3/4.</p>
<p>--Susan Nadeau, Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
