<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5660" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USWC crudes off with WTI, buyers watch pipelines.</title>
<headline>USWC crudes off with WTI, buyers watch pipelines.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast light crudes tracked WTI prices lower early Wednesday, with local business quiet as buyers waited for Canadian pipeline apportionments later this week.</p>
<p>September WTI fell around $1 to $22.05/22.20 a barrel on fading pipeline demand and the collapse of the September/October roll from 75 to 30 cents early Wednesday.</p>
<p>Cash values reacted to Tuesday's 40-cent fall in NYMEX September crude, which expired at $22.86 a barrel.</p>
<p>Alaska North Slope (ANS) slipped 40 cents to $20.00/20.35 a barrel, while deltas unchanged at $1.95 off September WTI.  </p>
<p>California refiners saw ample ANS supply and claimed the October delta would widen out to $3 a barrel from its current $1.95 off September WTI.</p>
<p>Traders said increased imports of Canadian heavy and sour crudes would come at the cost of light volumes, since IPL pipeline is expected to withhold light grades to help with maintenance in the line this September.</p>
<p>Prices for Line 63 also tracked WTI lower, with no spot deals done in recent weeks and supply and demand seen balanced in thin trade.</p>
<p>Pre-nominations for Line 63 shipments began late Tuesday, with restrictions announced in two days.</p>
<p>Kern River and Wilmington grades were unchanged late.</p>
<p>-- David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles bureau +1 213 380 2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
