<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5668" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Most IMM currency futures close light trade higher.</title>
<headline>Most IMM currency futures close light trade higher.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>IMM currency futures closed a session of light range-trading higher.</p>
<p>Yen broke down again late to day's lows and small losses when traders said a fund sold 800 Septembers after the contract had attempted to rise but stalled in choppy trade.</p>
<p>Pressure on yen stemmed partly from news overnight that a large Japanese consumer credit company had filed for bankruptcy, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;I definitely think that (bankruptcy filing) had some weight on it (yen),&quot; said a floor trader at the Chicago Mercantile Exchange.  </p>
<p>Marks advanced as traders reassessed the likelihood of an imminent a cut in German rates after a stronger-than-expected reading in the July's IFO Institute's business climate index.</p>
<p>The index rose to 94.1 from 90.4 in June, above forecasts for about a 91.0 level.</p>
<p>The IFO index redoubled attention on Thursday's council meeting after German M3 money supply data, released on Tuesday, showed slower growth and stoked talk of a cut in the 3.30-percent German securities repurchase rate.</p>
<p>&quot;No change,&quot; said one floor broker of the expected outcome of Thursday's Bundesbank council meeting.  </p>
<p>He said if Germany leaves rates unchanged, he expected a knee-jerk rise in the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it'll (dollar) test below 1.48 and make a run for 1.4715,&quot; he added. Those levels equate to about $0.6767 and $0.6806, respectively, in September mark futures.</p>
<p>Others looked for a German rate cut soon, albeit not necessarily on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I still think to keep some credibility and the EMU on track to some extent they have room to lower it (repo rate) at least five basis points,&quot; said a currency trader. &quot;I think it would be sending the wrong message if they didn't (ease).&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;I think they're (Bundesbank) going to cut, and that'll be it for a while,&quot; said another floor broker.</p>
<p>The Swiss franc also shaved gains late after advancing on safe-haven purchases linked to anxiety about the status of Russian president Boris Yeltsin's health.</p>
<p>The Interfax news agency reported on Wednesday that Yeltsin, the subject of rumors speculating he had heart surgery, would return to Moscow from holiday, but the Kremlin could not confirm that report.</p>
<p>Sterling edged up outright but slipped on crosses after the 0.6-percent month/month drop in July's U.K. retail sales.  </p>
<p>The drop fueled talk that U.K. chancellor Kenneth Clarke could press for a U.K. rate cut.</p>
<p>September yen eased $0.000010 to $0.009251, marks rose $0.0026 to $0.6754, Swiss francs advanced $0.0033 to $0.8346, Sterling gained $0.0022 to $1.5498, Canadian dollar slipped $0.0003 to $0.7285, Australian dollar rose $0.0042 to $0.7896, and Mexican peso lost $0.000125 to $0.131750. --Derivatives Desk 312-408-8750 E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
