<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5670" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY precious metals end weaker in lackluster trade.</title>
<headline>NY precious metals end weaker in lackluster trade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX and NYMEX precious metals futures ended mostly lower Wednesday, but the short term uptrend in gold and silver of the past few sessions is still seen intact, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Silver is still providing the lead, and being supported by the trade, and still looks like a buy on the charts above $5.17,&quot; one floor trader said.</p>
<p>COMEX September silver ended down 4.0 cents an ounce at $5.170, after trading in a $5.165-5.220 range, on total estimated volume of 19,000 lots for the silver strip.  </p>
<p>&quot;Demand prospects for silver are starting to brighten with the dollar expected to continue to weaken against the yen and some acceleration in global economic growth anticipated for the second half of the year,&quot; Smith Barney analyst David Rinehimer said in a weekly report.</p>
<p>COMEX December gold ended down $1.10 an ounce at $391.8, after trading in a $391.70-393.00 range, on total estimated volume of 13,000 lots.</p>
<p>In New York bullion trade, spot gold was quoted $386.60/387.10 at the close, from a London afternoon fix at $386.80 and a New York close Tuesday at $387.50/388.00.</p>
<p>&quot;Most producers are very bullish again, but ready to hedge above $388-390 basis spot gold, so the market is probably locked in this range, which allows good cash flow for miners,&quot; one mining finance house vice president said.</p>
<p>While silver and gold look to be still in short term uptrends, platinum group metals look to be still in downtrends, analysts said.</p>
<p>NYMEX October platinum ended down $2.30 an ounce at $401.5, while NYMEX September palladium ended down $1.65 at $125.60.</p>
<p>The end of last months strikes at the two largest South African platinum producers, Amplats and Implats, combined with the overhang of Russian stockpiles, continues to weigh on platinum group metal prices, analysts said.</p>
<p>But prospects for a tighter balance between world platinum production and consumption this year should limit the downside, they said.</p>
<p>--Clive McKeef, New York Commodities Desk, +212-859-1641.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
