<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5671" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Concorde Gaming seeks to settle dispute.</title>
<headline>Concorde Gaming seeks to settle dispute.</headline>
<dateline>RAPID CITY, S.D. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Concorde Gaming Corp said Wednesday it is in negotiations with three affiliated Native American tribes to settle disputes arising out of a management agreement for the 4 Bears Casino &amp; Lodge.</p>
<p>The casino and lodge is located on the Fort Berthold Indian Reservation in North Dakota.</p>
<p>&quot;A successful settlement of these disputes would eliminate ongoing litigation costs and enable the company to proceed with other opportunities where we have been restricted because of the legal uncertainty created by these contract disputes,&quot; Jerry Baum, president, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Concorde said declines in management agreement revenues from the 4 Bears Casino and in video lottery revenues in South Dakota contributed to an overall drop in revenues for the third quarter ended June 30 to $2.8 million from $3.3 million.</p>
<p>Earlier, Concorde reported third quarter earnings of $0.01 a share, down from $0.02. Litigation costs associated with the management agreement also hurt earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;With our revenue from the 4 Bears Casino &amp; Lodge being off due to road construction, a downturn in tourism and an increase in competition, our earnings per share were lower for the current period than the same period last year,&quot; Jerry Baum, president, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Baum said the decrease in revenues is expected to level off during the fiscal fourth quarter and first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RAPID CITY, S.D."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
