<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5680" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX crude breaks support in last hour of trade.</title>
<headline>NYMEX crude breaks support in last hour of trade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX crude oil prices broke key near-term support of $21.80 a barrel in the afternoon but traders didn't see much downside potential as a technical consolidation in heating oil lent crude support.</p>
<p>&quot;It's broken that support but doesn't seem very anxious, so it might rebound,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>However, traders noted some sell stops around the $21.75 level were triggered, with the support seen at around $21.45. Resistance was pegged at $22.05 a barrel.</p>
<p>October crude stood 38 cents lower at $21.73 a barrel, as the October-November spread coming in to 50 cents.  </p>
<p>They also cited a bearish build up in crude stocks indicated by weekly data by the American Petroleum Institute.</p>
<p>The October heating-to-crude crack was had widened $0.20 to $4.00 a barrel, traders said, with the strength in heat limiting crude's losses.</p>
<p>&quot;Heat is preventing crude from plummeting,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>September heating oil was 0.62 cent lower at 61.05 cents a gallon, while September gasoline, posting the sharpest losses, was 1.11 cents lower at 62.90 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>&quot;Gasoline is just really putrid right now,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>Traders were hammering down the September gasoline contract after weekly data from the U.S Energy Information Administration showed an unexpected build in gasoline stocks.</p>
<p>-- Harry Milling, New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
