<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5681" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mexican bolsa closure taken in stride by Wall St.</title>
<headline>Mexican bolsa closure taken in stride by Wall St.</headline>
<byline>George Lerner</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Protests that delayed the openning of the Mexican bolsa on Wednesday did not rattle nerves on Wall Street, as U.S. brokerage houses swiftly adapted to open outcry conditions, U.S. analysts said.</p>
<p>Mexico's stock exchange began floor trading three hours late after about 200 demonstrators, angry over the results of an entrance exmanination, blocked the entrance to the bolsa.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a short term inconveniece,&quot; said Eduardo Cabrera, chief Latin America strategist at Merrill Lynch. &quot;From a fundamental market point of view this was a minor issue.&quot;  </p>
<p>Cabrera said order processing might be slower due to the open outcry system but the process would function.</p>
<p>&quot;We are participating in the market,&quot; he said. &quot;It's an old style system, but that is the way it was done for many decades.&quot;</p>
<p>Geoffrey Dennis, equity strategist for Latin America at Bear Stearns, said the disruption may have slightly affected volume when U.S. players had sought more information about the closure, but trade in Mexican ADRs had remained liquid.</p>
<p>&quot;It disrupted a large chunk of the market, but it did not disrupt the most liquid part of the market,&quot; Dennis said.  </p>
<p>Across Wall Street, analysts and ADR traders seemed non-plussed about the protests and the resultant closure.</p>
<p>&quot;People did not focus on it,&quot; said one Latin American economist at a major U.S. investment bank. &quot;It didnt lead to dramatic nervousness.&quot;</p>
<p>Several Wall Street firms have recently adopted a bullish posture on Mexico's economic recovery, which was compounded by the Monday announcement that second quarter growth rose by 7.2 percent in year-over-year terms.</p>
<p>By Wednesday afternoon, Mexican ADRs rose in thin volume, and the bolsa's IFC index bolsa, after the three-hour delay, soon built on its record high close of 3,419.89 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The cool-headed reaction from Wall Street seemed firmly based in the conviction that the demonstration was a specific, localized outcry against a particular policy, and not a reaction against the economic austerity plan.</p>
<p>&quot;This doesn't look like any sort of challenge to economic policy,&quot; said Dennis. &quot;Had we heard these were Chiapas Indians disrupting the center of Mexico City or a mass rally by trade unionists, we might have been more concerned.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
