<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5683" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: D&amp;A Funding to take control of Kenwin.</title>
<headline>D&amp;A Funding to take control of Kenwin.</headline>
<dateline>TUCKER, Ga. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenwin Shops said Wednesday that D&amp;A Funding Corp would acquire a 52.7 percent stake in the company and Kenwin President Robert Schwartz would resign.</p>
<p>Control of day-to-day operations at Kenwin will be transferred to D&amp;A, it said.</p>
<p>D&amp;A will own 526,818 of Kenwin's outstanding shares and have the right to vote 610,796 shares, or 61.1 percent of the outstanding stock, Kenwin said.</p>
<p>D&amp;A President Donald Weiner will act as Kenwin chief executive on an interim basis, replacing Ira Abramson, who will serve as a consultant for the next year.  </p>
<p>D&amp;A will provide inventory to Kenwin's women's apparel shops. In an interim emergency measure, about $1 million in inventory is being shipped to the stores, Kenwin said.</p>
<p>D&amp;A intends to buy from Kenwin all of its authorized, but unissued, shares and treasury shares at $0.01 per share.</p>
<p>D&amp;A also will acquire 83,978 shares from relatives of the founders of Kenwin at a price to be determined by future earnings, but not exeeding $4.50 a share.</p>
<p>The family members are retaining 83,978 Kenwin shares but will execute irrevocable proxies to D&amp;A. Kenwin said.  </p>
<p>The transaction must be approved by Kenwin stockholders and is expected to be completed within two months, Kenwin said.  </p>
<p>Kenwin family members will immediately be paid 50 cents per share by D&amp;A. In each year thereafter, they will be paid 10 percent of the company's per share, pre-tax earnings.</p>
<p>In the aggregate, they will be paid no more than $4.50 per share.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TUCKER, Ga."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
