<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5687" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Small stocks do better under Dem. presidents - study.</title>
<headline>Small stocks do better under Dem. presidents - study.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Contrary to popular wisdom, investors in small companies should root for President Bill Clinton winning a second term over his Republican rival Bob Dole, a study suggests.</p>
<p>But shareholders in large companies should cheer for Dole over Clinton, according to a study released Wednesday by Liberty Financial Co Inc.</p>
<p>Small stocks performed better during almost all Democratic administrations than during Republican presidencies, the study found.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's the opposite of what most people would think,&quot; said Kenneth Leibler, chief executive of Liberty. &quot;There seems to be a perception, widely held, that the Republicans are better for business.&quot;</p>
<p>Since the end of the Great Depression in 1937, small stocks have risen an average of 17.2 percent a year under Democratic presidents, compared with 10.2 percent under Republicans.  </p>
<p>Going back to 1929 at the beginning of Republican President Herbert Hoover's administration, the differences are even more striking. Stocks rose an average 22.8 percent under Democrats versus 1.9 percent under Republicans.</p>
<p>The difference held for even more recent administrations. Small stocks have risen 19.9 percent a year during Clinton's term through June 30, bettering the 11.8 percent rise during President George Bush's four years and the 13.3 percent rise when President Ronald Reagan's two terms are added.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's just our belief that (correlation) comes from the emphasis on jobs in Democratic policy-making, and most jobs come from small companies rather than large companies,&quot; Leibler said.</p>
<p>By contrast, large companies performed better during the seven Republican administrations since the end of the Depression than under the six Democratic presidents.</p>
<p>The S&amp;P 500 index, which is weighted toward large companies, has risen 11.9 percent a year on average under Republican presidents during that period versus 10.2 percent under Democrats through the end of June.  </p>
<p>Liberty Financial focused the small-company study on the Ibbotson small-stock index, which tracks the 100 smallest companies in the Standard &amp; Poor's 500.</p>
<p>The stock market figures do not adjust for inflation, which erodes the return on a shareholder's investments.</p>
<p>Leibler said Liberty Financial, which owns several mutual fund companies, including Colonial Investments and Stein Roe &amp; Farnham Inc, has no affiliation with either political party.</p>
<p>-- Michael Ellis, Boston bureau, (617) 367-4176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
