<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5697" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Maxis says SimCity 3000 to be delayed.</title>
<headline>Maxis says SimCity 3000 to be delayed.</headline>
<text>
<p>WALNUT CREEK, Calif., Aug. 21 - Maxis Inc said Wednesday it has delayed the release of its new version of the popular software, SimCity, to mid-1997 from a previous early 1997.</p>
<p>In a statement, the company said SimCity 3000 needs &quot;further enhancements&quot; before being shipped.</p>
<p>&quot;The delay will help to ensure that every aspect of SimCity 3000 meets the expectations consumers have for this product,&quot; said Sam Poole, chief executive. &quot;The Sim brand is the cornerstone of the Maxis franchise and we will not compromise its quality.&quot;</p>
<p>Maxis shares were off 15/64 to 11-33/64 by mid-afternoon.  </p>
<p>The new SimCity 3000, a video game, will incorporate the latest 3-D design and mini-simulation.</p>
<p>Though the new SimCity's launch will be pushed back. Maxis said it is on track to launch four titles, SimCopter, SimGolf, SimPark and SimTunes, in time for holiday shoppers.</p>
<p>&quot;Releasing these new products simultaneously should allow us to command greater consumer attention during what is traditionally the heaviest buying period of the year,&quot; Poole said.</p>
<p>A fifth, The Streets of SimCity, is expected to be released in the first half of 1997.</p>
<p>SimCopter enables players to fly through cities that they build and perform various missions. SimGolf allows golfers to &quot;play&quot; the greens, change courses or design their own course.</p>
<p>The Streets of SimCity permits players to drive, or race, through cities of their own creation.</p>
<p>Children's titles include SimPark, in which players plan and build outdoor nature parks and SimTunes, which lets kids explore and experience the relationship between music and art.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
