<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5701" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US spot natgas retreats on cooler weather forecast.</title>
<headline>US spot natgas retreats on cooler weather forecast.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot natgas prices erased previous gains on Wednesday as forecasters called for cooler temperatures by week's end in the eastern U.S. and the threat of Hurricane Dolly to Gulf facilities faded, sources said.</p>
<p>Louisiana Gulf Coast swing prices fell by more than five cents to the $2.00-2.05 per million British thermal units area, with the higher-priced deals evident in late trading.</p>
<p>Early swing prices at the Henry Hub, La., hovered around $2, but as nomination deadlines drew near, prices crept up into the $2.04-2.06 area.  </p>
<p>The weakening storm also put downward pressure on the south Texas markets, where most deals were confirmed done in the high-$1.90s, down almost 10 cents.</p>
<p>Stingray Pipeline Co reported earlier Wednesday that its offshore Louisiana pipeline will return to normal by 1200 CDT/1300 EDT Thursday following a three-day maintenance outage.</p>
<p>The Gulf line is currently flowing at a rate of approximately 550 million cubic feet per day (mmcfd) as compared to the normal rate of about 780 mmcfd.</p>
<p>Despite average temperatures about five degrees above-normal in the region, Midcontinent prices dipped into mid-$1.80s, down about five cents from Tuesday's levels.</p>
<p>Sources saw the softening as a residual effect from the Gulf Coast price drop.</p>
<p>In the Permian basin, prices lost about nine to 10 cents to the high-$1.70s to low-$1.80s, but forecasts for above-normal temperatures next week in the West should bring more buyers to the marketplace and thereby prop up prices.</p>
<p>Prices at Topock (southern California border) extended their retreat as traders reported closing deals in the low-$1.70s, down more than 15 cents from Tuesday.</p>
<p>--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
