<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5703" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US natgas stocks seen up 75-85 bcf in weekly AGAs.</title>
<headline>US natgas stocks seen up 75-85 bcf in weekly AGAs.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. natural gas storage levels were expected to rise by 75 to 85 billion cubic feet (bcf) when weekly American Gas Association (AGA) data are released later today, industry sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was kind of cool in a lot of areas last week, so I expect a build at the high end of the range,&quot; said one Houston-based trader.</p>
<p>But with the bulk of the injection season now past, some were beginning to discount the importance of the weekly report.  </p>
<p>&quot;At this point, the AGAs are almost a non-event unless the number is seriously outside the norm,&quot; said another Houston trader, noting recent mild weather and forecasts for more of the same next week should translate into decent storage builds through August.</p>
<p>The Reuter poll of industry players showed expectations for an overall build ranged from 70 to 95 bcf for the week ended August 16. The four-week average is 84 bcf.</p>
<p>Last week, AGA showed stocks rose by 80 bcf, at the low end of expectations, but were still 458 bcf, or 20 percent, below the same year-ago period.</p>
<p>Last year at this time, stocks rose by 37 bcf, meaning a build today in the expected range would narrow the gap to last year to about 415 bcf.</p>
<p>With mostly moderate weather in the East last week, traders expected this week's build in the region to at least match last week's 55 bcf. Last year at this time, eastern stocks rose by 38 bcf.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the East will be more than 55 this week because last week was a fairly mild week,&quot; said one East Coast trader.</p>
<p>Last week, Consuming Region East stocks stood at 63 percent of capacity. The average weekly build in eastern stocks for the last four weeks was 64 bcf.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212 859 1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
