<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5706" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lawyers doubt Netscape charges will pass muster.</title>
<headline>Lawyers doubt Netscape charges will pass muster.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Antitrust lawyers doubt the Justice Department will decide Microsoft Corp has acted improperly, based on charges leveled against the company by rival Netscape Communications Corp.</p>
<p>Netscape has asked the department to take immediate action against Microsoft for &quot;far-reaching anti-competitive behavior&quot; involving the market for software used to browse the World Wide Web portion of the Internet.  </p>
<p>In an eight-page letter, Netscape charged that Microsoft offered improper payments and various inducements to computer makers and Internet service providers to entice them to use Microsoft's browser software.</p>
<p>Lawyers questioned whether the tactics described were unlawful and noted that in the market for browser software, Netscape is the dominant player and not Microsoft.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a bit of a stretch to call what Microsoft is described as doing a violation of the consent decree or a violation of antitrust laws,&quot; said Robert Skitol of Drinker Biddle &amp; Reath.  </p>
<p>In 1995, a federal judge approved the Justice Department's antitrust settlement with Microsoft, under which the computer software maker agreed to modify its licensing practices. Much of the investigation centered on how Microsoft achieved dominance in the market for operating system software.</p>
<p>By contrast, Skitol noted that in the latest dispute Netscape has a commanding lead in the growing browser market, with a share estimated at more than 80 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;In the browser category, Netscape is the elephant and Microsoft is the mouse,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Netscape said Microsoft's inducements were made on the condition that the parties involved would &quot;make competitors' browsers far less accessible to users than Microsoft's own browsers.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Absent some abuse of market power, it's hard to see how this is unlawful,&quot; said Phillip Proger of Jones, Day, Reavis &amp; Pogue.</p>
<p>&quot;If all Microsoft is doing is giving consumers higher value and competing on a value basis, then it's hard to say that's unlawful,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, lawyers doubted that the Justice Department would follow Netscape's suggestion and turn the issue back to the Federal Trade Commission for further investigation. They suggested that the department will want to retain the case.</p>
<p>A Justice Department spokesman was not immediately available to comment on the matter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
