<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5722" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Amgen boosts Epogen defense with EPO patent.</title>
<headline>Amgen boosts Epogen defense with EPO patent.</headline>
<dateline>THOUSAND OAKS, Calif. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Amgen Inc said Wednesday it has been granted a U.S. patent covering the product rights to recombinant erythropoietin (EPO), strengthening Amgen's protection for its drug, Epogen.</p>
<p>The patent gives Amgen a broad defense against other drug manufacturers making, importing or selling recombinant EPO in the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;(The patent) will be a very strong defense against potential EPO competition,&quot; Salomon Bros analyst Meirav Chovav said in a statement. Amgen's stock jumped 2-1/4 to 58 by mid-afternoon on the news.  </p>
<p>A competing company, Transkaryotic Therapies Inc, is developing a new genetic technology that may be used to produce EPO, and speculation about that technology has depressed Amgen's stock recently, Chovav said.</p>
<p>The new patent should help Amgen defend against the threat of Trankaryotic's technology, she said.</p>
<p>Epogen is used to treat anemia that is associated with chronic renal failure of patients undergoing kidney dialysis.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased to receive this patent as it adds to the strength of our intellectual property position on EPOGEN and helps ensure that we will be able to continue to provide this breakthrough therapeutic,&quot; Gordon Binder, Amgen chief executive officer, said in a statement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="THOUSAND OAKS, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
