<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5736" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hoechst fibers business sees 96 sales up.</title>
<headline>Hoechst fibers business sees 96 sales up.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hoechst AG 's world fibers business said Wednesday it expects its sales to rise to over $7 billion in 1996 compared to $6.6 billion last year.</p>
<p>&quot;We had sales of $6.6 billion in 1995 and expect to do in excess of $7 billion in '96,&quot; the division's president, William Harris, told a news conference here.  </p>
<p>Hoechst's fiber business had sales of $3.4 billion in the first half of this year.</p>
<p>Harris said Hoechst's world fibers business has changed its name to Trevira from Hoechst's Fibers Worldwide.</p>
<p>&quot;The umbrella name Trevira will not refer to any legal entity at this point. It will simply be the way we refer publicly to the $6.6 billion Hoechst business that includes fibers, resins, films and intermediates,&quot; Harris said.</p>
<p>Trevira is a Hoechst polyester trademark.  </p>
<p>In response to a question, Harris said Hoechst does not have any current plans to spin off its world fibers business from the rest of the company.</p>
<p>&quot;At this point there are no plans for the fibers business to be a separate legal entity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Harris said the overall polyethylene terephthalate (PET) packaging resins business is in a temporary slump that will probably continue into 1997 due to overcapacity.</p>
<p>&quot;However, we are still forecasting double digit growth for PET packaging resins for the next decade.  And we are not curtailing our plans for expansion in PET,&quot; Harris said.  </p>
<p>Last year the division said it announced plans to triple its PET resins business to 1.4 million metric tons per year by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Regarding its other businesses, Harris said the division's North American textile polyester filament business' sales are expected to rise about 10 percent above last year.</p>
<p>The business had sales of about $1.3 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>Harris said production at Hoechst's technical polyester joint venture with Reliance Industries Ltd will start in 1998.</p>
<p>Harris also said the company changed its brand name for acetate filament, which is used for women's designer fashions and linings, to Celanese acetate.</p>
<p>The company previously used the brand name Celebrate in its ads and promotions.</p>
<p>&quot;The Celebrate name, however catchy, does not work globally.  We hope to achieve consistency in our worldwide trademarks,&quot; Harris said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
