<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5740" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Spartech backlog rises.</title>
<headline>Spartech backlog rises.</headline>
<dateline>ST. LOUIS, Mo. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spartech Corp said Wednesday its current backlog stands at a record level of more than $34.0 million, up 12 percent from a year ago.</p>
<p>Based on the backlog, Spartech, which makes thermoplastic materials and polymeric compounds, said it remains cautiously optimistic about the fiscal fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Earlier, Spartech reported earnings for the third quarter ended August 3 of $0.20 a share, up from $0.16 a year ago. For the first nine months of the year, it earned $0.55 a share, up from $0.45 a year ago.  </p>
<p>&quot;Spartech Plastics, our extruded sheet and rollstock unit, continues to produce excellent results,&quot; Bradley Buechler, president, said in a statement. &quot;Third quarter 1996 sales generated by this 11-plant group rose approximately 16 percent as compared to 1995, with solid gains also being recorded in operating earnings.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that sales within the merchant compounding group declined modestly during the quarter. Spartech Vy-Cal plastics, a calendered PVC film operation, recorded a strong gain in operating earnings as a result of excellent volume and more stability in the price of raw materials, Buechler said.</p>
<p>The company said the acquisition of the Hamelin Group remains on track, with closing expected on or about September 30. The acquisition is expected to be accretive to earnings almost immediately, David Mueller, chief operating officer, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25140">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. LOUIS, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
