<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5745" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Argentine July industrial output up 7.0 pct - FIEL.</title>
<headline>Argentine July industrial output up 7.0 pct - FIEL.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine industrial output rose 7.0 percent in July from July 1995 and was up 4.5 percent compared with June 1996, said Argentine consultant firm FIEL on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall the figures confirm the recovery of industrial production in Argentina,&quot; Fernando Navajas, chief economist at FIEL, told Reuters Financial Television from Buenos Aires.</p>
<p>Navajas said the current level of Argentine industrial production was within the range of 1994 figures.  </p>
<p>Navajas said the industrial production data confirmed that the Argentine economy was on a path to recovery and indicated the manufacturing sector would continue to expand.</p>
<p>&quot;We are noticing a normalization of industrial production in Argentina across the board,&quot; &quot; Navajas said. &quot;The numbers will not be very impressive, but they will show the recovery is firm.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that durables good data, which had lagged in the recovery, were starting to increase on a month to month basis.</p>
<p>He noted problems, however, in applying the industrial data to the overall economy, and forecast that Argentina's gross domestic product would expand in 1996 by about three percent.</p>
<p>Navajas said the major policy challenge for the government lay in the addressing the fiscal picture, that is, to increase revenues and also to control public expenditure.</p>
<p>&quot;The governement and ministries have to show that they can manage the fiscal deficit and advance a line of reform,&quot; Navajas said.</p>
<p>-- George Lerner, 212 859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
