<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5751" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FORECAST-US July durables to confirm soft economy.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-US July durables to confirm soft economy.</headline>
<byline>Jose Paulo Vicente</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. durable goods report due out Friday should show orders rose slightly in July, but not enough to indicate an accelerating economy, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The data will likely confirm in the overall orders number that the economy was kind of sluggish in July,&quot; said Josh Feinman, global markets economist at BT Securities Inc.</p>
<p>In a Reuters survey, economists predicted a July durable goods orders rise of 0.3 percent. The ex-defense indicator is expected to post a 0.8 percent gain. Such a result would mark the third rise in durable goods orders this year.  </p>
<p>In June the overall number declined 0.6 percent, to a seasonally-adjusted $169.19 billion, reflecting weaker demand for aircraft, cars and business equipment.</p>
<p>The Department of Commerce is due to publish the indicator on Friday, August 23 at 0830 EDT/1230 GMT.</p>
<p>Because of anecdotal evidence and other economic data, analysts already know &quot;that consumer spending on durables was weak in July,&quot; Feinman said. &quot;The new information is what the business investment spending was doing, which we don't really know. And we're going to get some of that on the non-defense capital portion&quot; of the report, Feinman added.  </p>
<p>Analysts said transport orders -- mainly in the aircraft sector -- are expected to remain fairly weak in July after a strong 4.2 percent jump in May that reflected a surge in commercial aircraft demand.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking for a drop in transportation orders ... mainly aircraft orders,&quot; said Cary Leahey, senior financial markets economist at Lehman Government Securities Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd say any ex-transportation number below 1.0 percent would not be a big surprise to the (financial) markets,&quot; Leahey added.  </p>
<p>Capital goods are expected to show a fairly positive performance in July, but analysts said they did not expect scattered signs of economic strength to change the overall economic picture.</p>
<p>&quot;The capital goods sector is okay ... (but) this is just another indication that while July was a weakish month overall there were some patches of strength,&quot; Leahey said.</p>
<p>Looking at the manufacturing sector as a whole, analysts said the durable goods report is likely to confirm an incipient slowdown as suggested by the National Association of Purchasing Management (NAPM) index in July.  </p>
<p>The July NAPM index dropped to 50.2 from 54.3 in June. A reading below 50 is seen by the economists as an indication of a slowing manufacturing sector.</p>
<p>Looking at the broader picture, analysts said durable goods data could confirm the overall economy slowed in July, even if the overall headline number appears on the plus side.</p>
<p>&quot;People are going to say it's still a soft economy because all it did was reverse last month's decline,&quot; said Steve Ricchiuto, chief financial economist at Barclays de Zoete Wedd Government Inc.</p>
<p>-- (212) 859-1676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
