<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5765" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Rate worries weigh on dlr, Eurobourses down.</title>
<headline>Rate worries weigh on dlr, Eurobourses down.</headline>
<byline>Peter Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar sllipped against the mark on Wednesday and leading European shares closed lower after a respected business climate survey dampened expectations that Germany would ease credit this week.</p>
<p>Financial markets' hopes that the German Bundesbank was about to serve up a long-awaited cut in its main money market rate took a blow when the key confidence barometer issued by the Ifo economic institute emerged much stronger than expected.</p>
<p>Its survey of business conditions in the economy jumped to an eight-month high of 94.1 in July, a sharp rise from a three-month low of 90.4 in June.</p>
<p>Economists had predicted a figure of around 91 for July and were caught off-guard by the apparent sudden surge of confidence in a German economic recovery.</p>
<p>The news boosted the mark against the dollar and stengthened it against other European currencies. In late European trading the the dollar was off its lows of just above 1.48 marks but still well under the 1.49 level it touched in early Europe.</p>
<p>German bonds and shares fell as traders took the view that the Bundesbank would no longer feel under any pressure at Thursday's meeting of its policy-making council to trim its securities repurchase rate, or repo, to boost the economy.</p>
<p>The main Frankfurt DAX share index closed floor trading 16.5 points down at 2543.74 and extended its losses in post-bourse electronic trade, measured by the IBIS Dax, which closed more than one percent down at 2534.44.</p>
<p>London, Europe's largest bourse, which closed on Tuesday at a record high, was boosted to a fresh intraday peak of 3,894.4 early on after British retail trade figures. The data provided Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke with further ammunition if he wants to cut lending rates again on September 4, when British monetary authorities next meet.</p>
<p>Retail sales suffered a surprise 0.6 percent drop in July, providing evidence that while shops are busy, there is no danger of a runaway spending boom.</p>
<p>But the blue chip FTSE 100 index reversed itself in the afternoon and ended 11.1 points lower at 3,872.1 after a bout of profit-taking and a fall on Wall Street knocked prices back.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average opened lower and then continued to fall, pressured by profit-taking, softer bonds and brokerage downgrades of some technology issues. By the time London closed it was about 40 points or two thirds of a percent down.</p>
<p>London traders said a modest correction was in order, as the FTSE -- up almost five percent so far this month -- had settled higher for six of the last seven trading sessions.</p>
<p>French shares closed sharply lower due to a weaker franc, evaporating hopes of a German rate cut on Thursday and the lower start on Wall Street. But the market managed to remain above the 2,000 level and did keep some of Tuesday's 1.66 percent gain.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index ended down almost one percent at 2,000.64.</p>
<p>Analysts said weaker expectations of a German rate cut dimmed prospects that the Bank of France would trim its own rates, particularly in view of franc weakness.</p>
<p>&quot;The franc is still relatively weak. Even if the Bundesbank does something on Thursday, the Bank of France will wait,&quot; said economist Philippe Brossard of ABN-AMRO in Paris.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1545 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.4828 marks and 108.30 yen, compared with 1.4884 marks and 108.28 yen at the London close on Tuesday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS</p>
<p>The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares ended 11.1 points lower at 3,872.1.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index finished down 18.62 at 2,000.64.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt closed down 16.52 at 2,543.74.</p>
<p>The electronically traded IBIS DAX was down 27.68 at 2,534.44.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold closed at $387.25 compared with $387.55 at its close in London on Tuesday. Silver ended easier at $5.20.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
