<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5768" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: White dwarfs add to evidence of old universe.</title>
<headline>White dwarfs add to evidence of old universe.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>New guesses published on Wednesday about the age of the universe using white dwarf stars add to growing evidence that it is older rather than younger.</p>
<p>Astronomers said their findings indicated the Milky Way galaxy started forming between 14 and 17 billion years ago and gradually cooled and coalesced into stars 10 billion years ago.</p>
<p>Reporting in the science journal Nature, Terry Oswalt of the Florida Institute of Technology in Melbourne and colleagues at the NASA Goddard Space Centre in Maryland said they looked at white dwarfs nearby -- in the Earth's own Milky Way galaxy.</p>
<p>They measured light from the dying white dwarf stars to estimate when they had been created -- and from there when the galaxy first formed and the universe before that.</p>
<p>&quot;They cool slowly enough that even the oldest white dwarfs are still observable...and they therefore provide a record of the age and star-formation history of the local disk of the Milky Way -- and hence a useful constraint on the age of the Galaxy itself,&quot; they wrote.</p>
<p>The Milky Way probably started forming about a billion years after the Big Bang that scientists say started the universe.</p>
<p>Therefore, their measurements would indicate the universe could not possibly be any younger than 11.5 billion years  -- which is older than some recent theories that say it is only eight to nine billion years old.</p>
<p>Scientists do not yet agree on how old the universe actually is, but think it is anywhere between eight and 17 billion years old.</p>
<p>Earlier this month Alvio Renzini of the European Southern Observatory said they estimated the age of white dwarfs using light emissions to measure how much iron they had remaining in their cores. They said their findings put the stars at a minimum of 13 billion years old.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
