<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5771" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Tyrannosaurus had a mean bite, research finds.</title>
<headline>Tyrannosaurus had a mean bite, research finds.</headline>
<byline>Maggie Fox</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>It's official -- Tyrannosaurus rex could bite, and bite hard.</p>
<p>Measurements made by experts in California show its jaws were stronger than those of an alligator, and it could easily have ripped apart a struggling triceratops, for example.</p>
<p>The 6.5 metre (20 foot) tall carnivore epitomises everything terrifying about dinosaurs, with its 15 cm (six inch) long teeth and gaping jaws.</p>
<p>But some palaeontologists say Tyrannosaurus's tiny, useless-looking arms meant it must have scavenged on carrion rather than hunting down prey. Others have said its teeth and jaws did not look strong enough to tear apart a live victim.</p>
<p>But Gregory Erickson of the University of California at Berkeley and colleagues put the dinosaur's teeth to the test. They found the bones of a triceratops that had been killed by a tyrannosaur 70 million years ago and made impressions of the tooth marks.</p>
<p>&quot;We took dental putty and pushed it into some of puncture marks and when it came out it was identical to a Tyrannosaurus rex tooth,&quot; Erickson said in a telephone interview. They were serrated like the giant carnivore's were and curved backwards.</p>
<p>&quot;But the bones were spongy and wasn't clear whether it took a strong bite to do this.&quot;</p>
<p>Erickson, an expert in comparative anatomy, found that a cow's pelvis was very similar in strength and structure to a triceratops'.</p>
<p>So he hooked one up into a mechanical loading frame, which measures stresses, made a model of the tyrannosaurus's teeth and pushed them into the bone to the same depth as the indentations found in the actual triceratops.</p>
<p>&quot;When we punched the tooth into the cow bones, the bite marks were very similar to those we found on the triceratops pelvis,&quot; Erickson said.</p>
<p>The loader measured the stress required to do this. Erickson's group reported in the science journal Nature that the bite was very strong indeed.</p>
<p>&quot;It's more force than you see in any animal tested to date, which includes lions and sharks,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The closest bite, Erickson said, was seen in very large alligators when they are snapping at prey.</p>
<p>But Erickson said the findings still do not prove that the giant meat-eater was a bold hunter as opposed to a craven scavenger.</p>
<p>&quot;I think what we need to do is find bite marks like when big cats like cougars attack prey. If you were to find bite marks on dinosaurs from Tyrannosaurus rex from some sort of a killing bite like this, then you could say it was a predator.&quot;</p>
<p>Erickson said his work was important to find out how dinosaurs really behaved.</p>
<p>&quot;Palaeontologists early on were just digging up a dinosaur and saying what it looked like,&quot; he said. &quot;With our equipment, you can really get some neat data. Palaeontology is becoming more of a hi-tech science.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
