<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5772" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Receptors may offer key to Alzheimer's drug.</title>
<headline>Receptors may offer key to Alzheimer's drug.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two studies published on Wednesday offered hope for a drug that could be used to treat Alzheimer's disease, the most common form of dementia whose sufferers include former U.S. President Ronald Reagan.</p>
<p>Both studies suggested ways to close off reactions between brain cells and chemicals or proteins. Many drugs block receptors that allow chemicals or cells to attach to other cells, just as a door could be nailed shut.</p>
<p>In Alzheimer's, which affects 15 percent of people over the age of 65 and about half those over 85, proteins gum up and form &quot;plaques&quot; in the brain. The main component of this plaque is amyloid-beta peptide, which is known to be toxic to nerve cells and activates immune cells in the brain.</p>
<p>To have an effect on cells, the peptide would first have to attach. Shi Du Yan of Columbia University in New York and a team of international collaborators looked for the receptor, a kind of door into the cell, where this might happen.</p>
<p>They found that a known receptor,the receptor for advanced glycation end products (RAGE), was the door letting the peptide hook up to brain cells.</p>
<p>When the peptide interacted with a RAGE, immune system scavenger cells known as microglia were activated -- indicating that brain cells were stressed, they wrote in a report published in the science journal Nature.</p>
<p>Microglia are meant to clean up dead or damaged brain cells, and other studies show they may be involved in the brain damage seen in Alzheimer's.</p>
<p>Yan's group said the receptor may help keep the brain clear of the damaging peptides, but may become overwhelmed by the huge amounts produced during Alzheimer's.</p>
<p>In a second study published in Nature, Joseph el Khoury and colleagues, also at Columbia University, found a second interaction involved in Alzheimer's.</p>
<p>They found the microglia attach to the peptides via a receptor known as class-A scavenging receptor. They suggest the microglia are trying to clear out the peptide, but get mired down in the plaque.</p>
<p>The distressed microglia secrete poisonous chemicals, damaging cells around them.</p>
<p>Khoury's group said chemicals that would block this interaction could help delay the onset of Alzheimer's or cause it to progress more slowly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
