<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5777" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Ulster Society opposes raising of Titanic's hull.</title>
<headline>Ulster Society opposes raising of Titanic's hull.</headline>
<byline>Jane O'Sullivan</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Plans to raise part of the Titanic from the ocean floor 80 years after it sank are under attack from a society in Belfast, the doomed liner's birthplace.</p>
<p>The Ulster Titanic Society (UTS) said on Wednesday it was opposed to plans to raise a section of the hull, weighing 10 metric tonnes, from its grave in the North Atlantic because the site was sacred.</p>
<p>The Belfast-built Titanic, thought to be unsinkable, left Southampton, England for New York on its maiden voyage on April 15, 1912 packed with passengers.</p>
<p>But it collided with an iceberg and sank off the coast of Newfoundland with the loss of 1,522 lives.</p>
<p>The RMS Titanic Inc, a New York-based company with exclusive salvage rights to the wreck, hopes to raise a section of the hull in an operation planned for next week.</p>
<p>The company has already gathered some 4,000 artefacts from the doomed liner in three previous salvage efforts and says the hull would be an Important find for future exhibitions for the general public.</p>
<p>But the UTS said the wreck site was a grave site and should be left in peace.</p>
<p>&quot;The recovery of the artifacts has added nothing to the story of the Titanic, only to the coffers of RMS Titanic Inc. Anything to do with Titanic makes money and this latest venture is, I feel, unseemly and distasteful,&quot; UTS chairman Una Reilly said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The wreck has lain in peace and solitude for nearly 80 years, a fitting resting place for those who went down with her,&quot; Reilly added.</p>
<p>She told Reuters that the site, should be protected and regarded as an international grave site.</p>
<p>&quot;It was after all the final resting place of peoples of many different countries -- a true site of an international grave,&quot; Reilly said.</p>
<p>The 150-member UTS was set up in 1992 to commemorate the Titanic, built in Belfast's Harland &amp; Wolff shipyard. Among those who perished on the ship were several Northern Irish engineers.</p>
<p>Two cruise ships with some 1,500 people on board will witness the raising of the hull. It will also be seen by three of the handful of remaining survivors of the disaster.</p>
<p>A new Hollywood production about the sinking of the Titanic is currently underway and the luxury liner, regarded as the most magnificent ship of its time, has been the subject of countless other films and documentaries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
