<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5778" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain's Rifkind to raise ex-POWs' case in Tokyo.</title>
<headline>Britain's Rifkind to raise ex-POWs' case in Tokyo.</headline>
<byline>Alan Wheatley</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind will reopen the sensitive issue of compensation for British survivors of Japanese World War Two labour camps when he visits Tokyo early next month, officials said.</p>
<p>A group representing prisoners of war and civilian internees are pursuing legal action in Tokyo demanding compensation from the government for their ordeal and lobbied Rifkind last month to press their long-running case.</p>
<p>Although Britain believes the question of compensation was legally settled by the San Francisco peace treaty of 1951, Rifkind was left in no doubt that passions are still running high among prison camp survivors.</p>
<p>&quot;It's in those sorts of terms that he'll mention the issue,&quot; a British official told reporters.</p>
<p>More than 12,000 Britons died from disease and starvation in Japanese war camps or in work gangs.</p>
<p>Former Japanese Prime Minister Tomiichi Murayama apologised last August for his country's actions during the war, but British veterans had been hoping for an unequivocal apology on behalf of the entire nation to mark the 50th anniversary of World War Two.</p>
<p>&quot;I see no reason why our government can't back us on human rights grounds,&quot; said Arthur Titherington, secretary of the 12,500-strong Japanese Labour Camp Survivors' Association. &quot;Our claim is not based on legal matters or politics.&quot;</p>
<p>Rifkind will visit Tokyo from September 1 to 3 as part of an Asian tour during which he will tiptoe through several other diplomatic minefields. Chief among these is a long-running territorial dispute between Pakistan and India over Kashmir.</p>
<p>In Islamabad and Karachi from August 27 to 28, followed by a visit to Delhi from August 28 to 30, Rifkind will stake out a carefully balanced position on Kashmir that emphasises the need for political dialogue, observance of human rights and an end to outside interference, British officials said.</p>
<p>A further contentious issue in Delhi will be India's veto of a global treaty banning nuclear tests.</p>
<p>India says the proposed Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty would allow the five declared nuclear powers -- Britain, China, France, Russia and the United States -- to retain their nuclear arsenals while the nuclear &quot;have-nots&quot; would be barred from obtaining such weapons.</p>
<p>Britain strongly backs the pact and Rifkind would not be willing to dangle a carrot -- such as an agreement to share nuclear test data -- to get Delhi to drop its reservations.</p>
<p>&quot;We think the case makes itself without any incentives,&quot; a British official said.</p>
<p>Rifkind will also use his trip to try to cast new light on the plight of four western hostages, including two Britons, who have been held by Kashmiri rebels for more than a year.</p>
<p>Other stops on Rifkind's tour are war-torn Sri Lanka on August 30 to 31 and Mongolia -- the first by a British Foreign Secretary -- from September 3 to 4.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
