<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5779" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reuters historical calendar - August 28.</title>
<headline>Reuters historical calendar - August 28.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the major events to have occurred on August 28 in history.</p>
<p>1619 - Ferdinand II elected Holy Roman Emperor. He instigated the Thirty Years War and tried to outlaw Protestantism by his policy of &quot;One church, one king&quot;.</p>
<p>1735 - Count Andreas Peter von Bernstorff, Danish politician and diplomat, born. He took a leading part in Danish domestic reform and also maintained the country's neutrality.</p>
<p>1749 - Johann Wolfgang von Goethe. German poet, dramatist, novelist and scientist, born.</p>
<p>1774 - Elizabeth Ann Seton born. An American educator and religious leader who founded the Sisters of St Joseph, she was canonised in 1975 as the first U.S.-born saint.</p>
<p>1850 - Richard Wagner's &quot;Lohengrin&quot; was premiered at Weimar, Germany, under the direction of Franz Liszt.</p>
<p>1879 - Cetewayo (or Cetshwayo), last of the great Zulu kings, was captured by the British at the end of the Zulu wars.</p>
<p>1910 - Montenegro proclaimed its independence from the Ottoman empire, with Nicholas I as ruler.</p>
<p>1914 - The first big naval encounter of World War One took place between British and German ships off the North Sea island of Heligoland. The Germans lost three ships and 1,000 sailors; British casualties were 33 killed.</p>
<p>1922 - The first ever radio advertisement, a 10-minute property commercial by Queensboro Corp, was broadcast by station WEAF in New York.</p>
<p>1930 - Ben Gazzara, U.S. film and T.V. actor, born. On stage he appeared in &quot;Cat on a Hot Tin Roof&quot; and among his films was &quot;Anatomy of a Murder&quot;.</p>
<p>1945 - U.S. forces landed in Japan led by General George Marshall, supreme commander of the Allied occupation.</p>
<p>1963 - Dr Martin Luther King delivered his &quot;I have a dream&quot; speech to 200,000 civil rights demonstrators who had marched on Washington, .</p>
<p>1971 - 25 people died and 1,150 were rescued when fire broke out aboard the Greek liner Haleanna.</p>
<p>1973 - Princess Anne became the first member of the British royal family to visit the Soviet Union when she arrived in Kiev for an equestrian event.</p>
<p>1981 - In Kenya, Paul Nakwale was found guilty of murdering &quot;Born Free&quot; author Joy Adamson in January 1980.</p>
<p>1983 - Menachim Begin announced his resignation as Prime Minister of Israel.</p>
<p>1988 - 33 people were killed when jets from an Italian Air Force display team collided in mid-air and one crashed into the crowd during an air show at Ramstein, West Germany.</p>
<p>1990 - Iraq declared occupied Kuwait the 19th province of Iraq, renamed Kuwait City Kadhima and created a new district named after President Saddam Hussein.</p>
<p>1994 - Father Jean-Marie Vincent, a prominent Haitian Catholic priest loyal to deposed President Jean-Bertrand Aristide, was shot dead by suspected paramilitary gunmen.</p>
<p>1995 - At least 37 people were killed and 85 injured by a shelling attack on a busy street in Sarajevo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
