<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5783" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products - gas oil and fuel firming.</title>
<headline>Med oil products - gas oil and fuel firming.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Med oil products were mixed on Wednesday, traders said.</p>
<p>Gasoline was weaker as NYMEX futures eased. Interest was seen for Turkey and other destinations in the Black Sea.</p>
<p>Naphtha was softer as crude futures slipped. A Spanish refiner sold a heavy Algeciras cargo to an undisclosed party in the Med on Tuesday, at a p+c price.</p>
<p>Material remains scarce, with maintenance at the Skikda refinery sapping supply, but demand is limited too.</p>
<p>Gas oil was steady to slightly stronger although buyers and sellers appeared to be distanced.  </p>
<p>There was talk of at least four Russian cargoes hitting the Med before the end of August. Bids were put at quotes cif hi +50 cents, basis Genoa and offers at quotes cif hi +$2.0.</p>
<p>Traders said a Turkish tender for two plus one optional 25,000 tonne cargoes would mop up some of the material.</p>
<p>A Libyan cargo of low sulphur material was also due to load Sept 8-10. Traders said it was being offered at quotes cif high +$4.50 fob Ras Lanuf.</p>
<p>High sulphur cracked fuel oil was seen to be getting tight in the Med supporting a move for higher prices.  </p>
<p>Tender news dominated on Wednesday with Cepsa winning the Portugese tender for 30,000 tonnes loading end August and Tunisia withdrawing its 100,000 tonne buying tender.</p>
<p>Egypt's EGPC announced a tender that closes on September 2 to sell up to 11 cargoes of high sulphur cracked fuel. The tender will be announced on September 5.</p>
<p>A major was heard offering a 30kt straight run Tuapse cargo at high cif Med +$7. Some traders thought the price about $3 off the market.</p>
<p>A high sulphur cracked bunker spec cargo was sold at high cif Med plus below $1.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
