<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5786" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Mideast crude tanker market booms, but not rates.</title>
<headline>Mideast crude tanker market booms, but not rates.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Booming crude tanker chartering in the key Middle East Gulf was welcomed by owners even if the rise in activity did not herald a rise in rates.</p>
<p>VLCCs and one ULLC found employment both eastwards and westwards. KPC was seen taking a ULCC to the USG, six VLCCs were fixed to the Far East,and Fina fixed 275,000 tonnes into UKC.</p>
<p>VLCC rates Singapore and South Korea remained steady around W65 with VLCC trips to Japan assesssed between W65-73. Tankers bound for the U.S and Europe held firm at W60.</p>
<p>In the inter-UKC sector, rates continued their slight increase from the previous day with 80,000 tonners taking W105.  </p>
<p>An 80,000 tonne cargo fixed by Petroleum Limited travelling cross UKC on the Natura was placed at W105, brokers confirmed.</p>
<p>There was a single transatlantic trip seen, in which Sun fixed a 90,000 tonner on the Astro Sirius from Sullom Voe to Puerto Rico.</p>
<p>Rates across the Atlantic were placed around the W66 mark.</p>
<p>Fixing in the Mediterranean was again extremely poor, with a meagre three charters made this week. Brokers were unsure why the market was so quiet. Some said the region was in low gear following some public holidays last week.  </p>
<p>The Caribbean market saw rates settle around last done levels, shipping brokers said. Brokers said 70,000 tonners travelling up the US coast were steady around of W130-135.</p>
<p>--Mike Blouki,London Newsroom +44 171 542 7630</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
