<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5790" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Ex-UK air cargo stable, market hesistates over rate rises.</title>
<headline>Ex-UK air cargo stable, market hesistates over rate rises.</headline>
<byline>Helen Hill</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ex-UK cargo levels are remaining stable in all markets, with rates remaining firm to most destinations and industry sources are expecting a busy September, a Reuter survey shows.</p>
<p>But despite the improving market conditions, most carriers are very reticent about increase in rates in this autumn. Only a few have made murmurs about possible increases.</p>
<p>For many UK cargo players August was not a typical month in that it did not show such a dramatic slow-down as would usually be expected during the summer holiday season.</p>
<p>This was especially the case with those involved in the UK-Asia/Pacific market.</p>
<p>Barry Gibson of Singapore Airlines, said: &quot;We are moving towards the busier time of the year, we were expecting August to be quieter but there are no signs that it is running out of steam.&quot;</p>
<p>He, like others, is not sure of the reasons why the market has not seen its usual holiday slump.</p>
<p>Gibson added: &quot;British goods continue to be good value for money and people in the Pacific Rim are continuing to buy British products.&quot;</p>
<p>Rates to Asia are definitely firm and in some markets edging upwards slightly. Ex-London to Hong Kong is 1.20 stg a kg for a 100 kg shipment against 1.19 previously and Tokyo Narita is up slightly to 1.92 a kg. The Korean rate too has crept up to 1.80 but Singapore and Sydney have remained healthy but stable, at 1.23 stg and 2.05 a kg respectively.</p>
<p>Thai Airways cargo manager, Mike Miller, said that the market is remaining steady. He too, said the market has shown no signs of decline over the summer months, with flights remaining full out of the UK.</p>
<p>Both said rates are remaining firm and stable.</p>
<p>All Nippon Airways cargo manager, John O'Shea, said the Japanese market had benefitted from some freighter cancellations.</p>
<p>He described the market as &quot;rosy' adding that for once, the market was not suffering from any rates pressure. &quot;There are no problems maintaining the rates,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Europe-Japanese market had benefitted from the flower bulb season from the Netherlands with some of the bulbs also going from the UK to Japan, he said. Flower bulbs begin to be exported to Japan in early August.</p>
<p>ANA operates nine flights a week to Japan to Tokyo and Osaka.</p>
<p>The picture was also healthy on cargo levels ex-UK to Korea, said Korean Airlines cargo manager, Frank Smith. &quot;Up until now cargo levels had been very good but currently factory closures in the Midlands were causing a slight slow-down,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Smith was very optimistic about September adding that a few massive shipments were in hand, one of which involves shipping a mock-up aircraft fueslage to Korea for an air show.</p>
<p>He admitted that Korean Airlines is &quot;thinking about' rates rises if the volumes continue at present levels but the airline would not decide until autumn, he stressed.</p>
<p>Transatlantic traffic remains flat with a fair amount of spot-rating going on. One source said British Airway's inward &quot;summer sale' was continuing, which involves prices of U.S. 90 cents per 100 kg from the southern U.S. states to the anywhere in the UK.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps this would be fairer if two tonne shipments were involved but at 100 kg it is hard to compete with this,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>U.S. rates are generally sluggish. One insider said that on rates that stand in the early 0.60s can be lowered to 0.40 fairly easily.</p>
<p>American Airlines has announced that it will be increasing rates by five percent in the autumn.</p>
<p>Currently, it is not certain whether other carriers will follow. But so far, industry sources suggest that Northwest and Continental will both maintain present rates until the end of the year.</p>
<p>Continental Airlines cargo manager, Brian Coleman, said there is a lot of capacity across the Atlantic because of all the passenger flights and prices were generally holding steady but low.</p>
<p>In mid-September Continental will be replacing its daily Boeing 757 Manchester-Newark service with DC-10 aircraft, he added.</p>
<p>A source from another US carrier said the market was not particularly busy because of the holiday season. However, he added that rates are reasonably stable, though they are still slightly soft.</p>
<p>Any possible rates rises will be reviewed in September but at the moment the same level looks like it will be retained until the end of the year, he added.</p>
<p>Kevin Durnin of Viking Freight, cargo representative for Leisure Airways, said the Olympics has had a dramatic impact on cargo levels in July as Atlanta is the company's major gateway.</p>
<p>&quot;Atlanta was virtually gridlocked so most customers had been diverting traffic to other airports,&quot; he said. But August was picking up and more or less back on track, he said.</p>
<p>Rates, however, were still very soft, he added.</p>
<p>Business to the Middle East is fairly quiet as those in the Middle East try to escape the soaring summer temperatures and the Europeans take their holidays.</p>
<p>Rates are remaining stable, with rates to Dubai standing at 0.70 stg a kg for a 100 kg shipment.</p>
<p>As yet, none of the carriers has said on record that rates will be increased in this market but Taiwanese carrier has stated it will be increasing rates and it flies via Dubai.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Emirates Airline, based in Dubai, said the carrier trys to stick to only two rates reviews a year and wants to encourage stability in the market.</p>
<p>Latin America is proving a better market, rates are remaining firm and cargo levels healthy. Rates to Sao Paulo range between 2.00 to 2.05, said several sources and these tend to be towards the higher end at the moment.</p>
<p>Durnin said Lima is particularly good but generally Latin America is doing well.</p>
<p>Len Bunn, managing director of Air Marketing Associates, which is a general sales agent for 14 airlines, said: &quot; Latin American trade is very much growing, throughout the whole region.&quot;</p>
<p>AMA represents Challenge Air Cargo which operates 52 flights a week from Miami into Latin America. The company feeds UK traffic in via Orlando.</p>
<p>Because of the growth in traffic AMA opened its own office in Miami on August 1. The office is designed to be a communication centre for other forwarders and carriers who wish to trace their cargo through Miami airport.</p>
<p>Some sources said feedback from players in the market suggests that the industry has had enough of opportunistic carriers coming into the market.</p>
<p>Carriers enter the market, dump the rates and leave after having destroyed the market's stability, one source said. Government assistance is being sort on this matter, he added.</p>
<p>Chris Buckerfield, UK manager of leading freight forwarder, Air Express International, said the company was finding that there are significant developments in the Latin American market with a lot of activity throughout the region.</p>
<p>He commented that Africa is also seeing a pick up in activity as there is an increase in mining explorations and related equipment is needed.</p>
<p>Bunn, said Southern Africa generally is very buoyant. AMA also represents Air Namibia and he said there had been a strong increase in general cargo levels.</p>
<p>Commenting on the Eastern European region, Bunn said even though traffic is growing significantly, the market is still a difficult one.</p>
<p>AMA represents Aeroflot, CSA, Balkan Bulgarian, LOT and Transaero in this market.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a lot of red tape, companies have to be very innovative to do anything there. Therefore we do not just offer airport to airport, instead we offer services to the door. We hub from our offices in Moscow and St Petersburg.&quot; --Air Cargo Newsroom Tel +44 171 542 8982 Fax +44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
