<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5792" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dated Brent steadies, other North Sea crudes slide.</title>
<headline>Dated Brent steadies, other North Sea crudes slide.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea benchmark Dated Brent crude steadied after an early slide on Wednesday but other regional grades lost more ground amid lacklustre refinery demand, trading sources said.</p>
<p>A Sept 5-7 Brent cargo due to turn wet on Wednesday was kept by BP who then sold it for Sept Brent plus two cents after a Sept 4-6 fetched parity in early trade.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a temporary imbalance which meant something had to give. Brent came down but it looks like it might be fairly shortlived,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Oct Brent slid 20 cents to $20.27 a barrel by 1730 GMT.  </p>
<p>Intermonth paper spreads also clawed back some of their early losses with Sep/Oct pegged at +47/+51 cents and Oct/Nov at +42/+45 cents.</p>
<p>A handful of European refineries cut crude throughputs in response to poor margins, exerting pressure on other spot North Sea grades.</p>
<p>September cargoes of Forties, Ekofisk, Statfjord and Oseberg traded on Wednesday, with premiums for some of the grades giving up 10-15 cents a barrel.</p>
<p>Mediterranean markets were slow with refiners holding back and contemplating cutting runs, traders said.  </p>
<p>Sellers were relaxed with no very prompt cargoes and expecting good buying soon as refiners build stocks up again. Scheduled maintenance on the main pipeline feeding Russia's Novorossisk oil terminal will delay loadings by two days late this week once current stocks are used, shipping sources said.</p>
<p>The crude oil pipeline closed early on Tuesday and is due to reopen on Friday. With most buyers covered, Urals was assessed softer at Dated Brent -90/-85 cents. Two cargoes - one large and one small were available by the end of August.</p>
<p>Syria came down to Dated -40 cents from -30 cents for Sept Light but lifters were still holding out for a bigger cut.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
