<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5799" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: EU grains continue to reel under harvest pressure.</title>
<headline>EU grains continue to reel under harvest pressure.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Newly harvested material continued to weigh on European grains but prices recovered from lows in France and Britain where rain slowed field activity.</p>
<p>French wheat slid on weekend harvests in the north where good weather and high yield forecasts countered the damage done by drought further south. In Britain, good southern yields knocked some five stg off the price of delivered feed wheat.</p>
<p>German wheat was poised for further falls but buyers and sellers drifted apart. Spanish prices were broadly unchanged and the Italian market remained virtually shut for August holidays.</p>
<p>French wheat bottomed out at some 885 francs per tonne for August delivery at Rouen as mid-week thunderstorms stopped the harvest just short of completion, traders said.</p>
<p>August delivery Rouen was worth 894.77 francs including carrying charges. With fob costs also included, that equates to $182 per tonne fob or nearly five dollars over fob soft red winter, traders said.</p>
<p>Northern farmers confidently predicted a record wheat yield above 10 tonnes per hectare. While some officials did not rule out a double-digit yield for the region, most remained cautious until the last cuts had arrived.</p>
<p>Private analyst Strategie Grains increased French and European Union (EU) wheat forecasts, helping to depress prices. But firmer British cash prices were lending support by Tuesday.</p>
<p>The German harvest was making progress across the country with the exception of the north where some crops had not finished ripening and would take another eight to 10 days.</p>
<p>But buyers and sellers failed to agree on prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Buyers point to good harvests elsewhere in Europe and to early indications of good German yields and protein contents. Seln demand and won't lower their quality wheat prices,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The Hamburg grain exchange maintained its new crop bread wheat price (12.5 percent, 220 hagberg) at 282.50 marks.</p>
<p>This is 7.50 marks down from the start of the month.</p>
<p>Brokers said ex-farm bread wheat prices across the country of around 270-290 marks should be poisedge, having shed five marks so far in August.</p>
<p>British feed wheat delivered East Anglia slipped to 104 stg a tonne at the beginning of the week as harvest returned to full swing after last week's break. On Wednesday, sellers were asking 106 stg but there was no trade.</p>
<p>Traders said a stop-go harvest this year slowed by rain was supporting prices. &quot;The market is pretty much in equilibrium now,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Barley prices also dropped on completion of the new crop while compounders had yet to make purchase decisions.</p>
<p>French barley was moderately firm at 830 francs per tonne but largely ignored news of a new 800,000-tonne Saudi barley tender, with German intervention grain the main contender.</p>
<p>Maize prices were flat with few new crop indications, but plants reported in generally good condition in the southwest.</p>
<p>In Spain rain delayed maize harvesting in the south, but quality was reported to be generally good so far.</p>
<p>Otherwise trading was extremely quiet with the market in the depths of the holiday season.</p>
<p>Below are some of the key European grain prices pnch prices exclude carrying charges.</p>
<p>						Aug 21		 Aug 14</p>
<p>French wheat dlvd Rouen August	885 Ffr ($175)     900</p>
<p>French wheat dlvd Rouen Sept	  880 Ffr ($174)     895</p>
<p>French maize dlvd Bordeaux Oct	925 Ffr ($183)     925</p>
<p>German Hamburg exch bread wheat     282.50 Dm ($191)   282.50</p>
<p>spot UK feed wheat E.Anglia August	 106 stg ($164)     109.50</p>
<p>UK feed wheat E.Anglia Oct-Dec	113.50 ($176)	114.50</p>
<p>UK barley E.Anglia spot		  98 ($152)	   101</p>
<p>Spain milling wheat harvest	24,000 ($191)	24,000</p>
<p>Spain durum wheat harvest	  25,500 ($203)	25,750</p>
<p>Spain barley harvest		 21,000 ($167)	20,500</p>
<p>Spain maize Sept-Oct delivery    25,500 ($203)	25,750</p>
<p>-- compiled by Clelia Oziel, London Newsroom (44-171-542-8072) with contributions from Paris, Hamburg and Madrid.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
