<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5803" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: China copper stocks key to price - industry analyst.</title>
<headline>China copper stocks key to price - industry analyst.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>An estimated 85,000 tonnes of copper in Shanghai warehouses are key to the near-term direction of prices, industry specialists Bloomsbury Minerals Economics (BME) said.</p>
<p>The stocks, said to have been moved to China from London Metal Exchange (LME) warehouses over the past two months, were even more important since a global market surplus was smaller than expected, BME added in its latest review.</p>
<p>&quot;With the market surplus so tiny, the motivation of the owners of the 85,000 tonnes, whoever they are, is the most important short-term fundamental,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Much is still unknown about the Chinese supplies and their owners, but current prices took into account the range of possibilities, which included the stocks being returned to China's strategic stockpile, and being sold on to the market.</p>
<p>BME said it was rumoured that the stocks either belonged to the China National Nonferrous Metals Import and Export Corporation (CNIEC) or to Sumitomo Corp.</p>
<p>If the supplies were released on to the global market, prices would Follow the forecasts of &quot;extreme bears&quot; who say cash prices will fall from late August or September to give a first-half 1997 average of $1,750 per tonne and a second-half average of $1,650 per tonne.</p>
<p>If the Chinese stocks were not released, prices would follow a moderately bearish scenario and average $1,875 to $1,925 per tonne next year, according to BME.</p>
<p>Cash prices ended Wednesday afternoon at $1,955 per tonne.</p>
<p>Since the motivation of the owners of the Chinese stocks &quot;is a complete mystery to BME, we have opted for a view between the moderate and the extreme bears,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Players who were bullish were being mislead by LME stocks, regarded as an indicator of fundamentals.</p>
<p>&quot;Seasonally adjusted LME stock changes were a good guide to fundamentals for just one very brief period of history, from 1987 to 1992,&quot; BME said.</p>
<p>&quot;Since 1993, huge variations in stocks in Chinese bonded warehouses mean that seasonally adjusted Western stock variation again provides little or no guidance on fundamentals,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>BME sees cash prices averaging $2,028 in the third quarter of this year and $1,963 in the fourth.</p>
<p>They would steadily ease in 1997 from $1,930 in the first quarter to $1,710 in the fourth.</p>
<p>-- Eric Onstad, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8065</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
