<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5804" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Mixed outlook for London freight market.</title>
<headline>Mixed outlook for London freight market.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brokers were divided about the outlook for the London freight market for the next few weeks.</p>
<p>Despite reports of increased rates for Capers and Panamaxes in the Atlantic and another rise in the Baltic Freight Index, many brokers were not convinced that the market would maintain its upward trend.</p>
<p>But others said the healthy volume of Panamax period activity augured well.</p>
<p>The BFI rose four points to 1,113 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Fixture rates in key routes such as the U.S. Gulf/Japan for grain and Hampton Roads/Rotterdam for coal have seen some improvement but Far East rates remained flat, they said.</p>
<p>Alfios 63,400 dwt was reported fixed by Guinomar for two years delivery South Korea September-October at $8,400 daily with charterer's option of a third year at an undisclosed rate.</p>
<p>A number of charterers, including Cargill, were said to be seeking Panamaxes for various periods.</p>
<p>GRAIN - Mitsubishi was said to have fixed 52,000 tonnes heavy grain U.S. Gulf/Japan with Ocean Ruby for September 9-17 at $21.00 no combo, 50 cents up on a Navios deal at the end of last week for comparable dates.</p>
<p>But Dreyfus's fixture of Astraguillermo in the same trade at 50 cents less illustrated the relatively weak early September position in the U.S. Gulf, brokers said.</p>
<p>Angelic Spirit 65,767 dwt, waiting unfixed in the U.S. Gulf for a week, was finally booked by Pan Ocean delivery U.S. Gulf September 2-5 for a trip to South Korea at $11,000 daily plus $150,000 bonus, they said.</p>
<p>Cargill was reported to have covered Morning Cloud for 51,000 tonnes grains in early September Plate and Brazil/Continent at a lumpsum equivalent of $15.50 basis 2-1.</p>
<p>Grain timecharters included Oakby 64,197 dwt fixed on subjects to Halla delivery U.S. Gulf September 5-10 for a trip Far East at a steady $11,500 daily plus $150,000 bonus, while K Line were said to have covered a similar position with unnamed tonnage after failing on subjects with Antonis I Angelicoussis 69,346 dwt at $11,900 daily plus $200,000 bonus.</p>
<p>Iranian interests continued to negotiate tonnage privately for grain from Canada to Iran, and Egyptian charterers have been linked with another Panamax grain fixture from Nopac to Egypt, brokers said.</p>
<p>Handy-size business was virtually at a standstill, but Grandi Molini were linked with Mersini for 30,000 tonnes wheat prompt Rouen/Adriatic at only $11.50, they added.</p>
<p>COAL/ORE/FERTS ETC - There were gains for owners in the Atlantic minerals trades, brokers reported.</p>
<p>China Steel covered 110,000 tonnes iron ore from Tubarao to Kaohsiung for October 5-15 at $9.20, compared to last fixed at $8.75, they said.</p>
<p>Kleimar was said to have fixed Pawnee for 120,000 tonnes coal Hampton roads/Rotterdam for September 5-20 at $5.62-1/2.</p>
<p>In the East, British Steel was said to have taken one of U Ming's CSBC types with coal from Port Kembla to Port Talbot at close to $9,000 daily, BHP was reported to have booked Cape Australia for 140,000/10 tonnes coal Hay Point/Rotterdam and Hansaport at about $50, and Francois L D 145,229 dwt was said fixed for a Pacific round on private terms.</p>
<p>Galini 73,670 dwt was reported fixed for coal to the Continent basis delivery Cigading at about $5,000 daily, and Yukong was said to have taken a Panamax for coal or grain from Nopac to Bin Qasim on private terms.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom, +44 171 542 8071</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
