<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5809" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS- Handful of European refiners cut crude runs.</title>
<headline>FOCUS- Handful of European refiners cut crude runs.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A smattering of European refiners on Wednesday decided to crude runs to combat weak profit margins but most said they will maintain operations as normal.</p>
<p>Margins improved sharply on Tuesday after sliding on Friday to 18-month lows, but the recovery was not sufficient to stop some refiners in France, Italy, Sweden and Britain from trimming runs. Others were considering similar cuts.</p>
<p>Italy's Isab reduced operations at its 220,000 barrels per day (bpd) Sicily refinery. An Isab company official said on Wednesday that crude runs had been cut by 20 percent to the minimum required to meet sales commitments.</p>
<p>France's Total SA reduced throughput by about 15 percent at two of its three French plants, one in the north and one in the Med, until the end of the month, trading sources said.</p>
<p>Britain's 190,000 bpd plant at Killingholme trimmed runs slightly, estimated at 10,000-15,000 bpd.</p>
<p>Weak margins forced Sweden's Corral Petroleum to reduce runs last week by 30-40 percent at its 95,000 bpd Gothenburg plant.</p>
<p>Spain's Repsol SA, operator of four plants processing a combined 520,000 bpd, said it would make a decision by Thursday. &quot;We are seriously thinking about it. We will decide very soon,&quot; said a Repsol official.</p>
<p>Shell U.K. said it was eyeing a cut at its 260,000 bpd Stanlow plant.</p>
<p>But other refiners have not followed suit because margins have improved quickly since Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>European benchmark crude Dated Brent by Wednesday afternoon had slumped by about $1.00 a barrel, down nearly six percent, from Monday's close. Oil products were only slightly weaker.</p>
<p>Most Italian refiners, traditionally among the most sensitive in Europe to negative margins, said operations were continuing as normal on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Italy's biggest refiner, Agip SpA, said improving margins had extinguished any possibility of it reducing crude runs.</p>
<p>&quot;We think margins (in the Mediterranean) have improved by about a dollar,&quot; said an Agip official.</p>
<p>Saras said it was suffering losses but would not reduce operations at its huge 360,000 bpd Sicily plant.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not making money but I don't think we are going to take such a decision. We have commitments,&quot;said a Saras official.</p>
<p>In northern Europe several refiners considered cutting runs at the beginning of the week before pulling back from the brink.</p>
<p>Export-oriented refineries typically cut runs before others which rely on domestic retail markets to cushion them from the impact of price volatility in the spot market.</p>
<p>Corral's other Swedish refinery, the 200,000 bpd plant at Brofjorden, was thought unlikely to reduce.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw negative margins of 70 cents (a barrel) on Tuesday but they have improved since then,&quot; said a source familiar with that refinery's operation.</p>
<p>Norwegian state oil company Statoil is also unlikely to trim runs. &quot;I don't see us cutting runs, definitely not in Mongstad,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Britain's Texaco Pembroke, BP Grangemouth and Elf Milford Haven refineries all said operations had not been dented.</p>
<p>&quot;No, we are not contemplating it this stage. Margins are always under pressure, I am afraid, but not so that we would cut runs now,&quot;said an Elf Milford Haven official.</p>
<p>And traders said Britain's biggest refinery, Esso Fawley, was at full capacity.</p>
<p>In Rotterdam the three largest refiners -- Exxon (180,000 bpd), Nerefco (420,000 bpd) and Shell (374,000 bpd) were operating at normal levels, industry sources said.</p>
<p>In Belgium the 85,000 bpd BRC refinery has been cutting back on crude by using other feedstocks instead. Petrofina said it was running as normal at its 268,000 bpd Antwerp plant.</p>
<p>BP was operating as normal across its European refining system, a company official said. --London newsroom, 44 171 542 4984</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
