<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5810" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Sugar freight business routine, Santos stays focus.</title>
<headline>Sugar freight business routine, Santos stays focus.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Brazil continued as the main focus of demand on the sugar freight market on Wednesday and shipbrokers said most quoted business was routine with little concern over port congestion.</p>
<p>Glencore quoted for 25,000 tonnes in bulk from Santos to the Black Sea for August/September and 5,000 tonnes of bagged sugar from the same origin to Tema and Lagos for early September.</p>
<p>South Africa Sugar Association (SASA) was open for 17,000 tonnes from Durban to Japan for early September.</p>
<p>Firmer business included Mauritius Sugar Syndicate (MSS), which was reported to have fixed 18/18,250 tonnes of bulk sugar on its normal Port Louis to London route for September 9 at around stg 16.00.</p>
<p>Shipbrokers said Fiji Sugar Marketing fixed 20,000 tonnes of bulk sugar from Fiji to London for September 10/20, with the rate achieved thought to be just under $30.00, under the rate for previous similar orders.</p>
<p>Genoc was on subjects with its order for 14,000 tonnes of bagged sugar from Santos or Paranagua to Aqaba, Jeddah or Aden for early September.</p>
<p>Seven Seas fixed 12,000 tonnes in bags from south China to Pakistan for prompt dates at around $25.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8064</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
