<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5811" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RBL commodity traders to join C.Lyonnais Rouse.</title>
<headline>RBL commodity traders to join C.Lyonnais Rouse.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Employees of the soft commodities house  RBL Ltd will transfer on October 1 to  Credit Lyonnais Rouse Ltd (CLR) -- the trading arm of the French banking group Credit Lyonnais, market sources said.</p>
<p>An official from RBL said, &quot;A collective group of people who...have worked for RBL since its creation have amicably agreed with the shareholders of RBL to transfer...almost in their entirety to the Credit Lyonnais agriculturals division.&quot;</p>
<p>It was not immediately known whether RBL, a subsidiary of the South African investment banking group  Cavmont would fold after the departure of its six key cocoa and coffee brokers.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to be up to the shareholders to decide,&quot; said another RBL trader.</p>
<p>But cocoa traders said it could be practically impossible for RBL to keep the business going, given that the move leaves virtually no other key players in the company.</p>
<p>Some traders linked the transfer to the approaching merger of the London Commodity Exchange (LCE) with the London International Financial Futures Exchange (LIFFE) on September 16.</p>
<p>&quot;It makes sense to be part of a financially wealthy house if you're going to be a player with LIFFE,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Other small brokerage houses could also seek links with more powerful companies to beef up their global presence after the merger of the two exchanges.</p>
<p>But other sources said Cavmont has enough financial clout to inject fresh capital to RBL and that the move had no implications other than a group of traders moving to CRL.</p>
<p>For Rouse, the arrival of RBL brokers would help to strengthen its agriculturals team as RBL is one of the biggest cocoa players in the LCE.</p>
<p>&quot;They have the ability to put large crosses together because they have the secrecy by just being a small firm,&quot; said one cocoa trader.</p>
<p>They said CRL was eyeing more aggressive trades in cocoa and coffee. The company currently has six brokers and floor traders in soft commodities.</p>
<p>-- Clelia Oziel, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8072</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
