<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5814" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GDR REPORT - India adds to gains on short covering.</title>
<headline>GDR REPORT - India adds to gains on short covering.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian global depositary receipts (GDRs) added to Tuesday's gains after Bombay closed higher, but traders said that activity remains low and dominated by covering short postions.</p>
<p>&quot;It is difficult to see this as anything other than a trading policy, I would not bet on the GDRs doing anything other than hang on the gains of the local market,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>The HSBC James Capel Indian GDR index  JCEAI closed up 2.87 points, 4.14 percent, at 72.25 points, with the premium over the local market expanding to 10.86 percent compared with yesterday's 9.32 percent.</p>
<p>The Bombay Stock Exchange 30-share index rose 90.16 points, or 2.72 percent, to 3,406.22.</p>
<p>Hotel stocks, which have performed badly in the decline of the Indian market, continued to rebound, with Indian Hotels up $1.85 to $25.90/$26.90 and East India Hotels up 87 cents to $20.70/$21.70.</p>
<p>&quot;These stocks always lead, going up or going down,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Steelmaker SAIL added 75 cents to $10.75/$11.75 and Larsen &amp; Toubro $1.25 to $14.75/$15.75.</p>
<p>&quot;It is difficult to see large amounts of new money being committed to this market with such a vast level of new issuance in the offing,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Indian overseas telephone monopoly VSNL is set to offer GDRs worth $600-$800 million and State Bank of India up to $400 million.</p>
<p>The Capel Korea GDR Index ended down 1.42 points, 1.70 percent, at 89.14 points, a premium of 17.65 percent over the local market, compared with yesterday's 19.36 percent.</p>
<p>The Korea Composite Index fell 4.79 points to close provisionally at 789.12.</p>
<p>The Capel Taiwan GDR Index ended up 1.49 points, 1.70 percent, at 89.14 points, a premium of 7.12 percent after 7.79 percent yesterday.</p>
<p>The Taiwan Weighted Index rose 120.34 points or 1.99 percent to finish at 6,177.78.</p>
<p>-- David Chance London newsroom 44 171 542 5887</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
