<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5819" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK five-year gilts lose expensive tag in repo mkt.</title>
<headline>UK five-year gilts lose expensive tag in repo mkt.</headline>
<byline>Michael Peacock</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The gilt repo market saw rates bob up and down on Wednesday after a shock fall in UK retail sales, and the 7.0 percent gilt due 2001 lost much of its special status, dealers said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the five-year gilt had traded below three percent for one week. One week general collateral rates had been trading around 5.70/5.60 percent at the time.</p>
<p>They edged up slightly on Wednesday but traders said the gilts due 2001 were now trading above five percent overnight in the repo market.</p>
<p>&quot;The 7.0s of 2001 have freed up quite dramatically,&quot; one repo trader said. &quot;From three percent yesterday, to over five today.&quot;</p>
<p>The trader said the market was expecting the Bank of England to issue a tap in the stock to alleviate the squeeze.</p>
<p>The Bank has committed itself to ironing out anomolies in the gilt repo market if stocks are squeezed by market participants.</p>
<p>Overnight GC pushed up to about 6.00/5.90 percent on Wednesday as overnight unsecured money market rates firmed.</p>
<p>&quot;Rates have firmed, the Bank didn't take out the whole shortage,&quot; the repo trader said.</p>
<p>The Bank of England estimated Wednesday's money market shortage at 850 million stg, later revising that down to 750 million stg.</p>
<p>But it only managed to take out 691 million stg of the shortage and that only with 340 million stg of late assistance at possibly punitive rates.</p>
<p>Overnight cash rates closed near their highs on Wednesday having dropped in the morning after a surprise fall in UK retail sales reawakened rate cut speculation.</p>
<p>Money market traders said rates dropped across the curve after retail sales were shown to have fallen 0.6 percent in July. Overnight rates slid as low as 5-1/2 percent, they said.</p>
<p>But towards the end of the session, the overnight rate had pushed back up to 6-1/4, 6-00 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;It came off massively after the figures but it's moved right back up now,&quot; one trader said. &quot;Rates have been all over the place today. Tomorrow next is moving up quite a bit too.&quot;</p>
<p>One week money market rates stood at 5-3/4, 5-11/16 percent on Wednesday afternoon, unchanged from Tuesday's close. One month rates were also unchanged at the same level.</p>
<p>Short sterling futures picked up after the sales figures were released at 0830 GMT. The December future reached 94.23, up six basis points on the day, before easing back to 94.20.</p>
<p>At those levels, the contract is still pricing in no change to 5.75 percent base rates before the year-end.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
