<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5822" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Sports News - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Sports News - Aug 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Adelaide Crows coach Robert Shaw has announced he will quit the club at the end of the season, citing personal reasons and poor results as a basis for his decision. Crows chief executive Bill Sanders said the club will start the search for a new coach thi week. Page 22</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Fitzroy captain Brad Boyd claims he feared for his safety after angry Fitzroy supporters invaded the ground after Saturday's match with Brisbane. A group of supporters abused the Lions players in the belief that they were not trying against their merger partners. Page 22</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Canberra Raiders centre Ruben Wiki is the latest of a myriad of casualties to plague the rugby league camp. Wiki tore ankle ligaments when he rolled over on it, after colliding with team-mates at training and as a result he will not play again this season. Page 22</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Shane Heal, Boomer and Sydney King, is off to the US National Basketball League. Though terms of guaranteed contract were not disclosed, sources in the US have revealed that Heal will be paid the base rookie salary of $US250,000 a season by the Minnesota Timberwolves. Page 50</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A Tamil separatist leader has given assurances to the world that cricketers, including the currently touring Australians, will not be a target of Tamil commando strikes. General secretary of the All Ceylon Tamil Congress G. G Ponnambalam reiterated yesteray that civilians will never be targets of political action. Page 50</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australia will play England twice every year until 2003, but the proposal to turn the end of season Wallaby tour of the Isles to incorporate England as a grand slam tour has been put on hold. England is now seeking to convert the Wallabies traditional end of playing season match against the Barbarians into a Test. Page 50</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Neil Balme will apply for the coaching position with the Melbourne Hawks should the merger with Hawthorn be realised. But the likelihood of Balme having to prepare for another job interview is slight following the news that the Brian Dixon-led anti-merger group will offer members a new board if they vote against the merger. Page B8</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Former Geelong and South Australian coach Mal Blight is expected to be named as coach of the 1997 Adelaide Crows AFL side following the resignation of present coach Robert Shaw. Sources have revealed that Blight has had meetings with the Crows and is set to become the highest paid coach in AFL. Page B8</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Some of Australia's greatest players, including former Socceroo captains, have expressed their outrage over Soccer Australia's intention to ban at least three clubs from the competition, on the grounds that they have refused to remove ethnic symbols from club motifs. Page B6.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>HERALD SUN</p>
<p>Outspoken horse racing trainer Pat Hyland fired up a cold mid-weeker yesterday, criticising the VATC's decision to run two-year-old trials before the races at Sandown on Saturday. The first two-year-old race traditionally is not until October. Page 84</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>New Zealand has proved it is a nation created to play the game of rugby - even when crippled, at the Paralympics yesterday. Australia lost the wheelchair rugby to a robust and determined Kiwi side, 39-23. Page 82</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The AFL will probably not play a lightning series next season with AFL football operations manager Ian Collins yesterday confirming that no decision has been made as yet, but the series is unlikely to be continued due to the financial cost as it lost A$30,000 this season. Page 85</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>Breakaway racing proponent TeleTrak yesterday announced it will buy a property in Tasmania's north-east to establish a race track for it's televised night racing venture. The sale hinges upon the State Government giving Teletrak approval to conduct its race meetings which are set for the Asian betting markets. Page 83</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Melbourne Cricket Ground looks set to become next year's host of the one-off Bledisloe Cup rugby Test between the Wallabies and the All Blacks. The MCG board met yesterday for six hours, hearing a presentation from Victorian Premier Jeff Kennett and Mlbourne Major Events chief Ron Walker on the benefits of bringing top-class rugby south. Page 82</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The traditional schoolboy clash of the titans - the Joeys/Riverview match, drew a 17,500 crowd over the weekend, in a fine celebration of running rugby, which thrilled the massed supporters. In a see-sawing match the &quot;rugby-nursery&quot; of St Josephs went down 36-21, but displayed fine spirit in defeat. Page 77</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
