<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5823" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RUGBY UNION-Mehrtens given every chance for test.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-Mehrtens given every chance for test.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>All Black rugby coach John Hart delayed the announcement of his second test team in Pretoria, South Africa, on Wednesday to allow key back Andrew Mehrtens more recovery time.</p>
<p>NZPA reported that the Springboks also postponed releasing their playing 15 from a squad of 23 until match day on Saturday as the psychological war started for Saturday's crucial second test in Pretoria.</p>
<p>It was clear from Hart's explanation however, that Mehrtens might not be ready mentally for the match following an operation on his injured knee last week, NZPA said.  </p>
<p>It is likely Simon Culhane will retain his No 10 spot in an unchanged team that emerged with a 23-19 first test victory in Durban last Saturday. The team will be announced in Pretoria on Thursday morning (8pm Thursday NZ time).</p>
<p>&quot;My personal view is that we don't need to take a risk,&quot; Hart said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got to be very confident that Andrew Mehrtens is 110 percent. This is an awfully big test match and I'm not going in with a player who is not 110 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;Andrew Mehrtens is a matchwinner, he's a class act. They're different players and if Andrew was right then obviously he'd play.</p>
<p>&quot;But there is a lot of judgment on what is right. It's not the knee being right. It's the fact that coming back from the operation he missed a bit of training, missed a bit of time with us -- the mental preparation is not quite as good as maybe others who have been thinking a lot more about playing.</p>
<p>&quot;Realistically, I don't think he saw himself playing this week.&quot;  </p>
<p>However, Mehrtens' swift recovery saw him participating fully in today's physical training session. He took kickoffs and showed no signs of restrictions of movement on the injured knee.</p>
<p>The Springboks' postponement was due to centre Japie Mulder's recurring back problem, manager Morne du Plessis said tonight.</p>
<p>Mulder missed last week's test but said he was recovering well.</p>
<p>&quot;His selection or non-selection will determine our reserves and we're giving him every chance to play,&quot; du Plessis said.  </p>
<p>Likely All Black test 15: Christian Cullen, Jeff Wilson, Frank Bunce, Glen Osborne, Walter Little, Simon Culhane, Justin Marshall, Zinzan Brooke, Josh Kronfeld, Ian Jones, Robin Brooke, Michael Jones, Olo Brown, Sean Fitzpatrick (captain), Craig Dowd.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
