<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5825" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Rugby Union-Lomu yet to hit top form.</title>
<headline>Rugby Union-Lomu yet to hit top form.</headline>
<text>
<p>POTCHEFSTROOM, South Africa, Aug 20 - Jonah Lomu may have to wait another week to convince the All Black selectors he's ready to play test rugby again after yet another frustrating midweek game, NZPA reported on Wednesday (NZT).</p>
<p>The big winger failed to produce the form that shot him to international glory or do enough to threaten Glen Osborne's place in the second test side to be announced on Wednesday or Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;He's still not 100 percent when tries to turn -- it's not quite there but he did some quite strong things today,&quot; All Black coach John Hart said after the midweek match.  </p>
<p>Osborne played the last two tests on tour here in place of Lomu, who had failed to impress the national selectors in last week's midweek match as well.</p>
<p>A recurring left knee injury had sidelined him, allowing Osborne the opportunity to play in the No 11 jersey.</p>
<p>Last year's test fullback Osborne has done well to hold on to the spot and is highly likely to play his third consecutive match against South Africa on Saturday at Pretoria.</p>
<p>A win for the All Blacks on Saturday will mean their first ever test series victory in South Africa following their 23-19 first test win last Saturday.  </p>
<p>The All Blacks will still have one midweek match, against Griqualand West at Kimberley next Tuesday, in which Lomu should have another chance to prove himself, before the third test the following Saturday.</p>
<p>Lomu's frustration was evident in the midweek game after an ordinary 60 minutes when he collected a kick and raced straight ahead for 30 metres to smash into the Western Transvaal defence.</p>
<p>He appeared to have strained his knee again as he emerged from the ensuing ruck, limping and holding his left leg.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, he tried hard in the last quarter, joining a maul and then looking for work closer to the set pieces.  </p>
<p>Two other players, hooker Norm Hewitt and flanker Andrew Blowers, had only niggles, the All Blacks' medical team said.</p>
<p>The midweek side beat Western Transvaal 31-0, their third win in as many matches on tour but their most convincing one to date.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
