<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5827" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RUGBY UNION-Mind games for second test turn nasty.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-Mind games for second test turn nasty.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Springboks team manager Morne du Plessis on Wednesday in Pretoria accused the touring All Black rugby team of using deliberate fouls to prevent the Springboks from scoring tries.</p>
<p>The New Zealand Press Association reported that du Plessis said the All Blacks used what he termed as professional fouls in all their three tests to date, all won by the All Blacks.</p>
<p>Du Plessis believed that, had southern hemisphere referees controlled the last two games, South Africa would have won five penalty tries for such infringements.  </p>
<p>As northern hemisphere referees were not used to the new laws, he said, they tended to treat the fouls more leniently.</p>
<p>Both teams delayed naming their test sides today as the psychological battle began for Saturday's Loftus Versfeld showdown.</p>
<p>While the All Blacks postponed releasing their test 15 until Thursday morning (8pm Thursday NZ time), the Springbok management said their team would be named on Saturday.  </p>
<p>Such delaying tactics and hurling barbs at each other have been common in psychological wars leading up to important internationals, but the mind games began to turn nasty with du Plessis' accusations.</p>
<p>&quot;We're very concerned that New Zealand have deliberately conceded penalties when we've got close to their line,&quot; du Plessis said. &quot;They've done it in all the three games we've played against them.&quot;</p>
<p>Northern hemisphere referees had a cautious approach to matches at present as they were still coming to terms with the new scrum and lineout laws, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Once they get used to the new laws like the southern hemisphere refs, they'll be awarding penalty tries for those professional fouls,&quot; du Plessis said.</p>
<p>All Black coach John Hart, referring to last Saturday's 23-19 win over the Springboks, said both teams got penalised several times for killing the ball or stopping the ball being played.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's part of the game -- it's not a professional foul. I don't think anyone goes out to create fouls, certainly this (All Black) team doesn't,&quot; Hart responded.  </p>
<p>&quot;I'm not really interested in Morne du Plessis' view about our game.&quot;</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
