<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5839" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Nigeria bars Saro-Wiwa lawyer from visiting Canada.</title>
<headline>Nigeria bars Saro-Wiwa lawyer from visiting Canada.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER, British Columbia 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria is barring the lawyer for executed human rights activist Ken Saro-Wiwa from speaking at an international legal conference in Canada, a conference organiser said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Olisa Agbakoba, who represented Saro-Wiwa and eight other Nigerian minority rights activists, planned to speak on Aug. 29 at the Commonwealth Law Conference in Vancouver. About 2,300 judges, lawyers and justice officials from Commonwealth countries were scheduled to attend the event.</p>
<p>But Nigeria was withholding Agbakoba's passport and preventing him from travelling, said Kathleen Keating, a Canadian lawyer who will co-chair next week's conference.</p>
<p>&quot;He is definitely being stopped from leaving the country to speak on human rights issues. It has happened to him before. ... I don't have any expectation that he is going to be able to come,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Keating said the executive director of Nigeria's Civil Liberties Organisation, Abdul Oroh, hoped to attend the Vancouver meeting in Agbakoba's place but it was unclear whether he would be allowed to leave Nigeria either.</p>
<p>Oroh told the Vancouver Sun newspaper from Lagos that the Nigerian government had denied Agbakoba's repeated requests for a passport to attend the conference.</p>
<p>Nigeria was suspended last year from the Commonwealth, which groups 56 nations with links to Britain, after the executions of Saro-Wiwa and the eight other activists. The executions triggered international condemnation of Nigeria, which has been in crisis since the army annulled a 1993 presidential vote meant to end military rule.</p>
<p>Officials at Canada's foreign affairs ministry and Nigeria's High Commission in Ottawa were not available for comment.</p>
<p>The main powers in the Commonwealth group are Britain, Canada, New Zealand and Australia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER, British Columbia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
