<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5845" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>South africa: De Klerk apologises for miseries of apartheid.</title>
<headline>De Klerk apologises for miseries of apartheid.</headline>
<byline>Anton Ferreira</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former South African president F.W. de Klerk formally apologised on Wednesday for the miseries of apartheid and said rogue security forces had committed atrocities, but that he had never issued an order to kill or torture.</p>
<p>&quot;I have already publicly apologised for the pain and suffering caused by former policies of the National Party...I reiterate these apologies today,&quot; de Klerk told Archbishop Desmond Tutu's Truth and Reconciliation Commission.</p>
<p>De Klerk, whose National Party (NP) implemented apartheid in 1948 and began scrapping it 42 years later, made the apology during a three-hour summary of South Africa's race conflict intended to help the commission establish as full a picture of who did what, and why, during apartheid.</p>
<p>&quot;History has shown that as far as the policy of apartheid was concerned, our former leaders were deeply mistaken in the course upon which they embarked,&quot; said de Klerk, ousted by President Nelson Mandela's African National Congress (ANC) in South Africa's first all race election in April 1994.</p>
<p>Addressing the evidence of hit-squad killings of black activists that has emerged since the collapse of apartheid, de Klerk acknowledged his government and previous ones had approved &quot;unconventional&quot; actions which &quot;created the environment within which abuses and gross violations of human rights could take place&quot;.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;I want to make clear that within my knowledge and experience (unconventional strategies) never included the authorisation of assassination, murder, torture, rape, assault or the like...</p>
<p>&quot;Nor did I individually directly or indirectly ever suggest, order or authorise any such action.&quot;</p>
<p>De Klerk said some members of the security forces accused him of being a traitor for his dismantling of apartheid.</p>
<p>&quot;It has now become clear that certain elements misused state funds and were involved in unauthorised operations leading to abuses and violation of human rights,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>About 20 ANC demonstrators picketed outside the building where the commission met but de Klerk evaded them by entering through an underground garage.</p>
<p>ANC supporters in the packed public gallery of about 400 people jeered when de Klerk denied knowledge of a notorious hit-squad killing but Tutu admonished them to keep quiet or be thrown out.</p>
<p>&quot;I know how difficult it is to say 'I'm sorry' in public,&quot; Tutu told de Klerk at the end of his presentation. &quot;We are sure it will have a significant impact.&quot;</p>
<p>Tutu's deputy chairman, Alex Boraine, added: &quot;I don't think anyone should underestimate the power of a former state president saying 'I'm sorry'.&quot;</p>
<p>De Klerk said responsibility for what happened during apartheid lay with political leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;I accept such overall responsibility in respect of the period of my leadership,&quot; he said, but added that cabinet ministers should be held to account for specific actions only if such actions were executed &quot;in terms of a reasonable interpretation&quot; of cabinet instructions.</p>
<p>The ANC is due to present its view of the apartheid struggle to Tutu on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
