<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5846" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Burundi sanctions trigger Tutsi siege mentality.</title>
<headline>Burundi sanctions trigger Tutsi siege mentality.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bigg</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Tutsi minority in Burundi blames three weeks of stringent sanctions for the siege mentality in the capital as prices rise and fuel grows scarce.</p>
<p>Most Tutsi Bujumbura residents, who dismissed regional sanctions imposed on July 31 after the overthrow of the Hutu president by the Tutsi-dominated army, are now sombre.</p>
<p>&quot;The most dramatic effect of the embargo is the creation of a besieged mentality among Tutsis. We know we have to survive on our own,&quot; said a Tutsi analyst working for a Western company.</p>
<p>A foreign aid worker said five people were killed in the Bujumbura suburb of Kamenge on Tuesday but had no details. The capital has been relatively calm since before the embargo.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, queues of cars with drivers clutching government-issued ration cards stretched for a mile (1.6 km) at the few petrol stations in the capital with supplies of fuel.</p>
<p>Prices of basic foodstuffs available in fertile landlocked Burundi have risen by up to 50 per cent because of shortages of fuel to move goods by road from the interior to urban markets.</p>
<p>A 10-kg (22-pound) bunch of bananas, which cost some 1,000 Burundian francs ($3.33) in Bujumbura's main market before sanctions, now costs 1,500 francs ($5). A sack of charcoal costs 2,500 francs ($8.33) from 2,000 francs ($6.66) before July 31.</p>
<p>&quot;I spent all day looking for (cooking) gas and I didn't get anything. At least there is some fuel left, but we don't know how long this can go on,&quot; said Caritas Ndikuramana, a Tutsi.</p>
<p>Bujumbura's airport is closed, its lake port deserted and most Tutsi residents are afraid to drive out of the capital because of fears of attack by rebels of the Hutu majority.</p>
<p>New Tutsi military ruler Pierre Buyoya, who has said Burundi will overcome the regional sanctions, has also embarked on a charm offensive to win over foreign powers.</p>
<p>Regional African states demand a return to constitutional rule and peace negotiations with Hutu rebels to end three years of vicious civil war and massacres that have killed more than 150,000 people.</p>
<p>Buyoya sacked Army Chief of Staff Colonel Jean Bikomagu on Tuesday in what analysts saw as a bid to reassure powers behind sanctions and build the new ruler's image as a Tutsi moderate.</p>
<p>The move seemed to find favour with some Western officials.</p>
<p>&quot;Sacking Bikomagu is a bigger coup than the coup,&quot; said a U.N. official. &quot;Buyoya is either extremely brave or has a side deal organised, which we don't know about, to protect himself.&quot;</p>
<p>Bikomagu is implicated in a U.N. report on an attempted army coup in October 1993, in which the country's first Hutu president was assassinated, and subsequent Hutu-Tutsi killings.</p>
<p>Buyoya also replaced the chief of staff of the gendarmerie paramilitary police and the presidential palace army commander.</p>
<p>A Hutu opposition official, speaking in Nairobi, forecast Bikomagu would soon be made an ambassador, while the former head of the gendarmerie would become Burundi's head of immigration.</p>
<p>&quot;Bikomagu remains the largest power broker in Burundi. This was arranged to give Buyoya credibility abroad so he is seen as the man who is able to tackle the mono-ethnic army,&quot; he said. ($1=300 Burundian francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
