<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5848" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: De Klerk apologises for excesses of apartheid.</title>
<headline>De Klerk apologises for excesses of apartheid.</headline>
<byline>Anton Ferreira</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former South African president F.W. de Klerk on Wednesday apologised to Archbishop Desmond Tutu's &quot;truth commission&quot; for human rights violations under white rule, but said he never sanctioned an order to kill.</p>
<p>&quot;I stand before you today neither in shame nor in arrogance, but deeply conscious of my responsibility,&quot; de Klerk told commission members headed by Tutu, who won the 1984 Nobel Peace Prize for his non-violent opposition to apartheid.</p>
<p>Tutu's statutory Truth and Reconciliation Commission was set up to investigate human rights crimes committed in defence of white rule or in opposition to it, to pardon offenders and to compensate victims.</p>
<p>Apartheid ended in April 1994, when Nelson Mandela, jailed for 27 years for fighting white rule, was elected the country's first black president.</p>
<p>After four months of gruelling testimony from mainly black victims of white rule, including personal accounts of murder, rape, torture and the killing of children, the commission this week began hearing submissions by political parties.</p>
<p>On his way to the Good Hope centre de Klerk drove past a score of black demonstrators carrying placards reading &quot;Apartheid -- never again&quot; and &quot;How many people died during apartheid?&quot;</p>
<p>Inside, he was greeted with loud applause from the 300-strong crowd, mostly party supporters. Tutu began proceedings with a prayer.</p>
<p>Submitting a 29-page explanation of the actions of his National Party during 46 years of white rule, de Klerk conceded that many wrongs were inflicted upon the black majority:</p>
<p>&quot;The National Party is prepared to admit its many mistakes of the past and is genuinely repentant...we have gone on our knees before God Almighty to pray for His forgiveness.&quot;</p>
<p>De Klerk said the state of emergency imposed by his predecessor, P.W. Botha, in the 1980s &quot;created circumstances and an atmosphere which were conducive to many of the abuses and transgressions against human rights which form the basis of the Commission's present investigations&quot;.</p>
<p>He said most of the officials, police and soldiers who defended white rule were honorable men and women who believed they were protecting their country against communism.</p>
<p>&quot;They were convinced that their cause was just, necessary and legitimate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But de Klerk said none of the abuses that have been reported to Tutu's commission since it began work in April were officially sanctioned by his government.</p>
<p>&quot;In dealing with the unconventional strategies from the side of the government, I want to make it clear from the outset that, within my knowledge and experience, they never included the authorisation of assassination, murder, torture, rape, assault or the like.</p>
<p>&quot;Nor did I individually, directly or indirectly, ever suggest, order or authorise any such action,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>De Klerk said that after the National Party began to move away from strict apartheid, it was criticised from within white Afrikaner ranks for being too &quot;soft&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I suspect that many of the unauthorised actions that are now coming to light were at the time directed as much against the transformation process as they were directed against the revolutionary threat.</p>
<p>&quot;It has now become clear that certain elements misused state funds and were involved in unauthorised operations leading to abuses and violations of human rights,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>De Klerk said he accepted overall responsibility for government actions under his leadership, but said ministers and military leaders should accept the blame for things they ordered or allowed their juniors to believe they had ordered.</p>
<p>Ending with a call for reconciliation, he cautioned: &quot;No single side in the conflict of the past has a monopoly of virtue or should bear responsibility for all the abuses that occurred.</p>
<p>&quot;We must accept the importance of reconciliation, of coming to terms with ourselves, our neighbours and our past -- of forgiving and of being forgiven.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
