<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5849" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: ANC to tell S.African truth body of &quot;just war&quot;.</title>
<headline>ANC to tell S.African truth body of &quot;just war&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Anton Ferreira</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Nelson Mandela's African National Congress gives its version of history to South Africa's &quot;truth commission&quot; on Thursday in a presentation that will portray its anti-apartheid struggle as a &quot;just war&quot;.</p>
<p>The ANC submission to Archbishop Desmond Tutu's Truth and Reconciliation Commission will be presented by Deputy President Thabo Mbeki, who told reporters he would deal with such issues as &quot;just war versus unjust war&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to concentrate on the broad issue, not get involved in individual events,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An ANC statement said the party, which came to power in the country's first all-race election in 1994, wanted peace and reconciliation to become the cornerstones of the new democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;At the core of the ANC submission is the indictment of the system of apartheid as a crime against humanity...The struggle against apartheid cannot therefore be equated with acts committed in defence of this repugnant system.&quot;</p>
<p>The ANC's submission follows one on Wednesday by former president F.W. de Klerk, whose National Party introduced apartheid in 1948 and began dismantling it in 1990.</p>
<p>De Klerk told the commission he did not agree that the ANC had been fighting a morally superior war.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think that argument can apply to the father of a child killed by an (ANC) limpet mine. That child did not deserve to die and it remains an atrocity.&quot;</p>
<p>Mbeki said he did not think de Klerk had addressed the main issue in South Africa's race war, the apparent fear on the part of whites that they would be swamped by black hordes.</p>
<p>&quot;The role of the truth commission should be to find ways of ensuring such fears don't arise again,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mandela suggested setting up a truth commission in the early 1990s when reports emerged of human rights abuses committed in ANC military camps in exile.</p>
<p>He said the abuses should be dealt with in the wider context of the struggle for and against apartheid. The ANC has acknowledged executing about 30 of its own members in the camps.</p>
<p>The ANC statement said the movement was &quot;honest enough to acknowledge that human rights abuses did occur, (but) these abuses did not occur within the framework of official policy&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The ANC trusts that at the end of the process of truth and reconciliation, South Africa will emerge victorious and better able to march to the future with confidence that never again will such abuses occur in our country.&quot;</p>
<p>De Klerk apologised on Wednesday for the pain caused by apartheid and acknowledged that rogue members of the security forces committed abuses.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
