<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5855" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SIERRA LEONE: Zimbabwe's Caanan Banana mediates on Sierra Leone.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe's Caanan Banana mediates on Sierra Leone.</headline>
<dateline>FREETOWN 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Zimbabwean president Caanan Banana, acting as an envoy of the Organisation of African Unity, held talks in Sierra Leone on Wednesday to try to push forward its stalled peace process.</p>
<p>Banana, who had talks with Sierra Leonean rebel leader Foday Sankoh in Ivory Coast, told reporters that he had had talks with President Ahmad Tejan Kabbah and civic groups.</p>
<p>&quot;The search for peace is a collective one and this OAU-appointed team is in Freetown to consult with the president of Sierra Leone... and also with civic groups so as to move forward the stalled peace process,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Banana said Tejan Kabbah was keen the resume the peace process but he declined to comment on whether Sankoh had demanded the post of deputy head of state and withdrawal of foreign troops as conditions for a final deal.</p>
<p>Banana, OAU special envoy to Sierra Leone's war-ravaged neighbour Liberia, was Zimbabwe's president from 1980 to 1987.</p>
<p>Tejan Kabbah, who took over after the army restored civilian rule in March, had talks in Ivory Coast with Sankoh and his Revolutionary United Front (RUF) in April.</p>
<p>The two sides agreed to extend a ceasefire, which has been generally holding, but remain deadlocked on the issues of disarmament and withdrawal of foreign troops helping the government. The rebels took up arms in 1991.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OAU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SILEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FREETOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SIERRA LEONE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
