<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5856" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Liberty Life says on track for more gains.</title>
<headline>Liberty Life says on track for more gains.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Liberty Life Association of Africa said it was &quot;delighted&quot; with interim results and believed it was on track to achieve further gains after adopting the new Financial Soundness Valuation accounting practice last year.</p>
<p>Announcing the results, chairman Donald Gordon said that, while it was not accurate to compare results with the previous half because of the change in the accounting practise:</p>
<p>&quot;It does give an indication that we still feel we are on track on the financial soundness basis for our target 20 percent growth per annum - which is basically our target growth.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think we are on track and we are very delighted with our first half-year results,&quot; Gordon said.</p>
<p>Liberty Life's net taxed surplus attributable to shareholders jumped 57.9 percent to 667 cents per share from 422.5 cents per share previously.</p>
<p>Total new business written by the Liberty Life Group amounted to a record 2.297 million rand, representing a 26 percent increase over the 1.817 million rand recorded for the comparable period in 1995, he said.</p>
<p>He said Liberty Life would continue to maintain its standards by selling quality products.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as Liberty Life is concerned we are maintaining our standards...and really we are not going to follow all the speculative approaches that some of our competitors are doing,&quot; he said. -- Charles Phahlane, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
