<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5858" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GAMBIA: Gambians who break party ban face life in jail.</title>
<headline>Gambians who break party ban face life in jail.</headline>
<byline>Pap Saine</byline>
<dateline>BANJUL 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gambia's military government has threatened anyone contravening a ban on main political parties with life imprisonment and set tough penalties for political activity before the official start of election campaigning.</p>
<p>The Political Activities, Resumption Decree published on Wednesday said anyone involved in politics before campaigning for presidential elections starts on September 9 would face a fine of one million dalasis ($102,000) or life imprisonment.</p>
<p>Gambia's military rulers lifted a two-year ban on all political activity on August 14, then announced two days later that the country's three main parties would be excluded from political life.</p>
<p>They banned anyone who had served as a minister under ousted president Sir Dawda Jawara, head of state from independence from Britain in 1965 until 1994, and excluded Jawara's People's Progressive Party, the National Convention Party of Sheriff Mustapha Dibba, and Hassan Musa Camara's Gambia People's Party.</p>
<p>Any party contravening the ban on the three main political parties will be fined one million dalasis &quot;or in default all its members who subscribe to its constitution shall be eligible to imprisonment for life,&quot; the decree said.</p>
<p>Army ruler Captain Yahya Jammeh has said he will stand as a civilian candidate in the September 26 election but will not campaign as he does not want to get involved in politics.</p>
<p>It was not clear how the decree would affect the requirement for presidential candidates to gather 5,000 signatures from around the country by the September 5 registration deadline.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth said on Tuesday the election rules were obviously flawed and would allow the West African country's military leaders to strengthen their grip on power.</p>
<p>Jammeh's opponents will be drawn from two small parties, the leftist People's Democratic Organisation for Independence and Socialism, and the People's Democratic Party of Lamin Bojang -- provided they succeed in registering. Parliamentary elections are set for December 11.</p>
<p>Jammeh has said there would be no point in uncovering what he termed the corruption of the former government if those responsible were allowed to resume their political careers.</p>
<p>($=9.8 dalasis)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GAMB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANJUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
