<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5860" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Abacha tells Nigerian governors to back democracy.</title>
<headline>Abacha tells Nigerian governors to back democracy.</headline>
<dateline>ABUJA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigerian army ruler General Sani Abacha told 30 newly appointed state military governors at a swearing-in ceremony on Wednesday to give his democracy plan top priority.</p>
<p>&quot;You must see to a meticulous execution of the transition political programme and cooperate with various electoral officers in this regard,&quot; Abacha told them in the capital Abuja.</p>
<p>Last week all Nigeria's powerful state governors were removed at a stroke in the most sweeping change at state level since Abacha took power in 1993. No official explanation was given for the change.</p>
<p>All the new administrators are middle ranking army, navy and air force officers.</p>
<p>Africa's most populous nation has been in political crisis since 1993, when a previous military government annulled elections that would have ended a decade of army rule.</p>
<p>Last year Abacha set out a plan to restore democracy by October 1998. Critics at home and abroad say that is too late.</p>
<p>The administrators are chief executives of the 30 states and make up the second tier of authority in Nigeria after the federal government.</p>
<p>Abacha told the new administrators to: &quot;Ensure the continuity of projects already in progress in your states and resist attempts to embark on new projects not in tune with financial reality of the times.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABUJA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
