<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5862" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa-Belgium sex cases could be linked - police.</title>
<headline>S.Africa-Belgium sex cases could be linked - police.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African police said on Wednesday there could be a link between the child sex scandal rocking Belgium and the disappearance of five girls in Pretoria up to eight years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The modus operandi...as to what happened in Belgium and what's happening here in South Africa seems to be very, very closely related,&quot; Pretoria police director Reggie Mariemuthoo told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;The modus operandi in which our girls were abducted and kept in secret cellars in houses is similar to what happened in Belgium. The age groups are also more or less the same as those in Belgium.&quot;</p>
<p>South African paedophile Gert van Rooyen and his lover Joey Haarhof were linked by police to the disappearance of the girls, aged 11 to 13. Van Rooyen shot Haarhof and himself six years ago as police closed in on them.</p>
<p>The girls were never traced, despite a thorough excavation of van Rooyen's Pretoria home in May. The girls were allegedly kept in a cellar under the house.</p>
<p>In Belgium, convicted child rapist Marc Dutroux is the main suspect after the bodies of two eight-year-old child sex victims were found last weekend in his house in the southern Belgian city of Charleroi.</p>
<p>Two other girls were rescued from his house and at least another two are missing. Dutroux's wife, Michelle Martin, was also formally charged with being an accomplice in the abduction and illegal imprisonment of children.</p>
<p>Mariemuthoo said South African police had been investigating the &quot;very, very strong possibility&quot; of an international link to the van Rooyen case even before the Belgian scandal broke.</p>
<p>&quot;Immediately we heard about that we...then speculated that there is a strong possibility of a link between the South African case and that of Belgium.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked about the possibility of an international child sex ring, Mariemuthoo said: &quot;It is possible. Unfortunately we don't have any information on those lines at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>Mariemuthoo said he had been in contact with Interpol in Belgium and would send South African detectives there &quot;as soon as they (the Belgians) have discovered, for sure, that there is an international link&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
