<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5863" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>LIBERIA: Liberia shooting delays U.N. ceasefire monitors.</title>
<headline>Liberia shooting delays U.N. ceasefire monitors.</headline>
<byline>Jackson Kanneh</byline>
<dateline>MONROVIA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Nations observers travelling to the western Liberian town of Tubmanburg on Wednesday to monitor a new ceasefire were delayed by shooting along the highway, the U.N. said.</p>
<p>U.N. special representative Anthony Nyakyi told reporters the observers had difficulty in reaching the town, the main base of the ULIMO-J militia loyal to Roosevelt Johnson.</p>
<p>&quot;We could not proceed at first because of some shooting along the highway,&quot; Nyakyi said. The mission finally went ahead with a ULIMO-J escort.</p>
<p>Faction leaders still in the Nigerian capital Abuja after agreeing a new peace deal at the weekend accused each other of breaking the ceasefire, which was supposed to come into force on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The latest peace deal threatens faction leaders with sanctions, including seizure of assets and war crimes tribunals, if they are seen to be obstructing the peace process.</p>
<p>Johnson said he had complained to rival militia leader Alhaji Kromah about skirmishing in Bomi County, the  area around Tubmanburg.</p>
<p>The peace deal agreed with West African leaders on Saturday foresees the disarmament of an estimated 60,000 combatants and the holding of elections by May 1997.</p>
<p>Over a dozen peace deals have failed to end the war launched by Charles Taylor and his National Patriotic Front of Liberia (NPFL) in late 1989. Taylor and Kromah are both vice-chairmen of an interim ruling State Council.</p>
<p>Their attempt to arrest Johnson for murder in April triggered some of the bloodiest fighting of the war in the streets of Monrovia, pitting ULIMO-J and its ethnic Krahn allies against Taylor and Kromah.</p>
<p>The Liberia Peace Council, another Krahn faction, accused Taylor's forces on Saturday of attacking its positions in the southeast in Grand Gedeh County.</p>
<p>&quot;The ceasefire violation committee was meeting today to look into the allegations by the Liberia Peace Council about renewed fighing in the southeast,&quot; Nyakyi said. He said his observers could not reach the remote region.</p>
<p>NPFL officials in Abuja said they had received the accusation in a letter but could give no confirmation.</p>
<p>Johnson said he intended to return to the Liberian capital as soon as possible. The United States airlifted him out to peace talks in Ghana in May, but declined to fly him back.</p>
<p>Freed American slaves founded Liberia in 1847. The war has killed well over 150,000 people, hundreds of them in April and May.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONROVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LIBERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
