<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5865" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GHANA: Two Ghana opposition parties form poll alliance.</title>
<headline>Two Ghana opposition parties form poll alliance.</headline>
<byline>Harry Mouzalas</byline>
<dateline>ACCRA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ghana's two main opposition parties have agreed to present a joint candidate for December's presidential election but are finding it harder to agree on parliamentary candidates, party officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The New Patriotic Party (NPP) and the Peoples Convention Party (PCP) agreed last Friday to put up NPP leader Joseph Agyekum Kuffour for the presidency with incumbent vice-president Kow Arkaah as his running mate.</p>
<p>Presidential and parliamentary elections are set for December 7, with President Jerry Rawlings expected to seek a final term four-year term. The presidential vote is organised along U.S. lines with candidates for the presidency and vice-presidency running together.</p>
<p>&quot;Both parties are now nominating their parliamentary candidates. The thorny problem is that where both sides feel they are strong on the ground as far as a constituency is concerned, it will be very difficult for one side to give ground,&quot; PCP publicity secretary Dan Quartey said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope somehow that some compromise will be reached in such situations to resolve these issues to enable the alliance to make a strong showing in the elections.&quot;</p>
<p>Electoral commission chairman Kwadwo Afari Djan told both parties on Tuesday they could not use the same campaign symbol &quot;since they are distinct political entities legally recognised by the commission&quot;.</p>
<p>He said the commission would only recognise the symbol of the presidential candidate's party for the presidential poll, though the commission is holding further talks with alliance representatives.</p>
<p>The alliance has attracted criticism from PCP supporters who say the party has betrayed the tradition of Ghana's founding president Kwame Nkrumah.</p>
<p>Arkaah was previously allied with Rawlings but increasing antagonism between them exploded into a much publicised scuffle during a cabinet meeting last December.</p>
<p>Rawlings, 49, a former air force flight lieutenant who staged two successful coups before turning politician, is expected to stand as leader of the National Democratic Congress.</p>
<p>Opposition parties boycotted the 1992 parliamentary polls after accusing Rawlings of manipulating the presidential vote.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GHANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ACCRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GHANA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
