<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5869" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Blue chips strong on active Nigerian bourse.</title>
<headline>Blue chips strong on active Nigerian bourse.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue chip shares, with the exception of the brewing sector, made steady progress in active Wednesday trade on the Nigerian stock exchange, dealers said.</p>
<p>The all-share index could not be updated for technical reasons.</p>
<p>Interest continued to in Nigerian Tobacco Company as shares closed six kobo up at 2.10 naira. Shares had fallen from 6.00 naira at the beginning of the year to 2.00 naira last week.</p>
<p>The petroleum marketing sector performed generally well.</p>
<p>National Oil rose 18 kobo, to close at 25.00 naira. Texaco, Total and Unipetrol were each 10 kobo higher at 22.80 naira, 42.30 naira and 32.60 naira respectively. Agip was five kobo up at 11.80 naira, the same margin as Mobil which closed at 34.80 naira.</p>
<p>First quarter results from African Petroleum which showed a marginal increase in after tax profits left the company's shares unmoved at 27.55 naira.</p>
<p>Performance in conglomerates was mixed with the biggest, PZ Industries and Lever brothers both rising.</p>
<p>PZ closed 20 kobo higher at 31.40 naira, while Lever Brothers gained 12 kobo to 23.72 naira.</p>
<p>Other conglomerates were not so fortunate. CFAO closed eight kobo lower at six naira, John Holt fell five kobo to 11.55 naira and UAC lost three kobo to 11.35 naira.</p>
<p>Ashaka Cement gained five kobo to 13.87 naira, while West African Portland Cement rose eight kobo to 26.90 naira.</p>
<p>Food shares maintained a strong showing. Flour Mills gained 15 kobo to close at 10.70 naira, while Union Dicon rose the same amount to 30.60 naira.</p>
<p>Brewing remained depressed with Nigerian Breweries and Guinness down by five kobo each to 13.85 naira and 9.70 naira respectively.</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 263 03 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
