<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5870" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Africa police tackle white collar crime.</title>
<headline>Africa police tackle white collar crime.</headline>
<byline>Emelia Sithole</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senior African police officials ended a three-day conference on Wednesday pledging to cooperate to stem rising white collar crime across the continent.</p>
<p>Rainer-Diethardt Buhrer, an officer with the economic crime group of the international police organisation Interpol, said criminals were moving speedily across borders, and countries had no option but to cooperate to fight them.</p>
<p>&quot;National police bureaus used to operate within their own national areas but now international crime is moving with speed across borders there's need for countries to cooperate to fight it,&quot; Buhrer told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;International crooks know no boundaries...There is need for the (law enforcement) institutions in the region to pool their resources together for security needs,&quot; Zimbabwe's deputy commissioner Godwin Matanga said in closing the conference.</p>
<p>Saying Africa could no longer rely on handouts due to increasing international donor fatigue, he said the continent's police needed to establish a regional fund to train their officers in white collar crime, some types of which, such as computer fraud, were just emerging in Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;Our cooperation in the fight against cross-border and international crime will be enriched by our own self-reliance in the region,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Although the conference agreed there was a rise in economic crimes in Africa, delegates refused to release statistics. But experts pointed to cases of fraud through electronic money transfers, cheque forgeries, investment scams and illegal exports of precious stones.</p>
<p>In recommendations at the end of the conference for English- speaking Africa in Harare, the officials agreed to set up sub- regional and national legal committees to identify disparities in legislation on economic crimes and ways of harmonising them to boost cooperation among countries.</p>
<p>On Monday, when he opened the conference whose discussions were closed to the press, Zimbabwe's Home Affairs Minister Dumiso Dabengwa said the fight against white collar crime was frustrated partly by differences in laws defining offences and the severity of punishment in various African countries.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe's assistant commissioner Osborne Mawere, who chaired the conference organised by Interpol, said the legal committees would also take their recommendations to policy-makers and press them to cut immigration redtape inhibiting the speedy chase of criminals across borders.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
