<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5872" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Sound policy will stabilise S.Africa rand - Manuel.</title>
<headline>Sound policy will stabilise S.Africa rand - Manuel.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sound economic fundamentals bolstered by the macroeconomic strategy released in June will ultimately stabilise South Africa's volatile rand, Finance Minister Trevor Manuel told parliament on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Dismissing opposition criticism of his financial management during a three-day finance debate, Manuel repeated his assurance of Tuesday that the economy was performing well.</p>
<p>The 400-member National Assembly formally adopted the 173.7 billion rand budget on Wednesday with 12 votes against. The budget was implemented on March 13.</p>
<p>&quot;The economic fundamentals are sound,&quot; Manuel said in his closing address.</p>
<p>&quot;It is this which will provide for our currency an underlying value. Also, contrary to doomsayers...this economy will grow this year and every year hereafter to take us to six percent growth in the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;The trend in respect of fiscal discipline is exceedingly positive - from the heady heights of a deficit of nine percent in 1992/93 to the on-target 5.1 percent this year - and our unflinching planning is for four percent next year,&quot;Manuel said.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy is performing and we will align our policies to improve on that.&quot;</p>
<p>Manuel reaffirmed his commitment to the macroeconomic strategy for growth, employment and redistribution (GEAR) unveiled in June and subsequently condemned by labour and the ruling African National Congress's communist partners.</p>
<p>Manuel said proper implementation of the strategy was part of the programme to bolster the rand, which has fallen about 20 percent since February to 4.56 against the dollar on Wednesday, up from an all-time low of 4.59 earlier this week.</p>
<p>&quot;The GEAR is an integrated strategy, not a seven-day wonder... The GEAR is about transforming government - it is not going to be fully implemented in one month,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The strategy links fiscal discipline, wage and price restraint in the private sector and industrial and export promotion packages to double economic growth to six percent and boost job creation to about 400,000 a year by the turn of the century.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
