<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5874" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CENTRAL AFRICAN REPUBLIC: Central Africa cannot meet IMF targets - premier.</title>
<headline>Central Africa cannot meet IMF targets - premier.</headline>
<dateline>BANGUI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Central African Republic's prime minister has said the country will be unable to meet targets set by the International Monetary Fund because of economic losses caused by an army mutiny in May.</p>
<p>Jean-Paul Ngoupande told a national conference the looting and destruction in the city centre had caused a sharp fall in revenue, which meant the government could not meet commitments set out in a letter of intent signed in March.</p>
<p>Soldiers first mutinied in April but May's pay revolt turned into a protest against the government of President Ange-Felix Patasse. French troops intervened to support the president and 43 people were killed.</p>
<p>The 10-day meeting of the States General on National Defence opened on Monday with a call from Patasse for a truly national army free of ethnic or political bias.</p>
<p>In his Tuesday speech, Ngoupande said his priorities were to reestablish security, get government offices back to work, reconstruct damaged industries and businesses and clean up public finances.</p>
<p>Patasse appointed Ngoupande, previously ambassador to Paris, in June to head a national unity government including members of the party of former military leader Andre Kolingba and people from outside politics.</p>
<p>The authorities have made several calls on civilians to hand in weapons distributed during the army mutinies, with little success so far.</p>
<p>Three policemen were killed while pursuing bandits last Thursday, and a bar owner was shot dead in the capital's southern Lakouanga district on Tuesday night.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGUI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CENTRAL AFRICAN REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
