<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5877" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Tanzanian coffee official says taxes hurt output.</title>
<headline>Tanzanian coffee official says taxes hurt output.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The high level of taxation in the coffee sector has undermined government efforts to revitalise the industry, a senior Tanzania Coffee Board (TCB) official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Damian Salla, the board's public relations officer, said the government levied seven different coffee taxes &quot;which may eventually undermine efforts to revitalise the industry&quot;.</p>
<p>In a statement on Tanzania's Farmers' Day faxed to Reuters in the Kenyan capital of Nairobi, Salla urged the government to review taxation policies to save the sector. He did not say what percentage of farm earnings the taxes constituted.</p>
<p>The TCB is a parastatal body that acts as a government adviser on the industry.</p>
<p>Salla said coffee extension staff and other key officials in the sector believed output levels under the current crop area could be increased to reach an initial annual figure of 75,000 tonnes, and then up to 100,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>This could be attained if coffee growers planted high-quality seeds and observed other management practices such as proper pruning and the usage of inputs in &quot;correctly prescribed doses for the realisation of high yields&quot;.</p>
<p>Production has hovered around 50,000 tonnes or below, and will be lower in 1995/95 due to poor weather.</p>
<p>Salla said measures to increase output had included campaigns to step up replanting where trees had been uprooted, replacing aged coffee trees, production of quality seeds and increased planting of the high-yielding clonal robusta variety.</p>
<p>The Coffee Management Unit (CMU) in Tanzania's ministry of agriculture, in a separate statement, envisaged a steady annual rise in coffee output and also a steady rise in yields, but gave no figures.</p>
<p>The CMU also saw optimism in the improvement of coffee quality. Officials there said Tanzania was poised to produce 10 percent of its coffee in the top grades in the next few years.</p>
<p>&quot;This is becoming possible due to expected improvements in coffee processing practices,&quot; Salla said.</p>
<p>He said a great potential existed for Tanzanian coffees abroad because of current promotion efforts and a &quot;good name&quot;.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
