<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5879" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Zairean prime minister in Rwanda over refugees.</title>
<headline>Zairean prime minister in Rwanda over refugees.</headline>
<byline>Buchizya Mseteka</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's prime minister arrived in Rwanda on Wednesday for talks with the government on the fate of 1.1 million Rwandan Hutu refugees in Zaire since 1994.</p>
<p>Kengo Wa Dondo arrived while Rwandan Hutus, some accused of taking part in the 1994 genocide in Rwanda of up to one million Tutsis and moderate Hutus, were going back to Rwanda from neighbouring Burundi.</p>
<p>Kengo, who has repeatedly stressed the need for the Rwandan Hutu refugees to return to Rwanda, will hold talks with his counterpart Pierre-Celestin Rwigema, Rwandan officials said.</p>
<p>He will also meet Rwandan President Pasteur Bizimungu and military strongman and Vice-President Major-General Paul Kagame.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a visit to promote bilateral ties between the two countries. The main focus will be on Rwandan refugees now living in Zaire,&quot; said Claude Dusaidi, political adviser to Kagame.</p>
<p>Kengo's visit is the first by such a senior Zairean official since Kagame's Tutsi-dominated Rwandan Patriotic Front (RPF) rebels took power in 1994 and drove into exile in Zaire the Hutu government and Hutu soldiers held reponsible for the genocide.</p>
<p>The civil war in Rwanda and the seizure of power by the RPF led to strained ties between the two neighbouring states.</p>
<p>Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko has intervened in the past two years to stop Kengo from ordering the deportation of Rwandan Hutus in violation of international law.</p>
<p>Last August, Zairean troops forcibly expelled some 15,000 Rwandan and Burundian Hutus. The expulsions were only stopped after Mobutu stepped in following an international outcry.</p>
<p>Together with the refugees, eastern Zaire is also home to Rwanda's 40,000-strong former Hutu army and Hutu militiamen who infiltrate back into Rwanda and are a major security concern for Kigali.</p>
<p>Government officials said Rwanda would also raise with Kengo the issue of the rebels based in Zaire who together with Hutu rebels in Burundi have stepped up their attacks in Rwanda and Burundi this year.</p>
<p>Rwandan officials said they wanted assurances that Zaire would take action against rebels operating from its territory.</p>
<p>The rebels have disrupted economic activity in the Rwandan border towns of Cyangugu and Gisenyi, Rwandan officials say.</p>
<p>In Burundi, Hutu guerrillas operating from bases in eastern Zaire have gained ground this year in their ferocious war with Burundi's Tutsi-dominated army despite Zaire closing its border with Burundi to prevent an influx of refugees from the conflict.</p>
<p>In the largest repatration movement since they left in 1994, Rwandan Hutu refugees are streaming home from camps in northern Burundi, accusing the Tutsi-dominated army of harassment.</p>
<p>The U.N. refugee agency expected up to 5,000 Rwandan refugees to enter southern Rwanda from Burundi on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The refugee flood swelled after Burundian troops killed three refugees as they tried to flee Magara camp on Sunday. The army said soldiers fired after a Rwandan refugee shot at them.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
