<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5884" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: De Klerk sees truth of apartheid as elusive.</title>
<headline>De Klerk sees truth of apartheid as elusive.</headline>
<byline>Anton Ferreira</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former president F.W. de Klerk reached back to the year 1652 on Wednesday as he sought to place apartheid in a context that would not make his National Party look all bad.</p>
<p>&quot;The commission should consider the elusive nature of truth in an historical and political context,&quot; de Klerk told Archbishop Desmond Tutu's Truth and Reconciliation Commission at the start of a three-hour presentation of his party's hindsight view of South Africa's race conflict.</p>
<p>He said his ancestors had arrived with the first wave of white settlers 344 years ago, fleeing religious persecution of protestants in France, and became Afrikaners -- &quot;A people of Africa, white Africans&quot;.</p>
<p>De Klerk noted that South African governments inherited race segregation policies from British colonial administrations that ran much of the country in the last century.</p>
<p>&quot;We are all the children of our times and the product of the cultural and political circumstances into which we were born.</p>
<p>&quot;Deplorable as it now may seem, until the middle of this century hardly anyone in the European-dominated world considered that the indigenous peoples of the far-flung colonial empires were ready to rule themselves,&quot; de Klerk said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the southern states of the United States the colour bar was still firmly in place.&quot;</p>
<p>The National Party voted in to power by the white electorate in 1948 had fought the African National Congress partly because of its alliance with the South African Communist Party, &quot;one of the most Stalinist and pro-Soviet parties in the world&quot;.</p>
<p>Against the abuses committed by security forces, had to be set the record of the ANC's &quot;revolutionary strategy&quot; that included destruction of thousands of homes and schools and the deaths of 295 people by the &quot;necklace&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>During the 1980s young black activists killed suspected &quot;sell-outs&quot; in their communities by placing burning tyres around their necks.</p>
<p>&quot;The security forces were expected to play by the rules while their opponents could use any methods that they liked,&quot; de Klerk said, comparing apartheid governments with Britain:</p>
<p>&quot;There was a perceived need for unconventional counter-strategies of the kind developed by the British and others in successful campaigns against insurgency and terrorism.&quot;</p>
<p>De Klerk noted that he and his conservative predecessor P.W. Botha were the only National Party presidents still alive but said Botha had refused to collaborate in drafting the party's submission to the commission.</p>
<p>De Klerk said the National Party had changed drastically from the Botha days and now counted blacks, mixed-race Coloureds and Indians among its supporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
