<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5886" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African rand/bonds closing report.</title>
<headline>S.African rand/bonds closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The rand ended a subdued trading day unchanged from its previous close on Wednesday after trading in a tight range.</p>
<p>At the 1400 GMT finish, the currency was pegged at 4.5620/5670 -- unmoved from its Tuesday close.</p>
<p>Dealehe currency put in a strong showing before the official opening, touching a day's best level of 4.5480 on what was believed to be Reserve Bank intervention.</p>
<p>Those gains were short-lived, however, and the rand was back at the 4.56 level shortly after the 0700 GMT official opening, where it hovered for much the trading day -- moving in a tight 4.5525 to 4.5640 range.</p>
<p>Trade on the day was mainly driven by interbank dealings with importers and exporters expressing marginal interest.</p>
<p>Some traders said offshore players had also been seen buying and selling dollars. Overall volumes were generally low.</p>
<p>One dealer said concern had surfaced towards the close that the currency would stage a fresh assault on its lows in New York trade after the Reserve Bank withdrew from the market at 1345 GMT.</p>
<p>On Monday, the local currency sank to a fresh record low of 4.59 bid in New York trade.</p>
<p>Against the crosses, the rand was last at 7.0498/0607 on sterling from 7.0576/0686 on Tuesday and at 0.3262/3267 marks from 0.3258/3263 previously.</p>
<p>Bond yields were also range-bound in equally flat trade, taking some direction from what one dealer described as &quot;slightly negative&quot; July CPI data.</p>
<p>Initial demand from jobbers taking positions ahead of the CPI number helped the yield on the key R150 stock to an intraday low of 15.595 percent.</p>
<p>A trader said July consumer inflation -- which rose 7.1 year-on-year -- was slightly above market expectations of a flat 6.9 percent year-on-year rise, although it was exactly in line with Reuters' consensus forecast.</p>
<p>After the CPI release, the market was also faced with a rising 30-year U.S. Treasury yield to above the 6.80 percent level.</p>
<p>The yield on the benchmark R150 duly rose to a morning high of 15.655 percent and extended its rise to an intraday high of 15.69 percent in the afternoon.</p>
<p>It settled at 15.68 at the official close -- unchanged from Tuesday's close. Eskom's 168 was pegged at 15.815 percent from 15.75 percent previously.</p>
<p>Institutions were largely sidelined on the day, the dealer added. &quot;There is no particular value at these levels and there is no particular reason to sell either,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Bond Exchange figures showed foreigners were net sellers of 29.72 million rand of South African bonds on Tuesday after selling 33.52 million rand on Monday. Nominal cumulative volumes were pegged at 5.96 billion rand from 3.99 billion rand previously.</p>
<p>On the money market, three-month NCDs moved higher to between 16.75 and 16.90 percent from 16.65 to 16.85 percent on Tuesday, while 90-day BAs were also higher at between 16.15 and 16.25 percent from 16.05 to 16.25 percent previously.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank said Tuesday's shortage eased to 8.725 billion rand from 8.847 billion rand on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Paul Richardson, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
