<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5891" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria allows trade in bank stability securities.</title>
<headline>Nigeria allows trade in bank stability securities.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria's central bank said on Wednesday it will permit trading in 33 billion naira of stabilisation securities held on behalf of commercial and merchant banks.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the new liberal dispensation, banks are allowed to sell part or all of their holdings of stabilisation securities in the interbank market in order to improve their liquidity positions,&quot; a central bank statement said.  </p>
<p>The central bank forced commercial and merchant banks to buy the securities between 1990 and 1995 to mop up percieved excess liquidity.</p>
<p>The central bank this week redeemed 676 million naira of the securities held for merchant banks. A total of 3,324 million naira of the remaining securities will also be redeemed to merchant banks, particularly badly hit by the distress affecting the Nigerian banking sector.</p>
<p>The central bank says it is not planning to redeem the remaining 29 billion naira in stabilisation securities held on behalf of commercial banks.</p>
<p>An interest rate of 12.5 percent is attached to the securities.</p>
<p>&quot;As an incentive measure, stabilisation securities holdings are forthwith to be recognised as part of a bank's liquid assets for liquidity ratio requirements,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;Non-bank institutions are not allowed to purchase or deal in stabilisation securities.&quot;</p>
<p>Nigeria's military rulers have made strenuous efforts to clean up the Nigerian banking sector, which was hit by severe distress in 1994, with many banks failing due to poor management and outright fraud.</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>--Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
