<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5892" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African military keep lid on chemical weapons.</title>
<headline>S.African military keep lid on chemical weapons.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's white generals on Wednesday again balked at revealing full details of a controversial project to make chemical weapons during the last days of apartheid.</p>
<p>Despite intense pressure from members of the parliamentary public accounts committee, South African National Defence Force chief Georg Meiring and his top staff insisted that making public key details of &quot;Project B&quot; would be a &quot;serious breach of security&quot;.</p>
<p>But what they did reveal depicted a trail of intrigue and deception involving a foreign agent who disappeared with $1.6 million in state funds and the sale of state assets worth at least 50 million rand ($11 million) for 350,000 rand ($77,000).</p>
<p>Although Meiring refused to name the foreign agent or say where he was, documents before the committee said the Office of Serious Economic Offences was investigating the deposit of the $1.6 million &quot;into an account in Croatia&quot;.</p>
<p>Meiring said the agent had been used to buy &quot;very sensitive chemicals&quot; from an Eastern European country for Project B, which was aimed at developing chemical and biological weapons.</p>
<p>But the deal went sour and the agent disappeared with the money. An officer was sent to Europe to trace the agent, but he was &quot;set up&quot; and arrested after being repaid with &quot;fraudulent money instruments&quot;.</p>
<p>The agent had, however, since made a statement to the South African Embassy in Bonn and had contacted the defence force by telephone. He offered to help recover the money but Meiring said it had been difficult to keep in touch with him since then.</p>
<p>Committee members also questioned the sale of four companies involved in the project to senior staff for nominal amounts that did not bear any relation to their real value.</p>
<p>The committee then went into a closed session for a further briefing by Meiring. This was the second time this year that the committee had tried to get Meiring to lift the lid on the project in public. In May, he also refused to divulge details.</p>
<p>($=4.56 rand)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
