<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5895" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Partial text of de Klerk's apartheid apology.</title>
<headline>Partial text of de Klerk's apartheid apology.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>F.W. de Klerk, the white National Party leader who turned South Africa from apartheid towards democracy, sought on Wednesday to explain the policies of his National Party to a post-apartheid &quot;truth commission&quot;.</p>
<p>This is a partial text of his presentation:</p>
<p>&quot;I stand before you today neither in shame nor in arrogance, but deeply conscious of my responsibility...to be open, frank and helpful...to stand by those who served under me...to admit that which was wrong, to defend that which was right and to continue to build bridges in our quest for reconciliation.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a gross injustice to put all the blame for the conflicts of the past on the shoulders of the National party...the killing, torture and intimidation of so many black South Africans by the revolutionary movements cannot simply be justified by the struggle against apartheid.</p>
<p>&quot;The National Party is prepared to admit its many mistakes of the past and is genuinely repentant....and we have gone on our knees before God Almighty to pray for His forgiveness.</p>
<p>&quot;We are all children of our times and the product of the cultural and political circumstances into which we were born and with which we grew up. Deplorable as it may now seem, until the middle of the century, hardly anyone in the European-dominated world considered that the indigenous peoples of the far-flung colonial empires were ready to rule themselves.</p>
<p>&quot;However, in the 15 years between 1955 and 1970, most of the countries of Africa were granted independence. The receding empires left the whites of South Africa increasingly isolated and out of step with the rest of humanity.</p>
<p>&quot;We thought that we could solve the complex problems that confronted us by giving each of the 10 distinguishable black South African nations self-government and independence within... a commonwealth of South African states.</p>
<p>&quot;The homelands were too small, too poor and economically too unattractive to provide a decent livelihood for all their citizens. It was evident that the great majority of black South Africans totally rejected the concept of separate development.</p>
<p>&quot;The policy of separate development had clearly failed.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who fought on the side of the government believed that they were defending their country against what they perceived to be the aggressive expansion of Soviet communism.</p>
<p>&quot;On the other hand, those who fought against the government were often equally convinced that they were fighting against a bastion of capitalism and imperialism.</p>
<p>&quot;The great majority of those who served in the security forces during the conflict were honourable, professional and dedicated men and women. They were convinced that their cause was just, necessary and legitimate.</p>
<p>&quot;The revolutionary strategies adopted by the government's opponents blurred traditional distinctions between combatants and non-combatants, between legitimate and illegitimate targets, and between acceptable and unacceptable methods.</p>
<p>&quot;In dealing with the unconventional strategies from the side of the government, I want to make it clear from the outset that, within my knowledge and experience, they never included the authorisation of assassination, murder, torture, rape, assault or the like...Nor did I individually, directly or indirectly, ever suggest, order or authorise any such action.</p>
<p>&quot;The fundamental change of direction that I initiated...was not supported by some elements in the security forces. My colleagues and I were accused along the grapevine of being soft and of being traitors.</p>
<p>&quot;I suspect that many of the unauthorised action that are now coming to light were at the time directed as much against the transformation process as they were directed against the revolutionary threat.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, there rests an overall responsibility on the leadership of the various parties, organisations and institutions which were part of the conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;I accept such overall responsibility in respect of the period of my leadership.</p>
<p>&quot;However...responsibility should be attributed to... individual ministers for all decisions taken by them personally in their ministerial capacity, including authorised actions and operations executed in terms of a reasonable interpretation of instructions issued by them.</p>
<p>&quot;Reconciliation...cannot be achieved unless there is also repentance on all sides. It is in this spirit that I want to emphasise that it is not my intention to excuse or gloss over the many unacceptable things that occurred during the period of Natonal Party rule. They happened and caused immeasurable pain and suffering to many.</p>
<p>&quot;I should like to express my deepest sympathy with all those on all sides who suffered during the conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;I and many other leading figures have already publicly apologised for the pain and suffering caused by former policies of the National Party. I reiterate these apologies today.</p>
<p>&quot;No single side in the conflict of the past has a monopoly of virtue or should bear responsibility for all the abuses that occurred. Neither can any single side claim sole credit for the transformation of South Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;The transformation belongs to us all.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
