<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5896" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Nairobi index falls in dull trading.</title>
<headline>Nairobi index falls in dull trading.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Nairobi Stock Exchange 20-share index fell on Wednesday in a generally dull market, floor dealers and bourse officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;With most counters having made their mid-year announcements, stock prices are unlikely to encounter immediate changes,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>The index fell 19.31 points to 3087.41 while turnover was 9.700 million shillings on 304,631 shares from 9.135 million shillings on 394,742 shares on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A bourse official described trading as &quot;very dull&quot; as only a few counters traded. Agriculturals were in great demand but there was simply no supply to match.</p>
<p>George Wiliamson eased 50 cents to 65, Rea Vipingo traded 3,200 shares at 11.50, 11.20 and 11.25 from 11.45 and Sasini Tea &amp; Coffee shed 2.0 to 51.</p>
<p>In commercials, Kenya Airways traded 49,226 shares at a high of 10 shillings but closed at 9.95 while Nation Printers &amp; Publishers rose to close at 103 from 102.</p>
<p>Brokers said that there was still investor interest in National Bank of Kenya stock. The bank is due to announce its mid-year results in mid-September.</p>
<p>National Bank traded a total of 151,500 shares at 18.55, 17.50 and closed at 18 shillings.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Credit Finance Company eased to 19.15 from 19.20, Kenya Commercial Bank fell to 55 from 56 and Standard Chartered Bank eased 75 cents to 46.</p>
<p>Oil concern Total Kenya fell to 75 from 78.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
