<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5900" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Accusations haunt new Liberian treaty.</title>
<headline>Accusations haunt new Liberian treaty.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Tostevin</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Accusations of renewed skirmishing between Liberian factions surfaced in the Nigerian capital Abuja on Wednesday, days after a new deal was agreed to end six years of civil war.</p>
<p>&quot;I have complained to Alhaji Kromah about skirmishing in Bomi County (northwest Liberia), where one of our fighters was shot in the leg as we were handing over heavy weapons in accordance with the agreement,&quot; General Roosevelt Johnson told Reuters by telephone from Abuja.</p>
<p>The clash was not independently confirmed.</p>
<p>A peace deal agreed with West African leaders on Saturday forsees the disarmament of an estimated 60,000 combatants and the holding of elections by May 1997.</p>
<p>Over a dozen peace deals have failed to end the war launched by faction leader Charles Taylor and his National Patriotic Front of Liberia (NPFL) in late 1989. Taylor and Kromah are both vice-chairmen of an interim ruling State Council.</p>
<p>Their attempt to arrest Johnson for murder in April triggered some of the bloodiest fighting of the war in the streets of Monrovia, pitting Johnson's ULIMO-J faction and ethnic Krahn allies against Taylor and Kromah.</p>
<p>United Nations envoy in Liberia Anthony Nyakyi on Tuesday told Reuters ULIMO-J had returned two artillery pieces to the Nigerian-led West African peacekeeping force, seized during fighting in December and January.</p>
<p>The Liberia Peace Council, another Krahn faction, accused Taylor's forces on Saturday of attacking its positions in the southeast in Grand Gedeh County.</p>
<p>NPFL officials in Abuja said they had received the accusation in a letter but could give no confirmation.</p>
<p>&quot;A meeting between Taylor and his high command before coming to Abuja has mandated his troops to the extent that even when shot at they are bound not to retaliate,&quot; an NPFL statement said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>At least 150,000 people are thought to have been killed in the civil war in Africa's oldest republic, founded by freed slaves in 1847.</p>
<p>Leaders of all the significant factions are still in Abuja. Officials from several of them said they were hoping to meet with Nigerian military ruler General Abacha for further discussions on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sure we can sort things out, the peace plan must work,&quot; Johnson said.</p>
<p>Johnson said he intended to return to the Liberian capital as soon as possible. The United States airlifted him out to peace talks in Ghana in May, but declined to fly him back.</p>
<p>The latest peace deal threatens faction leaders with sanctions, including seizure of assets and war crimes tribunals, if they are seen to be obstructing the peace process.</p>
<p>Under the deal the West African peacekeeping force will start disarming the fighters in September. The operation is due to be finished by November.</p>
<p>&quot;We are hopeful that people will keep to their words in keeping with the Abuja accord and we have reasons to believe that they will comply with what they agreed,&quot; Nyakyi said on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
