<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5902" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenyan 1995/96 coffee earnings seen down 25 pct.</title>
<headline>Kenyan 1995/96 coffee earnings seen down 25 pct.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A strong local currency and decline in world prices will cut Kenya's coffee earnings this marketing year by 25 percent, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Assuming that the Kenyan shilling remains at current rates until October 1996, total earnings for marketing year 1995/96 (October/September) are forecast to decline by nearly 25 percent,&quot; a senior trader told Reuters.</p>
<p>Coffee Board of Kenya figures showed 1994/95 coffee earnings of $282 million against $244 million in 1993/94 with coffee Kenya's third foreign exchange earner after tourism and tea.</p>
<p>Private industry experts predict a marginal rise in Kenya's coffee output in 1995/96 to 96,000 tonnes from 94,800 in 1994/95. The Coffee Board has forecast production at 100,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;Our output targets are still in sight and the coffee bushes are doing well,&quot; said Board General Manager Aggrey Ole Murunga.</p>
<p>Kenya's coffee stocks reached 741,000 bags at the end of 1994/95 due to lower export volume and increased production and although exports in 1995/96 are forecast to rise, stocks will still rise to 772,000 bags.</p>
<p>&quot;The Kenyan coffee industry is concerned that with the increased level of production, stocks may continue to rise in the short-term,&quot; an official from a leading coffee house said.</p>
<p>A senior Coffee Board official said the 25 percent drop in earnings was still &quot;mere market speculation&quot; but the correct picture would emerge when export auctions resumed on August 27 after a a two-week recess.</p>
<p>At Kenya's weekly export auctions in Nairobi coffee is weighed in 60 kg bags but sold in units of 50 kg.</p>
<p>In the first half of 1995/96, the average Kenyan auction price for a 50-kg bag was 6,409.06 shillings ($110 at March rates) compared with 8,679.49 shillings ($148.36) in the same period in 1994/95, coffee auction figures showed.</p>
<p>The Central Bank of Kenya posted the shilling at a commercial mean of 56.99 against the dollar on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In recent months, mainly estate farmers have urged the government to allow them the right to decide whether to sell at the auctions or by private treaty.</p>
<p>The Coffee Board has consistently rejected these appeals on the grounds that dismantling the auction system will make buyers lose confidence and dramatically lower prices.</p>
<p>The Coffee Board also maintains the system ensures  quality coffee is available throughout the marketing year. With private sales, there will be no such assurance, senior board officials say.</p>
<p>A task force appointed by Agriculture Minister Simeon Nyachae to review the coffee industry in May reported that many buyers saw auctions as best suited for Kenya.</p>
<p>Nyachae's office has since commissioned an independent European Union-funded probe by audit and management firm Price Waterhouse on marketing and management in the sector. --Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
