<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5905" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: De Klerk tries to close chapter on apartheid rule.</title>
<headline>De Klerk tries to close chapter on apartheid rule.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>One of the last chapters on South Africa's apartheid rule, a policy of racial segregation and oppression, was written on Wednesday when former president F.W. de Klerk apologised for past human rights violations.</p>
<p>His Afrikaner-led National Party turned a tradition of racial inequality, during three centuries of Dutch and British colonial rule, into an official doctrine when it defeated more moderate parties in the whites-only general election in 1948.</p>
<p>In 1949, restrictive laws underpinning apartheid -- an Afrikaner word meaning separateness -- began to be implemented.</p>
<p>The four official race groups -- white, black, Indian and Coloured (mixed-race) -- had to live in separate areas, babies had to be registered by race, sex between whites and other races was banned and park benches, toilets and public facilities for races were segregated, with the best reserved for whites.</p>
<p>In 1959 the government created 10 black &quot;homelands&quot;, giving whites 87 percent of land and blacks the barren 13 percent.</p>
<p>1960 - Police killed 69 people in an anti-apartheid protest at Sharpeville, near Johannesburg. The government -- run by the National Party until 1994 -- banned black resistance groups.</p>
<p>1964 - Nelson Mandela and senior African National Congress associates were jailed for life for resisting apartheid.</p>
<p>1976 - Over 600 blacks died in a year-long uprising sparked by a Soweto student revolt against inferior apartheid education.</p>
<p>1986 - Emergency rule was declared. The U.S. Congress passed comprehensive sanctions, followed by many Western governments.</p>
<p>1989 - F.W. de Klerk replaced P.W. Botha as National Party leader and then president and won elections as a reformist.</p>
<p>1990 - De Klerk repudiated apartheid, unbanned some 30 black opposition groups and freed Mandela after 27 years in jail.</p>
<p>1991 - Apartheid laws and racist restrictions were repealed. Power-sharing talks started between the state and 16 anti-apartheid groups.</p>
<p>1992 - De Klerk won 70 percent in a referendum to test support among 3.3 million white voters for apartheid reforms.</p>
<p>1994 - Apartheid was given the final death blow when ANC won 62.65 percent of the vote in the first all-race elections.</p>
<p>1996 - Archbishop Desmond Tutu's Truth and Reconciliation Commission begins its task of revealing and healing the injustices of apartheid.</p>
<p>South Africans acknowledge the wounds of apartheid and its economic iniquities will take decades, or even longer, to heal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
