<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5907" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Mauritius bourse up on foreign investor buying.</title>
<headline>Mauritius bourse up on foreign investor buying.</headline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mauritius bourse share index rose 2.85 points to 324.19 on Wednesday as some leading stocks rose on buying by foreign investors, brokers said.</p>
<p>Traded volume was provisionally posted at 8.05 million rupees on 260,094 shares from 4.04 million rupees on 81,541 shares on Monday.</p>
<p>The Mauritius bourse official market trades on Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign investors bought a little today, mostly blue chip stocks such as Mauritius Commercial Bank, State Bank of Mauritius and Mauritius Breweries,&quot; said an official of a leading brokerage house.</p>
<p>The rise in prices of these leading shares pushed up the share index (Semdex), bourse officials said. They added that a majority of volume was concentrated in these stocks while the rest of the market remained flat and attracted thin trading.</p>
<p>Mauritius Commercial Bank was unchanged at 73 rupees on 32,302 shares while State Bank of Mauritius gained 20 cents to 8.50 rupees on 135,000 shares.</p>
<p>Mauritius Breweries surged 5.0 rupees to 123 on 13,950 shares but Mauritius Oil Refineries shed 10 cents to 7.90 rupees on 2,592 shares.</p>
<p>Investment-based United Docks remained at 40.50 rupees on 2,110 shares and National Investment Trust (NIT) was stable at 12.50 rupees on 10,000 shares.</p>
<p>Sugar security Mon Tresor Mon Desert was unchanged at 31.50 rupees on 3,460 shares and Savannah (ordinary) was stable at 123 rupees on 2,247 shares.</p>
<p>Conglomerate Rogers remained at 94.50 rupees on 10,000 shares and New Mauritius Hotels was unchanged at 28 rupees on 10,000 shares.</p>
<p>Hotel concern Sun Resorts was stable at 36 rupees on 2,943 shares and national carrier Air Mauritius climbed 3 rupees to 55 on 9,570 shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
