<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5908" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe strike seen as rising social frustrations.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe strike seen as rising social frustrations.</headline>
<byline>Cris Chinaka</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwe's public servants walked out of their jobs in a rare strike over pay this week, which many local political and economic analysts see as a reflection of heated social frustrations in the southern African state.</p>
<p>Some also believe the strike -- which took President Robert Mugabe's government by surprise -- may also trigger a round of general industrial unrest from workers in private and state enterprises who have been grumbling about low wages.</p>
<p>&quot;There is widespread frustration in the country, and it is much higher in the public service which is closer to political double standards,&quot; said John Makumbe, an outspoken government critic and political scientist at Harare's University of Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>&quot;What the strike shows is that the civil servants can no longer accept the perennial excuse from the government that it can't pay them decent salaries because it has no money. They see how the little there is is being used and mostly wastefully,&quot; Makumbe told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Public Service Association (PSA) union called the strike to press demands for wage rises of around 30 percent, rejecting as &quot;an unacceptable insult&quot; an up to eight percent increase recently awarded by the government.</p>
<p>&quot;Many&quot; in Zimbabwe's 180,000-strong civil service on Wednesday defied government orders to return to work, leaving some critical essential services partially paralysed, according to the PSA.</p>
<p>Major state hospitals throughout the country were struggling to cope with growing queues of patients, and the army was using state radio to recall medical personnel on leave to help out.</p>
<p>The government has declared the strike illegal and threatened to dismiss those who did not return to work on Wednesday, but the PSA said it would not give in without a concrete promise that its grievances would be addressed seriously.</p>
<p>Makumbe said Mugabe's government, whose spending accounts for about 40 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) and last year ran a 10.1 percent budget deficit, seemed only concerned with paying top officials.</p>
<p>&quot;That is what is fuelling public frustration,&quot; he said, noting that the government had paid most of its workers an average 20 percent wage rise last year while Mugabe and huge cabinet awarded themselves over 130 percent.</p>
<p>The ministers have not yet announced their own increases this year, but John Makoni, executive secretary of the Public Service Association, said there was &quot;justified suspicion&quot; the top leaders planned to take big rises again.</p>
<p>Makumbe and Kempton Makamure, another political analyst, said there was also general anger that Mugabe and his dominant ZANU-PF party -- who have ruled with little challenge over the last 16 years -- have a tendency to ride rough-shod.</p>
<p>Unconfirmed reports that the 72-year-old Mugabe had left Harare on a honeymoon with his former presidential secretary, Grace Marufu, 31, whom he wed at a lavish ceremony at the weekend, also fed public anger on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A Zimbabwe Congress of Trade Unions (ZCTU) official told reporters he feared the current civil servants strike could spark unrest in other private and state-owned sectors.</p>
<p>&quot;The possibilities are great but if the government shows flexibility that it is ready to negotiate...the others would take its lead and all we will get is hard bargaining,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Economist John Robertson said the strike showed government should have cut its civil service size and set itself on paying a leaner body better.</p>
<p>&quot;The government would certainly be in a position to pay well if it took this decision. It has been saying for years it wants to do this but it hasn't and this is the result,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The government says workers must demand &quot;reasonable salaries&quot; to help it bring down annual inflation, from about 22 percent now to around 15 percent by next June.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
