<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5909" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa's SAA expands West Africa flight routes.</title>
<headline>S.Africa's SAA expands West Africa flight routes.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African Airways (SAA) said on Wednesday it planned to strengthen its route network into West Africa by introducing a twice weekly service between Johannesburg and Abidjan from November 5.</p>
<p>It said in a statement that it would also increase its weekly service to Accra to twice weekly from November 4, due to the increasing demand for capacity on this popular route.</p>
<p>&quot;The scope of SAA's African route network is substantial and clearly identifies it as the leading carrier on the African continent,&quot; chief executive Mike Myburgh said.</p>
<p>&quot;The continuous growth potential and expansion of the African market - especially for travel to South Africa - cannot be underestimated.&quot;</p>
<p>SAA said that about 80 percent of the traffic on the new Abidjan route would be inbound to South Africa, with an anticipated 20 to 25 percent annual growth potential predicted.</p>
<p>SAA added it was also planning to introduce an additional weekly flight between Cape Town and Windhoek.</p>
<p>The addition of these flights means SAA now offers some 59 weekly departures to 15 destinations within the African continent and Indian Ocean islands.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
