<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5910" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: De Klerk apologises for decades of Afrikaner rule.</title>
<headline>De Klerk apologises for decades of Afrikaner rule.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>When F.W. de Klerk apologised to Archbishop Desmond Tutu's &quot;truth commission&quot; on Wednesday for the sins of apartheid, he was admitting the fault of generations of his white Calvinist Afrikaner nation.</p>
<p>In a 29-page submission explaining the actions of his National Party (NP) during 45 years of apartheid rule, the former president, 60, admitted that many grave mistakes were made.</p>
<p>Acknowledging the mistakes implicated even his own family.</p>
<p>&quot;I retain my deep respect for our former leaders,&quot; de Klerk told the commission that is slowly laying bare the gruesome reality of systematic white oppression.</p>
<p>&quot;Within the context of their time, circumstances and convictions, they were good and honourable men -- although history has subsequently shown that, as far as the policy of apartheid was concerned, they were deeply mistaken in the course upon which they embarked.</p>
<p>&quot;My own father was a cabinet minister under three prime ministers and my aunt was married to a prime minister of South Africa. I myself have always been a loyal supporter of the National Party,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But it was de Klerk who, in 1989, led a cabinet revolt against the increasingly autocratic rule of President P.W. Botha, who had pitted his white-led army and police against the aspirations of the five-to-one black majority.</p>
<p>As president from September that year, de Klerk quickly abandoned the tradition of brutally suppressing black dissent by allowing Tutu to lead a massive march through Cape Town.</p>
<p>On February 2, 1990, de Klerk stunned the world, including most of his own white cabinet, by legalising the long-banned African National Congress, including its armed wing, and the South African Communist Party.</p>
<p>Eight days later, he freed Nelson Mandela after 27 years of political imprisonment and immediately began talks that led to the country's first all-race elections in April 1994.</p>
<p>De Klerk and Mandela shared the Nobel Peace Prize in 1993 for their efforts to end white rule, but Mandela charged even then that &quot;although Mr de Klerk is in discussions with us, he is actually waging a war against our people.&quot;</p>
<p>The relationship between de Klerk, a chain-smoking whisky drinker, and the austere Mandela, who enjoys only an occasional glass of sweet wine, was often strained.</p>
<p>In October last year it degenerated to the extent where the leaders wagged angry fingers at each other in a Johannesburg street after Mandela had blamed de Klerk's former government for continuing violence and crime.</p>
<p>&quot;Our marriage is therefore not a marriage in the real sense of the word. There are some fundamental philosophical differences between us,&quot; de Klerk told Reuters at the time.</p>
<p>De Klerk, a small-town lawyer and a devout Calvinist from a fundamentalist wing of the Reformed Church family, was regarded as a conservative within the white National Party.</p>
<p>His wife Marike, with whom he raised three adopted children, bolstered the conservative label when she described the Afrikaner nation's Coloured cousins as &quot;the leftovers of creation.&quot;</p>
<p>Awed by his own family's central role in creating and implementing the network of segregationist laws that made South Africa an international pariah, de Klerk refused long after he repudiated apartheid to acknowledge that it had been a mistake.</p>
<p>But he has slowly expanded the scope of his apology to the barely qualified confession he made on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not my intention to excuse or gloss over the many unacceptable things that occurred during the period of National Party rule. They happened and caused immeasurable pain and suffering to many.</p>
<p>&quot;I should like to express my deepest sympathy with all those on all sides who suffered during the conflict,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>De Klerk was appointed as one of Mandela's two deputies after the landmark 1994 elections in which his party won 20 percent of the vote.</p>
<p>But he and his party were seen to be sidelined in the new government, having little influence on policy formation and being denied the opposition right to criticise the government of which it was at least nominally a part.</p>
<p>De Klerk withdrew from the coalition at the end of June this year, promising Mandela's African National Congress &quot;a very, very hard time&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
