<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5914" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: De Klerk begins long explanation of apartheid.</title>
<headline>De Klerk begins long explanation of apartheid.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>White former president F.W. de Klerk appeared before South Africa's &quot;truth commission&quot; on Wednesday to begin a lengthy explanation of apartheid from the point of view of his National Party which imposed it.</p>
<p>On his way to the Good Hope centre he drove past a score of black demonstrators carrying placards reading &quot;Apartheid -- never again&quot; and &quot;How many people died during apartheid?&quot;  </p>
<p>Inside, he was greeted with loud applause from the 300-strong crowd, mostly party supporters. Former archbishop Desmond Tutu began proceedings with a prayer.</p>
<p>The reformist de Klerk, who freed Nelson Mandela from jail in 1990 and smoothed the country's successful 1994 transition to democracy after 46 years of white minority rule, has said his party will accept the blame for &quot;many things that went wrong&quot;.</p>
<p>De Klerk said he planned to cover South Africa's history as far back as 1652 when the first white settlers arrived.</p>
<p>South Africans, especially the victims of apartheid, were waiting to see if he would expose new truths about the past, say sorry for its wrongs, or salvage what propaganda value he could for his reformed party, which quit Mandela's coalition in June for a new life in opposition, from the history of race war.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
