<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5915" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: U.N. expects 5,000 more Rwandan refugees to return.</title>
<headline>U.N. expects 5,000 more Rwandan refugees to return.</headline>
<byline>Christian Jennings</byline>
<dateline>BUTARE, Rwanda 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.N. refugee agency said it expected up to 5,000 Rwandan refugees to stream into Rwanda from Burundi on Wednesday as part of the biggest move back since they fled after 1994's genocide.</p>
<p>Paul Stromberg, spokesman for the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) in Rwanda, said 4,500 returned from Magara camp in northern Burundi on Tuesday despite heavy rain turning roads into seas of mud.</p>
<p>&quot;If it doesn't rain heavily again we expect 4,000 to 5,000 back today,&quot; said Stromberg. &quot;On Tuesday we had to call off the operation early because of problems on the Rwandan side of the border.&quot;</p>
<p>He said trucks stopped taking refugees out of Magara camp in Burundi after only four hours on Tuesday as rains on Monday had made an access road to a transit camp impassable so 2,500 were diverted to a stadium in the southern Rwandan town of Butare.</p>
<p>&quot;Between 1,000 and 1,500 had to spend a second night last night at the stadium,&quot; said Stromberg, adding another problem was a shortage of UNHCR plastic sheeting for the returnees.</p>
<p>&quot;We have about 14,000 still in Magara camp and at this rate we theoretically would be down to zero there in a few days. We are now in contact with Burundian authorities to establish what will happen to those people who don't want to return,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The refugee flood swelled after Burundian troops killed three refugees as they tried to flee Magara camp on Sunday. The army said soldiers fired after a Rwandan refugee shot at them.</p>
<p>Some refugees also stoned soldiers at Magara camp after refusing to tear down shelters left empty by returning refugees.</p>
<p>&quot;During the rock throwing incident at Magara it was clear that there are groups who desperately do not want to go back. We hope they will not stop others going back,&quot; Stromberg said.</p>
<p>He said after all those refugees who wanted to leave Magara had done so a repatriation campaign would move on to the last Rwandan refugee camp in Burundi at Rukuramigabo, which has some 13,000 Rwandans.</p>
<p>There were 135,000 Rwandan refugees in Burundi at the start of the year.</p>
<p>Refugees accuse the Tutsi-dominated Burundian army, which seized power on July 25, of a deliberate campaign of harassment and say they are leaving because they fear for their lives.</p>
<p>The flood of Rwandan Hutus this month from Burundi is the biggest mass movement homewards since a total of two million Rwandans fled to Burundi, Tanzania and Zaire in 1994 during civil war and the genocide of up to one million people by Hutus.</p>
<p>&quot;It is good to return. I have not seen Rwanda since August 1994,&quot; said refugee Tharcisse Nyanranzima, unloading plastic sheeting, a bucket and his brother's artificial limb off a lorry at Musange transit camp five km (three miles) outside Butare.</p>
<p>&quot;We should have come home before but the rumours and lies in the Burundi camps are incredible,&quot; said Nyanranzima on Tuesday as sodden refugees sloshed through mud towards the camp.</p>
<p>Hardline Hutus among the refugees say they fear they will be killed if they return to Rwanda in reprisal for the genocide.</p>
<p>Butare governor Atanase Samuhungu told Reuters he expected some refugees to face problems on reaching their home villages.</p>
<p>Burundi's new Tutsi military leader Pierre Buyoya pledged on Tuesday to protect the Rwandan refugees in line with international conventions and said a team of investigators had been sent to northern Burundi to check on their complaints.</p>
<p>Burundian army officers have accused the Rwandan Hutu refugees of backing Hutu Burundian rebels infiltrating Burundi.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUTARE, Rwanda"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
