<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5924" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia's Lebed says clinches Chechen truce.</title>
<headline>Russia's Lebed says clinches Chechen truce.</headline>
<byline>Dmitry Kuznets</byline>
<dateline>NOVYE ATAGI, Russia 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kremlin security chief Alexander Lebed clinched a truce with Chechen rebels on Wednesday night and, just hours short of a grim deadline, promised to halt Russian generals' plan to bomb Grozny.</p>
<p>&quot;Lebed gave a guarantee that there would be no storm of Grozny tomorrow nor in the future,&quot; separatist chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov told Reuters after his late-night talks with President Boris Yeltsin's personal envoy to Chechnya.</p>
<p>Lebed said the Russian army commander's ultimatum to clear the rebel-held Chechen capital before an all-out air and artillery bombardment on Thursday morning was &quot;a bad joke&quot;.</p>
<p>He would meet the separatists again on Thursday at 10 a.m. in the same village, Novye Atagi 20 km (12 miles) south of Grozny, to follow-up their talks on a truce and take &quot;concrete decisions on a ceasefire and separating the warring sides&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I have taken it upon myself never again to give the Chechen side ultimatums,&quot; said Lebed, the man to whom Yeltsin last week gave sweeping powers to make peace after the separatists humiliated the army and seized Grozny on August 6.</p>
<p>The last few days, however, has seen a stream contradiction in Russia over Chechen policy and Lebed was asked by reporters if he was sure he had the power to stop the generals.</p>
<p>&quot;I am going there (Grozny army headquarters) now to see to it that things will be quiet tomorrow,&quot; he said firmly.</p>
<p>Maskhadov, a former colonel in the Soviet army whose forces have proved more than a match for Russian troops in 20 months of fighting, said he was putting his faith in Lebed as a soldier.</p>
<p>&quot;His guarantee was the word of honour of a Russian officer,&quot; he said. &quot;As an officer in the Russia army I trust his word.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We hope Lebed will be able to conquer those in Moscow who do not want to conclude the war...We hope that never again will it be like when we negotiated and then the next day federal forces began to bomb our villages,&quot; Maskhadov said.</p>
<p>He warned, however, that if Lebed was thwarted by enemies in the Kremlin, the war would go on.</p>
<p>&quot;If Lebed does not succeed in stopping the war then we will fight on. That's nothing we're not used to,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>One Chechen woman ran up to a smiling Lebed after he had taken supper with Maskhadov and shouted: &quot;You're our only hope.&quot;</p>
<p>Turning to a small crowd of local people, Lebed said: &quot;We will strive to end the war and justify your hopes.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier in the day, Russian warplanes and artillery had pounded Grozny where tens of thousands of civilians have been unable or unwilling to join thousands of others who have fled.</p>
<p>But the bombing stopped as Lebed flew in and Grozny remained quiet all evening, lit only by the glow from burning buildings.</p>
<p>Asked about his tug-of-war with the generals, Lebed was quoted as saying earlier in the day: &quot;No one has given anyone any powers. You simply have to take it, as I am quietly doing.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Here we have to restore a single command structure.&quot;</p>
<p>Lebed has overall control of decisions affecting Chechnya. On two meetings with Maskhadov last week he laid the ground for a shaky ceasefire that has held for much of the past week.</p>
<p>Russian news agencies said Lebed met the Russian commander, General Vyacheslav Tikhomirov, before heading for the village of Novye Atagi 20 km (12 miles) south of Gronzy.</p>
<p>Tass quoted Lebed as saying after he met Tikhomirov that he would discuss &quot;demilitarising&quot; Grozny and pulling troops away from the foothills of the Caucasus in the south.</p>
<p>The tug of policy between Lebed and the generals highlighted confusion in the absence of Yeltsin. Aides said he was taking a short break in northwest Russia. Interfax said he would be back in Moscow on Wednesday and in the Kremlin on Thursday.</p>
<p>Civilians trapped in cellars, fearing carpet bombing from Russian forces, pleaded for help from the outside world and said they felt they had been abandoned in their own country.</p>
<p>&quot;We are living in uncertainty and confusion, we feel that we have been abandoned in our own country. We ask that you do everything possible to stop this war,&quot; said a handwritten appeal, passed to foreign journalists by a refugee.</p>
<p>The International Committee of the Red Cross urged Russia on Wednesday to extend the ultimatum for civilians to quit Grozny, saying the deadline did not give people time to leave.</p>
<p>The ICRC said in a statement that an estimated 60,000 people left the Chechen capital late last week and a further 70,000 fled on Tuesday. But about 120,000 remained.</p>
<p>Many of Russia's western partners condemned the threat of bombing and urged Russia to halt its Chechnya campaign.</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton sent a letter to Yeltsin urging an end to the violence in Chechnya. The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), which pulled its mission out of Grozny, also called for a peaceful settlement.</p>
<p>A statement by the 51-member Organisation of the Islamic Conference (OIC), the Moslem world's largest organisation, said the group's secretary-general, Hamid Algabid, &quot;expressed serious concern and anguish over the ultimatum&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NOVYE ATAGI, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
