<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5925" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia's Lebed meets rebel chief in Chechnya.</title>
<headline>Russia's Lebed meets rebel chief in Chechnya.</headline>
<byline>Dmitry Kuznets</byline>
<dateline>NOVYE ATAGI, Russia 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian security chief Alexander Lebed met rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov in Chechnya on Wednesday night and vowed to stop Russian generals carrying out a threat to bombard the capital Grozny.</p>
<p>Russian forces had pounded the rebel-held city before Lebed's arrival. Civilians trapped there pleaded for help from the outside world as warplanes dropped tonnes of high explosive.</p>
<p>But the bombing stopped as Lebed flew in and Grozny remained quiet, lit only by the glow from burning buildings.</p>
<p>Lebed, given sweeping powers by President Boris Yeltsin last week to settle the 20-month-old Chechen conflict, said he had come to bring peace and promised to find a solution to the army threat to launch an all-out bombardment on Thursday morning.</p>
<p>Lebed, echoing an earlier comment by Defence Minister Igor Rodionov, said the ultimatum was not approved in Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody agreed it with anyone. Everything is as it was, no one has given anyone any powers. You simply have to take it, as I am quietly doing,&quot; Lebed told Interfax news agency.</p>
<p>&quot;Here we have to restore a single command structure. There will be no more ultimatums.&quot;</p>
<p>Lebed has overall control of decisions affecting Chechnya. On two meetings with Maskhadov last week he laid the ground for a ceasefire. Before Wednesday's meeting, he was quoted as saying he intended to separate the warring sides &quot;as we agreed before&quot;.</p>
<p>The earlier bombing had seemed to signal the start of long-expected air raids to drive out the guerrillas who captured most of the city more than two weeks ago.</p>
<p>But Lebed said he &quot;came with peace&quot; and insisted he would settle the problem of the army ultimatum by Thursday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;We will no longer speak in the language of ultimatums,&quot; he was quoted as saying by Itar-Tass news agency. It was unclear, however, if the generals would heed his commands.</p>
<p>The Russian military command had given civilians 48 hours from Tuesday to quit Grozny before the assault started.</p>
<p>Russian news agencies said Lebed met the Russian commander, Vyacheslav Tikhomirov, before heading for the village of Novye Atagi 20 km (12 miles) south of Gronzy.</p>
<p>Tass quoted Lebed as saying after he met Tikhomirov that he would discuss &quot;demilitarising&quot; Grozny and pulling troops away from the foothills of the Caucasus in the south.</p>
<p>The tug of policy between Lebed and the generals highlighted confusion in the absence of Yeltsin. Aides said he was taking a short break in northwest Russia. Interfax said he would be back in Moscow on Wednesday and in the Kremlin on Thursday.</p>
<p>The military in Chechnya, humiliated by the separatists' August 6 attack on Grozny and fierce fighting in which hundreds were killed, had seemed set on avenging itself.</p>
<p>RIA news agency, quoting the head of the military prosecutor's office in Chechnya, said 420 Russian servicemen had been killed and 1,300 had been wounded in the latest fighting for the control of Grozny, once a city of 400,000 people.</p>
<p>Civilians trapped in cellars, fearing carpet bombing from Russian forces, pleaded for help from the outside world and said they felt they had been abandoned in their own country.</p>
<p>&quot;Our houses are bombarded continuously from heavy weaponry. We are in a desperate state, without bread, water, or light. There are no fighters in our houses, no soldiers, and no one is firing from them, but the bombardment never stops,&quot; said a handwritten appeal, passed to foreign journalists by a refugee.</p>
<p>&quot;We are living in uncertainty and confusion, we feel that we have been abandoned in our own country. We ask that you do everything possible to stop this war.&quot;</p>
<p>The International Committee of the Red Cross urged Russia on Wednesday to extend the ultimatum for civilians to quit Grozny, saying the deadline did not give people time to leave.</p>
<p>The ICRC said in a statement that an estimated 60,000 people left the Chechen capital late last week and a further 70,000 fled on Tuesday. But about 120,000 remained.</p>
<p>The United States, Germany and France condemned the threat of bombing and urged Russia to halt its Chechnya campaign.</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton sent a letter to Yeltsin urging an end to the violence in Chechnya.</p>
<p>The Moslem world's largest organisation called for Moscow to refrain from the use of force and to seek a political agreement to settle the crisis.</p>
<p>A statement by the 51-member Organisation of the Islamic Conference (OIC) said the group's secretary-general, Hamid Algabid, &quot;expressed serious concern and anguish over the ultimatum issued by the Russian military authorities followed by a threat to use all possible means against...Grozny.&quot;</p>
<p>The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), which has pulled its mission out of Grozny, also called for a peaceful settlement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NOVYE ATAGI, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
