<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5933" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: NATO mulls decision on 2,600 tonnes of Serb ammo.</title>
<headline>NATO mulls decision on 2,600 tonnes of Serb ammo.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>NATO is pondering whether to destroy some 2,600 tonnes of Bosnian Serb munitions spread over at least ten different locations, a NATO spokesman said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Major Brett Boudreau said NATO was pressing ahead with Operation Volcano to blow up 400 tonnes of contraband Bosnan Serb munitions, but had still not decided the fate of the extra supplies stored in recently declared sites.</p>
<p>&quot;All options are under consideration,&quot; said Boudreau, hinting the material might not be destroyed.</p>
<p>NATO mounted Operation Volcano on Saturday to destroy 400 tonnes of small arms ammunition and mines discovered by a routine NATO patrol in a schoolhouse in Margetici, near Sokolac, on August 5.</p>
<p>Since then 130 tonnes have been destroyed in a series of controlled explosions in blast pits, shooting towering columns of dirt, smoke and steam 4,000 feet (1,200 metres) into the air.</p>
<p>NATO responded on Tuesday to complaints by the mayor of Sokolac about damage to the underground aquifer which supplies his town by abandoning one set of blast pits even as it proceeded with demolition work in a second set of pits.</p>
<p>If NATO meets its weekend target for destruction of all the munitions found at Margetici, it will still face the problem of what to do about 16 other sites Serbs belatedly declared to NATO on August 5.</p>
<p>Some of the locations contain equipment other than weapons or ammunition, but in at least ten the contents are similar to Margetici.</p>
<p>Since all such sites should have been disclosed to NATO months ago under the terms of the Dayton peace agreement, they are liable to be seized and their contents destroyed.</p>
<p>But having proved its authority at Margetici NATO may be tempted to allow the Serbs to move the contraband to an already approved storage site.</p>
<p>That would save NATO the effort and responsibility entailed in transporting and destroying such a huge amount of material and might improve relations with the Bosnian Serbs.</p>
<p>Serbs have not been the only faction to violate clauses in the Dayton agreement dealing with weapons and ammunition.</p>
<p>NATO forces stopped a Bosnian Army truck carrying about 20 soldiers near Tuzla on Tuesday and discovered a number of unauthorised weapons inside.</p>
<p>Sources said the contraband, which included assault rifles and anti-tank weapons, would be destroyed.</p>
<p>NATO also reported it had destroyed a total of 1,242 weapons previously confiscated.</p>
<p>More than half the total were from the Moslem-led Bosnian Army side and included small arms, surface-to-air missiles, anti-aircraft machine-guns, mortars and rocket-propelled grenades.</p>
<p>&quot;The weapons were destroyed on 16 and 17 August after having been held for a period of time,&quot; said a NATO source who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;We're being even-handed about discharging our duty under Dayton. If we find unauthorised weapons or ammuntion we will confiscate and destroy it no matter whose it is.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
