<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5934" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Poland - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Poland - Aug 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- Poland's ombudsman, Adam Zielinski, has decided to file charges against the communications ministry's GSM cellular telephone operator licensing decision forcing operators to use the TPSA telecommunications monopolist network.</p>
<p>Law violations present in the decision were also jointly announced by the Antimonopoly Office and Consumers Federation.</p>
<p>- In 1995 taxpayers used the donation clause in the tax law to write off 4.3 billion zlotys.</p>
<p>&quot;In the coming five years the finance ministry will examine 3.6 million taxpayers who applied the donation clause in their tax returns,&quot; deputy finance minister Witold Manugiewicz said.</p>
<p>- Solidarity trade unions have demanded a 30 zloty monthly salary increase for public sector workers while Labour Minister Andrzej Baczkowski declared he is ready for a 15 zloty rise.</p>
<p>- Right-wing Movement for the Reconstruction of Poland (ROP) leader Jan Olszewski sharply criticised Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz for being televised wearing a baseball cap with the Mitsubishi company logo.</p>
<p>&quot;Jan Olszewski's accusation  are hilarious,&quot; government spokeswoman Aleksandra Jakubowska said.</p>
<p>- The newly formed Chemia Polska Holding should be privatised in the coming two or three years.  By year-end a list of firms to be included within the holding will be published, the holding's President Ludwik Klinkosz said.</p>
<p>- According to Agriculture Minister Roman Jagielinski this year's grain harvests should bring 24 million tonnes of grain, two million tonnes less than last year, while Central Statistics Office forecasts see the harvests at last year's results.</p>
<p>- Over the first seven months of 1996, 230,766 new cars were sold in Poland, which showed 33 percent sales growth compared with the same period last year. Fiat reported the largest sales, amounting to 9,8545 cars.</p>
<p>NOWA EUROPA</p>
<p>- Poles have been buying less beef recently, which shows they do not trust the government which repeatedly assured that no British beef was imported to Poland following the mad cow disease fear, Mokpol retail company representatives said.</p>
<p>- The Swedish-based Securitas security agency has entered the Polish security services market.</p>
<p>It bought two Polish-based security agencies, Norma and SET, and plans to invest extensively in marketing, Securitas information director Amund Skarhalt said.</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>-According to legal experts, the state's ZUS social insurance agency will not be able to withhold private passports of employers who are overdue with social insurance contributions.</p>
<p>The only thing ZUS can do is to take the recalcitrant payers to court, Wroclaw  University legal experts said.</p>
<p>- Pekao SA bank will be the first to introduce the housing contract credit system this autumn, Pekao official Jolanta Kiwinska said.</p>
<p>ZYCIE WARSZAWY</p>
<p>- Parliamentary deputies who joined the committee investigating the spy scandal invoving former Prime Minister Jozef Oleksy disagree on the committee's final report.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no chance for a compromise as the matter relates to a politician whose powers are still significant,&quot; opposition centrist Union for Freedom deputy Bogdan Borusewicz said.</p>
<p>- A banking consortium headed by Pekao SA and including three other consumer credit banks --  Bank Depozytowo- Kredytowy(BDK), Powszechny Bank Gospodarczy (PBG) and Pomorski Bank Kredytowy (PBK) -- will be formed in mid-September this year.</p>
<p>PARKIET</p>
<p>- Polish Development Bank (PBR) will be the third Polish bank to issue Eurobonds denominated in US dollars in accordance with the recent decision by the bank's extraordinary shareholders meeting.</p>
<p>- This week trade unions and the consortium of Euro Agro Centrum and South African Breweries (SAB) Ltd will start negotiations on the social package of the Browary Tyskie breweries, a controlling stake in which is to be bouhgt by the consortium in September.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
