<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5937" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Aug 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>STANDART</p>
<p>-- The lev fell beyond 200 per dollar on the interbank market on Tuesday on rising demand for foreign currency from final clients.</p>
<p>-- Journalists are to blame for the government's clash with wheat producers over grain purchasing prices, prime minister Zhan Videnov told municipal officials from Montana region. @</p>
<p>-- The National Electricity Company has halted all payments in a bid to raise $5 million owed to Russia for fuel deliveries for the Kozloduy nuclear power plant, Balkan news agency said.</p>
<p>TRUD</p>
<p>-- The government plans to ban the State Savings Bank from extending loans to the agricultural sector within three weeks, prime minister Zhan Videnov said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's most famous psychic Vanga has bequeathed all her property to the state, Petrich mayor Andon Chopakov said. @</p>
<p>-- German judiciary have agreed to extradite the head of Bulgaria's Life Choice get-rich-quick fund Michael Kapustin to face embezzlement charges in Bulgaria, an official from the Bulgaria's chief prosecutor's office said.</p>
<p>-- The central bank (BNB) on Tuesday cut to 20 percent from 50 percent the share of minimum required reserves of commercial banks that banks can use daily as an overdraft on their settlement accounts at the BNB.</p>
<p>The move was aimed at draining free liquidity to relieve pressure on the falling lev.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 981 8569</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
