<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5940" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Lebed says ends threat to Grozny, generals silent.</title>
<headline>Lebed says ends threat to Grozny, generals silent.</headline>
<byline>Dmitry Kuznets</byline>
<dateline>NOVYE ATAGI, Russia 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alexander Lebed, the man President Boris Yeltsin sent to make peace in Chechnya, said he had saved the people of Grozny from the Russian army's threat to flatten their city on Thursday morning.</p>
<p>But, with no word from the military command in the region, it may be daylight before the hundred thousand or so frightened civilians in the Chechen capital can feel surer that the president's man has prevailed over his own generals.</p>
<p>The Kremlin security chief said he agreed a ceasefire at an 11th hour meeting on Wednesday night with the commander of the separatist rebels who seized most of Grozny a fortnight ago.</p>
<p>Lebed assured Aslan Maskhadov that the Russian generals' ultimatum was &quot;a bad joke&quot; and said there would be no bombing.</p>
<p>&quot;Lebed gave a guarantee that there would be no storm of Grozny tomorrow nor in the future,&quot; Maskhadov, the separatist chief-of-staff, told Reuters after his late-night talks with Yeltsin's security chief in the village of Novye Atagi.</p>
<p>&quot;I have taken it upon myself never again to give the Chechen side ultimatums,&quot; said Lebed, telling local people who gathered around that he would strive to justify their trust.</p>
<p>The two men, who seemed at ease with each other, agreed the need for a truce. Lebed said they would meet at 10 a.m. (0600 GMT) on Thursday to take &quot;concrete decisions on a ceasefire&quot;.</p>
<p>But ceasefires have come and gone in 20 months of war in Chechnya. And, with Russia's chain of command looking more than usually tangled over the past few days, it will be some hours before Grozny can be sure that Lebed is as good as his word.</p>
<p>Asked about his tug-of-war with the generals, Lebed was quoted as saying: &quot;No one has given anyone any powers. You simply have to take it, as I am quietly doing.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We have to restore a single command structure.&quot;</p>
<p>The acting Russian commander in the region made his threat of an all-out bombardment on Monday. He accused the rebels of abusing a shaky truce agreed last week with Lebed's help and gave civilians 48 hours to Thursday morning to flee their homes.</p>
<p>His superior, General Vyacheslav Tikhomirov, returned from holiday and sounded equally bellicose on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The army seemed set on avenging the humiliation of losing Grozny to Maskhadov's irregular but well-led guerrillas.</p>
<p>Tikhomirov met Lebed before he headed off for his talks with Maskhadov. But by the small hours of Thursday there was still no confirmation from the generals that they would hold their fire.</p>
<p>One hopeful sign for those in Grozny -- the Red Cross estimated there were now about 120,000 after a similar number fled the past fortnight's fighting -- was the lull that set in over the city as soon as Lebed landed.</p>
<p>Reuters correspondent Lawrence Sheets saw Russian aircraft flying over Grozny on Wednesday afternoon, dropping more high explosive on the ruined capital in what seemed like a dress rehearsal for the promised all-out strike.</p>
<p>But around 6 p.m. (1400 GMT), all went quiet. At about the same time, Lebed, a tough-talking former paratroop general, flew in to the military base at nearby Khankala to meet Tikhomirov.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, as commander-in-chief of Russia's armed forces, is in overall command of Moscow's biggest military engagement since the Afghan war. But at his only public appearance in seven weeks he looked stiff and tired. Aides say he is resting and denied reports he has suffered a recurrence of heart trouble.</p>
<p>Interfax news agency said he was due back at his Kremlin desk on Thursday after a two-day break in the northwest lakes.</p>
<p>The absence has fuelled speculation about Yeltsin's health and the chain of command in Chechnya if he were not in control.</p>
<p>Lebed's Security Council added to that on Tuesday when it issued a statement questioning the authenticity of a presidential order instructing Lebed to restore order in Grozny -- an order it said was the cue for the army ultimatum.</p>
<p>Maskhadov said the separatist leadership remained wary of in-fighting in Moscow that could thwart Lebed's peacemaking.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope Lebed will be able to conquer those in Moscow who do not want to conclude the war,&quot; he said. But he warned: &quot;If Lebed does not succeed in stopping the war, we will fight on.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NOVYE ATAGI, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
