<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5949" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary to sign Romania treaty despite criticism.</title>
<headline>Hungary to sign Romania treaty despite criticism.</headline>
<byline>Sandor Peto</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary said on Wednesday it would sign a treaty with Romania to lay new foundations of their relationship despite strong criticism of the planned accord from opposition parties and ethnic Hungarian leaders abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;We are ready to sign the treaty in September,&quot; Foreign Minister Laszlo Kovacs told a news conference.</p>
<p>The treaty is essential for the two country's ambitions to join the European Union and the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation.</p>
<p>Hungarian and Romanian experts began negotiations in Budapest on Wednesday to put the last touches to the treaty, the fruit of some four years of on-off talks.</p>
<p>However, a torrent of criticism of the planned treaty since last week's breakthrough has introduced a sour taste into the talks as well as marring the celebrations of the 1,100th anniversary of the Hungarians' settlement in Central Europe held earlier this week.</p>
<p>Hungarian opposition leaders and representatives of Hungarian communities in both Romania and Slovakia have accused Budapest of neglecting the interests of millions of Hungarians living in neighbouring countries.</p>
<p>The focus of their anger is a footnote to the treaty agreed with Romania as a way out of the deadlock which they allege limits the scope of autonomy for minorities and could legally be applied also to a similar treaty recently signed between Hungary and Slovakia.</p>
<p>&quot;A planned footnote, refusing ethnic-based territorial autonomy and collective rights, practically means that it refuses all strivings for autonomy,&quot; said Miklos Duray, chairman of Coexistence, one of the largest ethnic Hungarian organisations in Slovakia.</p>
<p>But Kovacs said the footnote only confirmed the fact that the European Council's Recommendation 1201 on ethnic minority rights, to be included in the treaty, fails to refer to ethnic-based territorial autonomy or collective rights.</p>
<p>Hungary would continue to support the efforts of ethnic Hungarians to create autonomous organisations and practise their rights collectively according to European standards, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;The treaty will provide (ethnic Hungarians) a much wider reference base concerning their rights than before,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Fears in Slovakia and Romania -- mostly fuelled by nationalist parties -- that Hungary seeks to regain territories it lost to them after World War One have made the issue of ethnic autonomy rights a major stumbling block to the improvement of their relations with Hungary.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
