<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5950" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: OSCE penalises Bosnian Croats.</title>
<headline>OSCE penalises Bosnian Croats.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe, which is in charge of Bosnia's elections, penalised Bosnian Croats in a southern town on Wednesday for &quot;a serious violation&quot; of electoral rules.</p>
<p>OSCE representatives said an official of the ruling Croatian Democratic Union (HDZ) in Jasenica illegally took completed voter registration forms from the town's registration centre .</p>
<p>&quot;The actions of the HDZ constitute a serious violation of the integrity, confidentiality and non-partisan nature of the voter registration process,&quot; the OSCE's Election Appeals Sub-Commission (EASC) said in a statement.</p>
<p>It ordered the immediate dismissal of the local election commission president, the removal of HDZ candidate Vlado Bevanda from the party's list and the payment of a $10,000 fine by the HDZ.</p>
<p>The EASC has previously punished the ruling Bosnian Serb and Moslem parties for election infringements in Doboj and Bihac respectively.</p>
<p>U.S. envoy Robert Frowick, who heads the OSCE election mission in Bosnia, told reporters in Vienna on Wednesday that his organisation had problems in nine municipalities across Bosnia and had taken action against clear irregularities.</p>
<p>&quot;In Doboj (in Bosnian Serb territory) for example, there was an effort to tell individual voters that if they didn't register to vote as the authorities wished they would be denied humanitarian aid,&quot; Frowick said.</p>
<p>The OSCE demanded an end to the practice and got a public apology from the local Serb Democratic Party, which was also fined $25,000, he added. The fine will be deducted from the cash the OSCE is making available to all parties for campaigning.</p>
<p>In Bihacembers of the ruling Moslem SDA party were struck off the candidates' list and the party was fined for orchestrating an armed assault on former Bosnian prime minister Haris Siljadzic, who now heads the opposition Party for Bosnia Herzegovina.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
