<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5954" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish pork prices seen up in H2 on lower output.</title>
<headline>Polish pork prices seen up in H2 on lower output.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish procurement prices of pigs may rise by 30-35 percent in the second half of 1996 triggering a rise in pork belly prices, a Farm Market Agency (ARR) official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The average procurement price of pigs may rise from June to December by 30-35 percent,&quot; Magdalena Zadura told Reuters.</p>
<p>She added that such a price rise would likely push pork belly prices to five zlotys per kg. Last week frozen pork bellies sold at 4.20 zlotys per kg on Polish physical exchanges and fresh pork bellies traded at 4.80 zlotys. @</p>
<p>ARR forecasts a rise in pork prices because of an expected drop in output in the second half of the year following a fall in profitability of its production in the first half which resulted in an 8.1 percent reduction in the pig herd.</p>
<p>&quot;The current state of the pig herd signals that the production of pork will be about 15 percent lower in the second half compared with the same period of 1995,&quot; ARR spokesman Stanislaw Myslinski said.</p>
<p>The Agriculture Ministry forecasts meat production in the second half will be 150,000 tonnes lower than in the same period of last year, mainly because of lower pork production. @</p>
<p>Myslinski said, however, that ARR intervention sales should stabilise the market and prevent any significant shortage.</p>
<p>&quot;Considering that about 60,000 tonnes of frozen pork bellies from ARR reserves will hit the market in the second half, the total supply of meat is expected to be only four percent lower than in the second half of 1995,&quot; Myslinski said.</p>
<p>He added that so far intervention imports of meat were not being considered. --Robert Bogdanski +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
