<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5956" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian liberals demand halt to Grozny bloodbath.</title>
<headline>Russian liberals demand halt to Grozny bloodbath.</headline>
<byline>Elaine Monaghan</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's leading human rights activist left his sickbed on Wednesday to try to stop the Russian military bombing the Chechen capital Grozny and urged his fellow Russians and the West to help.</p>
<p>&quot;Something monstrous is happening right before our eyes,&quot; Sergei Kovalyov, who is recovering from a heart attack, told a news conference called at short notice on Pushkin Square.</p>
<p>As he spoke, bombs crashed down on the Chechen capital, in what might be the start of threatened air raids to drive out rebels who captured much of the city on August 6.</p>
<p>Kovalyov, 66, said all those who backed President Boris Yeltsin in last month's presidential election must urge him to stand by his campaign promises to stop the bloodshed in Chechnya.</p>
<p>&quot;We must not be silent. In the end, if there is no reaction, we must launch acts of civil disobedience,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Liberal members of parliament joined Kovalyov in calling for mass protests against the war, which began in December 1994 when Yeltsin sent his forces to crush Chechnya's independence drive.</p>
<p>White-haired and intense as ever but looking rather frail after his heart attack last month, Kovalyov urged Western leaders like Germany's Chancellor Helmut Kohl and U.S. President Bill Clinton to join his protest.</p>
<p>&quot;The time for persuasion has passed. It is time to make demands,&quot; said the former dissident, who spent 10 years in Soviet labour camps and internal exile.</p>
<p>&quot;A bloody attempt is being prepared to restore what cannot be restored -- the prestige of talentless generals,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Russian military in Chechnya has vowed to stage an all-out attack on Grozny on Thursday morning. Tens of thousands of civilians, given 48 hours to flee, have flooded out of the city, but the Red Cross says about 120,000 people remain.</p>
<p>&quot;Now a new assault is being prepared and Grad missiles and bombs will fall on the most defenceless people,&quot; Kovalyov said. &quot;Old people, children and pregnant women will suffer the most.&quot;</p>
<p>Sergei Yushenkov, a soldier turned liberal politician, said he could understand Western leaders' silence on Chechnya in the run-up to the presidential election as they feared Communist leader Gennady Zyuganov might win. &quot;But what's stopping them actively opposing the Chechen war now?&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kovalyov, once Yeltsin's human rights commissioner, has always criticised the 20-month-old Chechen campaign in which more than 30,000 people, mostly civilians, have been killed.</p>
<p>Many liberals had reservations in backing Yeltsin for re-election and the president, taking a break in the northern lakes far from Moscow, got a tongue-lashing on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Kovalyov mocked Kremlin aides, who explained Yeltsin's absence from Moscow by saying he had gone to the Valdai region to see if it was a good place for a longer holiday. &quot;What's he up to? Gone off to check if the roof's leaking?&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Was there really no one else apart from him to check what was going on in Valdai? This is a monstrous act of irresponsibility -- if it is true.&quot;</p>
<p>Interfax news agency later quoted a source close to Yeltsin as saying he would return to Moscow later on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Kovalyov said that perhaps Yeltsin was really ill, as has been widely speculated, in which case his prime minister should take over in line with the constitution.</p>
<p>&quot;If the president is sick, he has a legal deputy. His name is Viktor Stepanovich Chernomyrdin. We can demand action from him -- and with more success by the way,&quot; Kovalyov said.</p>
<p>&quot;How long will we put up with these desperate lies which they've been ramming down our throats...for more than 80 years?&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
