<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5959" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech Komercni share jump spurs Prague bourse.</title>
<headline>Czech Komercni share jump spurs Prague bourse.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A late rally by shares in Komercni Banka pushed the Prague Stock Exchange higher on Wednesday, in a listless summer holiday trading session.</p>
<p>Komercni, the Czech Republic's largest commercial bank, jumped 81 crowns near the end of the day, propelling the Reuters RPIX index 12 points higher to 1,152. The broader PX50 index rose 2.6 points, or 0.46 percent, to 567.5.</p>
<p>Dealers said the rise was similar to one experienced by SPT Telecom on Monday, when one investor purposely moved the price at the end of the day, which often occurs in the market, usually for accounting reasons.</p>
<p>Total volume on the day was light at 546,000 on turnover of 388.8 million crowns.</p>
<p>Electrical utility CEZ closed down slightly despite announcing lower half year profits.</p>
<p>CEZ's first half net profit, calculated according to Czech accounting standards eased to 5.1 billion crowns from a previous 5.57 billion. Under international accounting standards its net profit was 5.95 billion, down from 6.26 billion.</p>
<p>CEZ shares dipped two crowns to 1,043 crowns, with most analysts saying the market had already discounted the lower profit figure.</p>
<p>But, warned Jan Sykora, a broker with Prague's Wood and Company: &quot;There are still many unclear things. CEZ, despite the increase of market share, will rather lose its positions.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Alan Crosby, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
