<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5960" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russians pound Grozny, but policy confused.</title>
<headline>Russians pound Grozny, but policy confused.</headline>
<byline>Janet Guttsman</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian artillery and aircraft pounded the Chechen capital Grozny for several hours on Wednesday as new contradictions surfaced over Moscow's policy towards the breakaway region.</p>
<p>The military in Chechnya, humiliated by separatists who captured much of the city on August 6, seemed determined to use whatever force required to drive the rebels out of Grozny.</p>
<p>But President Boris Yeltsin's security chief, Alexander Lebed, who visited Chechnya on Wednesday for the third time in just over a week, wants to use peaceful means to resolve the conflict, in which tens of thousands of people have been killed.</p>
<p>&quot;I come with peace,&quot; he said as he arrived at the Russian army based outside Grozny, according to Itar-Tass news agency.</p>
<p>The president himself, seen just once in public since July 26, stayed out of sight, although Interfax news agency said he would return to Moscow on Wednesday from a two-day break in the lakelands of northwestern Russia and be back at work at the Kremlin on Thursday.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's press office, which has been almost as elusive as the president in recent days, could not comment on the report.</p>
<p>&quot;We are aware of the report. We can neither confirm it nor deny it,&quot; a spokesman said.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's disappearance has unsettled Russia's financial markets, where traders are also alarmed at a series of media reports that the president has had a recurrance of the heart problems which put him in hospital twice last year.</p>
<p>One rumour circulating on Wednesday said Yeltsin was dead, but this, like the other reports, was denied by the presidential press office. &quot;I am firmly convinced that he is alive. He has been signing decrees,&quot; a spokesman said.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's absence has also increased the sense of confusion about who is in charge of Russian security issues, which are theoretically shared between Lebed's Security Council and the ministries for defence and the interior.</p>
<p>&quot;When Yeltsin is absent there is a pervasive feeling that nobody is in command,&quot; said one Western diplomat. &quot;The basic problem is the lack of any regular institutional line of command on security matters.&quot;</p>
<p>Defence Minister Igor Rodionov on Wednesday dismissed an ultimatum by Russia's deputy military commander in the region for people to quit Grozny or face bombing raids.</p>
<p>Many civilians, afraid that the threat will be carried out, have already fled Grozny, although others are still hiding in the cellars of the city, home to 400,000 people before Russia sent in the troops in December 1994 to crush an indepedence bid.</p>
<p>Trapped residents, whose fears were heightened by shelling and bombing on Wednesday afternoon, pleaded for help.</p>
<p>&quot;Our houses are bombarded continuously from heavy weaponry. We are in a desperate state, without bread, water, or light. There are no fighters in our houses, no soldiers, and no one is firing from them, but the bombardment never stops,&quot; said a handwritten statement from local residents handed to reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;We are living in uncertainty and confusion, we feel that we have been abandoned in our own country. We ask that you do everything possible to stop this war.&quot;</p>
<p>Troops from both the defence and the interior ministries are based in Chechnya, but Lebed said after a visit there last week that they were demoralised and poorly clothed and equipped.</p>
<p>The latest fighting -- the head of the military prosecutor's office in Chechnya told RIA news agency that 420 Russian servicemen had been killed and 1,300 had been wounded -- has prompted criticism at home and abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;It should be clear to the parties involved that after 20 months of conflict the dispute there cannot be resolved by use of force,&quot; U.S. State Department spokesman Glyn Davies said.</p>
<p>&quot;There has to be an element of negotiation.&quot;</p>
<p>The German Foreign Ministry said Russia should look for a peaceful solution involving the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe, which on Wednesday abandoned its central Grozny office in anticipation of the threatened bombing.</p>
<p>Russian human rights campaigner Sergei Kovalyov, recovering from a heart attack, called on Yeltsin to stop the fighting.</p>
<p>&quot;Something monstrous is happening right before our eyes,&quot; the former dissident told an outdoor news conference on Pushkin Square in the centre of Moscow.</p>
<p>Kovalyov, once Yeltsin's human rights commissioner, was always an outspoken critic of the 20-month-old Chechen campaign in which more than 30,000 people, mostly civilians, have died.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
