<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5964" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Dayton is being badly implemented - Izetbegovic.</title>
<headline>Dayton is being badly implemented - Izetbegovic.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dayton accord is being badly implemented, forcing loyal citizens to accept in peace what they fought against in war, Bosnian President Alija Izetbegovic said in a speech on Wednesday.</p>
<p>His remarks cast doubt on the legitimacy of the Bosnian peace process and of nationwide elections scheduled for September 14.</p>
<p>&quot;No one can expect us to legalise something that we have been fighting against and ask us to accept the results of a war of conquest and genocide,&quot; Izetbegovic told an international conference on post-war Bosnia.</p>
<p>&quot;A hesitant, inconsistent and insufficient implementation of the Dayton agreement just leads to that. As days go by our doubts and questions are multiplying.&quot;</p>
<p>Dayton brought an end to the 43-month Bosnian war last December and set a course for the country's reunification as a unitary, multi-ethnic state within its pre-war borders.</p>
<p>Bosnia's three armies were supposed to stand down, freedom of movement was meant to be restored and refugees were guaranteed the right to return to homes from which had been ethnically cleansed.</p>
<p>The peace process was then to culminate in free and fair elections to establish common institutions to bind Bosnians together in a decentralized state comprised of a Moslem-Croat federation and a Serb republic.</p>
<p>The deployment of 53,000 NATO-led combat troops forced Bosnia's three armies to return to barracks and store their weapons and ammunition in cantonment areas open to inspection.</p>
<p>By comparison, the civilian side of the Dayton agreement has limped forward with constant obstruction from Bosnia's three main nationalist parties.</p>
<p>Hardline separatist Croats and Serbs have not abandoned their desire to break-away from Bosnia.</p>
<p>While Izetbegovic's Moslem nationalist SDA party preached multi-ethnicity during the war it too is drifting away from that position under constant pressure from Croats and Serbs whose mono-ethnic politics are proving contagious.</p>
<p>The SDA's commitment to a unitary state now appears based more on territorial ambition than ethnic tolerance.</p>
<p>These communal tensions have stymied freedom of movement, making it virtually impossible for refugees to return to their homes across what have become de facto ethnic boundary lines.</p>
<p>Even the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe which is supervising the elections admits there is little prospect of the vote being free or fair.</p>
<p>By most accounts the nationalist parties will win handily, with the Croats and Serbs interpreting the result as a referendum endorsing their partition policies rather than reunification.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot afford to lose in peace what we have defended with our blood in the hard years of the war,&quot; Izetbegovic told his audience on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Our goal is an integral and democratic Bosnia and Hercegovina and a stable peace.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
