<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5973" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish fixed bond prices seen rising at tender.</title>
<headline>Polish fixed bond prices seen rising at tender.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prices for Poland's fixed 16-percent two-year and 12-percent five-year bonds are expected to rise at the treasury's joint 800 million zloty primary auction on Thursday, analysts said.</p>
<p>They said the average yield on the two-year paper would likely fall below 19.6 percent from 19.95 percent at the last auction on July 18 and the maximum yield was expected to fall to about 19.7 percent from 20.25 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Yields on two-year paper are likely to fall in line with the graduall decline of T-bills yields, I expect them to be between 10 to 15 basis points below the last primary 52-week T-bill yield of 19.73 percent,&quot; said Piotr Las, deputy head of Fixed Income department at Creditanstalt Securities in Warsaw.</p>
<p>&quot;Two year paper may be a good alternative for those who usually purchase T-bills as an investment device rather than for trading,&quot; Las added.</p>
<p>The maximum yield for the five-year paper was expected to fall to below 18 percent from 18.06 percent on July 18 with the average yield falling to about 18.06 from 18.14 percent. @</p>
<p>They said demand at the auction would likely be around the treasury's offer with the majority of the bids placed for the shorter two-year paper.</p>
<p>&quot;We have observed increased turnover of two-year bonds on the secondary market and demand should concentrate on the shorter paper tomorrow as investors want to refresh their portfolios,&quot; said Pawel Dudzinski from Pekao SA.</p>
<p>The 16-percent two-year bonds mature on October 12 1998 and the 12-percent five-year bonds on October 12, 2001.</p>
<p>The settlement date for the shorter paper is September 5, 1996 and September 12, 1996 for the longer paper.</p>
<p>-- Krzysztof Wojcik +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
