<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5980" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: OSCE braces for invasion of Bosnia poll reporters.</title>
<headline>OSCE braces for invasion of Bosnia poll reporters.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds and perhaps thousands of reporters will descend on Bosnia to cover the mid-September elections, the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody knows for sure but we estimate there could be 2,500 or more journalists including Bosnian reporters for the period right around elections,&quot; said OSCE official Nicole Szulc. The OSCE is responsible for organising the vote.</p>
<p>Bosnians go to the polls on September 14 in their country's first post-war national elections.</p>
<p>Meeting the needs of the press will not be easy, especially since the OSCE estimates it could take up to ten days to tally the election results.</p>
<p>In order to count and disseminate results the OSCE is building a big media facility at Sarajevo's Skenderija Sports Centre, where some of the 1984 Winter Olympics events were held.</p>
<p>The OSCE's main tabulation centre will be located there, as will a press centre capable of seating 1,000 reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;People are going to be hanging around for days waiting for the count and we needed a spot that can accommodate them,&quot; explained Szulc.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll be able to project results into the press centre from the tabulation centre and transmit them directly to television cameras... It will be state of the art for this part of the world.&quot;</p>
<p>NATO-led peace implementation forces in Bosnia operate a sizeable press centre at Sarajevo's Holiday Inn where NATO, U.N. and other officials brief the media six days a week.</p>
<p>Spending money to keep two such centres running during the weeks around the election strikes some as an extravagance in a country where many people still live in poverty.</p>
<p>One critic on Wednesday estimated the OSCE's price tag at $1 million. Another put it a little lower, at one million Deutsche Marks.</p>
<p>If the OSCE knows, it isn't saying. But it makes the point that, whatever the cost, a substantial portion must be allocated to the computer centre needed to tabulate election results, which is not an elective expenditure.</p>
<p>&quot;The Holiday Inn isn't large enough to hold the crowd we expect and it wasn't suitable for the tabulation centre,&quot; explained Szulc.</p>
<p>&quot;We were particularly interested in having a location that is comfortable for Bosnian reporters since these are their elections. Skenderija is one of the few locations people still seem to have good feelings about, because of the Olympics.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
