<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5982" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbia sets local elections in November.</title>
<headline>Serbia sets local elections in November.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbia plans to hold local elections on November 3, the same day federal and Montenegrin polls are due to be held in rump Yugoslavia, state media reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The announcement piled more pressure on the fragmented opposition already struggling to prepare for the federal parliamentary vote.</p>
<p>Political analysts said holding municipal elections the same day as the federal polls will strengthen the hand of Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic's ruling Socialist party and his wife's neo-communist Yugoslav United Left (JUL).</p>
<p>Opposition parties, which hold a majority in some town councils, have long hoped to weaken the Socialists by asserting themselves at the local level.</p>
<p>With less than 80 days to organise themselves, the opposition will be hard-pressed just to preserve their current position.</p>
<p>Serbian parliamentary speaker Dragan Tomic said the local elections would also cover city assemblies for Belgrade, Kragujevac, Nis, Novi Sad and Pristina.</p>
<p>The tiny republic of Montenegro, which together with Serbia comprises what is left of Yugoslavia, is also holding its elections on November 3.</p>
<p>The ruling Socialists are relying on the tightly-controlled state media to help stifle the opposition, which is preoccupied with internal debates.</p>
<p>Milosevic is considered the de facto ruler of rump Yugoslavia. His second and final term as president of Serbia expires in 1997 and he is widely expected to run for the Yugoslav presidency next year.</p>
<p>The authorities hope November elections would provide Milosevic with a clear majority in the federal parliament.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
