<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5984" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech finmin says seeks broad spending cuts.</title>
<headline>Czech finmin says seeks broad spending cuts.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech finance ministry is seeking cuts of roughly more than one percent from the 1996 budgets of every ministry in order to balance the state budget by the year's end, a senior ministry official said.</p>
<p>&quot;The total we need to cut is roughly 9.3 billion crowns,&quot; Deputy Finance Minister Miroslav Havel told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Earlier, Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus told a news conference after a cabinet meeting that a finance ministry plan to balance the budget would be on the cabinet's agenda next week.</p>
<p>The treasury's Havel said the cuts, needed because of a projected 6.6 billion crown revenue shortfall and a 2.7 billion over-expenditure from the originally approved balanced budget, would not affect pensions or civil service wages.</p>
<p>&quot;(The cuts) will touch every ministry and in the same level -- the same percentaduction of several non-investment outlays. Certainly we're not cutting pensions or wages,&quot; said Havel, who directs budget planning for the ministry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
