<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5985" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian stocks mixed, traders predict stedy rise.</title>
<headline>Croatian stocks mixed, traders predict stedy rise.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks were mixed on Wednesday and traders predicted steady rise of blue chips as the number of share-buyers grows.</p>
<p>&quot;Zagrebacka Banka and Pliva will see a steady growth with more people buying shares instead of saving foreign currency,&quot; Marijana Reskovac of Karlovacka Banka told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Hoteliers might boom after the tourist season is over as their prices are pretty low at the moment,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>* Of seven active issues three rose, two were flat and one fell.</p>
<p>* Drugs firm Pliva gained 350 kuna to 11,350 trading 275 shares.</p>
<p>* Most active Zagrebacka Banka was up 20 kuna to 670 on volume of 16.049 units.</p>
<p>* Foodprocessor Podravka closed 20 kuna up at 215 kuna and 504 units changed hands.</p>
<p>* Brewerey Karlovacka Pivovara which last traded earlier in the month was up one kuna to 178 and sold 533 shares.</p>
<p>* Both hoteliers that traded stayed unchanged.</p>
<p>- Arenaturist was flat at 100 kuna with 529 shares sold.</p>
<p>- Laguna was also flat at 800 kuna but only 45 shares changed hands.</p>
<p>* Confectioner Kras, the only loser, edged down 5 kuna with 570 units sold.</p>
<p>* Daily volume up at 18,505 shares, turnover also higher at 14,047 kuna.</p>
<p>* Central bank's exchange rate: 5.2918 = $ 1. -- Metka Jelenc, Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-455075.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
