<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5986" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenian shares ease, seen lower by end Aug.</title>
<headline>Slovenian shares ease, seen lower by end Aug.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenian shares eased 0.12 percent on Wednesday and market participants said a gentle downward trend may continue to the end of August but forecast a rebound in September.</p>
<p>Creditanstalt analyst Gregor Kastelic noted investors would return from their holidays soon.</p>
<p>&quot;Then some capital should to return to the market..and investors...may show confidence in the newly listed shares of strong privatised companies,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Thirteen newly privatised companies have already been listed on the primary or OTC markets of the Ljubljana bourse and another 15 are expected by the end of the year.</p>
<p>* The seven-share SBI index eased 1.15 points to 982.92.</p>
<p>* Five shares fell and 10 rose, while eight were untraded.</p>
<p>* Turnover fell to 43 million tolars from 79.5 million.</p>
<p>* Financial consultancy Finmedia had the highest turnover and was the leading decliner, falling 3.14 percent to 15,842 tolars on volume of 575 shares for total turnover of 9.1 million tolars.</p>
<p>* Ordinary shares of bank Dolenjska banka were the top gainers, rising 3.2 percent to 10,916 on volume of 99 shares for total turnover of 1.1 million tolars. -- Marja Novak, Ljubljana newsroom, 386-61-125-8439</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
