<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="5991" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Oppostion voters cowed in Bosnia - U.N..</title>
<headline>Oppostion voters cowed in Bosnia - U.N..</headline>
<byline>Sabina Cosic</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bosnians supporting opposition politicians in the northwest of the country around Bihac are so frightened of reprisals they may not vote in upcoming elections, a U.N. spokesman said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;U.N. monitors... believe that this intimidation may continue up to the elections,&quot; U.N. spokesman Alex Ivanko told reporters in Sarajevo.</p>
<p>&quot;It will have dire consequences for the whole election process because people that support opposition parties will prefer, for security reasons, not to exercise their right to vote.&quot;</p>
<p>U.N. police operating in the Moslem-controlled Bihac area reported eight explosions there in the past week, all of them directed at people supporting candidates or parties in opposition to the ruling Moslem nationalist SDA party.</p>
<p>&quot;If the local authorities in Bihac are interested in having free and fair elections they only have weeks, if not days, to get their act together, although their committments are doubtful right now,&quot; Ivanko said.</p>
<p>Active harassment and intimidation of the political opposition in the Bihac area began in June when an SDA loyalist struck Bosnia's former Prime Minister Haris Silajdzic on the head with an iron pipe.</p>
<p>Silajdzic resigned his government position and broke with the SDA in January, forming his own party to run in opposition to the SDA for a seat on Bosnia's collective Presidency.</p>
<p>Ivanko said U.N. monitors in the Bihac area had received a letter from one of the local opposition parties accusing nine police officers and eight SDA supporters of intimidation.</p>
<p>Last week, U.N. police Commissioner Peter Fitzgerald met interior ministers from Bosnia's Moslem-Croat federation and its Serb republic who agreed to instruct local police to support free and fair elections.</p>
<p>&quot;They (the interior ministers) either failed to issue these orders, which is possible, or there was some bogus communication breakdown throughout the country, which I think is not very much possible,&quot; Ivanko said.</p>
<p>Ivanko said commissioner Fitzgerald would contact local police directly to get his message across even though &quot;we have some unconfirmed reports that people are being intimidated by local policemen&quot;.</p>
<p>Political intimidation also took place in Serb-controlled Teslic earlier in the week.</p>
<p>Ivanko reported that a factory director was forced from his job on Monday because of his opposition to the ruling Serb nationalist SDS party.</p>
<p>He was the second factory manager in Teslic to be replaced in the past week -- both by SDS supporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
