<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6000" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish zloty tracks dlr/mark, depos steady.</title>
<headline>Polish zloty tracks dlr/mark, depos steady.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish zloty tracked the mark's intraday gains against the dollar on European markets but finished little changed against the basket of currecies in lieu of nearly no large client orders.</p>
<p>The zloty closed at 1.81/1.78 percent from the trading band centre, a touch stronger than Monday's close at 1.77/1.75, but dealers said that no noticable currency-selling trend was felt today other than adjustments in line with dollar/mark moves.</p>
<p>&quot;The market delicately followed dollar/mark throughout the day and I don't expect much in the way of fireworks in the next few days,&quot; said Jacek Baprawski, forex dealer of Pekao SA.  </p>
<p>The zloty closed at 2.7330/40 per dollar, up from 2.7395/00 on Tuesday and at 1.8425/30 to the mark, down from 1.8384/89.</p>
<p>Dealers said the forex market was basically balanced with the zloty in its present band between about 1.8 and 1.6 percent from the parity rate -- the centre of the trading band.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems that neither the market nor the National Bank of Poland want to knock the zloty out of its present band,&quot; Pekao's Baprawski said.</p>
<p>On the money market overnight rates stabilised around 17.5 percent and dealers said they may ease on Thursday as the NBP failed to clear all surplus cash at today's bond outright.  </p>
<p>&quot;One-day rates should ease tomorrow as monthly tax payments are ending and the central bank's outright did not drain all surplus cash from the market,&quot; said Monika Gradowska of BIG SA.</p>
<p>O/N rates closed at 17.5/17.6 percent against 17.5/18.5 percent at opening and tomorrow/next rates were at 17.5/18.5 percent, a fraction higher from this morning's 17.3/18.3.</p>
<p>At today's outright bond sale the NBP sold 111 million zlotys of 17 percent two year fixed bonds, due on July 12, 1997, and nine million zlotys of 14-percent five year bonds, which mature on July 12, 2000.  </p>
<p>The minimum price of the two-year bonds was 99.14, up from 98.60 at last tender on August 9 and the minimum price of the five-year paper was 89.99, up from 89.60.</p>
<p>The central bank offered 250 million zlotys of the same two-year bonds and 100 million of the five-year papers at another outright sale on Thursday.</p>
<p>The NBP also said on Wednesday that net currency reserves, those held by the entire banking system, grew $580 million in July to $22.12 billion after dipping by $620 million in June.</p>
<p>-- Wojciech Moskwa +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
