<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6007" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania's Berisha pledges commitment to free vote.</title>
<headline>Albania's Berisha pledges commitment to free vote.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanian President Sali Berisha on Wednesday urged all political parties to participate in upcoming local elections, pledging his government's commitment to a free and fair vote.</p>
<p>Most opposition groups, citing fears of a biased electoral process, have threatened to boycott the nationwide local ballot on October 20, five months after a disputed general election cast a shadow over the ex-communist country's young democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;I invite them to participate (in the local polls),&quot; Berisha said at a news conference. &quot;I guarantee a serious engagement for free and fair elections&quot;.</p>
<p>Foreign governments, including the United States, have said they will keep a close eye on the local ballot and consider it a fresh test for democracy.</p>
<p>Albania's third multi-party general election, held on May 26 and June 2, was marred by widespread allegations of manipulation. All major opposition parties withdrew from the parliamentary poll in protest.</p>
<p>Berisha told reporters that the boycott, led by the main opposition Socialists, had been immoral.</p>
<p>He did not refer to demands by the opposition to restyle a recently-formed electoral commission, which many parties claim is biased in favour of Berisha's Democratic Party.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
