<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6019" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Civilians issue cry for help from Grozny cellars.</title>
<headline>Civilians issue cry for help from Grozny cellars.</headline>
<byline>Lawrence Sheets</byline>
<dateline>GROZNY, Russia 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Civilians trapped in the cellars of the Chechen capital, rocked by explosions and threatened with carpet bombing from Russian forces, pleaded for help from the outside world on Wednesday.</p>
<p>An elderly Chechen woman struggling along a dirt road to escape the city handed over the appeal, written in ballpoint pen on a flimsy sheet of paper.</p>
<p>The trapped civilians, many of them Russians, said they felt they had been abandoned in their own country.</p>
<p>&quot;In houses number seven and nine along Pobeda (Victory) Street there are many citizens, among them children, women and elderly people, who have spent eight days in the basements of their houses,&quot; it began.</p>
<p>&quot;Our houses are bombarded continuously by heavy weapons. We are in a desperate state, without bread, water or light. There are no fighters in our houses, no soldiers, and no one is firing from them, but the bombardment never stops.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are living in uncertainty and confusion, we feel that we have been abandoned in our own country. We ask that you do everything possible to stop this war.&quot;</p>
<p>Fourteen people had signed the appeal on behalf of themselves and their families. It listed 32 names altogether, about half of them Russian.</p>
<p>The woman, who gave her name as Zoya, said the civilians had begged her to hand over their appeal so that their message would reach the outside world.</p>
<p>She said they were not the only ones who had stayed behind because they had nowhere to go.</p>
<p>&quot;There are poeple left in basements all over the city,&quot; said Zoya, her face dripping with sweat from the flames shooting 10 metres (33 feet) into the air from nearby gas mains which had been hit in the two weeks of fighting.</p>
<p>&quot;Those bastards, the Russians. They've deceived us all the time.&quot;</p>
<p>On Saturday, Russia's acting military commander signed a ceasefire deal with the rebels, who took over much of the city on August 6.</p>
<p>But on Monday he accused them of digging in and threatened to unleash all his firepower on Grozny unless they left by Thursday.</p>
<p>Zoya, one of a trickle of refugees trying to flee on Wednesday, was pushing a handcart stacked high with suitcases and she had trouble stopping it tipping over.</p>
<p>Around her explosions went off every few minutes and the sunny sky was hazy with smoke from burning buildings. Helicopters hovered and warplanes screamed overhead.</p>
<p>Separatist fighters, who have vowed to fight to the death, drove along the road in jeeps and cars, hanging out of the windows screaming the Chechen battle cry &quot;Allahu Akbar&quot; (God is Great).</p>
<p>The refugees, in a side road near a main thoroughfare leading out of the city, had between 15 and 20 km (9-12 miles) of walking ahead of them and no guarantee they would get out alive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GROZNY, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
