<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6021" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian defence minister disowns Grozny threat.</title>
<headline>Russian defence minister disowns Grozny threat.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Defence Minister Igor Rodionov said on Wednesday the acting army commander in Chechnya had acted solely on his own initiative in threatening to bomb Grozny and had been &quot;given a dressing down&quot;, Itar-Tass news agency said.  </p>
<p>In a brief report from the southern Russian city of Volgograd, Tass quoted Rodionov as saying he had had &quot;nothing to do&quot; with a statement on Monday by acting commander General Konstantin Pulikovsky that he would begin an all-out bombing of the Chechen capital on Thursday morning to dislodge rebels.</p>
<p>&quot;He did not agree this question with me,&quot; Rodionov told Tass, adding that &quot;someone had provoked&quot; Pulikovsky into the threat and that the general had &quot;acted wrongly&quot;. He had been told it was up to Russia's leadership to decide such matters.</p>
<p>Pulikovsky's superior, General Vyacheslav Tikhomirov, returned to Chechnya on Tuesday. He told Interfax news agency on Wednesday he favoured &quot;the most decisive measures&quot; to drive out the separatists who seized Grozny on August 6, adding: &quot;They (the rebels) will not live to see further loose warnings from me.&quot;</p>
<p>Rodionov, also a general, was appointed last month at the insistence of new Kremlin security chief Alexander Lebed, an old army comrade. Lebed flew to Chechnya on Wednesday in an apparent last-ditch attempt to make peace with the separatists.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
