<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6023" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Ceausescu doctor quits government in reshuffle.</title>
<headline>Ceausescu doctor quits government in reshuffle.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The personal physician of the late dictator Nicolae Ceausescu has resigned as Romania's health minister as part of a reshuffle by the leftist ruling party to boost its image ahead of elections.</p>
<p>Bucharest radio said on Wednesday Health Minister Iulian Mincu and also Culture Minister Viorel Marginean had quit &quot;for personal reasons&quot;.</p>
<p>Government spokesman Ion Rosca told Reuters their departure was &quot;actually the reshuffle&quot; of the cabinet lead by Prime Minister Nicolae Vacaroiu.</p>
<p>Mincu, 69, gave a last insulin shot to Ceausescu hours before the dictator and his wife Elena fled Bucharest during the December 1989 popular revolt that ended communist rule. Ceausescu and his wife were later executed by firing squad.</p>
<p>Mincu became notorious under Ceausescu as the author of a &quot;rational nutrition programme&quot; which denied consumption of meat and sweets to Romania's starving population.</p>
<p>The programme was in line with the late dictator's drive to export most of the country's livestock and food products to earn hard currency and pay its huge foreign debt.</p>
<p>Mincu, appointed by Vacaroiu as health minister in 1992, told Bucharest radio he had resigned on health grounds but would continue to act as a senator of the ruling leftist Party of Social Democracy (PDSR).</p>
<p>Reports in the local media had said the PDSR planned a reshuffle in a last-ditch attempt to boost its image ahead of parliamentary and presidential elections due on November 3.</p>
<p>Analysts had called for more radical surgery, with some asking even Vacaroiu to resign.</p>
<p>Marginean had come under attack in the opposition press for allegedly using his position to spend large amounts from the public money to organise exhibits of his paintings abroad.</p>
<p>Vacaroiu confirmed the reshuffle on Bucharest radio. &quot;We are determined to take all necessary measures, if needed,&quot; he said when asked whether he expected other changes in his cabinet.</p>
<p>PDSR supporters had also called for a shake-up of the ranks of the government to improve its chances in November elections.</p>
<p>Wednesday's reshuffle is the fifth since Vacaroiu was appointed in 1992. He has relied on nationalists and neo-communists to keep his hold on power.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
