<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6029" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Rouble eases after funds set aside for T-bills.</title>
<headline>Rouble eases after funds set aside for T-bills.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The rouble eased on Wednesday as banks gathered sufficient funds for today's Treasury bill auctions, after rising briefly on dollar selling by a foreign bank, dealers said.</p>
<p>Today the central bank is auctioning 7.5 trillion roubles of six-month paper and four trillion roubles of three-month bills.</p>
<p>&quot;The period when foreigners were selling dollars (in the previous days) for today's auctions is over and the market is settling down as usual. Trading is rather calm,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Aljba Alliance Bank chief dealer Dmitry Slobodnik said the rouble had risen earlier as a foreign bank was selling dollars but the rouble's upward trend turned out to be short.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody expects roubles to come back to the market (after the T-bill auctions) as usual so the dollar is going up again,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Roubles for today settlement were quoted at 5,307-10 per dollar compared with an early 5,300-03 and 5,297-300 late on Tuesday. Tomorrow roubles eased to 5,316-18 per dollar from yesterday's late 5,300-03.</p>
<p>The central bank said it had set 5,285/5,325 as its bid and offer rates against the dollar on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Overnight rouble credits yielded 30-45 percent compared with Tuesday's late 50-70 percent.</p>
<p>As usual the rouble-dollar market was unaffected by renewed worries about the health of President Boris Yeltsin, which earlier pushed up the Swiss franc, traditionally a safe haven on global currency markets.</p>
<p>Yeltsin aides have repeatedly said the president is resting outside Moscow and is not ill.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is already immune to the rumours of this kind,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Slobodnik said: &quot;It is foreigners who are usually scared by such things but what this market reacts to are concrete things such as central bank instructions, reserve requirements and so on.&quot;</p>
<p>--Artyom Danielyan, Moscow newsroom (095) 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
