<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6034" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine denies that president met Taiwan VP.</title>
<headline>Ukraine denies that president met Taiwan VP.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A spokesman for Ukrainian President Leonid Kuchma on Wednesday denied a report by Taiwan radio that the Ukrainian leader had met Taiwan's Vice-President Lien Chan.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no meeting. Neither official, nor private or non-official. I officially deny that information,&quot; Serhiy Kutsiy told Reuters by telephone. &quot;There is no point at all for the president to meet him. The Chinese are even angry over his private stay in Ukraine.&quot;  </p>
<p>Taiwanese radio said on Wednesday that Kuchma had met the island's leader in Kiev. Kutsiy said there were no plans for a meeting before Lien's departure later today.</p>
<p>Lien, a professor of Taipei University, stayed in Ukraine for two days on a non-official visit at the invitation of the chancellor of Kiev State University.</p>
<p>China responded by cancelling a trip by a high-ranking government delegation to Ukraine, to be headed by a member of China's powerful State Council, according to a senior Chinese diplomat. Meetings with Kuchma and Prime Minister Pavlo Lazarenko were planned during the visit.</p>
<p>A foreign ministry spokesman in Beijing said China was voicing its concern to Ukraine over Lien's visit. Communist China regards Nationalist-ruled Taiwan as a rebel province and has sought to isolate the island diplomatically since a civil war separated them in 1949.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
