<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6049" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish O/N steady despite tax payments, zloty flat.</title>
<headline>Polish O/N steady despite tax payments, zloty flat.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish overnight deposits market was balanced with slightly more players seeking funds because of monthly tax payments, but rates held below the key 14-day reverse repo rate of 19.12 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said that after rate rises earlier in the week on banks' increased borrowing needs, players were reluctant to bid up prices and one-day rates found an equilibrium at around 17.5 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The rates were growing on increased banks' needs, but stopped below the central bank's 14-day reverse repo rate,&quot; said Adam Gadomski of Bank Handlowy SA.  </p>
<p>At 1005 GMT, overnight rates were flat at bid and down at offer at 17.5/17.61 percent and tomorrow/next rates traded at 17.3/18.6 percent, slightly down from Tuesday's 17.7/18.7.</p>
<p>Some dealers said such low one-day rates made room for arbitrage by placing borrowed cash with the NBP at much higher rates. Others said, however, banks were unable to take advantage of such an opportunity because of the limited scope of the central bank's recent short-term drainages.</p>
<p>&quot;The NBP often drains less than banks want and therefore the scope of arbitrage is small,&quot; Handlowy's Gadomski said.  </p>
<p>The NBP offered to sell outright 150 million zlotys of 2-year 17-percent fixed bonds maturing July 12, 1997, and 150 million zlotys of 5-year 14-percent bonds, due July 12, 2000.</p>
<p>The zloty was flat in slow early trade and was seen steady on absence of large client orders, unless some banks adjust currency postition later today, which dealers said may liven up trade just before the end of the session.</p>
<p>&quot;We are keeping the summer watch, but it seems many clients have gone on vacation,&quot; a foreign bank dealer here said.  </p>
<p>Dealers said that in the absence of domestic market moving forces the market mirrored dollar/mark moves in European trade.</p>
<p>At 1020 GMT the zloty was quoted at 2.7345/60 to the dollar, up from opening's 2.7385/05 and Tuesday's 2.7395/00. It was at 1.8423/28 to the mark, down from 1.8385/05 at the opening and Tuesday's 1.8384/89.</p>
<p>It was at 1.80/1.76 percent from the trading band centre, up a fraction from 1.79/1.70 percent from parity at 0715 GMT.</p>
<p>-- Krzysztof Wojcik +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
