<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6054" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian lev partly recovers to 198.20/199 to dlr.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian lev partly recovers to 198.20/199 to dlr.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bulgarian lev traded between 198.20/199.00 per dollar, firmer than its historic low of 200 per dollar on Tuesday and in a wider spread around Tuesday's close of 198.60/80 on the interbank market, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Trade has been calmer and relatively thin this morning with the lev fluctuating around yesterday's closing levels,&quot; a commercial bank dealer said.</p>
<p>The lev will probably trade stable between 198.00/50 today unless a major foreign currency buyer appears again in the market, the dealer added.</p>
<p>The relief could be however temporary because a traditional rise in foreign currency demand from energy importers at the end of August will continue to pressure the lev, another bank dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;A purchase order for volumes larger than $1 million instantly pushes the lev down like it happened yesterday because liquidity in the market has been low for months now,&quot; the second dealer added.</p>
<p>Demand for several million dollars, reportedly from the National Electricity Company, pressured the lev to 200 per dollar at midday on Tuesday from 198.00/50 at the opening and the central bank (BNB) moved to curb banks' lev liquidity.</p>
<p>The BNB cut to 20 percent from 50 percent the share of banks' minimum required reserves that banks can use as a daily overdraft on their settlement accounts at the BNB.</p>
<p>But the move could hardly deter a fresh lev fall, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the BNB decisison) might cause delays in the interbank settlement and even block it rather than support the lev, because only two or three highly liquid banks will remain in the market and will determine the exchange rate,&quot; a third dealer said. -- Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 981 8569</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
