<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6056" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: NATO abandons blast site over Serb concern.</title>
<headline>NATO abandons blast site over Serb concern.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>NATO on Monday agreed to abandon a set of pits they are using to destroy contraband Bosnian Serb munitions after local Serbs raised environmental concerns, officers said.</p>
<p>But NATO spokesman Lieutenant-Colonel Max Marriner said Operation Volcano would go ahead as planned in another set of pits also being used in the operation.</p>
<p>He said about 96 tonnes of small arms ammunition and mines had been destroyed since blasting began about 10 km (six miles) north of Sokolac on Monday.</p>
<p>Bosnian Serbs voiced concern about possible effects of the explosions on the local water table and complained about broken windows.</p>
<p>&quot;Lieutenant-General (Sir Michael) Walker (Commander of NATO ground forces in Bosnia) met with the Mayor of Sokolac and other municipal authorities on Tuesday and agreed to abandon one set of blast pits to meet their concerns,&quot; Marriner said.</p>
<p>&quot;Meanwhile, Operation Volcano continues in the second set of blast pits. About 30 tonnes were destroyed yesterday (Tuesday) evening, bringing the total so far to 96 tonnes.&quot;</p>
<p>Reporters who witnessed one blast on Tuesday saw a column of dirt, smoke and steam shoot some 4,000 feet (more than 1,000 metres) into the air.</p>
<p>A routine NATO patrol discovered what is now estimated to be 400 tonnes of small arms ammunition and mines in a schoolhouse in Margetici, near Sokolac, on August 5.</p>
<p>Because the Margetici site had not been declared to NATO as required under the terms of the Dayton peace agreement, NATO troops confiscated the material and prepared to destroy it in an operation codenamed &quot;Volcano&quot;.</p>
<p>About 2,000 NATO-led peace implementation troops were despatched to the area beginning on Saturday to ensure the operation went ahead without risk to local citizens or the environment.</p>
<p>NATO engineers dug two sets of blasts pits in a remote area near Margetici to contain the exploding munitions, detonated in lots of a few tonnes each.</p>
<p>On Monday the Serbs began complaining that blasts from one set of pits might contaminate the water in the local aquifer which serves the area. General Walker abandoned those pits on Tuesday but blasting continued in the other set.</p>
<p>The Bosnian Serbs have not been the only faction to violate clauses in the Dayton agreement about weapons and ammunition.</p>
<p>NATO forces stopped a Bosnian Army truck carrying about 20 soldiers near Tuzla on Tuesday and discovered it was transporting unauthorised weapons.</p>
<p>Sources said the contraband, which included assault rifles and anti-tank weapons, would be destroyed.</p>
<p>NATO also reported it had recently destroyed a total of 1,242 weapons it had confiscated.</p>
<p>More than half were from the Bosnian Army side and included small arms, surface-to-air missiles, anti-aircraft machine-guns, mortars and rocket-propelled grenades.</p>
<p>&quot;The weapons were destroyed on August 16 and 17 after having been held for a period of time,&quot; said a NATO source who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;We're being even-handed about discharging our duty under Dayton. If we find unauthorised weapons or ammuntion we will confiscate and destroy it no matter whose it is.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
