<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6059" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Milk price is expected to rise to 950 lei per kilo. Producers say rise follows energy and fuel price hikes.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Romania's wheat output this year is 42 percent of last year's 7.4 million tonnes.</p>
<p>- Purchasing price for sunflower seeds from this year's harvest was set at 615 lei per kilo.</p>
<p>AZI</p>
<p>- Meva SA railway carriage maker signed long-term contract with French companies  Socofer and  Finmhal on supply of parts and carriages.</p>
<p>ZIUA</p>
<p>- Medicine prices are expected to go up by 40 percent in September. Medicine makers import raw materials at leu exchange rate of 3,100 to dollar but sell medicines at older rate of 1,850.</p>
<p>- Radet thermal power utility requested 20 billion lei loan from Finance Ministry's economic recovery fund to pay its debts to electricity authority Renel RA.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- Edible oil price is expected to go up by at least 40 percent after rise in buying price for sunflower seeds.</p>
<p>- Leu's exchange rate at licensed currency shops is on slide. It fell from 3,450 to dollar to 3,465.</p>
<p>- Austrian Creditanstalt set up Romania's first depository for mutual funds. It plans to integrate depositary into bank to open in Romania in future.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- Bucharest stock exchange announced first 10 companies privatised under mass selloff which join in trading would be exempted from listing commissions.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Electoral campaign for the November 3 general polls will be a very tough one, with ruling Party of Social Democracy (PDSR), in a desperate situation, using rumours and calumny, says Remus Opris, campaign manager of opposition Democratic Convention (CDR) bloc.</p>
<p>- Newspaper publishes PDSR's statement accusing CDR candidate for presidency, Emil Constantinescu, of attack on national security. Constantinescu said in an interview he would be honoured to hand over the power to Romania's exiled king Michael, whom he considers the country's &quot;real leader&quot;.</p>
<p>- CDR's executive board says PDSR's accusations are &quot;an expression of its panic&quot;.</p>
<p>- Two men jailed in a prison in southern town of Tulcea on the river Danube hammered nails in their heads demanding to be moved to another jail.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Constantinescu's statement on monarchy could have a disastrous effect on the CDR parties in the general polls, says Cristian Tudor Popescu in the editorial.</p>
<p>- &quot;Emil Constantinescu puts CDR's chances in danger with the monarchy bomb&quot;, reads a front page headline including comments from politicians on the monarchy issue.</p>
<p>- President Ion Iliescu has chosen Iosif Boda, Romania's envoy to Geneva, as campaign manager and Ioan Mircea Pascu, deputy defence minister, as spokesman for the electoral campaign ahead of the November 3 presidential elections.</p>
<p>- Only the health and culture ministers will be replaced, said sources in the ruling PDSR.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- Romania needs a centre right government after the centre left formula stumbled and is no longer able to carry out radical reforms, said political analyst Silviu Brucan.</p>
<p>- Transport, agriculture and communication ministers, all of National Unity Party (PUNR), say treaty with Hungary must be signed, the text being very convenient to Romania.</p>
<p>- Oliviu Gherman, president of ruling PDSR and chairman of upper house of Senate will run again for parliament on the ruling PDSR list in the Transylvanian city of Cluj.</p>
<p>COTIDIANUL</p>
<p>- For the Bucharesters, President Iliescu is third after CDR leader Emil Constantinescu and former reformist premier Petre Roman, on list of candidates for presidency, shows poll by International Consulting and Development.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- Bucharest's mayor Victor Ciorbea replaced 25 of the 28 department managers of the capital's city hall.</p>
<p>VREMEA</p>
<p>- Newspaper wonders whether Emil Constantinescu's interview on monarchy is real or a set-up to discredit him now, when he was given certain chance in a second round of the presidential polls.</p>
<p>ZIUA</p>
<p>- According to constitution, President Iliescu's mandate can be extended only in case of war or catastrophe, says the newspaper, alleging that his mandate can be extended because &quot;there is an obvious economic and social catastrophy&quot;. ($=3,156 lei) -- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
