<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6062" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the reports carried by Estonia's newspapers on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- Estonian Anneli Ojastu won a gold metre in the women's 100 metre run in the Atlanta Para-olympics.</p>
<p>- The Swedish member of the Estonia commission Olaf Forssberg admits the possibility that some video tapes of the sunken ferry were not delivered to the Estonian side.</p>
<p>- Interview with Arnold Ruutel concentrates on events in August 1991 and the coming presidential elections.</p>
<p>- 361 former workers of Vohma Meat Producers are still waiting for wages and compensation with no hope for a new job.</p>
<p>SONUMILEHT</p>
<p>- The government decided to return two buildings to their former owner the Bank of Estonia and approved amendments to the law on gambling.</p>
<p>- Large sums circulate in religious sects in Estonia and the possibility that sects are being used for money laundering cannot be excluded, said the deacon of Tallin Kaarli church, Jaan Leppik.</p>
<p>EESTI PAEVALEHT</p>
<p>- Estonian Prime Minister Tiit Vaehi met his Finnish counterpart Paavo Lipponen in Helsinki. Both premiers were hopeful that visa-free travel between their countries would be established by the end of 1996.</p>
<p>- 255 million kroons has been allocated by Tallin council for road repairs in 1996, half of the works have been completed and 100 million kroons spent.</p>
<p>- President Lennart Meri and British Ambassador to Estonia Charles de Chassiron opened on August 20 a restored memorial stone to British sailors who lost their lives in battles in 1721; the former stone was destroyed in the Soviet period.</p>
<p>ARIPAEV</p>
<p>- Estonian Energy service department cut off electricity in the Tallinn Meat Producers, causing a financial loss for several private companies who receive power from the same line.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
