<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6065" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - August 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - August 21.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Belgrade press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>NASA BORBA</p>
<p>- Owner of the cargo on the plane that crashed at Belgrade on Monday, Yugoslav Misko Djordjevic, was one of 12 on board.</p>
<p>- Kragujevac arms factory workers continue strike in front of city council, demanding wages.</p>
<p>- Walls in Bosnian Serb town of Visegrad plastered by posters of ousted leader Radovan Karadzic, Serbian Radical Leader Vojislav Seselj and Party of Serbian Unity Zeljko Raznatovic Arkan.</p>
<p>- Recently adopted oil-product import quotas being revised to let Montenegro import oil products for its users.</p>
<p>- Military court in southern Serbian town of Nis sentences four Croatian spies to between one and five years in jail.</p>
<p>POLITIKA</p>
<p>- Yugoslav and Croatian Foreign Ministers will sign agreement on normalising relations on August 23; the remaining open issues will be resolved in intensive diplomatic contacts over the next few days, says Croatian Deputy Foreign Minister Ivan Simonovic after visit to Belgrade.</p>
<p>- Yugoslav exploration crews continue probing for oil on Montenegrin coast after a four-year break.</p>
<p>- Heads of the Yugoslav, Serbian and Bosnian Serb Chambers of Commerce agree to barter seeds for agricultural products.</p>
<p>- Yugoslav government committee sets draft platform for talks on succession to speed up negotiations and tear down &quot;outer wall&quot; of sanctions.</p>
<p>- Operation Volcano, demolishing Bosnian Serb contraband munitions, negatively affecting preparations for September 14 elections, says Bosnian Serb Acting President Biljana Plavsic.</p>
<p>BORBA</p>
<p>- Both Yugoslavia and other countries are underestimating the danger of terrorism in the Serbian province of Kosovo, says Yugoslav Parliament's Defense and Security Board Chairman Radmilo Bogdanovic.</p>
<p>VECERNJE NOVOSTI</p>
<p>- Although crime in Serbia is on the rise, number of jail sentences is dropping, Institute of Criminology and Sociological Research analysis shows.</p>
<p>POLITIKA EKSPRES</p>
<p>- Out of 220,000 Bosnian refugees in Yugoslavia, 98,000 will vote in absence, over 122,000 will vote in Bosnia, says Yugoslav Refugeee Committee chairwoman Bratislava Morina.</p>
<p>-- Belgrade newsroom 381 11 +2224305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
