<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6069" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories reported by Hungary's press, based on information by Nepszabadsag's Hungary Around the Clock service. For further details on how to subscribe to Hungary Around the Clock, please contact Monica Kovacs at (361) 351 2440 or fax your request to (361) 351 7141.</p>
<p>ALL PAPERS</p>
<p>- A multitude of commemorations were held across Hungary at the weekend to mark the millecentennary, the 1,100th anniversary of Magyar tribes settling in the Carpathian basin. President Arpad Goncz said Hungary has reached a turning point.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Gyula Horn said in Kaposvar on Sunday that Privatisation Minister Tamas Suchman stands the good chance of succeeding Imre Dunai as minister of industry and trade.</p>
<p>- The leaders of ethnic Hungarian organisations beyond the borders opened fire on the draft of the Romanian-Hungarian basic treaty at the weekend, demanding that yet another Hungarian summit be convened to discuss the issue.</p>
<p>- President Arpad Goncz on Saturday conferred an honorary medal on former US president Jimmy Carter, who was helping build homes in Vac over the last few days.</p>
<p>- President Arpad Goncz addressed the second world congress of Finno-Ugric peoples in Parliament on Saturday.</p>
<p>- The Austrian government notified Hungarian Prime Minister Gyula Horn on Tuesday that it will take all necessary measures at once to alleviate the monumental back-ups that have occurred in recent days at Hungary's border with Austria.</p>
<p>- A railway car repair company owned by the Hungarian State Railways has teamed up with its partial owner Adtranz in winning a $30 million international tender for the renovation of railway cars of the Bulgarian State Railways.</p>
<p>NEPSZABADSAG</p>
<p>- In an extensive interview, Hungarian Democratic Forum President Sandor Lezsak said his party intends to be radical in deeds not in words.</p>
<p>MAGYAR HIRLAP</p>
<p>- A fair share of the milling company Del-Gabona Rt of Szeged is back in the hands of the state.</p>
<p>- The agricultural trading company Agrimpex saw its sales revenue increase 21 percent in the first half over the same period last year.</p>
<p>- The world's most advanced fighter plane, the F/A-19 Hornet held a demonstration flight at Kecskemet air base on Friday.</p>
<p>- Rock and soul queen Tina Turner is giving a concert in the People's Stadium tonight.</p>
<p>VILAGGAZDASAG</p>
<p>- Industrial production fell in June by 7.8 per cent after a 7.3 per cent rise the previous month, according to the Central Statistics Office.</p>
<p>- Household savings grew by HUF 60.2 billion in July, a much higher degree than in previous months, the National Bank of Hungary announced Friday.</p>
<p>- Whirlpool Magyarorszag Kft saw a stagnating first half in terms of individual appliances sold, which amounted to HUF 2 billion in turnover.</p>
<p>NAPI GAZDASAG</p>
<p>- Combined first half turnover in the retail and catering sectors amounted to HUF 1,255 billion representing a 20 per cent growth over the same period of 1995, according to the Central Statistics Office.</p>
<p>- Joint ventures accounted for 70.4 percent or $9.1 billion of Hungary's 12.8 billion export volume last year and rose further to 78.9 per cent by the end of the first half, according to an analysis by the Ministry of Industry and Trade.</p>
<p>- Fotex showed slight signs of improvement in the second quarter with both its net profit of HUF 113 million and its sales revenue of HUF 8,496 million exceeding the respective figures of a year before.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom (36-1) 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
