<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6071" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in Latvian newspapers on Wednesday. Prepared for Reuters by the Co-operation Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- The government dismissed the chief of the state revenue service Imants Grikis and appointed Andrejs Sonchiks to replace him. The official explanation is that he was replaced in connection with an overall reorganisation of the service, the unofficial reason is that he failed to solve a dispute with market workers who did not want electronic cash registers.</p>
<p>- The deputy chairman of the parliament education committee Juris Celmins said plans by Prime Minister Andris Shkele to reform the system of paying wages to teachers is contrary to the law on education and the law on the state budget.</p>
<p>- Foreign ministers of the three Baltic States and five Nordic Countries met in Riga. They discussed the abolition of visa regulations, security problems and integration with the EU.</p>
<p>- The government approved a package of draft laws needed to reform the border troop service by giving them over to the ministry of the interior.</p>
<p>- The parliament defence committee prepared the draft law on compulsory military service for its second reading. To pass the law, Shkele may ask parliament to convoke an extraordinary session this Friday.</p>
<p>- A Riga city council committee has revealed several transgressions of the law by the administration of the Riga central district in restoring the right of ownership to several houses in the district.</p>
<p>- In Vilnius, the newly appointed Latvian ambassador to Lithuania, Atis Sjanitis, presented his credentials to Lithuanian President Algirdas Brazauskas.</p>
<p>DIENA</p>
<p>- The privatisation of enterprises by liquidating them may lead to an increase in the level of unemployment in Latvia, which was at 7.1 percent in July.</p>
<p>NEATKARIGA RITA AVIZE</p>
<p>- Lithuania's parliament called on Latvian deputies not to ratify the licence agreement between Latvia and Amoco, which, the Lithuanians believe, may harm relations between the two countries.</p>
<p>BIZNESS &amp; BALTIYA</p>
<p>- According to statistical data, in the first half of 1996 cargo turnover in Latvian ports increased by 15 percent.</p>
<p>DIENAS BIZNESS</p>
<p>- Latvian van maker RAF is going to offer ambulance vehicles made on the basis of the Chevrolet Astrovan.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
