<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6075" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: FEATURE - Estonia's president fights for re-election.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Estonia's president fights for re-election.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Lannin</byline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Baltic state of Estonia holds presidential elections on Monday which will pit charismatic incumbent Lennart Meri against a parliament worried he is abusing his power.</p>
<p>Meri has no rivals yet in this former Soviet republic but his re-election is not automatic because some politicians have accused him of flouting the consitution.</p>
<p>&quot;During Lennart Meri's presidency, the most noticeable change has been the turning of the president's office into a non-existent upper house of parliament,&quot; said nationalist politician Juri Adams in leading newspaper Postimees.</p>
<p>In Estonia, which quit the former Soviet Union in 1991, parliament chooses the president in a system similar to that of Germany and Italy.</p>
<p>Meri needs the backing of 68 of parliament's 101 members in a first round of voting on August 26. If he fails, a second vote will be held next day.</p>
<p>With a wry sense of humour and strong intellect, Meri has been an eloquent spokesman for his country of 1.5 million people since his election in 1992 in the heady days of post-Soviet freedom.</p>
<p>His key theme has been driving Estonia's bid for entry to the European Union (EU) and NATO as the best guarantee against a resurgence of expansionism in its huge neighbour, Russia.</p>
<p>Russia has ruled Estonia for most of the last 200 years and many Estonians suspect it is eager to reassert its influence.</p>
<p>Western diplomats say Meri has kept Estonia's profile higher than its size would seem to merit.</p>
<p>&quot;He has had the charisma and character that Estonia needed after regaining independence,&quot; a Western diplomat told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;He could still be a good president but now what is needed is not too much idealism but pragmatism,&quot; the diplomat added.</p>
<p>At home Meri has been criticised for authoritarian tendencies, arrogance and taking on resonsibilities which are more properly those of the government.</p>
<p>One of the main criticisms levelled against him is that he signed an agreement in 1994 on the withdrawal of Russian troops from Estonia without consulting parliament.</p>
<p>His critics say the agreement was too generous because it allowed many former Soviet military pensioners to stay in Estonia.</p>
<p>Many Estonians regard the 300,000 Russians living in their country as colonists and especially dislike former Soviet military personnel.</p>
<p>Meri has also been accused of falling under the influence of Western liberals and Moscow to be soft on Estonia's Russians by rejecting laws on citizenship which seemed too harsh to him.</p>
<p>Most Russians in Estonia are Soviet-era immigrants and do not have citizenship. They must undergo formal naturalisation, involving a test of Estonian, which most do not speak.</p>
<p>Estonian politicians say that before they vote for Meri again they want to make sure he will abide by the rules that dictate the relationship between parliament and president.</p>
<p>The main problem is that the Estonian constitution, adopted in 1938, just two years before the country was annexed by the Soviet Union, is vague about this relationship.</p>
<p>Adams, a member of the nationalist Fatherland Union party and a severe critic of Meri, is drafting a law that would force the president to operate within clearly defined limits.</p>
<p>&quot;The weakest point in the restored Estonian state is currently the office of the president,&quot; Adams wrote in Postimees.</p>
<p>Meri's closest rival in the election is expected to be Arnold Ruutel, a former senior Communist and a leader of Estonia's indepence drive.</p>
<p>He has so far refused to say whether he will stand but he and Meri have been political rivals before.</p>
<p>Meri's 1992 election was at the expense of Ruutel, who won more votes in a deadlocked national poll but was later rejected by parliament for Meri.</p>
<p>Despite the dislike of politicians, many ordinary people approve of Meri and see him as a good spokesman abroad.</p>
<p>He at one time enjoyed 67 percent support in opinion polls although this has fallen recently to around 45 percent.</p>
<p>Although the latest polls do not give him a majority, Ruutel received only 15 percent backing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
