<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6078" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SURINAM: Arson ruled out in Surinam parliament blaze.</title>
<headline>Arson ruled out in Surinam parliament blaze.</headline>
<dateline>PARAMARIBO, Surinam 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Electrical failure and not arson caused a blaze that destroyed Surinam's 18th century National Assembly, a combined team of Surinamese and Dutch police said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Aug. 1 fire, which also gutted the Foreign Affairs and General Affairs ministries, started in the National Assembly's main chamber, Chief Inspector Henk Holtslag, who headed a team of Dutch police experts, told a news conference.</p>
<p>The fire spread quickly through the wooden buildings which had inadequate fire prevention facilities, Holtslag said. The buildings were also locked, hampering attempts to put out the fire once it was discovered, he said.</p>
<p>The blaze occurred five days before legislators were due to meet in the National Assembly to choose the country's next president, leading to early suspicions of arson.</p>
<p>The vote eventually took place in a nearby church. The Surinamese government plans to rebuild the National Assembly at the same site. The Dutch government said it will contribute to the building's reconstruction.</p>
<p>Surinam also lost many of its most important historical documents in the fire including the 1667 Peace of Breda Treaty under which Great Britain exchanged Surinam with the Netherlands for Nieuw Amsterdam which later became New York.</p>
<p>Paramaribo, the capital of the small former Dutch colony in South America, is famous for its colonial wooden architecture.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SURM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARAMARIBO, Surinam"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SURINAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
