<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6079" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Cuba scorns Clinton decision to name new U.S. envoy.</title>
<headline>Cuba scorns Clinton decision to name new U.S. envoy.</headline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cuban Foreign Minister Roberto Robaina on Wednesday criticised President Bill Clinton's decision to name a special representative for Cuba, saying the envoy was set for &quot;the most sterile mission of his career.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton on Friday named Stuart Eizenstat, a Department of Commerce undersecretary, to be his special representative for the promotion of democracy in Cuba. His mission will be to persuade U.S. allies to join a U.S.-led campaign to force the Cuban government to implement political and other reforms.</p>
<p>Commenting on the fact that Eizenstat visited Miami this week and held talks with anti-communist Cuban exiles there, Robaina suggested he would have done better to try to learn about &quot;the real Cuba.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;That way he would have found out that they are making him repeat lies like a parrot and that he's being used to carry out the most sterile mission of his entire career,&quot; he told Cuban news agency Prensa Latina in Havana.</p>
<p>One of Eizenstat's tasks will be to try to explain to U.S. allies like Canada, Mexico and the European Union, which have trade and investment links with Havana, why Washington insists on its policy of seeking to curb foreign investment in Cuba.</p>
<p>Robaina said it was ironic that Eizenstat, who also keeps his post of undersecretary for international trade, had been given the job of &quot;interfering with free trade between nations,&quot; a reference to the latest U.S. embargo legislation.</p>
<p>The Cuban minister recalled an announcement by Clinton in July in which he suspended for six months the right to file lawsuits under the so-called Helms-Burton law, which threatens legal sanctions against foreign firms which &quot;traffic&quot; in expropriated properties in Cuba formerly owned by Americans.</p>
<p>Robaina said Eizenstat, who is shortly expected to visit Canada, Mexico and Europe, would be travelling to &quot;remind all these countries that they have six months of sovereignty left.&quot;</p>
<p>International criticism of the Helms-Burton law has focused on its &quot;extraterritorial&quot; features which critics say seek to apply U.S. laws outside of the United States and therefore infringe the sovereignty of other states.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
