<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6080" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HAITI: Haiti rocked by armed attacks, Marines arrive.</title>
<headline>Haiti rocked by armed attacks, Marines arrive.</headline>
<byline>Nicole Volpe</byline>
<dateline>PORT-AU-PRINCE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A small group of U.S. Marines arrived in Haiti on Wednesday after a week of escalating violence marked by three assassinations and attacks on a police station and parliament.</p>
<p>The rash of violence in Haiti threatened the nation's fragile two-year-old security and what the Clinton administration called a foreign policy success, according to Western diplomats and other experts.</p>
<p>With the U.S. presidential election drawing near, some experts said further political violence in Haiti could emerge as a campaign issue.</p>
<p>While officially the group of 50 Marines were sent to Haiti only to perform routine exercises, U.S. embassy sources privately acknowledged they would welcome the added benefit of a show of force. The Marines will march through the capital in full uniform and carrying weapons.</p>
<p>The arrival of the troops underlined growing international concern about Haiti.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems as though the same old scenario is playing out here again,&quot; said a U.N. official after hearing that a leader and member of an opposition party associated with the disbanded military was assassinated.</p>
<p>Pastor Antoine Leroy, considered to be the number two man in the Mobilisation for National Development Party (MDN), and party member Jacques Florival were killed outside of Florival's suburban home on Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>Florival was handcuffed before he was shot in the head, officials said.</p>
<p>The killings came the day after what was widely believed to be an attack by former Haitian soldiers on a police station and parliament building on Monday morning.</p>
<p>The attackers shot automatic weapons and lobbed grenades, wounding two officers and killing a shoeshine boy.</p>
<p>Last Saturday some 19 members of the MDN were arrested in a raid at one of their meetings at which President Rene Preval said the men were planning the attack.</p>
<p>&quot;Out with the Macoutes,&quot; said Preval on Monday, referring to the Ton Tons Macoute, the murderous military security force formed under the former Francois and Jean-Claude Duvalier dictatorships.</p>
<p>Whether the string of violence was retailatory escalation between the ex-military and the Haitian government and police was a question haunting those who hoped for democracy and order after former President Jean-Bertrand Aristide was restored to power in 1994 by U.S. troops.</p>
<p>Aristide was deposed in a 1991 bloody military coup. Upon his return he disbanded the military, which was replaced by the internationally trained Haitian National Police force.</p>
<p>Port-au-Prince Mayor Joseph Emmanuel Charlemagne offered the theory that the Monday morning attack on the police station was staged by the Haitian government to justify arrests of former soldiers.</p>
<p>&quot;Preval is in error to accuse a single sector of comitting destabilising actions,&quot; Charlemagne said.</p>
<p>U.S. embassy officials said they were suspicious of the low number of injuries and deaths in the Monday attack.</p>
<p>Supporters of Haiti's former brutal military, speaking on the condition of anonymity, claimed the Haitian government may be behind the attack on the police station as well as Tuesday's assassnations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT-AU-PRINCE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HAITI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
