<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6082" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil troops to clear Yanomami land of miners.</title>
<headline>Brazil troops to clear Yanomami land of miners.</headline>
<byline>William Schomberg</byline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's army, air force and police will be called up to clear 3,000 wildcat gold miners out of the remote lands of the Yanomami Indians, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Operation Yanomami will be launched in late September or early October in an attmept to clear the miners from the Yanomami Indians' vast Amazon reservation on the border with Venezuela, four years after a similar operation that failed.</p>
<p>&quot;The actions to be taken are an example of the Brazilian government's unquestionable determination to preserve the environment and protect Indian lands,&quot; the Foreign Relations Ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>Officials at Brazil's Justice Ministry said they were waiting for release of about $6 million by the government economic team before completing the plan.</p>
<p>&quot;This time we will make sure the miners don't re-occupy the area,&quot; said a ministry spokesman.</p>
<p>In 1992 the Brazilian government launched the high profile Operation Free Forest to clear about 10,000 wildcat miners, known in Portuguese as garimpeiros, from the Yanomami land. But many drifted back.</p>
<p>In 1993 an estimated 16 Yanomamis were killed in a clash with miners.</p>
<p>Carlos Zacquini, a director of the non-governmental Yanomami Commission, said 10 planes a day fly in and out of the reservation, ferrying miners and supplies, while government observation posts have been closed for lack of funds.</p>
<p>&quot;Yet again, the government is promising to solve the Yanomami's problems. Let's hope this time they stick to it,&quot; he said by telephone from the jungle city of Boa Vista.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
