<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6083" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico's top cop sees Raul Salinas verdict next year.</title>
<headline>Mexico's top cop sees Raul Salinas verdict next year.</headline>
<byline>Rene Villegas</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's Attorney General said on Wednesday that a verdict on murder charges against ex-President Carlos Salinas de Gortari's brother Raul was not expected before next year.</p>
<p>Antonio Lozano Gracia told a news conference that he believed prosecutors had firm proof against Raul Salinas, accused of masterminding the Sept. 28, 1994, killing of ruling party Secretary-General Jose Francisco Ruiz Massieu.</p>
<p>&quot;There are sufficient elements and firm proof that strengthen the accusation,&quot; Lozano said, without giving details. He said a verdict was expected by February 1997.</p>
<p>Raul Salinas was arrested on Feb. 28 last year on the murder charges and later was accused of forgery and illicit enrichment in connection with some $100 million prosecutors said he  accumulated under a false name in Swiss and other foreign bank accounts.</p>
<p>Raul Salinas denied all the charges against him.</p>
<p>Lozano said an investigation into his finances and into possible ties to drug money-laundering continued.</p>
<p>In the most wide-ranging news conference since taking his post in December 1994, Lozano also said that a new special investigator would be named soon to continue the investigation into the March 23, 1994, assassination of top politician Luis Donaldo Colosio.</p>
<p>Colosio was the presidential candidate of the long-ruling Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI) for elections held two years ago. His replacement as candidate, Ernesto Zedillo, won the presidential elections for the PRI.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
