<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6085" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico gov't says no plans to raise GDP forecast.</title>
<headline>Mexico gov't says no plans to raise GDP forecast.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's Finance Ministry said on Wednesday that it expects the economy to grow more than its official three percent forecast for this year, but it has no plans to change the figure.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible, in fact probable, that the rate of economic growth at the end of the year will surpass three percent,&quot; Manuel Ramos Francia, director of planning at the Finance Minsitry, told reporters.</p>
<p>Ramos Francia would not say how much more than three percent he expected the economy to grow, saying it depended on several factors.  </p>
<p>But he said the ministry has no plans to raise its projection, which it uses mainly to draw up the federal budget for the upcoming year.</p>
<p>&quot;We try to use conservative estimates so that we have a cushion in the budget. In this case, as we expected, the numbers have turned out in our favor. Raising our projection now would make little sense,&quot; he said. Last week, the government said the economy grew 7.2 percent during the second quarter, much higher than the five percent official forecast during that period. Many private sector economists have since raised their GDP forecasts for the year.</p>
<p>Officials also said they do not fear a strong peso will hurt export growth, pointing to recent trade figures as evidence exports are still growing at a healthy pace. They said rising imports of capital and intermediate goods are evidence the export sector is expanding production capacity.</p>
<p>Alejandro Valenzuela, the spokesman for the government's economic recovery plan, expected inflation during August to continue to fall. Inflation for the first half of August is due out on Thursday.</p>
<p>He said the government intends to bring inflation as close as possible to the 20.5 percent target for the year.</p>
<p>-- David Luhnow, Mexico City newsroom 525 72895659</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
