<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6088" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine bonds slump on renewed Congress concerns.</title>
<headline>Argentine bonds slump on renewed Congress concerns.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine bonds slumped Wednesday on news that Congress may not pass the government's latest economic measures until early October.</p>
<p>The market started the session on a gentle downward path, but the decline accelerated on the news.</p>
<p>&quot;We need a quick passage of the measures through Congress,&quot; said Agustin Etchebarne, chief economist at private consultancy C&amp;E Consultores.</p>
<p>The 5.5 percent dollar-denominated Bocon Previsional 2 due 2001 fell $0.70 to 114.30. Argentina's FRB due 2005 fell 5/8 to 76-5/8.  </p>
<p>The delay in passage of the measures, which include fuel tax hikes, will also mean &quot;it will be time lost that the government could have collected more taxes,&quot; said Etchebarne.</p>
<p>Indeed, Carlos Rodriguez, the chief aide to Economy Minister Roque Fernandez, said Wednesday delays in Congress to pass the bills will mean the aim of reducing Argentina's deficit by $1.2 billion by year-end will be more difficult.</p>
<p>Fernandez has said that without his economic measures the budget deficit this year will come to $6.6 billion.  </p>
<p>Rodriguez said, &quot;If it was calculated on four months, and now there are only two, then it's obvious, it's a matter of algebra. What makes it worse is that if the (new) fuel tax is voted in October it only takes effect from November.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition, local media reported Wednesday the scrapping of one of the measures to extend the retirement age of women to 65 from 60 and the possibility that value added tax will not be lowered to 20 percent from 21 percent at the beginning of next year as stated initially.  </p>
<p>Traders said these concerns could grow during the week with an International Monetary Fund mission in town assessing the economy. Fernandez is expected to have his first meeting with the IMF team on Friday.</p>
<p>In the money markets, one-day call money rates rose to 9.75 percent from 8.60 percent.</p>
<p>-- Axel Bugge, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 54 1 318-0668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
