<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6090" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Bank shares push Colombian stocks to higher close.</title>
<headline>Bank shares push Colombian stocks to higher close.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gains in bank shares helped lead Colombian stocks to a higher close in otherwise lackluster trading on the country's two main exchanges, brokers said.</p>
<p>Medellin's IBOMED general price index rose a paper-thin 0.15 percent, closing at 13,275.64 on lower-than average volume of 1.09 billion pesos. But the IBB in Bogota closed up 1.03 percent, ending the day at 851.78. Brokers said 1.8 billion pesos of shares traded hands in Bogota.</p>
<p>The day's biggest winner by far was Banco de Bogota, the country's third largest bank in terms of assets.  </p>
<p>Traders said the bank snapped its recent losing streak to close up 6.73 percent at 5,550 pesos per share.</p>
<p>&quot;It's one of the shares that had lost the most in recent weeks,&quot; one broker said. &quot;People now want to take advantage of the low price,&quot; he added, saying the stock had been undervalued.</p>
<p>Brewer Bavaria SA, hit by recent bouts of profit taking, also managed to end its losing streak, closing 1.40 percent higher on the day at 3,600 pesos per share.</p>
<p>Volume in Bogota was heavily concentrated in blue chip Banco Ganadero, the country's largest bank in terms of assets.  </p>
<p>A 40 percent stake in Ganadero will be sold to Banco Bilbao Vizcaya of Spain next week and market players widely expect its stock to tick up sharply once the deal goes through.</p>
<p>More than 771 million pesos of Gandero's preferential shares traded hands in Bogota and they closed up 0.89 percent at 225 pesos a share, brokers said.</p>
<p>Ganadero's ordinary shares were also heavily traded, but they ended the session unchanged at 284 pesos per share.</p>
<p>-- Javier Mozzo, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
