<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6097" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Approval of Nicaraguan 'dry canal' study delayed.</title>
<headline>Approval of Nicaraguan 'dry canal' study delayed.</headline>
<dateline>MANAGUA, Nicaragua 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The approval of a feasibility study for a &quot;dry canal&quot; across Nicaragua to complement the Panama Canal has been delayed to August 27, a company official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We came here to sign it on August 15, but the Nicaraguan government had some more paperwork to do, so their approval of the study has been delayed to August 27,&quot; Don Bosco, president of the Canal Interoceanico de Nicaragua S.A. (CINN), told Reuters. Despite the postponement, there is an understanding the government will approve the study, project coordinator John Sobke said.  </p>
<p>Sobke said the possibility of the dry canal becoming a reality was &quot;as real as you can get.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;With the problems the canal options in other countries have had, we're the only game in town,&quot; Sobke said.</p>
<p>The proposed dry canal is a 236 mile (377 km) rail system to transport container cargo across the Central American isthmus.</p>
<p>The $1.4 billion project, the largest in Nicaraguan history, will include two new container ports and surrounding free-trade zones and will meet the demands of the expanding container shipping market, CINN general manager Juan Carlos Rivas said.</p>
<p>The feasibility study is expected to take one year and construction three to four years. Crossing Central America on the dry canal will take three hours and will be cheaper than crossing the Panama Canal, Rivas said.</p>
<p>The project is expected to create 20,000 direct jobs and 70,000 spin-off jobs in Nicaragua, one of the poorest countries in Latin America.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020028">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA, Nicaragua"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
