<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6098" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Lima stock prices slip, Telefonica resists undertow.</title>
<headline>Lima stock prices slip, Telefonica resists undertow.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares on the Lima stock exchange closed down slightly Wednesday, but avoided a larger fall because benchmark Telefonica del Peru held firm, brokers said.</p>
<p>Thursday is expected to see prices stabilize as the recent gradual decline has brought many stocks close to their floor, they added.</p>
<p>Wednesday, the General Index fell 0.21 percent to 1396.1 points, while the blue-chip Selective Index slipped 0.66 percent to 1,900.9 points, according to preliminary stock figures.  </p>
<p>Telefonica closed up 0.36 percent at 5.50 soles on improved volume of 1.1 million shares.</p>
<p>Despite Telefonica's generally low volumes this month -- due to the absence of foreign investors from the market -- the stock is still acting as a benchmark for prices, dealers said. The stock's firmness Wednesday signals the market as a whole may soon begin to reverse this month's slippage, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a general confidence in the market,&quot; said Gustavo Bedoya of the local brokerage Prisma. &quot;The drops we have seen are normal for this time of the year. There are no macroeconomic factors, however, that warrant a strong fall.&quot;  </p>
<p>The electricity sector, which has defied the general sluggishness all month, had a mixed session Wednesday. Players took profits on Luz del Sur, which dropped in heavy volume, but both Edegel and Edelnor continued their rally.</p>
<p>Luz del Sur fell 2.92 percent to 3.66 soles on 3.6 million shares, Edegel rose 4.54 percent to 5.76 soles on 822,000 shares and Edelnor closed up 1.73 percent at 3.53 soles on 723,000 shares.  </p>
<p>Market volume was an improved 44.0 million soles ($18.0 million), where, 21 stocks rose, 25 fell and 38 were stable.</p>
<p>-- Claudia Guillen, Lima newsroom, 511 221-2134</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
