<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6101" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine stocks stagger to close sharply off.</title>
<headline>Argentine stocks stagger to close sharply off.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine stocks tumbled Wednesday to close at a five-month low in a market gripped by fears Congress may stall belt-tightening reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is unforgiving of the slightest disappointments -- it wanted the measures to come under scrutiny right away and now it seems it will have to wait until October,&quot; said Adolfo Adorno of Agra traders.</p>
<p>Congressional leaders said Wednesday it may take up to six weeks to screen the controversial package of fiscal reforms.</p>
<p>The MerVal index fell 3.4 percent to 497.06, after losing 2.0 percent Tuesday and 2.0 percent last week.  </p>
<p>&quot;The markets reflected public opinion today, the same as last week,&quot; bolsa President Julio Macchi told reporters after the close. &quot;This state of uncertainty may continue until there is a clear political decision to pass the reforms, and there is nothing worse than uncertainty for the markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders noted beyond the rush for political endorsement of Economy Minister Roque Fernandez's first package of measures, the reforms could also ironically have some negative implications for investors as they could be complemented with a rise in personal wealth tax. There is also speculation the government may decide to tax fixed-term deposits.  </p>
<p>Fernandez, who took over from Domingo Cavallo three-and-a-half weeks ago, is scheduled to report on the measures Thursday in Congress.</p>
<p>Traders said heavy selling in Argentine stocks by one U.S. emerging market investment fund helped drive prices lower in the session.</p>
<p>But they noted bargain-hunters may soon start to sift through the rubble and position stocks for a knee-jerk rally Thursday or Friday.</p>
<p>The broad market closed down 3.1 percent, with losers thrashing winners 43 to three and four issues ending flat.  </p>
<p>Floor volume slowed to a very weak 16.3 million pesos from 20.1 million Tuesday, while over-the-counter deals recovered to 80.4 million pesos against Tuesday's dismal tally of 39.1 million.</p>
<p>Worst bolsa performances were in main-tier stocks: carmakers Renault and Sevel reeled 6.9 percent and 6.1 percent respectively, holding company Comercial del Plata sank 6.4 percent and construction stock Polledo closed off 5.6 percent.</p>
<p>No MerVal stocks posted gains.</p>
<p>-- Carmen Pignotti, Buenos Aires Newsroom 541 318-0657</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
