<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6108" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Bolivia, Cuba discuss anti-drug cooperation.</title>
<headline>Bolivia, Cuba discuss anti-drug cooperation.</headline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bolivian Justice Minister Rene Blattmann held talks with Cuban officials on Wednesday that included analysis of a possible bilateral accord against drug-trafficking.</p>
<p>The idea of formal anti-drug cooperation was discussed during Blattmann's visit with Cuban Justice Minister Carlos Amat, Cuba's domestic news agency, AIN, said.</p>
<p>It quoted the Bolivian minister as saying, &quot;This is a battle which must be waged with equal energy in all parts, in the countries that produce the raw material, those that are used as a transit point for drug-trafficking and in consumer nations, because there can be no weak link in this chain.&quot;</p>
<p>Amat said Cuba, which has anti-drug accords with about 10 other countries, mostly in Latin America, was preparing a new law to strengthen its fight against illegal drugs.</p>
<p>Bolivia is one of the world's biggest producers of coca leaves, the raw material for cocaine, while Cuba lies astride major air and sea drug-smuggling routes that link producers in Latin America with consumers in Europe and the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
