<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6113" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico, Japan sign credit accords for $960 mln.</title>
<headline>Mexico, Japan sign credit accords for $960 mln.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico and Japan signed three credit accords Wednesday worth a total $960 million to support environmental projects and business lending in Mexico as well as Mexican exports to Japan, Mexican Foreign Minister Jose Angel Gurria said.</p>
<p>At a ceremony at the Mexican presidential residence of Los Pinos in Mexico City, Gurria said the accords consisted of:</p>
<p>- an environmental credit accord for $460 million aimed at helping clean up pollution in Mexico City;</p>
<p>- an accord between Mexico's foreign trade bank Bancomext and Japan's Eximbank for $250 million;</p>
<p>- an accord between Mexico's development bank Nacional Financiera and Japan's Eximbank, also for $250 million.  </p>
<p>The credit accords were signed between various members of the Mexican cabinet and high-ranking Japanese officials in the presence of Japan's Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto and Mexican President Ernesto Zedillo.</p>
<p>Hashimoto is here on the first leg of a 10-day, five-nation tour of Latin America.</p>
<p>No other details were given about the credits. Neither Zedillo nor Hashimoto spoke at the brief ceremony.</p>
<p>The support comes as Hashimoto seeks to open a new trade front for Japanese industry in Latin America. Tokyo has already pumped nearly $60 billion in direct investment into the region over the past 14 years and its economic aid doubled between 1990 and 1995 to $1.14 billion.</p>
<p>Mexico was the first stop on a trip that will also take him to Chile, Brazil, Peru and Costa Rica.</p>
<p>A potential cloud over his trip was lifted Monday when kidnappers released a top Japanese electronics executive in the Mexican-U.S. border city of Tijuana after a $2 million ransom was paid.</p>
<p>After nine days in captivity, Mamoru Konno, president of a U.S. subsidiary of Japan's Sanyo Electric Co was found in the basement of an unoccupied building after a Mexican police official contacted kidnappers with the money.</p>
<p>--Chris Aspin, Mexico City newsroom 525 7289530</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
