<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6120" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ECUADOR: Ecuador to revise foreign oil deals - Petroecuador.</title>
<headline>Ecuador to revise foreign oil deals - Petroecuador.</headline>
<dateline>QUITO, Ecuador 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ecuador's government will revise all contracts with foreign companies with crude oil operations in the country, Patricio Lopez, head of the state oil company Petroecuador, said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Each company is a separate problem and we have to revise each one of them. Each firm has a contract and what we are going to do is simply revise them so that each one becomes a benefit for the state,&quot; Lopez told reporters.  </p>
<p>Lopez, who has been ratified as Petroecuador boss by the country's populist new President Abdala Bucaram, said Ecuador has banned U.S. oil firm Maxus Energy Corp from operating its oil installations in Ecuador until it agrees to sign an deal giving Petroecuador participation.</p>
<p>Maxus, which is owned by Argentina's YPF, has operated in Ecuador for nine years but its installations are now under army guard.</p>
<p>Other oil firms operating in Ecuador include  Tripetrol, France's ELF Aquitaine and Occidental Petrolem Corp of the United States.</p>
<p>Lopez tried to give assurances that the decision to revise foreign oil contracts would not harm foreign investment.</p>
<p>&quot;No way -- as long as companies hand over to the Ecuadoran state a stake, since it is owner of the land and soil and has to have some benefit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lopez said the decision to ban Maxus operations was &quot;no surprise&quot; to Maxus, which he said would had investment plans worth $700 million until 1999 &quot;but last year we had $720 million invested: so there is over-investment, which must be recovered by the Ecuadoran state.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;They (Maxus) are aware the state must recover this and so we are going to hold talks with them,&quot; said Lopez.</p>
<p>-- Gustavo Oviedo, Quito Newsroom, +5932 258433</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="QUITO, Ecuador"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ECUADOR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
