<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6121" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentina promises probe into union shoot-out.</title>
<headline>Argentina promises probe into union shoot-out.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Brown</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Argentine government promised on Wednesday to investigate the role of union leaders in Tuesday's gunfight between rival labour groups that was condemned as a lapse into Argentina's violent past.</p>
<p>Seven men were injured in the shoot-out at a union leisure centre, where the Central Confederal Committee of trade unions was scheduled to vote on a general strike next month to follow a 24-hour strike on Aug. 8 against austerity measures.</p>
<p>The injured men were out of danger. But the credibility of the trade union movement, already poor, was in tatters.</p>
<p>Labour Minister Armando Caro Figueroa promised a probe into &quot;whether union leaders encouraged the presence of outsiders who should not have been at the Confederal.&quot; He threatened to withdraw union status from the labour groups involved.</p>
<p>Newspapers carried front-page pictures of union men firing pistols and La Nacion's front-page column lamented that &quot;in the best traditions of the '70s, unions lapsed into struggling for the leadership of the labour movement with firearms.&quot;</p>
<p>Opposition politicians accused the unions of playing into the hands of President Carlos Menem's Peronist government, whose austerity measures and failure to address 17.1 percent unemployment they are supposed to be opposing with strikes.</p>
<p>Carlos &quot;Chacho&quot; Alvarez of the centre-left Frepaso said &quot;this just favours the policies of the government.&quot;</p>
<p>Radical Party leader Rodolfo Terragno called on union bosses to &quot;avoid a return of the ghosts we exorcised in 1983&quot; -- a reference to the return of democracy after six years of brutal military rule. He hinted at &quot;sectors of power using these methods to divide those who are leading social protest.&quot;</p>
<p>Menem's Chief of Staff Alberto Kohan denied any suggestion of government involvement. &quot;It would be unfair to attribute this to a government manoeuvre to get in the way of a CGT strike,&quot; he told reporters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The gunfight broke out when construction workers loyal to the largest CGT union federation stopped truckers loyal to the rival MTA labour group attending the strike debate. The MTA broke with the CGT in 1994, accusing it of being too soft on the free-market economic policies of Menem's government.</p>
<p>CGT boss Gerardo Martinez pledged to resign Tuesday if his group was deemed responsible and rescheduled the strike vote for Friday at the CGT's grand city-centre headquarters. A CGT spokesman warned against a repeat of violence between CGT men and truckers at a Confederal Committee meeting last August.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's hope our 'companeros' the truck drivers don't break the windows again like last time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An MTA spokesman said his group would stay away Friday &quot;in case they shoot at us again and we get the blame.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES, Argentina"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
