<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6123" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Telmex stock rallies on Mexico cheer.</title>
<headline>Telmex stock rallies on Mexico cheer.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Market cheer about a nascent economic recovery in Mexico carried bellwether stock Telefonos de Mexico higher by midday on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Telmex was up 5/8 to 34 in New York and had gained 2.09 percent in its local L shares.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the Mexico story that's carrying Telmex right now. People like the numbers they are seeing out of Mexico,&quot; said one trader in New York.  </p>
<p>Mexican shares have rallied across the board following news last week the economy grew 7.2 percent during the second quarter -- a sharper rise than expected and the first quarterly gain since the December 1994 peso crash.</p>
<p>After months of lagging the Mexican market on worries about upcoming competition for the telephone giant, Telmex has been caught in the wave of optimism. On August 13, its ADR was at 31-1/4.</p>
<p>The stock is still off the yearly 37-3/8 high set on April 19.  </p>
<p>Telmex shares could have some mileage left in the short run because it is still the first stock that comes to many investors' minds when they think of Mexico, traders said.</p>
<p>How much worries about competition, which begins in earnest on January 1, 1997, will weigh on the stock remains to be seen, however.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are going to need to see that Telmex can defend its own turf,&quot; said another Mexico City-based trader.</p>
<p>-- David Luhnow, Mexico City newsroom 525 7289565</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
