<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6125" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: ARCO seeks partner for Venezuela oil deal.</title>
<headline>ARCO seeks partner for Venezuela oil deal.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Atlantic Richfield Co (ARCO) and Venezuela's Corpoven are seeking an additional partner or partners for a $3.5 billion project to upgrade heavy crude which the two companies signed Wednesday, company officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;We do anticipate taking one or two additional partners into the project,&quot; ARCO chairman Mike Bowlin told a news conference in Caracas after signing the deal.</p>
<p>The additional partner will likely provide the outlet for the synthetic 25-degree API crude ARCO expects to upgrade from 9- degree API crude in Venezuela.  </p>
<p>ARCO's refineries in California and Washington State were poorly placed to take the crude, Bowlin said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is natural that the market will probably be in the Texas Gulf Coast...but we do think it will be a marketable product and we will look for downstream integration with someone else,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bowlin refused to comment on which companies had been approached to join the joint venture. Corpoven officials have said that Philipps Petroleum Co was a likely candidate.  </p>
<p>Bowlin insisted that the venture, which will produce 180,000 barrels per day of synthetic crude -- similar to Alaska North Slope -- by 2006, was a first step into penetrating Venezuela's oil industry.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope this will be the first of many new endeavors we will undertake in this country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>ARCO Coal Company President Stephen Mut added that Venezuela &quot;is one of a few countries where ARCO can participate across the whole spectrum of our activities,&quot; including coal and petrochemicals.</p>
<p>-- Omar Lugo, Caracas newsroom, 582 834405</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
