<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6129" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile's Banco Concepcion plans capital increase.</title>
<headline>Chile's Banco Concepcion plans capital increase.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chile's Banco Concepcion will carry out a capital increase for not less than $50 million by year-end to finance its expansion plans, said general manager Jorge Selume.</p>
<p>The increase will be through an issue of new shares which will be suscribed by the Infisa financial group, the bank's largest shareholder.</p>
<p>The increase will take place after Banco Concepcion has repaid debt owed to the Central Bank, a process, which is expected to be completed by November, he told reporters.  </p>
<p>&quot;Once the agreement with the Central Bank has been signed and paid, we will immediately carry out a capital increase,&quot; said Selume. &quot;Although the rise has not yet been agreed by the board, it will not be less than $50 million.&quot;</p>
<p>Banco Concepcion, which is not publicly listed, has a debt with the Central Bank of around $670 million.</p>
<p>Under new rules for repayment of private bank debts to the Central Bank, Banco Concepcion has been allowed to pay the debt's market value, rather than its much higher face value.</p>
<p>Once the capital increase has been carried out, the bank will be 75 percent owned by the Infisa financial group, which controlled Banco Osorno until it was taken over by Spain's Banco Santander this year.</p>
<p>-- Margaret Orgill, Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595 x212</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
