<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6135" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil industrial output in June up 0.5 pct - IBGE.</title>
<headline>Brazil industrial output in June up 0.5 pct - IBGE.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian industrial output in June rose 0.5 percent from May, and fell 3.9 percent compared with June 1995, the National Statistics Institute (IBGE) said in a statement.</p>
<p>The slight month-on-month increase in June shows a moderate recovery in industrial production when compared with May's 0.6 percent drop, the IBGE said.  </p>
<p>Industrial production in the first half of 1996 fell 4.6 percent, the IBGE said.</p>
<p>The recovery in industrial production was also evident when comparing the second quarter of 1996 with the first, according to the IBGE. Output fell 9.1 percent in the first quarter, but only 0.1 percent in the second quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;It is to be hoped that the recovery in industrial output will continue in the next few months given an easing in monetary policy which helps increase sales of durable goods, as well as semi- and non-durable goods,&quot; the IBGE said in the statement.  </p>
<p>The IBGE also cited an increase in construction work, especially in public works, as a positive impact on industrial production.</p>
<p>Nine of the 20 sectors covered in the IBGE survey were affected by the upturn in industrial output in June, led by textiles, up 6.4 percent, leather goods, up 6.1 percent, and paper and cardboard, up 3.8 percent.  </p>
<p>The tobacco, pharmaceutical and toiletries sectors showed the biggest declines in production at 16.8 percent, 9.4 percent and 5.4 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>Production of durable consumer goods and non-durable goods rose 1.6 percent and 0.7 percent in June, respectively, the IBGE said.</p>
<p>-- Simona de Logu, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 507 4151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
