<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6136" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil, Bolivia to ratify gas pipeline Sept. 4.</title>
<headline>Brazil, Bolivia to ratify gas pipeline Sept. 4.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil and Bolivia are due to ratify on Sept. 4 a contract which will pave the way for construction of a $1.9 billion natural gas pipeline, a Brazilian official said.</p>
<p>The two countries' presidents would put their names to the contract which was signed earlier this month by their respective national energy companies, Luiz Menezes, a superintendent in charge of the project with Brazil's Petrobras said.  </p>
<p>Under the terms of the contract, Petrobras and its partners will buy 8.0 million cubic meters of Bolivian gas per day in the first year of the project at a price of $2.60 per million British Thermal Units (BTU).</p>
<p>The volume of gas will rise to 16 million cubic by the eighth year while the pipeline will be capable of carrying up to 30 million cubic meters of gas per day.</p>
<p>Menezes said negotiations over financing were ongoing with the World Bank, the Inter-American Development Bank, Brazil's National Development Bank and the export-import banks of several countries.  </p>
<p>&quot;We expect to close the financing by February or March and begin construction in April,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Seventy percent of the $1.9 billion cost of the project is to be raised through financing with the partners providing the rest in equity, Menezes said.</p>
<p>The first tenders for equipment, principally the 500,000 tonnes of steel tubing which will run the length of the 1,900-mile (3,000-km) pipeline, should be published after the Sept. 4 signing, he said.  </p>
<p>Brazilian Energy Minister Raimundo Brito said he was preparing a presidential decree to expropriate land lying on the proposed course of the Brazilian leg of the  pipeline between the Bolivian border and the southern city of Porto Alegre.</p>
<p>Petrobras has lined up with British Gas, Tenneco Inc and Broken Hill Proprietary Co while Bolivia's Yacimentos Petroliferos Fiscales Bolivianos is partnered with Enron Corp.</p>
<p>-- William Schomberg, Brasilia newsroom 5561 2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
