<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6138" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia reproves U.S. for calling officials liars.</title>
<headline>Colombia reproves U.S. for calling officials liars.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA, Colombia 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bogoto has told Washington to mind its manners after U.S. State Department official Robert Gelbard called Colombian President Ernesto Samper and his interior minister liars.</p>
<p>&quot;The tone used by Mr. Gelbard is contrary to the most fundamental rules of diplomacy, and it contributes nothing to the construction of balanced and friendly relations between the two countries,&quot; the government said in a statement issued late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In remarks on Tuesday to reporters in Washington that were broadcast by Colombian media, Gelbard, assistant U.S. secretary of state for international narcotics and law enforcement affairs, called both Samper and Interior Minister Horacio Serpa liars.</p>
<p>He was reponding to assertions by the two men that U.S. Ambassador Myles Frechette had never told them about a supposed coup attempt against Samper being hatched last August.</p>
<p>Frechette spoke publicly about the planned coup for the first time in a television interview last week. He said he had been approached by a group of civilians claiming to represent a faction within the military and they had asked him about possible U.S. support for an anti-Samper putsch.</p>
<p>A day after the TV interview, Samper said he was &quot;surprised&quot; that Frechette had not contacted Colombian authorities to warn them about the planned coup. Serpa made a similar comment, saying Frechette had acted wrongly in keeping the alleged plot secret for a year.</p>
<p>&quot;I realise that President Samper and his Interior minister have said we did not approach them, but as is often the case with the Colombian government, they're lying,&quot; Gelbard said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The statement issued in Bogota on Tuesday night rejected this version of events.</p>
<p>&quot;The president and his ministers were not informed at any time by the United States ambassador that civilians supposedly representing sectors of the military had approached his office to explore the U.S. reaction in the event of a possible coup d'etat,&quot; the statement said. It added that Gelbard's remarks &quot;do not warrant additional comment by the Colombian government.&quot;</p>
<p>Gelbard has been one of the most outspoken critics of Samper because of charges that his 1994 election campaign was partly financed by Colombia's leading drug traffickers.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Colombia's chief prosecutor denied a government official's claim that a secret U.S. slush fund had been used to coax witnesses into testifying about links between drug lords and some of the country's top political figures.</p>
<p>&quot;It's false,&quot; Prosecutor-General Alfonso Valdivieso, an anti-drug crusader and sworn enemy of drug lords and corrupt politicians, said of the supposed fund. &quot;There's no basis to this,&quot; he added in an interview with the Caracol television network.</p>
<p>The fund, allegedly consisting of about $70 million, was denounced in a speech in the Senate late on Tuesday by Attorney-General Orlando Vasquez Velasquez. Vasquez, a former interior and ruling Liberal Party senator, won release from custody on Aug. 8, three months after the Supreme Court ordered his arrest on drug corruption charges.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA, Colombia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
