<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6140" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks electronic trade data delayed again.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks electronic trade data delayed again.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mexican stock exchange said Wednesday that electronic trading data would be delayed beyond their target time of 1030 local time/1130 EDT/1530 GMT and that floor trading continued to be suspended.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, traders said they expected extremely scarce trading on Wednesday after demonstrators blocked the main entrances of the stock exchange building, disrupting normal operations.  </p>
<p>&quot;Another 15 minutes more because they are making adjustments to the (computer trading system),&quot; a bolsa spokesman told Retuers.</p>
<p>Bolsa officials originally said electronic trade data would be released at 0930 local time/1030 EDT/1430 GMT, which would have been one hour beyond the normal opening bell. That target time has since been postponed twice.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, dealers said they were holding off from trading because of the chaos caused by the demonstration.</p>
<p>Many dealers went home or returned to their brokerage house offices upon seeing that student demonstrators and their parents blocked the main entrances. Riot police kept open a back door where a few bolsa officials and traders entered.</p>
<p>&quot;The feeling here is that people pretty much have written the day off,&quot; said one trader in New York. &quot;The market is just in disarray. The Dow is down 40 points and the Mexican ADRs aren't in synch.&quot;  </p>
<p>In New York, Telmex ADRs were up 1/2 to 33-7/8 while Televisa ADRs were down 1/4 to 31-1/8.</p>
<p>The disruption came after the IPC index set an all-time high on Tuesday, closing at a record 3,401.79 points.</p>
<p>-- Dan Trotta, Mexico City newsroom, (525) 728-9507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
