<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6143" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentina's Fernandez takes package to Congress.</title>
<headline>Argentina's Fernandez takes package to Congress.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's Economy Minister Roque Fernandez will explain his new austerity package to legislators Thursday and the measures could pass Congress in early October, a key lawmaker said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Jorge Matzkin, head of the ruling Peronist Party bloc in the lower house of Congress, made the announcements after meeting with Fernandez, cabinet chief Jorge Rodriguez and other senior officials at the government house.</p>
<p>The package launched earlier this month and sent to Congress Wednesday could win approval &quot;in the first days of October&quot;, although that date is just tentative, Matzkin said.  </p>
<p>Local newspapers said the package was sent to Congress one day later than expected due to last minute revisions.</p>
<p>These included the scrapping of a plan to extend the retirement age of women to 65 from 60 and the possibility that value added tax will not be lowered to 20 percent from 21 percent at the beginning of next year as stated initially, the papers said.</p>
<p>Some analysts had feared the measures would be watered down due to the reluctance of many legislators to endorse economic policies which have already resulted in one general strike this month and threats of a new one in September.  </p>
<p>The measures, which mainly include fuel tax increases, seek to reverse the larger-than-expected budget gap of $2.5 billion in the first half of the year. Fernandez has said that without the measures the budget deficit would be $6.6 billion for the whole year. With them, it will be $1.2 billion lower.</p>
<p>The measures, which the government hopes will generate more revenue, will also come under review by the International Monetary Fund this week. The first half deficit was more than $1.0 billion higher than that agreed with the IMF.</p>
<p>An IMF team is currently in Argentina and is expected to have its first meeting with Fernandez on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Axel Bugge, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 54 1 318 0668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
