<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6153" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Demonstrators block entrance of Mexican bourse.</title>
<headline>Demonstrators block entrance of Mexican bourse.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Demonstrators gathered outside the Mexican Stock Exchange on Wednesday, blocking the entry of traders, a spokesman for the exchange said.</p>
<p>But he told Reuters the demonstration would not prevent the market opening on time because of the market's electronic trading system. The market is scheduled to open at 0830 (1300 GMT).  </p>
<p>&quot;There is a demonstration but there is no problem concerning operations because in the event that they do not let traders inside the market will start up with its electronic system,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Floor trading was expected to start around 30 minutes behind the bell, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that we will get in because there are not that many demonstrators outside, but we will probably start trading late on the floor, although the electronic system is ready,&quot; one trader said. &quot;It is not going to be the same volume, but we are not going to be without the exchange,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Witnesses said around 200 demonstrators -- students and parents protesting against Mexico's single examination system and school allocations -- were outside the exchange, which straddles Mexico City's main Reforma boulevard.</p>
<p>--Chris Aspin, Mexico City newsroom (525) 7829530.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
