<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6155" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Tropical Storm Dolly to emerge in Gulf of Mexico.</title>
<headline>Tropical Storm Dolly to emerge in Gulf of Mexico.</headline>
<dateline>CANCUN, Mexico 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tropical Storm Dolly, downgraded after touching land Tuesday in southern Mexico, is set to emerge into the Gulf of Mexico, authorities said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Cleaving its way westerly across the Yucatan peninsula, Dolly is expected to leave land and move into the shallow waters of the Gulf around 1200 EDT/1700 GMT, National Meterological Service said.</p>
<p>Storm warnings are still out across much of southern Mexico from Puerto Progreso in the Yucatan state to Ciudad del Carmen in Campeche state. There were no reports of deaths.  </p>
<p>Currently, Dolly is centered over the town of Pich in Campeche state and packing sustained winds of 65 km/h (41 mph) and gusts of 85 km/h (53 mph).</p>
<p>By 1300 local/1800 GMT it is expected to have slid to a position 90 km (56 miles) north of the island of Isla Aguada in Campeche state, still maintaining its force and provoking waves of up to 4 meters high.</p>
<p>&quot;The cyclical movement of the storm will cause rains above 7 cm (2.8 inches) in the states of Quintana Roo, Yucatan, Campeche, Tabasco, Chiapas, Oaxaca and Veracruz, landslides in Chiapas and possible flooding in low areas of Yucatan, Campeche and Tabasco,&quot; National Meterological Service said.  </p>
<p>Quintana Roo authorities, where Dolly touched land Tuesday after racing across the Caribbean, have still not estimated crop damage in the area. The area harvests mainly corn and beans.</p>
<p>Mexico's Communications and Transportation Ministry said Tuesday 29 ports had been forced to close to small vessels, although the state-owned oil monopoly Petroleos Mexicanos (Pemex) said none of its crude export ports had shut down operations.</p>
<p>Pemex said it had taken preventive measures against Dolly ahead of the system's arrival in the Gulf of Mexico.</p>
<p>&quot;This afternoon, the transfer to dry land began of workers carrying out support work on sea installations, leaving behind just operational personnel,&quot; Pemex said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Pemex has substantial oil and gas operations in the Gulf of Mexico, especially in Campeche state and are often affected by hurricanes and storms. Last year the hurricanes Opal and Roxanne closed down operations for several days, affecting production and shipments.</p>
<p>--Chris Aspin, Mexico City newsroom (525) 7289530</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANCUN, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
