<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6158" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the highlights of the main Sao Paulo and Rio de Janeiro newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>GAZETA MERCANTIL</p>
<p>-- CHRYSLER TO MAKE DAKOTA IN BRAZIL</p>
<p>U.S. automaker Chrysler Corporation is investing $315 million to build a factory in Brazil for the production of new Dakota pickup trucks.</p>
<p>-- LIGHT WANTS TO BUY CERJ</p>
<p>Brazilian power company Light, which was privatized three months ago, is planning to bid for Rio de Janeiro's state-owned power distributor Cerj when the firm goes on auction in November.</p>
<p>-- AUDITOR CAUTIOUS ON BAMERINDUS RESULTS</p>
<p>Independent auditors have cautioned that Brazilian bank Bamerindus still has serious liquidity problems and poor reserves for overdue loans despite posting a profit in the first half of this year.</p>
<p>O GLOBO</p>
<p>-- STATUTE ON MINORS HINDERS FIGHT AGAINST CRIME</p>
<p>Rio de Janeiro's state Security Secretary Nilton Cerqueira is calling for a lowering of the age at which minors can be held responsible for the crimes they commit. He says the current statute hinders the fight against crime.</p>
<p>-- COMPANIES TO HELP GOVT IN FIGHT AGAINST ILLITERACY</p>
<p>Six large companies, including Votorantim, Bovespa and BM&amp;F, are to help the government finance a program against illiteracy in the north and northeast of Brazil.</p>
<p>-- JUDGES HAVE RESTRICTED THE LAW ON COHABITATION</p>
<p>Judges in Rio de Janeiro have defined the law on cohabitation more precisely, specifying that only couples who have lived together for at least five years are eligible for some type of compensation should the relationship break up.</p>
<p>FOLHA DE SAO PAULO</p>
<p>-- SAO PAULO ARCHBISHOP CALLS FOR STRENGTHENING OF POLICE</p>
<p>The cardinal and archbishop of Sao Paulo d. Paulo Evaristo Arns has called for a strengthening of the police force to fight the crime wave in Sao Paulo.</p>
<p>-- SAO PAULO STATE GOVT CRITICIZES FIESP FOR CRIME STANCE</p>
<p>Sao Paulo's state Security Secretary Jose Afonso da Silva has criticized industry federation Fiesp for supporting the anti-crime campaign Reage Sao Paulo, saying Fiesp was responsible for unemployment which is a major cause of crime.</p>
<p>-- POLLUTION WORSENS AND ALERT IS ISSUED FOR MAUA</p>
<p>Air quality worsened in greater Sao Paulo Tuesday for the third time since traffic restrictions were implemented August 5. An alert was issued in the area of Maua on the outskirts of Sao Paulo.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified the stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- Simona de Logu, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 507 4151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
