<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6161" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexican mob takes law into its own hands.</title>
<headline>Mexican mob takes law into its own hands.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Townsfolk in central Mexico took the law into their own hands on Tuesday, seizing an armed robber and threatening to burn him to death or hang him if any of the people injured in the hold-up died, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Mexican television showed the 32-year-old burglar, Felipe Trejo, his bruised face caked with dried blood, bound hand and foot and surrounded by an angry mob in the small town of Santiago Tolman, some 40 miles (60 kms) east of the capital.</p>
<p>Locals, claiming that local police were corrupt and ineffectual, vowed to hold him for 48 hours and kill him if either of the two people shot during the hold-up late on Monday died of their wounds.</p>
<p>They also warned that he would face the same fate if his three accomplices in the robbery did not hand themselves in.</p>
<p>The few policemen in the town were outnumbered by the crowd and appeared to be keeping a low profile. Such incidents of spontaneous mob anger are rare in Mexico.</p>
<p>&quot;If there were justice and we knew for sure that the law would be applied, we would hand him over,&quot; Guadalupe Vargas, a woman at the scene, told CBS Telenoticias. &quot;But there's no law, so what we're doing here will serve (as an example).&quot;</p>
<p>Trejo, for his part, looking dazed and speaking in broken sentences, urged his accomplices to hand themselves in. &quot;They say they're going to carry out justice. But I should not pay alone, all (four) of us have to pay for what we did.&quot;</p>
<p>State officials acknowledged that crime rates had risen and that law enforcement efforts were often a failure. &quot;The people, to a certain extent, are right,&quot; the state deputy attorney general Gerardo de la Riva told CBS Telenoticias.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been assaults, and in some cases the people have not had the results they expected.&quot;</p>
<p>Since Mexico plunged into an economic crisis in December 1994, crime and unemployment have soared. The Mexican police -- long accused of harbouring corrupt officials -- are often suspected of turning a blind eye to criminals or actively supporting them.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
