<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6165" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico's July preliminary trade surplus $461 mln.</title>
<headline>Mexico's July preliminary trade surplus $461 mln.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's preliminary trade surplus in July was $461 million, on exports of $8.017 billion and imports of $7.556 billion, the Finance Ministry said.</p>
<p>It said the accumulated trade surplus between January and July was $4.588 billion.</p>
<p>In a Reuters survey, an average of 12 economists had forecast a July surplus of $524.9 million, with exports seen at $7.41 billion and imports at $6.86 billion.  </p>
<p>The Finance Ministry noted that the value of both exports and imports in July was significantly higher than both the same month last year and June 1996, which it said was partly due to a greater number of working days in July 1996.</p>
<p>July exports were 32.6 percent higher than last year. In the first seven months of the year, exports totalled $53.486 billion, 20.3 percent higher than in the same period last year.</p>
<p>Manufactured goods exports were $6.903 billion in July. Non-maquildarora sales abroad were up 37.2 percent, while maquiladora exports climbed 33.5 percent.</p>
<p>Exports of petroleum products were $892 million, up 24.8 percent . Crude oil export revenues were $79 million lower than in June 1996, however, because of lower export volumes in July.  </p>
<p>Agricultural exports were $190 million and mining exports $32 million in July.</p>
<p>Total imports of $7.556 billion were 40.2 percent higher than in July 1995, though the Finance Ministry noted that in July 1995 they hit their second-lowest level of that year.</p>
<p>It said the sharp rise was also explained by the recovery of aggregate demand, chiefly in the growth of fixed capital formation and economic output.</p>
<p>Imports of agricultural goods were up 106.4 percent in the January-July period to $2.716 billion, partly due to favorable prices abroad.</p>
<p>Imports of intermediate goods were $6.179 billion in July, up 41.6 percent from the same month last year. Capital goods imports rose 30.9 percent to $903 million in the same month, while consumer goods imports rose 41.8 percent from July 1995, fueled largely by increases in purchases abroad of gasoline, meat, food, drink and automobiles.</p>
<p>In the first seven months of the year, total consumer goods imports were worth $3.385 billion, 12.8 percent above the same period last year.</p>
<p>-- Henry Tricks, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9560</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
