<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6167" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian General News - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian General News - Aug 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>According to superannuation and remuneration consultants, the Federal Budget's new tax on super contributions will pressure employers to move back to executive salary packaging to try to push incomes under the A$70,000 threshold for the new tax. Experts also warn that the changes could push highly paid executives out of the superannuation system and into tax effective negative gearing investments. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Approaching its eighth month of pre-trial argument, Supreme Court Judge Justice Frank Vincent yesterday handed down his 13th ruling in the case against Melbourne business identity John Elliott. Allegations of conspiracy to defraud Elders of A$66.5 million using sham foreign exchange transactions were laid against Elliott and three other former Elders colleagues on Christmas Eve 1993. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Under a plan estimated to save A$570 million over four years by restricting the number of general practitioners who are receiving Medicare payments, the Federal Government proposed in Tuesday's Budget that only one-third of medical graduates be allowed to practice. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Senator Mal Colston's defection from the Australian Labor Party will make it possible to deliver the Government passage of its legislation in the Senate and while senior Government figures believe he will vote in favour of the Telstra sale, it is unlikely he will support the Workplace Relations Bill. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>The Australian Labor Party is expected to decide to oppose the introduction of up-front nursing home fees and the increase in daily resident fees at a meeting on August 30, jeopardising Federal Treasurer Peter Costello's projected A$310 million in savings over the next four years. Higher education and health cuts are emerging as two other contentious issues for the opposition parties. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The defection of Senator Mal Colston from the Australian Labor Party has made it possible for the Government to pass the Telstra sale legislation without ALP, Democrat or Green support and senior Labor figures believe Colston will vote in favour of the Bill, forming an alliance with Tasmanian Independent Brian Harradine. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Tax advisers have predicted a swing back to negative gearing and non-cash remuneration, such as cars, payment of school fees and other costs, as high income earners attempt to avoid the Federal Government's new superannuation contribution surcharge. The surcharge is set to apply to people with taxable income of more than A$70,000. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a bid to save A$100 million-plus a year, the Australian Defence Force has come up with a 10-year plan to reduce the number of regular Army forces by between 2000 and 3000 and boost the number of General Reserve troops by 5000. The plan also proposes the scrapping of the Army's existing two divisions, to be replaced by smaller and highly mobile joint taskforces. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>According to superannuation consultant Grant Abbott, a new policy contained in the Budget, which will include super savings in the means test for social security payments, will force unemployed people over the age of 55 to use their superannuation savings to live on, unable to claim the job search allowance. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>High income earners affected by the 15 per cent tax surcharge on any tax-deductible super contributions will be forced to quit superannuation schemes and turn to gearing into property or shares, according to analysts. The surcharge announced in the Budget will be phased in over the annual income range of A$70,000 to A$85,000. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>According to industry sources, the surcharge on superannuation contributions will cause major administrative problems for superannuation funds, replacing the former uniform system. The plan announced in Tuesday's Budget will force those earning more than A$85,000 to pay a 15 per cent surcharge on superannuation contributions and those earning more than A$70,000 will face a phased-in surcharge. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Researchers believe a poison secreted by a South American tree frog could replace conventional painkillers and may even be a safe alternative to the nicotine in cigarettes. The poison is 200 to 500 times more active than morphine and does not have the side effects of other painkillers. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Rating the Budget as a &quot;seven or eight out of 10&quot; for keeping election commitments, Prime Minister John Howard yesterday defended allegations by welfare groups that the A$1.8 billion cuts unfairly targeted the poor, claiming the Budget was economically reponsible even though it would do nothing to tackle Australia's high jobless rate. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Earlier denying a deal had been done in return for Government support for Senator Mal Colston's Senate Presidential nomination, Prime Minister John Howard last night confirmed the chances of a double dissolution over the Telstra sale legislation had been educed by Colston's defection from the Australian Labor Party. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Brian Woinarski, QC, from the office of the Victorian director of public prosecutions, will today address the Supreme Court on yesterday's ruling by Justice Frank Vincent in the trial of businessman John Elliott and others over the alleged theft of A$66.5million from Elders IXL. The ruling cannot be reported for legal reasons. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The only company to increase its business disconnections between April and June this year, United Energy, has received a warning from regulator-general Robin Davey to reduce its residential and business power disconnections or face lower and redistributed profits as a result of a reduction in the cost of electricity. Page A1.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
