<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6168" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Business News - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Business News - Aug 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>A wide-ranging Federal Government review will examine the effectiveness of business and other tax concessions worth almost A$18 billion. To be conducted in time for the next Budget in May 1997, the review will also examine the overall efficiency of the tax system and is expected to result in tax concessions being changed into direct Budget outlays programs. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Tax experts warned yesterday that a major expansion in the capital gains tax net announced in the Budget would be costly for large listed companies. Under the changes, companies will have to search their share registers and identify their ultimate owners on September 20 to show that their ownership has not changed since September 1985. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After posting a disappointing net profit of A$233.6 million for the 12 months to June 30, food and discount retailer Woolworths Ltd yesterday announced plans to move into petrol retailing and &quot;category killers&quot;. Woolworths blamed the increase in the corprate tax rate for the flat net profit. Page 15.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a bid to secure higher returns away from the stagnant Australian market, Pioneer International Ltd chief executive Dr John Schubert said yesterday the company could invest more than A$1 billion in the next two years. According to Schubert, the company is aggressively pursuing concrete and quarrying acquisitions in Europe and the United States. Page 16.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Cost-cutting gains from its merger with Ampol have offset thin petroleum refining margins to give Caltex Australia Ltd a large rise in earnings in the first half. The company recorded a net profit of A$30.3 million in the six months to Junh A$11.9 million in the first half of last year. Page 16.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Claiming an expert's report deemed the offer to be &quot;fair and reasonable&quot;, Futuris Corporation Ltd managing director Alan Newman has dismissed speculation that the company will increase its unconditional A$250 million offer for Elders Australia Ltd. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Tax groups and superannuation funds are angry over the Budget decision to axe a 10-year-old tax bonus, which will add millions of dollars to the tax compliance burden for public companies and superannuation funds. Tax groups have warned that the minor chnge to the capital gains tax will hit business with significant compliance costs and super funds said the decision to double the superannuation tax on high-income earners will lead to higher costs on all fund members. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After reporting a virtually unchanged A$233.6 million net profit for 1995-96, Woolworths Ltd managing director Reg Clairs warned of a continuation of the tough trading environment, but hoped that an aggressive expansion program, including moves into petrol retailing and electronics superstores, would set Woolworths on a strong growth pattern. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Although Treasurer Peter Costello has made it clear the Government expects the business community to support its Budget, business leaders have warned the Coalition that unless labour market impediments are rapidly removed, infrastructure upgraded and sovereign risk issues made clearer, the expected wave of new investment will not occur. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Prompted by the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission's decision to block Wattyl Ltd's bid for Taubmans Industries Ltd, allowing South African conglomerate Barlow Ltd to purchase the paint manufacturer, the Business Council of Australia has again called for an overhaul of the mergers test under the Trade Practices Act. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Federal Government's decision to save A$1.255 billion over the next four years by reducing the top research and development tax concession rate has sparked criticism from industry leaders, including BHP managing director John Prescott, who warned that the reduction will mean some important future projects may not go ahead in Australia. Page 24.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The AMP Society is leading the charge from life offices to introduce retirement savings accounts after the Federal Government supported the new superannuation product in Tuesday's Budget. AMP is thought to be close to launching an account, while other life offices, including Norwich, Prudential and National Mutual, have confirmed they are examining retirement accounts. Page 24.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Commonwealth Bank shares struck a six-month high yesterday, following the announcement of the Bank's 14 per cent increase in annual net profit to A$1.12 billion. CBA's managing director David Murray described the result as robust, but warned that further growth in earnings is unlikely in the coming year due to flat trading conditions. Page 27</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Woolworths has introduced a swag of new initiatives in a bid to offset the weak retailing environment and set the company on a strong growth pattern, including moves into petrol retailing and electronics superstores. Page 27</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Federal Budget has received a positive response from market economists, but some of them along with many of Australia's corporate chiefs, are concerned that the harsh spending cuts may slow economic activity in the short term. Westpac's general manage of economic strategy and planning Bill Evans claims the A$7.2 billion in savings will dampen economic activity by 0.5 per cent this financial year. Page 27</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Caltex Australia has posted a strong rise in interim profit due to its A$3 billion oil merger with Ampol last year, but warned yesterday that further growth from efficiency gains may be slowed by tough competition in the petrol industry. For the six-month to June, Caltex's net profit was A$30.3 million. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Pioneer International has escaped a tough year to June with a modest rise in net profit to A$252 million. Falling income from building materials in Australia, Europe and the United States was offset by A$70 million from Pioneer's Ampol Petroleum and buoyant Asian operations. Page 29</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>According to a report by Moody's Investors Service, Telstra's leading market position will enable it to withstand competitive pressures. The report said Moody's Aa2 rating for Telstra was based on the company's position in the local telecommunications market, its financial strength and Australia's supportive regulatory environment. Page 29</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Woolworths has unveiled its diversification plans as it reported a 0.04 per cent rise in net profit to A$233.6 million for the year to June 23. New initiatives in diversification, outlined as part of an aggressive expansion program, including moves into petrol retailing and electronics superstores, are set Woolworths on strong growth pattern. Page 29</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Tax experts claim that an overlooked Budget measure will hit almost every listed Australian company, adding millions to their future tax liabilities and significantly increasing compliance costs. Listed companies, more than 50 per cent of whose shares have changed hands since 20 September 1985, will no longer be exempt from capital gains tax. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Commonwealth Bank has delivered a 14 per cent rise in profit to A$1.12 billion, but warned that further growth in earnings is unlikely in the coming year. CBA's managing director David Murray described the result as robust, with cost controls assisting in offsetting the effects of intense competition in the financial services sector. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australis Media's share price more than doubled yesterday after trading resumed following the announcement that a consortium including Kerry Packer' Publishing and Broadcasting will inject A$132 million of equity into the troubled pay TV group. The share jumped to a high of 34 cents before closing at 25 cents with more than 4.6 million shares traded. Page B1</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The sale of a A$23 million parcel of shares in Mount Leyshon Gold Mines yesterday could clear the way for it to be later absorbed into Robert de Crespigny's merged Normandy group. Broker Hartley Poynton specialled a line of 6.62 million Mount Leyshon shars at A$3.42 each on a cum-dividend basis, which represents an 8.5 per cent stake in the gold miner. Page B3</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following reporting a virtually unchanged A$233.6 million net profit for 1995-96, Woolworths Ltd managing director Reg Clairs warned of a continuation of the tough trading environment but hoped that an aggressive expansion program, including moves into petrol retailing and electronics superstores, will offset the weak retailing environment. Page B3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
