<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6170" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Missing Irish Backpacker's bank account accessed.</title>
<headline>Missing Irish Backpacker's bank account accessed.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian police in the state of Queensland said they were still concerned for the safety of three missing Irish backpackers, despite a telephone message on Wednesday that the three were looking for work.</p>
<p>&quot;We still have concerns as we do not know who left the message,&quot; a police spokesman told Reuters, adding that one of the backpacker's bank accounts was accessed on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Sandra Mahon, Stuart Gamble and Neil Hewson, all aged 25, were last seen in Cairns on Queensland's far north coast on Saturday.</p>
<p>Police said they were initially concerned for the tourists' safety as Mahon was in a &quot;distressed and upset state&quot; when she contacted her father in Ireland on Saturday.</p>
<p>Mahon told her father she had been attacked and the telephone line then went dead, police said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday police in Cairns said a small withdrawal had been made from Mahon's bank account from a bank in Mission Beach, 100 km (62 miles) south of Cairns.</p>
<p>A message on her father's answering service also said the three were heading for Inkermann, 550 km (342 miles) west of Cairns, to look for work.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
