<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6171" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia's Howard does not want early poll.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia's Howard does not want early poll.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Primie Minister John Howard repeated that he did not want a double dissolution of both houses of parliament but declined to rule out the option altogether.</p>
<p>&quot;I've never really wanted a double dissolution,&quot; Howard said in television interview when asked if such an event was now less likely.</p>
<p>When pressed again on whether it was less likely that he would now have a double dissolution, Howard replied, &quot;Oh, I hope it is.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;The Australian people don't want a double dissolution, they want us to govern, they expect us to get our legislation through,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I suspect that they believe that the minor parties should be reasonably co-operative and not obstructionist,&quot; Howard said.</p>
<p>The government can dissolve both the upper and lower houses of parliament and call fresh elections before its current term expires if the Senate, the upper house, fails to pass the same bill or bills on two separate occasions.</p>
<p>It can then force the blocked legislation through a combined sitting of both houses.  </p>
<p>The government does not have a majority in the Senate and requires the votes of two of the independent or minor party senators to carry its legislation.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273 2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
