<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6199" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Centaur raises A$102 mln by placement.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Centaur raises A$102 mln by placement.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Centaur Mining &amp; Exploration Ltd said it raised A$102 million through the placement of 60 million shares at A$1.70 each to Australian and international institutions.</p>
<p>The funds will be used for the Cawse nickel/cobalt project development and construction and other working capital requirements, chairman and managing director Joseph Gutnick said.</p>
<p>The placement is subject to shareholder approval at a meeting to be held around September 17, Gutnick said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The placement was jointly arranged by Bell Securities Ltd and Prudential-Bache Securities (Australia) Ltd, Gutnick said.</p>
<p>They will be paid a commission of 4.0 percent of total funds raised via the placement, he said.</p>
<p>The placement will increase Centaur's issued capital to 380.13 million shares. The placement price compared with Wednesday's closing market price of A$1.82.</p>
<p>Centaur said on August 6 that it expected to recoup its development costs of A$176 million for the Cawse nickel/cobalt project, which is in Western Australia, in the first two years of operation.  </p>
<p>The mine should come on stream in late 1997, initially producing around 8,400 tonnes of nickel and 2,000 tonnes of cobalt, Ken Hellsten, Centaur's general manager of operations, then told a metals conference in Melbourne.</p>
<p>Based on an average nickel price of US$3.50 a pound and a cobalt price of $12 a pound, the project is forecast to generate annual cash flow of between A$90 million and A$100 million in the first two years, Hellsten said.</p>
<p>He said cash operating costs of the mine would average $0.27 a pound, taking into account credits for cobalt.  </p>
<p>Over the first five years, Cawse is scheduled to produce an average of 8,400 tonnes of nickel and 1,400 tonnes of cobalt, annually, Hellsten said.</p>
<p>The resource could sustain an increase in production to between 30,000 and 35,000 tonnes per year of nickel and 2,500 tonnes per year of cobalt, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Once the plant is up and running ... we will look very seriously at that expansion, but clearly with the aim of keeping our cash costs down,&quot; Hellsten said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
