<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6200" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Dominion sees nickel project increase.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Dominion sees nickel project increase.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Test work near the main deposit of the proposed Yakabindie nickel project in Western Australia has identified an opportunity to lift projected recoveries, Dominion Mining Ltd said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Testing of orebody samples has show that an immediate increase in recovery to around 67 percent from the design sign-off of 63.7 percent is likely to be achieved easily, Dominion said.</p>
<p>It is possible that concentrator recoveries in excess of 70 percent will be achievable on completion of further evaluation, the company said.  </p>
<p>A rise in recoveries would lower production costs of the project, Dominion said.</p>
<p>Most of the test results for earlier feasibility studies on the project worked to a flowsheet that suited smelter feed but did not optimise concentrator recovery, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;The downstream process developed for Yakabindie has significantly less demanding requirements for metals plant feed than a smelter,&quot; Dominion said.</p>
<p>Talks were taking place with selected groups about possible support for the project, it said.  </p>
<p>Dominion said in its June quarter report that Yakabindie could begin production by mid-1997, up to 12 months earlier than originally scheduled, and produce up to 30,000 tonnes per year of nickel metal by the end of calendar 1998 at a capital cost of A$540 million.</p>
<p>Fellow miner North Ltd decided in December last year not to take up an option which could have given it a stake of up to 80 percent in  the project.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
