<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6202" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Australia IR law near moment of truth - Howard.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Australia IR law near moment of truth - Howard.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John Howard said he would not break up his industrial relations (IR) reform package, and said the &quot;moment of truth&quot; was approaching.</p>
<p>Speaking in a television interview, Howard said that he would not separate the unfair dismissal law from other labour market reforms, although Democrats leader Cheryl Kernot had said that measure could have already been passed by the Senate.</p>
<p>&quot;She knows as well as I do that that takes away some of the pressure on the minor parties to pass the rest of the industrial relations legislation,&quot; Howard said.  </p>
<p>Howard said all components of the reform were important, and he wanted to deliver them all.</p>
<p>The legislation was referred to a Senate committee in May.</p>
<p>&quot;The moment of truth on the IR legislation approaches, because the Senate report will be in in a few weeks time, and everyone has to stand up and be counted on the industrial relations legislation, including the Labor Party,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kernot's left-leaning minority Democrats has said it opposed many aspects of the IR reforms proposed by the government aimed at replacing laws passed by the former Labor government.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273 2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
