<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6204" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - GDP forecasts ignore labour mkt reform - Howard.</title>
<headline>RTRS - GDP forecasts ignore labour mkt reform - Howard.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John howard said budget growth forecasts were based on existing rigidities in the economy, including the labour market.</p>
<p>&quot;&quot;Well, those levels of growth of course are predicated on the existing regidities in the economy, for example a regulated labour market,&quot; Howard said in a television interview, responding to a question suggesting the budget growth forecasts would not lead to significant drops in unemployment.</p>
<p>&quot;If we can get our industrial relations reforms through the Senate, then I believe that will start over time to make a contribution,&quot; Howard said.  </p>
<p>After growing at 4.1 percent in each of the last two years, the government forecast the economy to grow at 3.5 percent over 1996/97 (July/June) in its budget released on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The unemployment rate is only expected to fall to 8.25 percent from the 8.5 percent at the end of 1995/96.</p>
<p>Earlier in the interview Howard declined to nominate an unemployment rate target for the end of his government's term.</p>
<p>His Liberal-National coalition government does not have a majority in the Senate, Australian's upper house, and need minority party votes to get the labour market reforms into law.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273 2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
