<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6206" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia wool group agrees on stockpile sale.</title>
<headline>Australia wool group agrees on stockpile sale.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A major section of the Australian wool industry has supported a minimum quarterly release of 90,000 bales of wool from the country's 2.18 million bale stockpile, a statement by Wool Council of Australia (WCA) said.</p>
<p>WCA president Rod Thirkell-Johnston expressed optimism over an industry-wide approach to wool stockpile management after an industry meeting convened by the Australian National Committee (ANC) of the International Wool Textile Organisation.</p>
<p>A more united approach should ensure commitment to industry views by the Minister for Primary Industries and Energy John Anderson, Thirkell-Johnston said.  </p>
<p>As well as supporting the 90,000 bale minimum quarterly release, the ANC-convened group supported a target date for completion of the stockpile selldown by December 31, 2000, with the revised programme to start from January 1, 1997.</p>
<p>Agreement was not reached on whether Wool International (WI) should have full commercial flexibility to sell the stockpile or whether a 250,000 bale maximum a quarter should be imposed, he said.</p>
<p>The former Labor government set a fixed quarterly disposal schedule of 182,000-192,000 bales which woolgrowers believe helps to keep auction prices down when the market is weak.  </p>
<p>The WCA firmly believed that a cap was not necessary and that WI should assume full commercial responsibility, recognising that it was accountable to its grower shareholders as well as to the government, Thirkell-Johnston said.</p>
<p>He said this view, expressed by all state farm organisations, reflected overwhelming grower sentiment and did not represent an insurmountable difference within the industry.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100124">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
