<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6207" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Aug 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>NIHON KEIZAI SHIMBUN</p>
<p>A circuit resale business will be started in the cellular phone market next January, industry sources said. The new business will purchase circuits in bulk from cellular phone service companies and retail them to corporate subscribers.</p>
<p>Japan Communication Inc, a Tokyo-based telecom-related venture company, has reached an agreement with DDI Corp group firms on purchasing cell phone circuits.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>The world's largest non-bank, GE Capital Service Inc, plans to purchase 80 percent of shares of Marubeni Car System, a car lease subsidiary of Marubeni Corp, for 25 billion to 30 billion yen.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Mitsubishi Heavy Industries Ltd is expected to increase its parent current profit by 11 percent from a year earlier to 185 billion yen in the year to next March 31, about 10 billion yen more than earlier forecast.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Nikken Chemicals Co Ltd plans to triple production of artificial sweetener erythritol to 7,000 tonnes by the end of 1997 to meet growing demand for low-calorie foods. Ajinomoto Co Inc also plans to boost production of aspartame sweetner by five percent.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Asia Internet Holding, a Tokyo-based Internet access provider, plans to set up a joint company in South Korea to offer international access services for providers there from late September. The new company, AIH Korea, will be capitalised at 54 million yen.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
