<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6209" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: S.Korea to import less jet/kerosene this winter.</title>
<headline>S.Korea to import less jet/kerosene this winter.</headline>
<byline>Raj Rajendran</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean jet/kerosene imports this winter are expected to fall by about 20 percent compared with last year, industry sources in Seoul said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The major impact of the reduced demand is expected to be felt on the spot market, where imports could fall as much as 30 percent because endusers have increased the amount of jet they take on a term basis, traders said.  </p>
<p>Sources estimated South Korean spot imports during the winter would amount to about seven-to-eight 30,000-tonne cargoes a month. This is compared to the average of between 10-12 cargoes per month that were imported last winter.</p>
<p>&quot;Refiners have signed more term contracts this year to avoid the high spot prices when you buy in winter,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>The source said the country's leading importer of jet had sealed term contracts with several MidEast and North African producers and one Japanese trading house for the supply of up 540,000 tonnes during the winter.  </p>
<p>The refiner had sealed up about 80 percent of its winter requirement in term contracts, the source said.</p>
<p>As reported, a second refinery -- Hanwha Energy -- has secured a term contract with Petronas for the purchase of up to 1.2 million barrels of jet for the winter. Hanwha is expected to seal another term contract soon, he said.</p>
<p>A third refiner is said to be negotiating to finalise term contracts for the winter. This refiner last year had term contracts with at least two suppliers, traders said.  </p>
<p>Two other Korean refiners, Hyundai Oil and Ssangyong Oil, who have both started up new crude distillation units (CDU) since the last winter, were self sufficient, they said.</p>
<p>Ssangyong Oil late last year started up a 220,000 bpd CDU and Hyundai Oil started up a 200,000 bpd CDU in July this year.</p>
<p>Korean sources said imports could be reduced further depending on the start-up time of two new refineries.</p>
<p>Yukong Ltd plans to start-up a 240,000 barrel per day (bpd) CDU in late September with commercial production slated by end October. Honam Oil plans to start-up a 220,000 bpd CDU in November.  </p>
<p>&quot;If these two CDUs come onstream as scheduled, Korean demand in the first quarter will be much lower,&quot; another source said.</p>
<p>--Singapore Newsroom (+65-870-3093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
