<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6212" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea 3-yr yields end higher on drying liquidity.</title>
<headline>S.Korea 3-yr yields end higher on drying liquidity.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yields on three-year corporate bonds edged up again on Wednesday, ending at a new year high, as money demand was continued rising ahead of the Korean Thanksgiving holidays, brokers said.</p>
<p>The three-month CDs fell back on bargain hunting, while the overnight call rates remained unchanged with banks sticking to the daily routine deals.</p>
<p>* 3-yr corporates end at 12.58 pct vs 12.49 on Tuesday</p>
<p>* 3-mth CDs close at 15.75 pct vs 15.80</p>
<p>* Overnight call average 16.50 pct unchanged from Tuesday</p>
<p>Three-year corporate yields ended higher on Wednesday as liquidity continued tightening up ahead of the Korean Thanksgiving holidays in September, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sentiment remained depressed with liquidity in circulation drying up,&quot; said a Samsung Securities broker.</p>
<p>Brokers said money demand was rising as companies, hit by worsening profitability, were chasing for funds to meet their operating expenses.</p>
<p>They said three-month CDs were bought on bargain hunting after a recent sharp rise in yields.  </p>
<p>Brokers forecast a similar trading pattern on Thursday.</p>
<p>New issues for the three-year corporates were estimated at 47 billion won worth on Thursday, compared with 47.5 billion won today.</p>
<p>The overnight call rates remained unchanged with no particular inter-bank deals.</p>
<p>--KIM MYONG-HWAN (822) 727 5645</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
