<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6227" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea unveils major securities liberalisation.</title>
<headline>S.Korea unveils major securities liberalisation.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea announced sweeping reforms of its securities market on Thursday, including the abolition of quotas on new stock issues.</p>
<p>Quotas on initial public offerings (IPOs) will be scrapped on September 1, according to a statement by the Ministry of Finance and Economy.</p>
<p>The package adopts many of the proposals recommended by the Korea Securities Research Institute in July.</p>
<p>From September 1, the government will also lift controls on capital increases by local firms and financial institutions. But it will maintain the current level of control over state-run corporations when they are privatised.  </p>
<p>Requirements for IPOs and capital increases will also be tightened from this date. All companies seeking to list or increase their capital will be required to have more than a 50 percent return on paid-in capital over three years, an asset value of more than 15,000 won ($18.3) per share and earnings per share (EPS) of more than 10,000 won.</p>
<p>The current standard is a 30 percent return on capital, an asset value of 7,500 won per share, and EPS of 5,000 won.</p>
<p>Large companies which paid an average dividend of 400 won or more per share over the past three years, will be free to increase their share capital.  </p>
<p>Smaller firms will be required to pay an average dividend of 300 won per share, a ministry official said.</p>
<p>Issuing companies must disclose their future dividend policy at the time of new stock issues.</p>
<p>To liberalise the pricing of IPO issues, the government said it would remove the mandatory pricing guidelines set by the Securities Exchange Commission, effective September 1.</p>
<p>In an effort to prevent the dominance of equity financing by the nation's large conglomerates, the government will impose limits on the nation's top 10 conglomerates.  </p>
<p>The Korea Stock Exchange currently stipulates that investors deposit securities and cash equal to 40 percent of the value of stock they want to buy.</p>
<p>Margin trading in stocks on the second tier of the bourse will be also allowed from September 1.</p>
<p>The government will permit home trading from personal computers from the first half of next year, allowing investors to place and receive confirmation of orders through their terminals.</p>
<p>Some rules require a revision of the Securities Exchange Law and the government will submit the necessary amendments to parliament in October.</p>
<p>From September 1, annual capital increases by a company affiliated with one of the top 10 conglomerates will be restricted to four percent of the total outstanding value of the stock or 100 billion won, whichever is larger.</p>
<p>The daily share price fluctuation limit will be expanded to eight percent from November and to 10 percent in the first half of 1997, compared with six percent currently.</p>
<p>From September 1, securities houses will be allowed to set their own margin requirements for stock purchases, the ministry official said.</p>
<p>-- Seoul newsroom (822) 727 5647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
