<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6234" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan's vice-premier to meet Mandela.</title>
<headline>Taiwan's vice-premier to meet Mandela.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan said on Wednesday Vice-Premier Hsu Li-teh will meet President Nelson Mandela during his upcoming visit to South Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;Vice-premier Hsu will meet with President Mandela shortly after his arrival in South Africa and they will have a lunch together,&quot; the island's Foreign Minister John Chang told a news conference.</p>
<p>Hsu is scheduled to leave for South Africa on Sunday to review investment projects and seek new business opportunities.</p>
<p>Hsu will visit Pretoria, Cape Town and Johannesburg before returning to Taipei on September 3.</p>
<p>South Africa is the biggest of Taipei's 30 diplomatic allies. The number of states recognising Taiwan fell by one on Monday to 30 as impoverished Niger, which split with Beijing to recognise Taipei in 1992, switched back to Beijing.</p>
<p>Chang described relations with South Africa as &quot;solid&quot; and &quot;stable&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The most difficult time was in March, but we have gone through the difficult period,&quot; Chang said, referring to a high-profile visit to Beijing by South African Foreign Minister Alfred Nzo.</p>
<p>South Africa has openly expressed willingness to establish diplomatic ties with China.</p>
<p>Beijing maintains that countries seeking formal ties with China must first sever relations with what it regards as a renegade Republic of China government, which took refuge on the island after losing a civil war to the communists in 1949.</p>
<p>South African trade ties with China have soared in recent years, fuelling pressure for formal recognition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
