<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6241" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Metrobank in $50 mln borrowing.</title>
<headline>ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Metrobank in $50 mln borrowing.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Metrobank of the Philippines launched a five-year US$50 million floating rate certificate of deposit deal into Asian debt markets on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The certificates were launched at par to float at 85 basis points over the three-month London Interbank Offered Rate. With fees, the all-in return to all management levels is 95 basis points.</p>
<p>Bankers Trust arranged the deal for Metrobank, the first five-year FRCD for a Philippine bank.</p>
<p>All of the other banks have tapped the market for three years, mostly successfully. Philippine bank deals has been popular because investors like the Philippines' economic story, and for a while at least, Philippine paper was relatively rare.</p>
<p>But bankers said spreads have come in significantly over the last year or so. At the same time, issuance has been stepped up, eroding the rarity value of Philippines issues.</p>
<p>&quot;The spreads already have tightened so not as many banks are interested in Philippine paper as before,&quot; said one syndicate manager, adding that some banks aren't ready to take Philippine exposure out to five years.</p>
<p>With several bank issues already launched this year, &quot;people may be a bit tired of Philippine names,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Bankers also said the Metrobank deal is offering a scanty spread comapared with recent bank issues.</p>
<p>For example, the country's biggest bank Philippines National Bank earlier this month set a three-year FRCD that paid 81 basis points all-in, and some bankers said that deal is a hard sell.</p>
<p>State-held Land Bank of the Philippines is paying 90 basis over LIBOR for three-year paper.</p>
<p>But others pointed out that Metrobank, as the Philippines second-largest bank and its most profitable, may attract lenders eager to establish a relationship.</p>
<p>Hong Kong Chinese Bank set a US$50 million FRCD. The deal has puts and calls in years three and four and will float at 60 basis points over LIBOR.</p>
<p>With fees, the all-in return is 75 basis points.</p>
<p>Lippo Ltd holds a major stake in Hong Kong Chinese Bank.</p>
<p>-- Andrea Ricci (852) 2843-6371 fax (852) 2845-0636</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
