<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6245" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MONGOLIA: Mongolia cholera death toll at nine, 117 infected.</title>
<headline>Mongolia cholera death toll at nine, 117 infected.</headline>
<byline>Irja Halasz</byline>
<dateline>ULAN BATOR 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>An outbreak of cholera in Mongolia has claimed one more life, bringing the death toll to nine since the disease was first diagnosed two weeks ago, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The disease had infected 117 people and there were 33 more cases of suspected cholera, a health ministry spokesman said.</p>
<p>A total of 2,058 people around the remote north Asian nation were in quarantine and the northern regions sealed off for the second week, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The southern town of Zamiin Uud on the Mongolian-Chinese border was closed off on Wednesday afternoon after laboratory tests confirmed that a 23-year-old man had died of cholera on Friday, town officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;He was a construction worker working at the hospital building,&quot; mayor Dashtsoo told Reuters. &quot;Laboratory tests confirmed he had cholera,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dashtsoo said another man who had been in close contact with the worker had contracted cholera and was in critical condition in a local hospital, where another person was suspected of having the disease.</p>
<p>More than 70 people who had been in contact with the victims had been quarantined and the town isolated since Wednesday afternoon, Dashtsoo said.</p>
<p>Border traffic would continue through the town but no local residents would be allowed in or out, he said.</p>
<p>Trains between Moscow, Ulan Bator and Beijing have been allowed to make non-stop trips through quarantined northern regions. International flights from the capital have continued as scheduled.</p>
<p>Officials had sealed off the northern cities of Erdenet and Darkhan, all of Selenge province and parts of Central province after an outbreak in Selenge's Khoetol county on August 8.</p>
<p>Local trains from Ulan Bator to the isolated northern regions resumed service on Tuesday but no people from quarantined areas have been allowed out.</p>
<p>In Khoetol county, where the bacteria had been traced back to a military unit after it had been spread by contaminated food, 81 people had been infected and 13 more were suspected of having the disease, health officials said.</p>
<p>Newspapers in Ulan Bator said many people had slipped out of sealed areas by traversing vast, unpatrolled grasslands and avoiding guarded roads.</p>
<p>Health officials in Ulan Bator said the epidemic had spread to another county in Central province that surrounds the capital. In Batsumber county, 65 km (40 miles) north of Ulan Bator, one person was sick with cholera and 51 people were in quarantine.</p>
<p>In the capital, 706 people had been quarantined and there were at least 11 cholera patients in the Hospital for Infectious Diseases. Three more people were suspected of having cholera.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MONGLA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ULAN BATOR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MONGOLIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
