<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6248" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: U.S. aflatoxin scare mays spark corn rally - trade.</title>
<headline>U.S. aflatoxin scare mays spark corn rally - trade.</headline>
<byline>George Hsu</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan grain buyers said on Wednesday world corn prices could rise sharply if a cancer-causing toxin found in Texas spreads to major northern U.S. corn belts, but Japanese traders shrugged off the worries. The Taiwanese buyers said the price rises could be seen in the premiums paid by importers over Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) corn futures.  </p>
<p>&quot;If large corn producing areas are infected with the fungus, the premium will rise,&quot; a buyer at Hui Shung Agriculture and Food Corp said. &quot;It would be harder to find No.2 or better grade corn if this becomes widespread in major corn producing states.&quot;</p>
<p>Aflatoxin, a potent carcinogen, has been discovered in much of the corn harvested along the Texas Gulf Coast, and Texas grain sources said more may be found as the harvest moves north.</p>
<p>State-owned Taiwan Sugar Corp said the potential losses in U.S. corn production could boost prices sharply, but that this would depend on the size of the contaminated area.  </p>
<p>&quot;Texas is not a key corn producing state, so the market may not show a strong reaction to the news,&quot; a company buyer said.</p>
<p>Japanese corn traders expressed little concern about aflatoxin damage to the U.S. corn crop so far, because they source most imports from the U.S. Midwest.</p>
<p>Japan imported 16.36 million tonnes of corn in calendar year 1995, of which 16.03 million tonnes came from the U.S., according to Finance Ministry data.</p>
<p>Corn is mainly used for animal feed in Japan.  </p>
<p>&quot;We usually buy corn from the U.S. Midwest, particularly Iowa and Illinois,&quot; a corn trader at a major trade house said. &quot;So I don't think aflatoxin discovered along the Texas Gulf Coast poses a serious threat to our imports in the near term.&quot;</p>
<p>But some traders said they will be forced to buy some Texas corn this year because of historically low grain stockpiles in the U.S. and supply concerns about the new crop in the Midwest.</p>
<p>&quot;Chances are we'll have to buy some Texas corn to offset supply concern for the new crop,&quot; a corn trader at another Japanese trading house said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
