<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6249" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Jurong Shipyard cautious about second half.</title>
<headline>Jurong Shipyard cautious about second half.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jurong Shipyard Ltd should see a slight improvement in its second half results if the ship repair market remains stable, chairman Lua Cheng Eng said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We should see some improvement in second half results if market conditions remain as the first half,&quot; Lua told reporters after the group announced its interim results.</p>
<p>Jurong reported a 31 percent fall in net profit to Singapore $15.45 million (US$10.95 million) for the six months ended June 30.</p>
<p>The results were largely in line with market expectations, which have been bearish on shipyards for some time.</p>
<p>&quot;Jurong's results were within expectations going by the interim results of the other yards released so far,&quot; said Koh Bee Ann, an investment analyst with GK Goh Securities.</p>
<p>Lua said the ship repair market continued depressed in the first half of the year and competition remained keen among local and overseas yards.</p>
<p>Jurong repaired 102 vessels during the period, which was almost the same as the second half of 1995, he said.</p>
<p>He said Jurong's new dock, which started operations in July, should have a capacity of about 40 vessels for the remaining five months of the year with the contract value for each vessel expected to be about S$1 million.</p>
<p>Lua said the new dock should be able to attract new business because it can accommodate larger vessels.</p>
<p>Because of the fall in earnings, Jurong has halved its interim dividend payout to 3.75 cents or 7.5 percent per share, Lua said.</p>
<p>- Singapore Newsroom 65-8703080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
