<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6254" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine ICC Telecoms to cut subscriber target.</title>
<headline>Philippine ICC Telecoms to cut subscriber target.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>ICC Telecoms, a unit of BayanTel, said on Wednesday it will cut its target subscriber base to 150,000 from 200,000 this year due to the interconnection problems being experienced with Philippine Long Distance Telephone Co (PLDT).</p>
<p>&quot;We are forced to downscale because of congestion. We have made a commitment to our board to have these subscribers in place but PLDT has a problem with interconnection. Government has moved very decisively and we expect a dramatic development soon,&quot; BayanTel executive vice president Primitivo Penaranda told reporters.</p>
<p>Among the new entrants in the telecommunications industry, only ICC Telecoms has exceeded the target for its roll-out of telephone lines in the first half of the year.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the National Telecommunications Commission asked PLDT to comply with its commitment to facilitate full interconnection with its competitors.</p>
<p>BayanTel, the telecommunications company of the powerful Lopez family which controls Benpres Holdings, complained that PLDT provided only 1,590 trunk lines versus a requirement of 4,590 trunk lines in July.</p>
<p>PLDT senior vice president Antonio Samson said PLDT had always been up to date in its interconnection agreement with BayanTel and other carriers.</p>
<p>&quot;The additional trunks that we have provided BayanTel recently were even taken out of our spares at the expense of our expansion programmes just to meet their requirements,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom (632) 841-8937</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
