<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6264" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan launches latest drive for U.N. seat.</title>
<headline>Taiwan launches latest drive for U.N. seat.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan launched its latest drive for a United Nations seat on Wednesday, a move likely to further anger China after Taipei secretly sent its vice-president to Beijing's diplomatic partner Ukraine.</p>
<p>&quot;Our purpose is to seek the basic rights of 21.3 million people in the Taiwan region and an appropriate representation in the United Nations,&quot; the foreign ministry said in a statement entitled &quot;The Republic of China on Taiwan and the U.N&quot;.</p>
<p>The statement was being distributed in eight languages to Taiwan's overseas offices to lobby for support before the U.N. General Assembly session in September.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not want to challenge communist China's existing U.N. seat,&quot; the statement said. &quot;International society should face the issue seriously and act to support...this legitimate proposal.&quot;</p>
<p>Taiwan launched similar U.N. bids in 1993, 1994 and 1995 but China, with veto power as one of five permanent members of the U.N. Security Council, has easily shot them down.</p>
<p>Communist China and Nationalist Taiwan have been bitter rivals since the two split after a civil war in 1949.</p>
<p>Beijing strongly opposes Taiwan's efforts to win diplomatic allies and a U.N. seat, regarding Taiwan as a renegade province unqualified for sovereign foreign ties.</p>
<p>Beijing took China's U.N. seat from Taipei in 1971 and has intensified its drive to isolate Taiwan's government.</p>
<p>Beijing on Monday won the latest round in Taiwan's struggle for recognition, wooing the impoverished African country of Niger back four years after it switched recognition to Taipei.</p>
<p>Since Niger's switch, only 30 states recognise Taiwan's exiled Republic of China rather than the Beijing government.</p>
<p>Taiwan has pledged to carry on its drive for a higher international profile and strives to strengthen unofficial ties with countries where it has no formal relations.</p>
<p>Beijing said on Wednesday it was voicing concern to Kiev over Vice-President Lien Chan's surprise visit to Ukraine, which one Taipei newspaper called an &quot;unexpected happy surprise&quot;.</p>
<p>Lien made a secret detour to Ukraine after making an official visit to the Dominican Republic.</p>
<p>Vice Premier Hsu Li-teh was scheduled to visit South Africa, Taiwan's biggest diplomatic ally, on August 25.</p>
<p>Foreign minister John Chang returned recently from Haiti and Paraguay, countries that recognise Taiwan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
