<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6273" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian crudes steady/lower, some MidEast oil trades.</title>
<headline>Asian crudes steady/lower, some MidEast oil trades.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crude oil prices in Asia were steady to lower on Wednesday in outright terms, with differentials vague as players continued to assess the market for new-month trades.</p>
<p>The Brent/Dubai for October held $1.90/$2.00, despite Brent's decline in future pits on Tuesday. Dubai intermonth spreads for Oct/Nov and Nov/Dec were also steady around 30 cents.</p>
<p>Paper Tapis was steady despite the overnight losses on Brent and NYMEX. September was bid at $21.10 and October was valued around the $21.00 level.  </p>
<p>Two October Oman deals were heard done, one at MPM +3 between a European trader and a Japanese trader. The deals could not be confirmed.</p>
<p>If confirmed they would represent the first October trade of the MidEast crude. Earlier in the week traders discounted talk of a similarly-priced deal.</p>
<p>A major sold a combined September Lower Zakum and and October Umm Shaif to another major at a combined price of around ADNOC +7 cents. The deal was made up of a cargo of each crude.</p>
<p>Traders said there was still a cargo of Lower Zakum overhanging the September market.  </p>
<p>Two cargos of Masila were still be available too, they said.</p>
<p>Mobil said its 108,000 barrels-per-day Altona refinery was operating at 80 percent rate and would rise to 100 percent by the middle of next week. Mobil sold a cargo of Kutubu delivered into Hawaii that had been standing off the refinery when the CDU and cracker problems arose.</p>
<p>Traders said a Tapis deal said done last week at ICP +60 cents to a major was a top-up cargo. They valued the Tapis premium at 50 cents for value on a cargo size.</p>
<p>--Singapore, N. Fullick (+65 870 3081), J. Oshima, Tokyo (+813 5473-3708)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
