<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6275" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore sees exports growing 7-8 pct in 1996.</title>
<headline>Singapore sees exports growing 7-8 pct in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore said on Wednesday it expected non-oil domestic exports to grow by seven to eight percent in 1996 year-on-year, compared with an increase of 14 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>The Monetary Authority of Singapore (MAS) said in its annual report the slower growth was due to the recent downturn in the global electronics industry. But it said concerns about the impact of this downturn on Singapore had been overstated.</p>
<p>&quot;U.S. orders for electronics products have picked up slightly in recent months, suggesting that the industry should bottom out by early next year,&quot; the report said.  </p>
<p>MAS said the current slowdown appeared to be related mainly to an inventory overhang in electronic components, chiefly semi-conductors and disk-drives.</p>
<p>&quot;The inventory-to-shipments ratio in personal computers (which is the chief source of demand for components) is still low. Indeed, U.S. sales of PCs remain firm, albeit slightly weaker than in 1995,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>It said the markets for Singapore's electronics exports had become more diversified, the U.S. share of Singapore's electronics exports having declined steadily to 35 percent from 60 percent in the mid 1980s.  </p>
<p>The MAS said it expected overall extrenal demand for Singapore's products to be slightly weaker in 1996 compared to last year, but gave no details.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703199)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
