<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6278" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks end 2.2 pct higher as funds make buys.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks end 2.2 pct higher as funds make buys.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Stock Exchange of Thailand (SET) index rose 2.20 percent in moderate trade on Wednesday as a local support fund and a Japanese fund entered the market and bought large capitalised stocks, brokers said.</p>
<p>The SET index ended 23.62 points higher at 1,095.03 on 5.1 billion baht trade. Gainers trounced decliners 265 to 82 while 90 issues unchanged. The SET-50 index was 2.30 points higher at 83.55.</p>
<p>&quot;The Japanese fund entered the market quietly today and bought large capitalised stocks which are now relatively cheap,&quot; said Thanadech Mahapokai of Book Club Finance.  </p>
<p>The first portion of a 21 billion baht market support fund entered the market earlier this week in an attempt to shore up the battered bourse which slid 15 percent in July.</p>
<p>Thanadech said the Japanese fund also entered the market on Wednesday apparently as Thai share prices were now seen as cheap although the uncertain local political situation was still having a negative impact on the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Market sentiment was fine today after the Japanese fund entered the market and started buying finance, bank, energy, communications and building stocks,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Thai Farmers Bank topped the active list, gaining four baht to 172. Finance One rose seven to 110 while Siam Cement surged 44 to 924 and Shinawatra Computer and Communications advanced 14 to 362.</p>
<p>Investors, especially foreigners, have been selling stocks since last month on concern about the government's ability to tackle economic problems, and, since last week, on worry about government stability.</p>
<p>Opposition parties are planning a no-confidence motion against Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa, accusing him of mismanagement and inefficiency. The censure debate is due on September 11. -- Suthep Chawla (662) 252-9950</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
