<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6280" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Nikkei ends up on Dow, Fed but off highs.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Nikkei ends up on Dow, Fed but off highs.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The SIMEX Nikkei futures closed firmer on Wednesday along with Wall Street, but dropped off their highs on profit-taking, dealers said.</p>
<p>After trading to a high at 21,460, light profit-taking pressured the key Nikkei 225 September contract to end at 21,285, some 80 ticks above its previous settlement. Its intraday low was at 21,220.</p>
<p>December ended at 21,300 against its previous close at 21,220. Total turnover for the two contracts was 20,500 lots.  </p>
<p>Dealers said Nikkei was fuelled by the Dow's overnight gain after the Federal Open Market Committee decided on Tuesday to leave U.S. interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>However, stable Japanese domestic market fundamentals capped any upside potential in futures as dealers were mostly sidelined ahead of the August 28 Tankan.</p>
<p>Most dealers were expecting the Tankan to be a non-event, reflecting a gradual improvement in the Japanese economy.</p>
<p>Near-term support and resistance for September remained at 20,800 and 21,600., dealers said.</p>
<p>-- Angela Tan, Singapore newsroom (65 8703083)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
