<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6293" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL share index ends up 1.57 pct as blue chips rise.</title>
<headline>KL share index ends up 1.57 pct as blue chips rise.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue chips, led by Malayan Banking (Maybank), surged on renewed institutional buying, pushing the key market index up 1.57 percent at the close, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange's Composite Index ended at 1,122.82, up 17.38 points.</p>
<p>Second liners, however, took a breather after several days of sharp advances, with the Second Board index closing up a mere 0.16 point at 506.43.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the blue chips turn to take centre stage, thanks to Maybank,&quot; said one institutional dealer.  </p>
<p>Maybank jumped 1.40 ringgit to 23.90 on volume of 1.86 million shares, after announcing higher-than-expected full-year earnings. Dealers said the absence of huge write-off of loans to troubled companies Perwaja Steel and Amcol Holdings as rumoured in the market also brought investors back into the stock.</p>
<p>Other blue chip gainers included Genting which rose 30 cents to 18.70 and volume-leader Sime Darby, up 10 cents to 8.00.</p>
<p>Market volume was 219 million shares. Gainers outnumbered losers 413 to 171.</p>
<p>Spot month Composite Index futures closed up 17.9 points at 1,117.4. -- Syed Azman (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
