<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6305" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli agent denies he told of crushing skulls.</title>
<headline>Israeli agent denies he told of crushing skulls.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Benajamin Netanyahu's office said on Wednesday that a Shin Bet secret police officer had denied he told an Israel newspaper he crushed the skulls of two Arab bus hijackers while they were in his custody.</p>
<p>Yedioth Ahronoth, Israel's largest daily, replied that it stood behind its published interview with Shin Bet's Ehud Yatom.</p>
<p>The police killing of the two captured hijackers in 1984 led to a major scandal and a crisis in Shin Bet when a cover-up failed. The graphic description which Yedioth attributed to Yatom last month shocked Israelis and angered agency officials.</p>
<p>The prime minister's office, under which Shin Bet operates, issued a statement on Wednesday saying agency head Ami Ayalon had reprimanded Yatom for giving the interview without the service's approval.</p>
<p>It added Ayalon accepted Yatom's denial that he had told Yedioth that he crushed the hijackers' skulls.</p>
<p>Israel's B'Tselem human rights group called on foreign countries to arrest and try Yatom if he should ever be in their territory since a presidential pardon granted years ago meant he could not be tried in Israel.</p>
<p>The families of the two hijackers said they would seek compensation after publication of the Yatom interview.</p>
<p>Yedioth Ahronoth quoted Yatom as saying: &quot;We put them in our van and then I received instructions from (Shin Bet chief) Avraham Shalom to kill them, so I killed them with a big stone. I crushed their skulls.&quot;</p>
<p>The newspaper said censors initially banned publication of his account.</p>
<p>Israeli commandos raided a bus in April 1984 after four Palestinians hijacked it and threatened to kill the passengers. Two of the hijackers were killed in the raid along with an Israeli woman passenger.</p>
<p>Israeli officials said at the time the other two hijackers, in their late teens, died in custody of their wounds but newspapers published photographs of the two being taken from the scene unhurt, prompting an internal inquiry.</p>
<p>The affair took a turn when Shin Bet officials conspired to frame top army officer Yitzhak Mordechai -- now Israel's defence minister -- for the killings.</p>
<p>When the coverup became known two years later, Shalom and three other top officials resigned from the agency. They received presidential pardons along with seven other agents involved in the affair, including Yatom.</p>
<p>&quot;The war against terrorists is aimed at preventing the death of innocent people and it involves actions that aren't consistent with perfect morals,&quot; the newspaper quoted Yatom as saying.</p>
<p>Yatom, whose brother Danny Yatom heads Israel's Mossad spy service, told the newspaper he was &quot;one of the few people who emerged emotionally fit from the affair,&quot; and said he was proud of his actions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
