<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6309" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Palestinian cabinet to curb security forces.</title>
<headline>Palestinian cabinet to curb security forces.</headline>
<byline>Wafa Amr</byline>
<dateline>RAMALLAH, West Bank 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat has decided to rein in security forces following the death of two West Bank Palestinians in separate incidents this month, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>They said the Palestinian cabinet decided at a meeting in Gaza last week attended by Arafat to set up guidelines that would curtail the powers of security forces and probe those suspected of financial and moral corruption.</p>
<p>The decisions were based on the recommendations of a ministerial committee that probed the death of an inmate by torture in a Nablus prison and a demonstrator during a riot in Tulkarm. The recommendations, obtained by Reuters, were only revealed on Wednesday.</p>
<p>One recommendation read: &quot;Studying the conditions of the security forces to uncover elements who are financially and morally corrupt and those whose nationalist loyalty is in doubt in order to preserve the integrity of the (Palestinian) Authority and the reputation of the (security) forces.&quot;</p>
<p>The recommendations also included defining the powers of security forces, enhancing coordination between various security bodies and enforcing laws that ban human rights abuses.</p>
<p>The cabinet also decided to review the cases of hundreds of inmates held by the Palestinian Authority and free those who had not been charged.</p>
<p>&quot;We have begun to see these decisions implemented on the ground,&quot; said Public Works Minister Azzam al-Ahmed during a meeting of the Palestinian Legislative Council in the West Bank town of Ramallah. &quot;The Authority is truly trying to carry out its duties,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ahmed said about 120 of the more than 700 prisoners detained without trial in February and March following a wave of suicide bombings by the militant Islamic Hamas group in Israel that killed 59 people had already been freed.</p>
<p>Local Government Minister Saeb Erekat said: &quot;The Authority is exerting real efforts to handle serious issues that could destroy our homeland.&quot;</p>
<p>Human rights groups have accused PLO security forces of systematic torture and charged that the Palestinian Authority was not doing enough to end the abuses.</p>
<p>Arafat has said he would not tolerate torture.</p>
<p>A Palestinian military court this month tried and sentenced three naval police officers to prison terms of between 10 and 15 years after they were convicted of torturing prisoner Mahmoud Jumayal who subsequently died of injuries.</p>
<p>Several Palestinian lawmakers, usually critical of the Palestinian Authority, hailed the decisions as a sign that the cabinet was serious.</p>
<p>&quot;We welcome the decisions of the cabinet because they mirror those of the Legislative Council,&quot; said council member Salah al-Taamari.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RAMALLAH, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
