<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6310" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Amnesty says alarmed at Egyptian militant's death.</title>
<headline>Amnesty says alarmed at Egyptian militant's death.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The human rights group Amnesty International called on Wednesday for an investigation into the death of a suspected Moslem militant at Egyptian police offices and said it feared for the lives of five other detainees.</p>
<p>&quot;Amnesty International has received alarming reports that Ahmed Mohamed Abdelazim Higazi died last week in the headquarters of the State Security Investigations Department (SSI) in Cairo allegedly as a result of torture,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The news of his death heightens fears for the other five people who are believed to be still held in the SSI headquarters and who have also allegedly been tortured... (Amnesty) has repeatedly urged the government to set up prompt and thorough investigations into all allegations of torture,&quot; the group added.</p>
<p>It named the five men as Sayed Abbas Sayed, Taha Mansour, Saeed Taghour, Hisham Mohammed Abdu and Abdel Hamid Qutb Khalil.</p>
<p>Interior Ministry officials could not immediately say if the men were being detained at the SSI. They declined to comment on Amnesty's allegations and did not confirm or deny that Higazi had died in custody.</p>
<p>Amnesty said it believed torture used included &quot;beatings, electric shocks, suspension in contorted positions and the extinguishing of cigarettes on their bodies.&quot;</p>
<p>On Monday, the militant Islamist group Vanguards of Conquest said Higazi was one of 44 detained in the second half of July and had been tortured to death by the Interior Ministry.</p>
<p>The group, one of several fighting to overthrow the government and turn Egypt into a strict Islamic state, is a revival of the organisation that gunned down president Anwar Sadat in 1981.</p>
<p>Human rights groups say at least 26 Egyptian detainees died in custody last year and that torture or maltreatment contributed to most of those deaths. The state says it investigates complaints of torture and punishes officers found guilty of abuses.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
