<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6316" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Coalition force in Saudi relocate HQ from Riyadh.</title>
<headline>Coalition force in Saudi relocate HQ from Riyadh.</headline>
<byline>Hilary Gush</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coalition troops enforcing a &quot;no-fly zone&quot; over southern Iraq from Saudi Arabia have relocated their headquarters to a new, more secure base south of the capital Riyadh, a U.S. Air Force official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The movement of the headquarters of the Joint Task Force Southwest Asia to Eskan Village from Riyadh is finished,&quot; U.S. Air Force spokesman Major James Stratford said, adding that the move involved 170 U.S., British, French and Saudi personnel.</p>
<p>The relocation is part of last month's joint Saudi-U.S. plan to shift U.S. troops to new locations in the kingdom to improve security for American forces there after two deadly bomb attacks targeting them in the oil-rich state in the past year.</p>
<p>A huge fuel truck bomb ripped through a U.S. housing complex in Dhahran in June killing 19 American airmen. In November a bomb at a U.S.-run military training centre in Riyadh killed five Americans and two Indians.</p>
<p>More threats against Americans in the kingdom have been received since the last attack.</p>
<p>Stratford said preparations for the relocation of most of the U.S. troops in the kingdom had started.</p>
<p>The U.S.-Saudi plan allows for the relocation of 4,000- 5,000 troops from Dhahran and Riyadh to the more remote Prince Sultan Air Base at al-Kharj 100 km (60 miles) southeast of the capital.</p>
<p>The Pentagon has said the new protection plan will cost about $200 million to be shared equally by the two countries.</p>
<p>Around 40,000 Americans live and work in the oil-rich kingdom. The State Department has said &quot;several hundred&quot; Americans were involved in official duties in Saudi Arabia as well as the troops.</p>
<p>Operation Southern Watch is designed to prevent a repeat of Iraq's strikes on Shi'ite Moslem dissidents that followed Baghdad's defeat in the 1991 Gulf War, or a buildup of Iraqi ground forces close to its southern border with Kuwait.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
