<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6322" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan stock close higher at end of week.</title>
<headline>Jordan stock close higher at end of week.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordanian stocks ended the week higher on Wednesday with reports of calm in the southern town of Karak after protests against bread price hikes.</p>
<p>The official Amman Financial Market 60-share index firmed 0.33 percent to 139.54 from 139.08 points on Tuesday, but still was below the key 140-point psychological barrier.</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected the upward trend to continue now that the government appeared in control following riots that broke out in Karak on Friday and spread to nearby towns, forcing King Hussein to send in his army to restore order.</p>
<p>The riots, the worst since the 1989 unrest, were fuelled by the government's decision on Tuesday to almost double prices of bread in line with IMF-agreed economic reforms.</p>
<p>A total of 291,270 shares changed hands in an low 453,798 dinar turnover in the cash-squeezed market, with no demand from foreign investors.</p>
<p>The market first broke the 140-point barrier at the end of June and has since slid to levels not reached since 1993. But it began a gradual pickup in trade at the start of last week.</p>
<p>Investors are eyeing half-year results and any signs of a possible easing of interest rates after prices dropped to near bottom levels.</p>
<p>The Pearl Investable Index -- an independent index of the 45 best-performing shares from the official market -- firmed 0.43 percent to 80.19 points. It was 16.04 percent down on last year.</p>
<p>Along with lack of institutional support, the market has suffered since the start of the year from a liquidity crunch blamed on high interest rates by the state to protect the dinar.</p>
<p>Large investors and institutions have avoided the market, which has fallen over 20 percent this year, with most of the trading dominated by floor traders.</p>
<p>Industrials dominated on a 248,848 dinar turnover and an index rise of 0.78 percent, banks had a 165,714 dinar turnover and an index rise of 0.04 percent while services had a 39,237 dinar turnover and an index rise of 0.03 percent.</p>
<p>A total of 118,463 shares worth 75,101 dinars changed hands in weak trade in the parallel market.</p>
<p>--  Amman newsroom takes queries on +962 6 623 776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
