<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6323" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwait shares rise on thinner volumes in the week.</title>
<headline>Kuwait shares rise on thinner volumes in the week.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares rose on the Kuwait Stock Exchange in the week to Wednesday with the index closing 1.5 percent higher at 1,610.2 points.</p>
<p>The official index rose 24.1 points or 1.5 percent with gains leading losses 30-12. Eight stocks were unchanged.</p>
<p>Daily average volume fell 22.9 percent to 97.8 million shares, with a total volume for the week of 489 million shares.</p>
<p>&quot;As you see prices rose, the market is strong. The fall in volume is only normal&quot; after weeks of active trading, said Khaled al-Saleh chairman of Gulf Brokerage Company said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are many reasons to make the market strong. Mid-year results of listed companies were good and there is a big capital flow into the country,&quot; said Saleh.</p>
<p>Total value traded reached 87.7 million dinars ($293 million) in the week, firming 25.2 percent on a daily average basis of 17.5 million dinars.</p>
<p>Contracts rose seven percent to an average of 1,115 a day.</p>
<p>&quot;Expectations are also positive about firms' performance in the third quarter,&quot; said Saleh al-Salami, local shares portfolio manager at the Kuwait International Investment Company.</p>
<p>Dealers expected the market to be more active after a September deadline for the payment of a bad debt installment by private sector firms and investors. The total debt owed to the state amounts to about $20 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The payment will give a boost of confidence to the market that there will be no share dumping,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>The most active stocks during the week were Commercial Bank, Burgan Bank, Investment Projects, United Realty, Pearl of Kuwait Real Estate and Fujairah Cement.</p>
<p>Banks were the most active sector by value with 28.9 percent, followed by property with 27.4 percent and foreign firms with 21.7 percent.</p>
<p>Trading in shares of non-Kuwaiti firms listed on the exchange was the most active by volume with 32.5 percent. The property sector came second with 32 percent and banks were third with 19.7 percent.</p>
<p>($1 = 0.299 dinars)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
