<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6324" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Asthma drug helps sleeping heart patients breathe.</title>
<headline>Asthma drug helps sleeping heart patients breathe.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A drug typically used for asthma can dramatically reduce the number of times a sleeping heart patient temporarily stops breathing, according to a study released on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A research team from the Veterans Affairs Medical Centre in Cincinnati followed the cases of 15 volunteers with heart disease whose breathing rhythm paused an average of 47 times per hour. When those 15 took the asthma drug theophylline, the number of long-lasting pauses dropped to about 18 per hour.</p>
<p>The study, published in Thursday's New England Journal of Medicine, suggests a better way to deal with one form of sleep apnea, a cessation in the nighttime breathing pattern where inhalation stops for at least 10 seconds.</p>
<p>Unlike conventional sleep apnea, where an obstruction in the upper airways temporarily blocks breathing and often wakes the sleeper, the form of apnea in this study is known as &quot;central apnea,&quot; where the muscles bringing air into the lungs are reluctant to work.</p>
<p>Central apnea is found in an about 45 percent of people with heart disease. Apnea, by disrupting sleep, leaves some sufferers feeling extraordinarily tired in the morning.</p>
<p>The research team, led by Dr. S. Javaheri, found that theophylline treatments did not seem to influence the stages of sleep a person experienced or the number of times the patient woke up.</p>
<p>There are other treatments for sleep apnea. Heart patients might benefit from hooking themselves up to a machine that forces air into their lungs, or by breathing oxygen at night. But patients may be reluctant to wear the apparatus, or it may fall off during the night.</p>
<p>&quot;On the basis of our findings,&quot; the Javaheri team said, &quot;theophylline may be a reasonable alternative approach.&quot;</p>
<p>The drug is made by several manufacturers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
