<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6325" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Drug found more effective for enlarged prostate.</title>
<headline>Drug found more effective for enlarged prostate.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A study of 1,229 men showed that terazosin was far more effective than another prostate drug, finasteride, in relieving urination difficulties caused by an enlarged prostate.</p>
<p>The study in Thursday's New England Journal of Medicine said the men suffered from benign prostatic hyperplasia, which occurs when the walnut-size prostate expands to constrict the neck of the bladder and make urination difficult. It said this was a troublesome, but not always dangerous, condition.</p>
<p>In their comparison of the two drugs, a team from several Veterans Affairs hospitals led by Dr. Herbert Lepor of the V.A. Medical Centre in New York, gave a placebo, terazosin, finasteride or a combination of the two drugs to men who were having trouble urinating.</p>
<p>Recipients of terazosin, marketed under the brand name Hytrin by Abbott Laboratories, showed the biggest improvement. Men who got finasteride, sold as Proscar by Merck &amp; Co., showed little significant change compared to the placebo recipients. Volunteers who received both drugs had just as much improvement as those who got terazosin alone.</p>
<p>But finasteride may not be as ineffective as the new study suggests. In an editorial in the Journal, Dr. Patrick Walsh of Johns Hopkins Hospital in Baltimore said previous studies, using men whose prostates felt enlarged, showed that finasteride worked well.</p>
<p>The new study involved men who had urinary problems, no matter how big their prostates felt to examining physicians. It used men whose prostates averaged 37 millilitres in volume, while the typical prostate in the two earlier experiments was at least 27 percent larger.</p>
<p>Walsh said the new findings suggested that finasteride could be useful if the prostate felt enlarged. If it did not, terazosin was likely the best option.</p>
<p>If the symptoms were severe, he added, &quot;Surgery may be the best approach.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
