<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6328" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Three dead, two wounded in Alabama shooting spree.</title>
<headline>Three dead, two wounded in Alabama shooting spree.</headline>
<dateline>AURORA, Ala 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three people, including a 5-year-boy and his mother, were killed Wednesday during an early-morning gun battle inside a home in the rural Alabama community of Aurora, police said.</p>
<p>Two men also were wounded in the assault and rushed to a nearby hospital, where they underwent emergency surgery. They were not identified but hospital officials said one remained in critical condition.</p>
<p>Etowah County Chief Sheriff's Deputy Kirby Johnston said a woman was taken into custody as a possible suspect but had not been charged. One of the wounded men also was suspected of involvement, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's unusual when you have three people killed and two shot. There's nothing even been close to anything of this magnitude in Aurora,&quot; Johnston said.</p>
<p>More than a dozen shots were fired in the melee. Afterwards police found three handguns inside the house.</p>
<p>The shootings took place sometime before 6:30 a.m. EDT when a neighbour, roused from sleep by one of the wounded men, phoned the local 911 emergency hotline.</p>
<p>The dead were identified as 34-year-old Kenneth Holmes, his 25-year-old sister Belinda Jeanette Holmes and her 5-year-old son Christopher.</p>
<p>Aurora is located outside the city of Gadsden, 75 miles northeast of Birmingham.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AURORA, Ala"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
