<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6329" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton signs health bill, broadens lead in polls.</title>
<headline>Clinton signs health bill, broadens lead in polls.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, U.S. Political Correspondent</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton signed a popular health reform bill on Wednesday in his latest move to blunt Republican Bob Dole's rise in public opinion polls.</p>
<p>Two new polls, by Louis Harris and Associates and by American Viewpoint, both showed Clinton leading Dole by 10 percentage points.</p>
<p>Harris had the president ahead 49 percent to 39 percent among registered voters. Independent Ross Perot had the support of 8 percent of respondents in the poll, which had a margin of error of plus or minus 3 percentage points.</p>
<p>American Viewpoint, conducted by Republican pollster Linda DiVall, showed Clinton at 46 percent, Dole at 36 percent and Perot at 10 percent.</p>
<p>In a quiet day in the campaign leading up to the Nov. 5 general election, Clinton signed the second of three bills he will make law this week, putting his signature to a measure that will help millions keep their medical insurance. He signed a bill raising the minimum wage on Tuesday and will sign a welfare reform measure on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;With this bill, we take a long step toward the kind of health care reform our nation needs,&quot; said Clinton, who was thwarted two years ago in his effort to achieve a sweeping overhaul of the U.S. health care system.</p>
<p>The law guarantees access to insurance for people who change jobs if their new employer offers coverage and forces insurance companies to end a practice of excluding people with pre-existing medical problems.</p>
<p>&quot;No longer will you live in fear of losing your health insurance because of the state of your health,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>Dole was quick to claim credit for the achievement.</p>
<p>&quot;This bill includes many of the important health insurance reforms I've promoted for years and should end once and for all the Clinton prescription of big-government health care,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>Clinton aides said the president would follow up on Friday by announcing that he accepts a Food and Drug Administration recommendation that tobacco be regulated as a drug.</p>
<p>Such a declaration might hurt Clinton in tobacco-growing states like Kentucky, Tennessee, Virginia and the Carolinas but could be popular elsewhere.</p>
<p>Vice President Al Gore was in Kentucky speaking to a conference of Veterans of Foreign Wars, a group addressed by Dole on Tuesday and to be addressed by Perot on Thursday.</p>
<p>The political arm of the 2 million-strong group has already endorsed Dole, but that did not stop Gore from attacking the Republican candidate. He said Dole's proposed tax cuts would inevitably lead to cuts in veterans' benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;Look behind the rhetoric and look at the facts,&quot; Gore said.</p>
<p>Dole campaign spokesman Nelson Warfield asked the 50-year-old Clinton to follow the 73-year-old Dole's example by releasing all his medical records.</p>
<p>&quot;Clinton aides are often credited with staging events to demonstrate Bill Clinton's youth and vigour,&quot; Warfield said.</p>
<p>&quot;Those campaign tactics ... carry a whiff of hypocrisy when Bill Clinton refuses to meet the same standards for full disclosure that every other president has followed in recent years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In Texas, Reform Party presidential nominee Perot listed James Campbell, his former boss, as a &quot;stand-in&quot; vice presidential candidate on forms filed with the Federal Election Commission. But the Perot campaign said Campbell would not be his eventual running mate.</p>
<p>Perot's spokeswoman declined to say when he would name a vice presidential choice. There were reports that at least two prominent members of Congress had already turned him down.</p>
<p>The Federal Communications Commission gave television networks the green light to offer the major presidential candidates free air time. The agency ruled that proposals for free time made by Fox, ABC and the Public Broadcasting Service did not violate &quot;equal time&quot; provisions of federal communications law.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
