<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6331" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FCC okays free TV time for presidential candidates.</title>
<headline>FCC okays free TV time for presidential candidates.</headline>
<byline>Roger Fillion</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Federal Communications Commission gave television networks the green light on Wednesday to offer the major presidential candidates free air time during the autumn general election.</p>
<p>The approval ensured that TV stations will give President Bill Clinton and Republican Bob Dole -- and quite possibly Reform Party candidate Ross Perot -- free access to the airwaves to make unfiltered pitches for why they should be president.</p>
<p>The FCC said the proposals made by Fox, ABC, and the Public Broadcasting Service did not violate the &quot;equal time&quot; provisions of federal communications law.</p>
<p>The agency also said the proposals represented &quot;on-the-spot coverage of 'bona fide' news events,&quot; and so are exempt from the requirement that TV stations give equal opportunity to all legally qualified candidates.</p>
<p>The approval also placed added pressure on the networks to accept a proposal from a bipartisan group that wants to establish a standardised format for free broadcasts.</p>
<p>&quot;The last hurdle is the major commercial networks and the big cable-TV operators,&quot; said Paul Taylor, chief advocate for the Free TV for Straight Talk Coalition.</p>
<p>Taylor said the FCC decision &quot;clears away any regulatory underbrush&quot; that could have thwarted the group's proposal for candidates to deliver 10 made-for-TV mini speeches 2-1/2 minutes in length during the last month of the campaign.</p>
<p>Clinton and Dole generally accepted the proposal, which was similar to the PBS plan. But ABC, CBS, NBC, Fox and CNN did not agree to set aside the uniform blocks of time required, instead opting to push their own formats.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope this ruling will encourage our commercial television colleagues to join us in broadcasting these appearances at the same time each weeknight,&quot; said PBS President Ervin Duggan.</p>
<p>Sens. John McCain, an Arizona Republican, and Bill Bradley, a New Jersey Democrat, have invited network executives to meet with the Free TV/Straight Talk coalition and work out a standard format. A meeting was scheduled for Sept. 10. Network representatives were expected to attend.</p>
<p>Rupert Murdoch was the first to ask the FCC for permission to allow his Fox network to provide free time to &quot;major&quot; candidates without giving minor or fringe candidates the same opportunity.</p>
<p>Campaign-reform advocates supported the free-time concept, charging that attack ads and 10-second sound bites on the evening news were superficial and poisoned the political process.</p>
<p>The FCC said it was relying on broadcasters' discretion and good faith news judgments, stressing that the proposals must include reasonable safeguards against broadcaster favouritism.</p>
<p>The Fox proposal was for a one-hour programme on the eve of the Nov. 5 election, in which time would be split evenly among candidates selected for inclusion by an independent panel. Fox also proposed 10 60-second slots devoted to election issues.</p>
<p>ABC proposed a one-hour prime-time programme in the last week of the campaign, with the candidates appearing together without interruptions from a third party.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
