<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6347" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Kevorkian's 36th assisted suicide is Texan, age 76.</title>
<headline>Kevorkian's 36th assisted suicide is Texan, age 76.</headline>
<byline>David Lawder</byline>
<dateline>PONTIAC, Mich. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dr. Jack Kevorkian attended the suicide of a terminally ill Texas woman on Tuedsay night while controversy continued over the death of a nonterminal patient last week.</p>
<p>Louise Siebens, 76, of McKinney, Texas, suffered from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, or Lou Gehrig's disease, and died in the presence of Kevorkian, her daughter Ginny and her son-in-law Jerry Burnett, Kevorkian's lawyer, Geoffrey Fieger, said.</p>
<p>Siebens, a former church typist, was diagnosed with the fatal muscular disease in 1995 and was confined to a wheelchair, Fieger said.</p>
<p>Hours before Siebens died, Fieger defended his client's role in helping to end the life of Judith Curren, a 42-year-old registered nurse from Pembroke, Massachusetts, who suffered from chronic fatigue syndrome and muscular pain. Curren died on Aug. 15 from a lethal injection.</p>
<p>Fieger acknowledged that Curren's illnesses were not terminal but said her suffering, which frequently included AIDS-like symptoms, was intolerable. He disputed a coroner's statement on Monday that an autopsy of Curren's body had shown no evidence of disease.</p>
<p>&quot;This was her decision. It was unwavering. It was immutable and based on solid medical evidence,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Boston Herald printed excerpts on Wednesday from Curren's medical records, obtained from her husband, Franklin Curren, which showed that doctors believed she suffered from a painful, debilitating disease but could offer no cure.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not know what to suggest for her,&quot; wrote Dr. Stephen Lipson, an orthopedic surgeon at Beth Israel Hospital in Boston, who saw her in January. &quot;Clearly she suffers from a complex abnormality.&quot;</p>
<p>At about 10:11 p.m. EDT Tuesday (0311 GMT Wednesday), Kevorkian brought Siebens' body into the emergency room of Pontiac Osteopathic Hospital.</p>
<p>The 68-year-old retired pathologist briefly provided some information about Siebens, then left, Dr. Robert Aranosian, the hospital's emergency room director, said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the usual routine -- he arrives, he's here briefly, then he leaves,&quot; Aranosian said.</p>
<p>Siebens' death is the 36th Kevorkian has acknowledged attending since he began his crusade for doctor-assisted suicide in 1990. It was the eighth since he was acquitted of assisted-suicide charges for a third time in May.</p>
<p>Fieger denied on Wednesday that Kevorkian, who has not faced new charges since his last acquittal, was stepping up his assisted-suicide activity. He said Kevorkian was exercising restraint in helping end patients' suffering.</p>
<p>&quot;He's treated hundreds and hundreds of people,&quot; Fieger said. &quot;Most of them go on to die naturally.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PONTIAC, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
