<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6359" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Insect damage found in eastern Illinois corn - tour.</title>
<headline>Insect damage found in eastern Illinois corn - tour.</headline>
<dateline>EL PASO, Ill. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Corn borer and Japanese beetle damage was prevalent in east-central Illinois cornfields, said crop scouts on the second day of the Pro Farmer Crop Tour.</p>
<p>&quot;In the corn fields we were getting 30 or 40 ears (per 30-foot row sample) and we should have been getting 70,&quot; said Gus Sundermeier, an Illinois corn and soybean farmer and 14-year tour veteran, who attributed some of the low ear count to the insect infestations.  </p>
<p>Scouts traveling on one of the 14 tour routes through Illinois found corn borer and Japanese beetles in Iroquois, Ford and Livingston Counties.</p>
<p>In Iroquois county, Japanese beetles had devoured the silk and halted corn's pollination. Ears in those fields measured an average of 2-1/2 inches long versus six inches in other eastern Illinois fields.</p>
<p>Heat stress was also noted and lower leaves were yellow or light green.</p>
<p>&quot;A fair percentage of the corn is starting to fire up,&quot; said Sundermeier, referring to the yellowing.  </p>
<p>All surveyed Illinois soybean fields were podding. Most plants sampled had more than 20 pods, while many fields surveyed in Indiana had no pods. However, most of the sampled Illinios fields still had blooms.</p>
<p>Soybean fields were generally free from disease but few had full canopies. In several fields with 30-inch wide rows the canopies had up to one foot of space between rows at a time when there should be no space. Plant height ranged from 15 to 28 inches.</p>
<p>The tour will move west through Illinois Wednesday, enter Minnesota Thursday and conclude in Iowa Friday.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EL PASO, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
