<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6360" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stingray US Gulf gas flows seen back midday Thurs.</title>
<headline>Stingray US Gulf gas flows seen back midday Thurs.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Natural gas flows on Stingray Pipeline Co's offshore U.S. Gulf pipeline will return to normal by 1200 CDT/1300 EDT Thursday following a three-day maintenance outage, the company said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The line will be back by noon tomorrow at the latest, which is about four hours late,&quot; said a company spokeswoman, noting the pipeline would be accepting nominations for tomorrow on a percentage basis.</p>
<p>The line is currently flowing at a rate of approximately 550 million cubic feet per day (mmcfd), compared with the normal rate of about 780 mmcfd.</p>
<p>On the first day of the outage, testing of the electrical current in the system was being done at Holly Beach, offshore Louisiana.</p>
<p>On the remaining two days flows were being curtailed at West Cameron 509 so that the electronic switch gear in the compression system could be tested.</p>
<p>Stingray Pipeline Co is a partnership between a subsidiary of Leviathan Gas Pipeline Partners Ltd and a subsidiary of Natural Gas Pipeline Co of America, which in turn is a unit of Occidental Petroleum.</p>
<p>--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
