<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6363" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. anti-terrorism rules go into effect Thursday.</title>
<headline>U.S. anti-terrorism rules go into effect Thursday.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Americans from Thursday will be prohibited from receiving or giving money to so-called rogue states Cuba, Iran, Iraq, Libya, North Korea, Syria and Sudan which might be used to fund violent acts, the Treasury Department said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Stemming from a U.S. anti-terrorism law passed in April, the rules are designed to block U.S. and foreign organizations from being able to raise money for extremist purposes by governments on Washington's list of rogue states.</p>
<p>The rules, announced by the Treasury Department's Office of Foreign Assets Control on Wednesday, do not target legitimate business deals in Syria and Sudan, U.S. officials said.</p>
<p>Unlike the other countries listed, Syria and Sudan are not already subject to other broader U.S. trade or investment sanctions.</p>
<p>The rules &quot;prohibit United States persons from receiving unlicensed donations and from engaging in financial transactions with respect to which the United States person knows or has reasonable cause to believe that the financial transaction poses a risk of furthering terrorist acts in the United States.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. companies had raised concern that the anti-terrorism law might stymie their businesses in Syria and Sudan, but the new rules provide blanket permission for any deals that do not funnel money toward extremist organizations.</p>
<p>However, a Treasury Department spokesman said that even companies that are sure their transactions are legal should be aware &quot;that they could be asked for supporting documentation at a later date&quot; to prove they had no reason to believe their money would be diverted.</p>
<p>Organizations breaking the law would be subject to criminal penalties.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LIBYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SYRIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
