<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6373" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: United States urges Kurdish rivals to stop warring.</title>
<headline>United States urges Kurdish rivals to stop warring.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Wednesday urged rival Kurdish parties in northern Iraq to stop fighting and accept a U.S. invitation to peace talks in London.</p>
<p>Fighting between the two Kurdish groups broke out at the weekend, shattering a ceasefire brokered by the United States early last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Prior to the outbreak of the fighting we invited the Kurdish leaders to meet with us in London to pursue the reconciliation process under our auspices,&quot; State Department spokesman Glyn Davies said.</p>
<p>&quot;We therefore call upon the leaders of the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan and of the Kurdistan Democratic Party to exercise maximum restraint, end offensive actions immediately, and participate in these talks with us.&quot;</p>
<p>Davies said continued fighting could &quot;create opportunities for outside players whose agendas have nothing to do with the best interests of the citizens of northern Iraq.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he was referring to Iran, whose forces were accused by the KDP on Wednesday of shelling its positions in the Western-protected Kurdish enclave in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>Davies said there had been no agreement so far by the Kurdish parties to attend the proposed London talks, which would be attended by Robert Deutch, the State Department official who chaired previous talks in Ireland.</p>
<p>The mountainous region of northern Iraq has been split into rival Iraqi Kurdish zones since fighting broke out between the two groups in 1994. Around 3,000 people died until the ceasefire last March.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
