<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6378" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYS steps in to help Utica pull off its debt sale.</title>
<headline>NYS steps in to help Utica pull off its debt sale.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York State, which waited about as long as it could to see if the cash-strapped City of Utica, which was at risk of default, could tap the debt markets without assistance, said on Wednesday that it bought some of the city's notes.</p>
<p>The purchase, which is unusual, was signalled on Tuesday, when a spokesman for the state comptroller, H. Carl McCarl, said the office was discussing the matter with the city.</p>
<p>Completing the transaction hinges on Utica's Common Council carrying out certain promises that the state Comptroller required in order to ensure that its short-term investment has adequate protection, a spokesman said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's essentially a done deal,&quot; said Steven Greenberg, the spokesman.</p>
<p>No details about what sort of commitments the state required from Utica were immediately available.</p>
<p>The state last year helped to rescue the financially beleagured City of Troy by buying a modest amount of the debt it issued through a state-imposed control board,</p>
<p>Utica, which has a population of about 68,000 and around $53.5 million of debt outstanding, needed to sell around $24.5 million of debt in time to repay about $25 million of debt that matures on Friday.</p>
<p>It started trying to sell the debt on August 14, and had hoped to complete the transaction by August 16, but the offering stretched into August 20, when it was finally priced.</p>
<p>The state plans to buy $2.145 million of the approximately $11.5 million bond anticipation notes that Utica is issuing. The city also has sold approximately $12.5 million of bonds.</p>
<p>Utica, which is facing a budget gap of as much as $2 million in its 1997 budget and has a history of deficit financing, is rated CCC by Standard &amp; Poor's, which signifies that there are factors that place it at risk of default.</p>
<p>Moody's Investors Service has given it a slightly higher rating of Ba.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
