<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6380" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: 15 tons of Nazi gold went missing after war -- document. [CORRECTED 1:30 GMT 22/8]</title>
<headline>15 tons of Nazi gold went missing after war -- document. [CORRECTED 1:30 GMT 22/8]</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A newly discovered document in the U.S. National Archives says Hitler's Foreign Minister Joachim von Ribbentrop rushed 15 tons of gold out of Berlin before it fell in 1945, but most of it disappeared.</p>
<p>The document, a 1948 letter from a key prosecutor at the Nuremberg War Crimes Tribunal to U.S. military occupation officials, raises the possibility that more than half of what was called &quot;the Ribbentrop Gold Fund&quot; disappeared while allegedly in U.S. and British hands.</p>
<p>The letter was written by Deputy Chief Nuremberg War Crimes prosecutor Robert Kempner, who warned of the danger to the Allies if underground Nazis had control of all or part of the gold bullion, which would be worth about $250 milliion today.</p>
<p>Kempner said, &quot;a large amount of uncontrolled gold constitutes a force of evil and mischief in the hands of unscrupulous opportunists working closely together and located in many countries all over the world.&quot;</p>
<p>The letter was found by World Jewish Congress researchers examining the question of looted Jewish assets moved by the Nazis into Swiss banks during the war. It was in an archive relating to &quot;Project Safehaven,&quot; the U.S. intelligence effort after the war to locate Nazi assets.</p>
<p>The WJC said the document was found in the last few weeks. Drexel Sprecher, a prosecutor who worked closely with Kempner during the trials, said he had never heard of the &quot;Gold Fund&quot; nor did he recall Kempner ever mentioning the subject.</p>
<p>Von Ribbentrop, Hitler's foreign minister from 1938 to</p>
<p>1945, was hanged in 1946 (Deletes month)</p>
<p>after being found guilty of war crimes. He was the highest ranking Nazi to be executed.</p>
<p>In his letter, Kempner said that 6.5 tons of the gold was sent to von Ribbentrop's castle in Fuschl, Austria, where most of it was allegedly turned over to American troops there. Meanwhile, two tons were sent to Schleswig-Holstein and allegedly handed over to British troops.</p>
<p>But a WJC spokesman said there was no record of U.S. troops receiving the gold in Fuschl. He added that a preliminary check by British authorities could also find no reference to the gold in Schleswig-Holstein.</p>
<p>Kempner said that another three tons were sent to the German side of Lake Constance (Corrects name of lake),</p>
<p>where part of it was then ferried to Berne, Switzerland.</p>
<p>The remaining gold in the &quot;Ribbentrop Fund&quot; was sent to Spain, Sweden, Switzerland, Turkey and Portugal in the last two years of the war, according to his letter.</p>
<p>Some of the gold that went to Lake Constantine was recovered by U.S. troops but the other four tons was feared to have fallen into Nazi hands.</p>
<p>The gold in the &quot;Ribbentrop Fund&quot; came from bullion looted in Belgium and from concentration camp victims, according to other documents.</p>
<p>Previous documents from Project Safehaven show that the Germans sent $4 billion in gold by today's prices to Switzerland during the course of the war. The documents also allege a close working relationship between the Nazis and Swiss banking officials.</p>
<p>On Dec. 10, 1941, the British Embassy in Washington warned the U.S. Treasury Department &quot;that every leading member of the governing groups in all the Axis countries have funds in Switzerland. Some of the leaders have fortunes. ...&quot;</p>
<p>One document identifies an account held for Hitler in Switzerland, apparently a repository for royalities for his book &quot;Mein Kampf.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
