<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6384" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Year 2000 computer bug to cost government billions.</title>
<headline>Year 2000 computer bug to cost government billions.</headline>
<byline>Tabassum Zakaria</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. government agencies must find billions of dollars in their budgets for an antidote to the millennium bug that looms over computers ready to strike in 2000, government officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>No additional appropriations will be made to fix the problem and government agencies must submit their strategies to the Office of Management and Budget before Nov. 1.</p>
<p>The cost for the U.S. government was estimated at $9 billion to $30 billion. Estimates for a worldwide fix range from $300 billion to $600 billion.</p>
<p>The problem is one of digits. In the 1960s and 1970s computer programmers used two digits to represent the year instead of four, expecting the programmes to be obsolete by the millennium. So most computers either think &quot;OO&quot; means 1900, or reject it as invalid.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no new money in the budget,&quot; Edward Springer, a staffer from the Office of Management and Budget, said at a Year 2000 seminar. &quot;Agencies will reprogram resources to fix this problem,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Funds already appropriated for new computer system or design features would be &quot;prime targets&quot; for shifting to pay to fix the millennium bug, Springer said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see dollars as the primary constraint here, I see time as the primary constraint,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>With 40 months left until 2000, government officials said it was imperative that agencies start working on solutions.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem must be addressed now,&quot; said Joe Thompson, chief information officer at the General Services Administration, where the seminar was held.</p>
<p>&quot;When its two zeroes appear at the turn of the century, computers will interpret that result as being Jan. 1, 1900, not 2000,&quot; he said. &quot;If we don't fix the problem, systems will fail, data will be corrupted ... business will not be as usual.&quot;</p>
<p>If left unfixed, the millennium bug could mean Treasury would be unable to write checks dated 2000 and automated teller machines would read the &quot;OO&quot; date as expired.</p>
<p>The banking and insurance industries have been in the forefront in addressing the problem because of mortgages and actuarial tables, said Robert Cook, a staffer from the House Science Committee's technology subcommittee.</p>
<p>He also emphasised that new appropriations would not be made to deal with the problem.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the current budget constraints, members (of Congress) are reluctant to dedicate new funds,&quot; Cook said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the current budget climate, there's not going to be a lot of enthusiasm to follow the state of Nebraska's lead,&quot; Cook said, referring to the state's imposition of a two-cent per pack cigarette tax to pay for dealing with the problem.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
