<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6385" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - prices slacken w/Treasuries.</title>
<headline>U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - prices slacken w/Treasuries.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. municipal bonds were flat to down a quarter of a point in late trade on Wednesday, as the market continued to outperform the benchmark 30-year U.S. Treasury bonds, which fell half of a point.</p>
<p>Although volume remained light as is typical in August, which meant few transactions were priced, fairly robust supplies of bonds in the secondary market also weighed on municipal bond prices.  </p>
<p>In early trade, there were a sizable number of bid wanted lists circulating, but traders said that as the day progressed, potential buyers, who were wary of the pressure exerted by the softer Treasury market, turned cautious.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that because of the combination of the Treasuries, which had a little sell-off, and the fair amount of bid-wanted lists, I don't think people got too aggressive on the bid,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>And one of the new issues that hit the market was not as well-received as expected, as the underwriters only placed about one-half of the $120 million of bonds that were sold by Connecticut. The offering of general obligation bonds was priced at a true interest cost of 5.14 percent.</p>
<p>The outlook for municipal bonds hinges in part on whether September U.S. Treasury futures hold support clustered around 110 and at 109-3/4, a trader said. The contracts, traded on the Chicago Board of Trade, ended down eight ticks at 110-20/32.  </p>
<p>The September municipal bond futures fell nine ticks to 116-12/32.</p>
<p>This left the MOB spread between the two futures contracts at 147, a level that is considered fairly rich.</p>
<p>Actively quoted issues included Intermountain Power Agency Utah Supply Revnue Refunding of July 2021, which have a five percent coupon. The issues were offered at 5.80 percent on a net basis, up one basis point from offers seen on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Cook County Illinois Capital Improvement of November 2022, which have a 5-7/8 percent coupon, were bid at 99-3/4, down an eight of a point from Tuesday.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
