<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6386" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Judge orders levy on ballot for Cleveland schools.</title>
<headline>Judge orders levy on ballot for Cleveland schools.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. District Court judge in Cleveland on Wednesday ordered that a 13.5 property tax mill operating levy be placed on the November ballot for the Cleveland schools.</p>
<p>The judge's order came after the Ohio Department of Education, which took control of the schools in March 1995, filed a motion asking the court to override the Cleveland School Board's decision Monday rejecting a referendum to increase the levy.</p>
<p>In his order, Judge George W. White ordered the state superintendent of schools to certify the levy request with the Cuyahoga County Board of Elections before Thursday's deadline for inclusion on the November ballot.</p>
<p>Steve Puckett, an assistant state superintendent of education, said the levy was needed to improve services at the schools and to start paying off the district's operating debt.</p>
<p>According to Bryan Christman, the schools interim chief financial officer and treasurer, the district has about $87 million of operating debt that is due to mature in December and next June.</p>
<p>In addition, the school system also faces a a $23 million deficit in its $500 million general fund budget, he added.</p>
<p>Christman said the levy would raise about $67.5 million a year.</p>
<p>Puckett said the state pushed for the levy request because it was Cleveland's turn to start supporting its schools.</p>
<p>&quot;The state's position is the community needs to come to the plate and supply local revenues,&quot; he said, adding that the last levy passed for the Cleveland schools was in 1983.</p>
<p>Puckett said without the levy increase, the school system would face a budget gap of $150 million next year. He added the levy request was supported by the state and the plaintiffs in an ongoing federal desegregation case involving the Cleveland schools.</p>
<p>A 1994 consent decree provided for the placement of an operating levy before voters each year, unless all parties -- the state, the district and the plaintiffs -- agreed that such a move would be counterproductive.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the Cleveland school face the possibility of a teachers' strike shortly after school starts on Aug. 28, Christman said.</p>
<p>--Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
