<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6388" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gown, veil, no bride at Rodman's &quot;wedding&quot;.</title>
<headline>Gown, veil, no bride at Rodman's &quot;wedding&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Wulfhorst</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wedding plans for the world's most tattooed, pierced, dyed, cross-dressing basketball star fell through on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Chicago Bulls forward Dennis Rodman, despite his predictions, did not get married in a midday ceremony at New York City's landmark Rockefeller Centre. What he did do was appear in a floor-length white wedding dress, attract a screaming throng of fans and sign copies of his book &quot;Bad As I Wanna Be&quot; at Fifth Avenue's Barnes &amp; Noble store.</p>
<p>&quot;It's him and his dress. That was it,&quot; said a bookstore spokeswoman. &quot;It was all a publicity stunt.&quot;</p>
<p>Rodman, whose penchant for dying his hair, tattooing his body and speaking his mind has brought perhaps as much attention as his athletic prowess -- he's the National Basketball Association's top rebounder -- had been threatening to wed stripper Stacy Yarborough.</p>
<p>He announced his wedding plans to talk show host David Letterman on Tuesday night. But on Wednesday, Yarborough was nowhere to be found.</p>
<p>Bride-less, basketball's bad boy nonetheless played the role to the hilt. He arrived in a horse-drawn carriage, accompanied by four tuxedo-clad female attendants. He wore an orange wig, elbow-length gloves and two earrings in his nose.</p>
<p>Hundreds of fans, many of whom waited more than an hour in light rain in a line that stretched well around the block, burst into wild applause.</p>
<p>Inside, Rodman was demure, fluttering his false eyelashes and complying with fans' requests for signatures, handshakes and photographs. Asked why all the regalia, he replied, &quot;What better place to be the bride than New York?&quot; and returned to the business of selling books.</p>
<p>However, he did say, perhaps in jest, that he still planned to tie the knot.</p>
<p>Outside, the news of the non-nuptials delighted Grace Kim, a fan from Basking Ridge, New Jersey. &quot;I told my friends if he meets me, he'll marry me,&quot; the 18-year-old said, clutching a bag of books she hoped he would sign.</p>
<p>&quot;It means I still have a chance,&quot; she said happily.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
