<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6391" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CalPERS says earned 15.4 pct on investments.</title>
<headline>CalPERS says earned 15.4 pct on investments.</headline>
<dateline>SACRAMENTO, Calif. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The California Public Employees' Retirement System (CalPERS) said on Wednesday it earned a 15.4 percent rate of return on investments, ending the 1995-1996 fiscal year with a portfolio valued at $100.7 billion.</p>
<p>The performance increases the fund's growth rate to nearly 32 percent over the last two years, CalPERS said. CalPERS fiscal year-end return on total equity investments yielded approximately a 24 percent return.</p>
<p>About 34 percent of the fund was invested in fixed income, 61 percent in equities and six percent in real estate.  </p>
<p>CalPERS said its fiscal year ended June 30.</p>
<p>&quot;CalPERS continued growth and sound investment strategy are key indicators that we are prepared to meet the challenges that we will face in the coming years,&quot; Charles Valdes, chair of the CalPERS investment committee, said in a statement. &quot;However, we must remember that the market has not always been good to the fund.&quot;</p>
<p>Market forces and sluggish state and national economies had limited the 1994 return rate to 2.5 percent, CalPERS said.  </p>
<p>As an increasing number of the one million members covered by CalPERS retire in the decades ahead, the fund's annual disbursements will soar from $3.5 billion today to $34 billion by the year 2024, CalPERS said.</p>
<p>Approximately 81 percent of the total fund comes from investment returns, while the remaining difference is contributed by employers and employees. Employer contributions total about 11 percent, while employees provide about eight percent, CalPERS said.</p>
<p>In addition to its performance results, the system reported that approximately $11.6 billion -- or 12 percent of the fund -- has been invested within the state of California.</p>
<p>CalPERS is the nation's largest public pension fund. The system provides retirement and health benefits to one million current and retired employees and their families.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150214">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SACRAMENTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
