<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6393" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT wheat ends lower on slack demand, vomitoxin.</title>
<headline>CBOT wheat ends lower on slack demand, vomitoxin.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A slowdown in export sales coupled with prospects for increases in the deliverable supply of wheat after a recent rejection by Egypt of U.S. soft red supplies pressured CBOT wheat futures to a lower close, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is still the vomitoxin talk in wheat,&quot; said Ron Kucha of O'Connor and Co.</p>
<p>Egypt recently rejected U.S. soft red winter wheat on concerns about vomitoxin.</p>
<p>Other than a &quot;gentleman's agreement&quot;, there are no provisions to keep wheat containing vomitoxin from being posted for delivery on CBOT wheat futures contracts.</p>
<p>Wheat also sagged on diminished fears of frost damage.</p>
<p>An Environment Canada meteorologist early Wednesday said temperatures dipped overnight in the foothills of Alberta but key grain growing regions in the Canadian Prairies remained frost free.</p>
<p>Phil Wright of Environment Canada said it appears there was little, if any, danger of frost.</p>
<p>Wheat rallied early this week on concerns about potential cold weather damage to portions of the Canadian spring wheat growing region.</p>
<p>Wheat closed two to 4-1/4 cents per bushel lower, with September down 3-1/2 at $4.51.</p>
<p>Wheat futures volume was estimated at 14,000, down from 14,636 Tuesday.</p>
<p>In the wheat options pit volume was thin with Paine Webber a seller of December $4.50 puts and Refco Inc sold September $5.00 puts, traders said.</p>
<p>Wheat options volume was estimated at 4,500, up from 4,388 Tuesday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
