<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6399" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Educ. Dept. says 6,000 new schools needed by 2006.</title>
<headline>Educ. Dept. says 6,000 new schools needed by 2006.</headline>
<byline>Vicky Stamas</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Education Secretary Richard Riley said Wednesday about 6,000 more schools will be needed to accommodate a record 54.6 million children that will reach school age in the next 10 years.</p>
<p>The finding is part of a special back-to-school report prepared by the the Education Department's National Center for Education Statistics on what demographers call the &quot;Baby Boom Echo,&quot; the children of the baby-boom generation who are now in school.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, these increases are placing a serious demand on schools and the communities that invest in them,&quot; Riley said, noting that a record 51.7 million students will enter the nation's classrooms this fall.</p>
<p>&quot;California, for example, can expect to add some half- million students to its high schools over the next decade, a 33 percent increase in enrollment in a state that already has one of the highest average class sizes in the country,&quot; Riley said in a press statement.</p>
<p>Michael Decker, vice president for policy analysis at the Public Securities Association, predicted that localities will continue to look to the new issue tax-exempt bond market to help finance the 6,000 new schools.</p>
<p>Obviously, the demographics will &quot;put pressure on communities&quot; searching for ways to pay back debt, Decker said. &quot;But going back many decades, schools have traditionally been built by bonds and I think they will continue to be.&quot;</p>
<p>That is because a growing population also signals a stable or growing economy, which translates into more tax revenue to fund schools, Decker said.</p>
<p>According to the report, in addition to California, states where enrollment is expected to jump by more than 10 percent by 2006 are Alabama, Alaska, Delaware, Hawaii, Maryland, Oregon and Washington.</p>
<p>In all, 33 states will have rising enrollments, mostly in the far West and Southeast, the report says. Seventeen states and the District of Columbia can expect a decrease, the report says.</p>
<p>&quot;Unlike the 1960s when the end of the enrollment boom was soon in sight, this current increase is a long, slow, rising wave,&quot; said Riley.</p>
<p>&quot;And, we see no immediate fall off. We are only at the midpoint and we have 10 more years of growth ahead,&quot; he said, siting the trend among baby boomer offspring to delay marriage and childbearing as one reason for the steady rise.</p>
<p>Riley said, &quot;Portable classrooms or double sessions are not realistic answers to a long-term persistent growth in the number of students.&quot;</p>
<p>He sited as an example Clark County School District in Nevada, where enrollments have nearly doubled over the past 10 years and where 15 new schools will open their doors in the next two years.</p>
<p>Riley said high school enrollment will jump by 15 percent nationwide over the next decade and the number of college students will grow by about two million, to 16.4 million by 2006.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the ratio of workers to retirees will continue to drop, he said, from about five to one in 1970 to around 2.6 to one in 2030, when an influx of new workers is expected to stabilize the ratio, according to the report.</p>
<p>The report is available on the department's homepage at http://www.ed.gov/NCES/pugs/.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
