<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6405" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton signs health care reform bill.</title>
<headline>Clinton signs health care reform bill.</headline>
<byline>Steve Holland</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton signed into law on Wednesday limited health reform that will help millions of Americans keep their medical insurance.</p>
<p>The action immediatedly brought election-year charges from Republicans that the law was three years overdue.</p>
<p>At a colourful South Lawn ceremony complete with a Marine Corps band playing patriotic songs, Clinton put his name on the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 as key members of Congress and others looked over his shoulder.</p>
<p>&quot;With this bill, we take a long step toward the kind of health care reform our nation needs,&quot; said Clinton, who was thwarted two years ago when he sought a sweeping overhaul of the U.S. health care system.</p>
<p>The law guarantees access to insurance for people who change jobs if their new employer offers coverage and forces insurance companies to end a practice of excluding people with pre-existing medical problems.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we declare a victory for millions of Americans and their families. No longer will you live in fear of losing your health insurance because of the state of your health,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>It lets self-employed people take a bigger tax break on health coverage they buy for themselves. It also authorises a pilot programme of 750,000 so-called Medical Savings Accounts to replace conventional health insurance policies for employees of small companies or self-employed people.</p>
<p>The ink was hardly dry on the law before fax machines were rolling out reams of reaction statements from Republicans trying to claim their share of credit for the law, since they control Congress.</p>
<p>&quot;This bill includes many of the important health insurance reforms I've promoted for years and should end once and for all the Clinton prescription of big-government health care,&quot; Republican candidate Bob Dole said.</p>
<p>Party chairman Haley Barbour charged at a news conference that Clinton was taking credit for &quot;another accomplishment of the common-sense Republican Congress.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the law could have been passed three years ago &quot;were it not for the Clintons' wrongheaded scheme to create a government-run health care system.&quot;</p>
<p>The law emerged from a joint effort by Republican Sen. Nancy Kassebaum of Kansas and Democratic Sen. Edward Kennedy of Massachusetts to bring about modest health care reform after the death of Clinton's own sweeping shakeup, denounced by Republicans as a government takeover of health care.</p>
<p>That effort was spearheaded by Clinton's wife, Hillary, and at the signing ceremony, the president singled her out for praise as she watched from the front row.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe, Hillary, that this justifies all those days on the road and all those nights you stayed up reading the incomprehensibly complex issues of heatlh care,&quot; he said to applause.</p>
<p>Clinton, who signed an increase in the national minimum wage on Tuesday and is to sign welfare reform legislation on Thursday, said there was more work to do on health care reform. Currently about 40 million Americans lack medical insurance.</p>
<p>Clinton gave credit to members of both parties for the legislation. A White House fact sheet, however, said that if it Clinton had not exerted pressure, the bill would not have been brought to a vote.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
