<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6413" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Democrats lay miles of cable for convention.</title>
<headline>Democrats lay miles of cable for convention.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anyone who has something to say to the Democrats at their convention next week can say it over the Internet, convention organisers said Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Democrats' address is http://www.dncc96.org.</p>
<p>In a test of the convention's elaborate multi-media communications system, Democratic National Committee Chairman Don Fowler welcomed state party chairmen to an Internet &quot;chat room,&quot; where he started the dialogue with a message that they would be renominating President Clinton for a second term.</p>
<p>Fowler toured the United Centre convention site, stopping off at the Democratic News Service nerve centre where radio interviews and television images can be beamed to hundreds of stations that cannot be there.</p>
<p>He also tested an electronic voting system that will tally votes of the 5,000 delegates. But the state-by-state verbal roll call will be preserved for old time's sake, Fowler said. &quot;We've tested for that and people like the roll call vote.&quot;</p>
<p>The electronic voting system, which works by touching a television screen, also can connect delegates to the Internet.</p>
<p>A spokesman for AT&amp;T., Stan Gorski, said 25,000 telephones were installed at the convention site and &quot;miles&quot; of fiber optic and copper cable was laid. The company anticipated one million &quot;hits&quot; per day on the convention's web site.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
