<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6414" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME lumber plummets to lower close after new high.</title>
<headline>CME lumber plummets to lower close after new high.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME lumber futures set a new contract high of $395.30 per thousand board feet in September early before prices fell sharply on profit taking and hedge selling prompted by slowing cash dealings, traders said.</p>
<p>September dropped for a near limit loss of $9.90 per tbf and November touched the $10.00 limit loss before futures closed $9.20 to $3.00 lower. September ended down $8.30 at $386.50 and November was off most at $350.50 per tbf.</p>
<p>Initial carryover demand from Tuesday's sharp gains lacked follow through and prices quickly fell on profit taking. Values worked lower much of the day before tumbling late.</p>
<p>Added hedge selling touched off sell stops and futures fell limit or near limit before short covering pared losses just ahead of the close. Reports that cash trade had slowed prompted much of the pressure. Random Lengths quoted cash spruce at $412, up $1 from last Friday, but the trade had been expecting a larger gain, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;That is the first sign that we have seen in a month that cash may finally be slowing,&quot; said Neil Schmaedick, Smith Barney Forest Products analyst. &quot;There seems to be enough secondary wood around to compete with the mills at this time.&quot;</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
