<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6415" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. wildfires area shrinking, more blazes feared.</title>
<headline>U.S. wildfires area shrinking, more blazes feared.</headline>
<byline>Adam Entous</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Firefighters gained ground on Wednesday on some of the largest wildfires sweeping the western United States, but officials warned new blazes could ignite as lightning storms build in the parched region.</p>
<p>Cooler temperatures in recent days have helped thousands of firefighters and soldiers gain ground on the worst blazes in California, while crews in central Oregon said they were containing that state's most vicious fire.</p>
<p>The National Interagency Fire Centre on Wednesday reported six new large fires in Idaho, Montana, Nevada, Utah and Wyoming for a total of 29 major fires scorching 349,364 acres (139,745 hectares). The latest fire count was down sharply from Sunday, when the fire centre reported a total of 46 large fires on 502,970 acres (201,188 hectares).</p>
<p>&quot;But we're now starting to go back to hot and dry weather, and as dry thunderstorms return to the region we can expect more fires to start,&quot; warned Renee Snyder, a spokeswoman for the fire centre in Boise, Idaho. &quot;The thunderstorms will bring lightning and the lightning will bring fires.&quot;</p>
<p>On Wednesday, more than 20,166 personnel were assigned to the fires, supported by 164 helicopters and 38 airtankers. Faced with a shortage of crews, authorities put soldiers, prison inmates and firefighters from the East on the lines.</p>
<p>In northern California, thousands of firefighters and more than 600 soldiers continued to gain ground on the so-called Fork fire about 100 miles (160 km) north of San Francisco. It shrank slightly overnight to 73,600 acres (29,440 hectares) from 77,000 acres (31,160 hectares), allowing residents evacuated from the Long and Spring valley areas to return.</p>
<p>In San Luis Obispo County, midway between San Francisco and Los Angeles, a wildfire has now consumed 90,000 acres (36,000 hectares), up from 69,000 acres (27,600 hectares) on Monday. The fire has increased in size because firefighters were igniting unburned vegetation inside the control lines. Officials expect to contain the blaze fully on Thursday.</p>
<p>In Utah, authorities said they hoped to get the upper hand soon on a 9,300 acre (3,720 hectare) blaze in the southwestern part of the state, north of Cedar City.</p>
<p>In southwestern Colorado, some 479 firefighters battled a 4,700 acre (1,880 hectare) blaze in Mesa Verde National Park. Fire information officer Bob Irvine said the fire was now 30 percent contained but there were fears it would be whipped up if the humidity dropped.</p>
<p>Tourists in Colorado to see the treasured cliff dwellings of the Anasazi people were still not allowed in the park, Irvine said. Park officials said they believed the cliff dwellings were safe because they were not surrounded by trees, but Irvine said officials will not know for sure until they can go back into the park and examine the ruins.</p>
<p>In Oregon, authorities said they had contained the largest of the active fires in the central part of the state. The Simnasho fire on the Warm Springs Indian reservation stood at over 109,000 acres (43,600 hectares) but was fully contained.</p>
<p>&quot;The crisis is over,&quot; said Terry Virgin of the Central Oregon Interagency Dispatch. &quot;But we're extremely dry. If we get (lightning) strikes, we're going to have other fires.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
