<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6416" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs end mostly off, Aug pork bellies dn limit.</title>
<headline>CME hogs end mostly off, Aug pork bellies dn limit.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME hog futures ended mostly lower and August pork bellies again fell the limit as falling cash markets and increased hog runs and slaughter weighed on values, traders said.</p>
<p>Hogs finished 0.400 cent a lb lower to 0.125 higher with October off 0.150 cent at 53.400 cents per lb. August pork bellies ended limit down at 89.375 cents while next year contracts closed mixed, up 0.400 to off 0.150 with February up 0.350 at 82.150 cents.</p>
<p>Despite technical short covering, hog futures were pressured from declining cash markets, traders said.</p>
<p>Futures found technical support around 53.000 cents, basis October, and moved up for net gains at times on local short covering. Funds had sold at the start. But gains failed to hold as indications for cash hogs Thursday were again lower, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market doesn't hold a rally&quot; even with October holding a discount to cash, said Vince Wright, floor manager for Packers Trading.</p>
<p>Prudential Securities, Dean Witter, Merrill Lynch and Rand Financials sold October early with Rand Financials buying on the rally, traders said. Funds sold again late, sources said.  </p>
<p>August pork bellies fell the daily limit for the third consecutive day and the fifth limit loss in six days, knocked lower by the recent skid in fresh belly prices, traders said. Cash has fallen $14 per cwt to $82 from its high of $106 on August 8. This is the lowest cash level since July 5 and it continues to leave futures at a large premium to cash.</p>
<p>&quot;The hog slaughter (rate) is just too much for the market,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Increased hog marketings have resulted in a stepped up pace of slaughter and the added product has turned cash belly prices down from 20-year highs, they said.</p>
<p>USDA estimated Wednesday's slaughter at 348,000 head, bringing the week-to-date total to 1,008,000, up from last week's 998,000 in the comparable period but below last year's 1,028,000.</p>
<p>However, next year contracts showed technical support on an oversold condition. Spreaders also bought February and sold August, they added.</p>
<p>Estimates on Friday's monthly USDA Cold Storage Report ranged from 35.1 million to 38.7 million lbs on hand August 1, below 47.1 million on hand a year ago.</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
