<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6430" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME live cattle end mostly down, Aug sets new high.</title>
<headline>CME live cattle end mostly down, Aug sets new high.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME live cattle futures closed mostly lower on profit taking, but August posted a new contract high on support from strong cash markets and rolling of short positions into back months, traders said.</p>
<p>August live cattle set a new contract high of 69.900 cents and closed strong, up 0.375 at 69.875 cents. Other months finished 0.225 lower to unchanged.</p>
<p>Spot August continued to show strength following the record feedlot trade this week as well as the outlook for tighter showlists the next few weeks and an expected bullish cattle-on-feed report Friday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The record (feedlot) movement is bullish and the cattle (on feed) report is also expected to be constructive,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Texas Panhandle/western Oklahoma feedlots reported a record 141,600 head weekly trade and Kansas a record 118,000 head for the week. Early estimates on the report averaged 86.2 percent for total August 1 on-feed numbers in the seven major feedlot states. July placement estimates averaged 110.5 percent and July marketings 102.4 percent.</p>
<p>Backs eased on profit taking from an overbought condition and heavy placement estimates were also negative, they said.  </p>
<p>Refco and Cargill Investor Services bought August on the advance but selling by Cargill Investor Services and R.J. O'Brien later capped the market. Refco and Lind-Waldock sold October while spreaders sold October and December and hedgers sold December, pit sources said.</p>
<p>In live cattle options, volatility was weak on selling of at- and out-of-the-money calls in October and December early. Hedging interest, selling puts and buying calls was cited in February late, pit sources added.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle ended mixed as short covering generally offset pressure from higher corn futures, traders said.</p>
<p>November paced the recovery after being very oversold Tuesday on its late limit break. Stone Traders notably sold November. Scattered commission house short covering supported other months, they said.</p>
<p>The latest CME feeder cattle index was up $0.35 at 62.92 per cwt.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle closed 0.200 cent lower to 0.500 higher with October up 0.275 at 63.450 cents.</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
