<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6432" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Army jails soldier on China spy charges.</title>
<headline>U.S. Army jails soldier on China spy charges.</headline>
<byline>Jim Wolf</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Army has charged a 20-year-old computer specialist with spying, apparently for China, after he demonstrated a flaw in a military computer network and gave a computer code to a Chinese friend, the soldier's parents said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Pfc. Eric Jenott of the 50th Airborne Signal Battalion at Fort Bragg, North Carolina, has been under arrest since late June, his father, John Jenott, said.</p>
<p>The Army said Jenott was being held in a &quot;pre-trial confinement facility&quot; at the Marine Corps base at Camp Lejeune, North Carolina, while an investigation continued, but declined comment on any charges.</p>
<p>John Jenott said his son, a fluent Chinese speaker whom he described as a &quot;computer genius&quot; with a longstanding interest in China, had given a young Chinese friend what the son described as an unclassified computer code.</p>
<p>&quot;Just a young guy -- one of his friends. And he said he gave him some computer code pass number that was not even classified. He said he didn't get any money for it. He just kind of did it as a friendly gesture,&quot; the father said.</p>
<p>He said his son knew the person to whom he gave the code from one of several trips he had made to China. His son, &quot;not your average kid-out-on-a-skateboard-type guy,&quot; could read and write Chinese and lived with a Chinese family in Vancouver, Canada, for about a year when he was in high school, he added.</p>
<p>He said his son told him that before giving away the code, he had been trying to show his superiors a security flaw in a sensitive communication system and eventually demonstrated that he could get secret data without authorisation.</p>
<p>&quot;He was trying to say we have a weakness,&quot; John Jenott said in a telephone interview from his home in Graham, Washington. &quot;This stuff about being a spy -- it's ridiculous.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;They're blowing this way out of proportion,&quot; added the soldier's stepmother, Kelly Jenott.</p>
<p>Jenott's court-martial is currently scheduled to begin Sept. 24 but likely will be delayed, perhaps until October or November, his father said. He said an Army major at Fort Bragg, whom he declined to name, had tried to enlist his help in getting his son to sign a confession so prosecutors would not seek the death penalty.</p>
<p>Jenott said his son had told him: &quot;'Dad, I'd rather die than sign that.' He said it's not true. He said 'I'm not a spy. I didn't commit espionage. And I'm not going to sign something that says I did.'&quot;</p>
<p>Jenott's civilian attorney, Timothy Dunn of Fayetteville, North Carolina, did not return a call seeking comment.</p>
<p>The Fayetteville Observer Times, which broke the story of Jenott's arrest on Wednesday, quoted Army documents as saying he had given &quot;secret computer passwords relating to the national defence&quot; to a foreign national.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
