<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6433" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton signs modest health reform law.</title>
<headline>Clinton signs modest health reform law.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton, opting for modest health care changes after failing to achieve sweeping reforms, on Wednesday signed a bill making it easier for workers to take their health insurance with them when they change jobs.</p>
<p>The bill also allows a pilot programme for 750,000 so-called Medical Savings Accounts to replace conventional health insurance policies for employees of small companies or self-employed people. In addition, it gives the self-employed a bigger tax break on health coverage they buy for themselves.  </p>
<p>At a White House signing ceremony, Clinton said: &quot;With this bill we take a long step towards the kind of health care reform our nation needs. It seals the cracks that swallow as many as 25 million Americans who can't get insurance or who fear they'll lose it.&quot;</p>
<p>He said: &quot;This bill is a clear boost to our values as Americans. It offers opportunity by allowing people to take their health insurance from job to job. It rewards responsibility by helping people to work who desperately want to work.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton's drive for universal health insurance, championed by first lady Hillary Rodham Clinton, collapsed in 1994. After Republicans took control of Congress in 1995, both Congress and the Clinton administration turned to more modest steps to reform the system.</p>
<p>The new law, sponsored by Republican Senator Nancy Kassebaum of Kansas and Democratic Senator Edward Kennedy of Massachusetts, generally protects those who change jobs or become ill from losing their medical benefits.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
