<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6436" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: S&amp;P cuts Richmond Pkg Auth, Calif., to BBB-plus.</title>
<headline>S&amp;P cuts Richmond Pkg Auth, Calif., to BBB-plus.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's Corp Wednesday said it has downgraded its rating on Richmond Parking Authority, Calif.'s lease rental bonds series 1977 to triple-B'-plus from single-A'-minus, issued for Richmond, Calif.</p>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's has assigned its triple-B'-plus rating to Richmond Joint Powers Financing Authority's $6.5 million Port Terminal lease revenue bonds series 1996 due 2016, also issued for Richmond, Calif.</p>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's has affirmed its ratings on Richmond Joint Powers Financing Authority's following bonds:</p>
<p>-- $13 million Port Terminal lease bonds series 1994 (Union Bank of California LOC) at single-A'/A-1',</p>
<p>-- $16.8 million refunding revenue bonds series 1995A at single-A', and</p>
<p>-- $5.18 million refunding revenue bonds series 1995B at single-A'-minus.</p>
<p>The downgrade is based on the city's increased exposure to the deteriorating operations of the Port of Richmond. The city is obligated to service the port's series 1994 and 1996 revenue bonds with general fund resources to the extent that net port revenues are insufficient. The port's multi-year operating statistics for tonnage, landings, and net revenues demonstrate very weak trends, making it increasingly likely the general fund commitment will be called upon. Additional rating factors include an adequate financial position, a concentrated local economic base participating in a broad and diverse regional economy, and moderate debt levels.</p>
<p>The rating on the series 1996 bonds also reflects the city's covenant to budget and appropriate lease payments, and good project essentiality. The bonds are secured by the port's Terminal No. 1 and site, and are payable from a subordinate lien on net port revenues backed by city lease rental payments. Proceeds will provide funds for port capital improvements, including dredging the harbor to 38 feet to facilitate ship access. The Joint Powers Finance Authority's series 1995A and 1995B ratings are based on the credit quality of the underlying obligations securing the bonds, respectively, pursuant to issuance under the Marks Roos Local Bond Pooling Act.</p>
<p>Richmond (population 90,900) is located 16 miles northeast of San Francisco on the western shore of Contra Costa county. In recent years, the city's financial performance has been detrimented by recessionary pressures, state revenue shifts, and a lack of local revenue-raising options. Ongoing fiscal stress is reflected in 1995's unreserved general financial position of $1.6 million, or 2.9% of expenditures and 1996's estimated unreserved $1.2 million, or 1.8%. The projected unreserved balance for budgeted 1997 is $1.5 million, or 2.3%. Richmond participates in the broad Oakland metropolitan statistical area economy. The local economic base is dominated by Chevron Corp., representing one-third of the property tax base. The city is a distribution center, with strong warehousing, trucking and shipping facilities. Per capita incomes measure 71.5% of county and 91.1% of state averages. Debt is moderate at $1,686 per capita and 2.4% of true value.</p>
<p>OUTLOOK: Stable.</p>
<p>The outlook reflects improved financial management with budgetary balance achieved absent reliance on one-time measures, and the expectation that any claims on the general fund for port-related debt service will be offset by expenditure controls in order to preserve an adequate financial position, Standard &amp; Poor's said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
