<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6444" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gray leaf spot not seen hurting U.S. corn yields.</title>
<headline>Gray leaf spot not seen hurting U.S. corn yields.</headline>
<byline>Alby Gallun</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gray leaf spot, a fungal disease that damages corn leaves, has spread across the U.S. Corn Belt but isn't expected to have much of an impact on yields this fall, crop experts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's all over, but I don't think it's that severe in most locations,&quot; said Donald White, professor of plant pathology at the University of Illinois. &quot;Last year, it looked like we had more disease at this time.&quot;</p>
<p>Gray leaf spot, or GLS, needs high humidity, moderate temperatures and frequent rains to flourish.  </p>
<p>The disease &quot;got off to a real heavy start&quot; early this summer when rains doused much of the eastern Corn Belt, but recent cool, dry conditions have limited its spread, White said.</p>
<p>Gary Munkvold, extention plant pathologist at Iowa State University, doubted GLS would cause much yield loss in Iowa.</p>
<p>&quot;Frost is probabaly a much bigger threat to yield than gray leaf spot,&quot; he said. &quot;I don't think gray leaf spot is going to stack up as a big factor in comparison.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said the disease was widespread across the state but was especially prevalent in southeast Iowa.</p>
<p>But GLS doesn't pose much of a threat because only a small percentage of corn plants have GLS lesions on middle and upper leaves, which play a vital role in nourishing the plant as it reaches maturity.</p>
<p>&quot;For the most part, it's confined to the lower leaves,&quot; said David Wysong, University of Nebraska extension plant pathologist. &quot;It's not going to have an impact on yields so long as it's confined to the lower leaves. It's the mid and upper leaves that actually fill the grain.&quot;</p>
<p>Wysong said GLS infestation was most heavy in the eastern third and south-central part of Nebraska but had been found &quot;in just about every county that produces corn.&quot;</p>
<p>The disease has also been reported in Indiana and Ohio.</p>
<p>Pathologists linked the rising incidence of GLS to conservation tillage because the fungus thrives on crop debris. Farmers can limit the disease by using convential tillage, planting GLS-tolerant corn hybrids or spraying crops with a fungicide.</p>
<p>312 983 7294</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
