<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6448" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Navy probes wires cut on nuclear submarine.</title>
<headline>U.S. Navy probes wires cut on nuclear submarine.</headline>
<dateline>NEW LONDON, Conn. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Navy said on Wednesday it was investigating the severing of electrical wires aboard a nuclear submarine.</p>
<p>&quot;The Navy is looking into the possible deliberate, wrongful destruction of government property aboard the fast attack submarine U.S.S. San Juan,&quot; Lt. John Wallach, a public information officer at the New London Naval Base, said.</p>
<p>He said several wires in a supply cabinet aboard the 360-foot (120-metre) submarine were found to have been cut during a routine inspection on June 12. &quot;There was never any danger to the nuclear reactor, never any danger to the safety of the crew. Repairs were effected pretty quickly and she got back to business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Federal agents from the Navy Criminal Investigation Service were conducting the probe, begun when a watch commander spotted a non-functioning indicator light. Upon examination, it was discovered that several wires in the supply cabinet behind the panel had been cut, Wallach said.</p>
<p>He played down a suggestion that it was sabotage. &quot;First, that assumes falsely that a human being did this and number two, a sinister motive. The investigation is still going on.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S.S. San Juan and its crew of 130 is based at New London but is currently at sea, Wallach said, adding: &quot;She has been out to sea several times since the incident.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW LONDON, Conn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
