<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6450" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT - Nasdaq Composite still languishing.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Nasdaq Composite still languishing.</headline>
<byline>Betty Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The tech-laden Nasdaq Composite is still languishing after its July rout, diverging from the rebound in NYSE listed stocks that have catapulted the Dow industrials to within arm's reach of record territory.</p>
<p>&quot;There is still a big divergence between what has happened on the NYSE and Nasdaq. Nasdaq, mainly because of technology, has really languished. The advance/decline is pretty horrible compared with the NYSE,&quot; said Frank Gretz, a technical analyst at Shields &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Analysts said the divergence weighed on the overall market.  </p>
<p>Ricky Harrington, a technical analyst at Interstate/Johnson Lane, said the divergence &quot;was a good enough reason to see the market correct.&quot;</p>
<p>The Dow was off 38 points to 5684 in quiet Wednesday early afternoon trading. The Nasdaq Composite lost two to 1122.</p>
<p>On July 5, Wall Street was sent into a tailspin after a shockingly strong June payrolls report. Further stock selling was fueled by dismal earnings and warnings from such notable companies as Motorola and Hewlett-Packard. In total, the Dow slumped 10 percent or some 500 points before regaining its footing but Nasdaq endured a 20 percent bear market.  </p>
<p>Since July 5, the Dow has risen nearly two percent and is nearing its May 22 record closing high of 5778.00. But the Nasdaq Composite is still off about three percent despite its recent rebound.</p>
<p>&quot;Secondary and technology stocks are still not doing well. Nasdaq has languished for three weeks and has had a rally in a bear market so far,&quot; Gretz said.</p>
<p>Market analysts said the Dow's recovery has been aided by a flight to quality with investors mindful of the July blowup of more speculative issues. But they noted that not all technology issues have received an equal drubbing.  </p>
<p>Like other blue chips, premier technology issues -- the last to sell off in July's correction -- have enjoyed brisk buying. Intel was off 3/8 to 79-1/8 Wednesday, not far from its 52-week high of 83-1/4, and Microsoft was off one to 122-3/8 and near its year-high 126-1/8.</p>
<p>-- Wall Street desk 212 859 1721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
