<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6466" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rodney King sentenced to 90 days in jail.</title>
<headline>Rodney King sentenced to 90 days in jail.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rodney King, the black motorist beaten by white police officers in a videotaped incident that ultimately led to the 1992 Los Angeles riots, was sentenced Wednesday to 90 days in jail for hit-and-run driving.</p>
<p>King was also placed on two years' probation for his misdemeanor conviction, which stemmed from a fight he had with his estranged wife last year.  </p>
<p>Passing sentence, Municipal Court Judge Michael Kanner called King's actions &quot;reprehensible.&quot; Prosecutors alleged during King's trial that his wife Crystal got out of their car during an argument and when she reached back in the passenger window for her purse, King drove off, dragging her and sending her tumbling to the ground.</p>
<p>A jury last month found King guilty on one count of hit-and-run driving but acquitted him of the more serious charges of spousal abuse and assault with a deadly weapon.</p>
<p>The prosecution had asked that King receive the maximum penalty of one year in jail and a $5,000 fine. But the judge sentenced him to 90 days in the Los Angeles County jail, fined him $100 and ordered him to pay his wife's medical bills.</p>
<p>King first entered the public spotlight in March 1991 when white police officers were captured on videotape beating and kicking him after a high-speed chase. The April 1992 state court acquittals of four officers touched off rioting in Los Angeles that left more than 50 people dead and caused an estimated $1 billion in damage.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
