<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6469" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Seven rescued from disabled tug in Dolly's path.</title>
<headline>Seven rescued from disabled tug in Dolly's path.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seven crew members were rescued from a 110-foot tugboat after it became disabled in the Bay of Campeche in the path of tropical depression Dolly, the U.S. Coast Guard said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The crew of the tugboat Thor, disabled by a jammed rudder, was rescued by the Liberian-flagged Lockness, which was operating in the area and volunteered to steam toward the disabled boat, the Coast Guard said.</p>
<p>&quot;The call came in Tuesday, and they picked them off the tug at 2 a.m. this morning (0700 GMT),&quot; Coast Guard Petty Officer Renee Gordon said. The crew was being taken to port in Houston in shipping lanes well out of the path of the storm.</p>
<p>Dolly, downgraded to a tropical depression on Wednesday, was churning its way across the Yucatan Penninsula about 35 miles south-southwest of Campeche, Mexico.</p>
<p>Dolly, the Atlantic hurricane season's fourth named storm, was expected to strengthen after emerging into the warm waters of the Bay of Campeche and eventually make landfall along the coast of northern Mexico or south Texas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
