<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6470" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Plains record weekly cattle sales - USDA.</title>
<headline>U.S. Plains record weekly cattle sales - USDA.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>This week's active U.S. Plains feedlot cattle sales broke week-to-date record high levels, according to the U.S. Agriculture Department.</p>
<p>Texas Panhandle/western Oklahoma feedlots by Wednesday had posted a week-to-date figure of 141,600, topping the previous record of 136,800 set for the week ended February 22nd this year, USDA said.</p>
<p>Kansas feedlot sales for the week through Wednesday were 118,800, above the 115,059 level set the week ended July 28, 1995, according to USDA.</p>
<p>Daily record highs remained intact despite Wednesday's active sales. The record high level for daily sales in the Panhandle area is 104,800 set February 22 this year, and the daily record high in Kansas at 88,000 was set last September.</p>
<p>There were 96,600 head reported sold Tuesday in the Panhandle and 70,100 in Kansas.</p>
<p>Cattle marketing weeks run from Friday through Thursday and one reason for this week's big volume was large purchases of cattle Friday last week left over from the previous week's showlists, USDA marketing sources said. About 20,000 head were sold in the Panhandle area on that day and 35,000 in Kansas.</p>
<p>Cattle sales on Fridays are typically light, sources said.</p>
<p>--Bob Janis, 312-983-7347--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
