<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6471" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Seagull Energy tests onshore Texas find.</title>
<headline>Seagull Energy tests onshore Texas find.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seagull Energy Corp said on Wednesday its tested an onshore well at 3.3 million cubic feet of gas per day and an offshore well at 8.5 million cubic feet of gas per day in Texas.</p>
<p>Seagull is the operator and holds 75 percent interest in each discovery, it said.</p>
<p>Vastar Fee No. 1 well located in Vidor, Texas, tested at 3.3 million cubic feet of gas and 77 barrels of condensate per day. The well was tested at that rate through a 12/64 inch choke with a flowing tubing pressure of 3,725 pounds per square inch, Seagull said.</p>
<p>At Brazos 377 No. A-1 located 25 miles offshore Freeport, Texas, Seagull and its partner encountered 35 feet of productive sands that tested 8.5 million cubic feet day of natural gas through a 24/64-inch choke with a flowing tubing pressure of 1,620 psi.</p>
<p>Seagull also said it has now been awarded all 10 blocks from OSC Sale 157 held in spring 1996, since it and its partners were the high bidders. Gross high bids from Seagull and its partners on the 10 blocks totaled $6.5 million with Seagull's net being $2.5 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
