<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6478" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Miss Universe hiding after weight problem reports.</title>
<headline>Miss Universe hiding after weight problem reports.</headline>
<byline>Kieran Murray</byline>
<dateline>LAS CRUCES, N.M. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alicia Machado, the reigning Miss Universe beauty queen hit by allegations she was getting chubby, was in hiding on Wednesday as officials denied ordering her to lose weight or risk losing her crown.</p>
<p>Machado, a 19-year-old Venezuelan who won the title in May, was in a New Mexico hotel room and pageant organisers said she would stay out of sight until Wednesday night, when she was to make an official appearance at the televised 1996 Miss Teen USA event.</p>
<p>Security was beefed up with police deployed to a hotel in the resort town of Las Cruces where the pageant was being held. No one was allowed onto the fifth floor where the teenage contestants and, presumably, Machado had their rooms.</p>
<p>Although she was nowhere to be seen, Machado and her waistline were the talk of the town.</p>
<p>&quot;It's her body, her deal. She won the crown and they shouldn't take it away from her just for putting on a few pounds,&quot; said Autumn Smith, the reigning Miss Alabama USA. &quot;But, at the same time, if I'd won Miss Universe, I'd want to look the best I possibly could for that one year,&quot; the tall, 21-year-old brunette added.</p>
<p>The pageant world was jolted on Monday when officials of the Miss Venezuela Organisation said Machado had been given an ultimatum by Miss Universe organisers to shed 27 pounds (12 kg) in two weeks or risk having her title taken away.</p>
<p>At 5 feet 7 inches (1.73 metres), she weighed 112 pounds (51 kg) in May when she became the fourth Venezuelan to win the world's top beauty title. Immediately after winning, she told reporters she planned to do &quot;something I haven't been able to do in three weeks: eat, eat, eat and sleep.&quot;</p>
<p>People close to her said she succumbed to a passion for pasta and cake.</p>
<p>News of the alleged ultimatum sent reporters from around the United States and Latin America scrambling to get to Las Cruces and track down Machado. It also brought criticism of Miss Universe organisers, who have traditionally denied claims that pageants are glorified meat markets by stressing the importance of personality and &quot;inner beauty.&quot;</p>
<p>They responded by saying no threats were ever made against Machado and that they were &quot;distressed&quot; by the reports.</p>
<p>&quot;A weight requirement is not part of our titleholder employment contract,&quot; said Martin Brooks, president of Los Angeles-based Miss Universe Inc. He said the organisation was &quot;extremely happy with Alicia and feel she fulfils her obligations as Miss Universe 1996 exceptionally well.&quot;</p>
<p>Venezuelan pageant organisers also backed away from their earlier comments. &quot;She obviously has a weight problem which affects her swimsuit contracts but this does not mean she will be stripped of her crown,&quot; one official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Teen pageant officials reassured the 51 contestants that reports of an ultimatum to Machado were false and that personality and friendly disposition were as valued as ever.</p>
<p>&quot;They told us it was all totally not true,&quot; said Jodi Webb, 18, the reigning Miss Teen Utah.</p>
<p>David Regalado, a New Mexico policeman on guard duty at the hotel, said he had not seen Machado in person but did see her on television and was impressed. &quot;She sure is beautiful. They say she got fat but she looks just fine to me,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>News of Machado's weight gain made front-page news in her home country. Venezuela takes its reputation as the world's beauty queen capital very seriously.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS CRUCES, N.M."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
