<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6487" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. power output drops 9.9 pct vs. year-ago - EEI.</title>
<headline>U.S. power output drops 9.9 pct vs. year-ago - EEI.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The electricity deliveries in the continental U.S. totaled 71,452 gigawatt hours (GWh) for the week ended Aug 17, down 9.9 percent from the same period in 1995, the Edison Electric Institute (EEI) said Wednesday.</p>
<p>The amount of power supplied last week to the eastern half of the U.S. was sharply lower from levels a year ago due to unseasonally cool temperatures.</p>
<p>EEI said the Central Industrial section, which includes Ohio, Michigan, Illinois, Indiana, parts of Missouri, Wisconsin, Pennsylvania and West Virginia, showed the largest decline last week, down 19 percent at 13,829 GWh.</p>
<p>Electricity deliveries west of the Rockies were higher from the comparable 1995 period, with the Pacific Southwest showing the greatest increase, up 17.3 percent at 6,428 GWh, according to the EEI.</p>
<p>Dry, scorching heat blanketed most of the West last week.</p>
<p>Electric output in the 48 contiguous states for the latest week was down 5.2 percent from the previous reported week.</p>
<p>Year-to-date, domestic power production stood at 2.11 million GWh, up 2.4 percent from the comparable period in 1995, EEI said.</p>
<p>--New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
