<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6493" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US science group puts supercomputer order on hold.</title>
<headline>US science group puts supercomputer order on hold.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Science Foundation (NSF) said it was withholding approval to buy four Japanese-made supercomputers until dumping allegations are resolved.</p>
<p>U.S. supercomputer maker Cray Research filed a petition July 29 with the Commerce Department alleging Japan's NEC Corp was selling supercomputers on the U.S. market at less than fair prices.</p>
<p>&quot;In my view, it would be inappropriate for NSF to approve this procurement until the dumping issue has been resolved,&quot; NSF director Neal Lane said in a statement dated Aug 20 but received here Wednesday.  </p>
<p>The National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR) tentatively agreed on May 20 to buy four NEC supercomputer systems. The government-funded NSF is the primary funding agency.</p>
<p>Lane said he was acutely aware that the NCAR needed state-of-the-art equipment to maintain world leadership in climate modeling research. &quot;I feel, however that acting now on this procurement would be inconsistent with the responsible stewardship of taxpayer monies,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Both the Commerce Department and the U.S. International Trade Commission have said they will investigate the dumping charges which NEC has strenuously denied.</p>
<p>The ITC will make a preliminary determination by September 12 on whether or not U.S. industry is being injured.</p>
<p>If the ITC's preliminary decision is affirmative, the Commerce Department has said it will continue its investigation and issue it own preliminary finding no later than January 6, 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
