<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6497" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgium braced for funeral of child sex victims.</title>
<headline>Belgium braced for funeral of child sex victims.</headline>
<byline>Lorrayne Smith</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A grieving nation prepared on Wednesday to bury two eight-year-old victims of a paedophile gang as Belgian police, under attack for past bungling, continued their search for other missing girls.</p>
<p>Belgium has been in a state of shock since the weekend when convicted child sex offender Marc Dutroux, 39, led police to the bodies of Melissa Russo and Julie Lejeune in the garden of a house he owned near Charleroi, southern Belgium.</p>
<p>The girls, abducted in June 1995, starved to death early this year. They will be buried on Thursday after a televised public memorial service in their eastern Belgian home town of Liege at which police expect up to 100,000 people.</p>
<p>Dutroux, who served time between 1989 and 1992, also told police of two other abducted girls -- Laetitia Delhez, 14, and Sabine Dardenne, 12. They were found alive in a makeshift dungeon in another of his houses. Both had been sexually abused.</p>
<p>Dutroux's wife has been implicated in the case.</p>
<p>The whereabouts of An Marchal and Eefje Lambrecks -- abducted by Dutroux a year ago -- remains a mystery.</p>
<p>Parents and the public prosecutor in charge of the case are optimistic they will be found alive.</p>
<p>Media here have likened the outpouring of grief over Russo and Lejeune's fate to the unprecedented display of mourning that followed the death of much-loved King Baudouin three years ago.</p>
<p>Mountains of flowers covered the lawns at the girls' homes.</p>
<p>Hundreds of weeping mourners have been filing past white coffins with the bodies of the two friends from morning till night for the past three days.</p>
<p>The government called for one minute's silence at 11 a.m (0900 GMT) on Thursday, the start of the memorial service.</p>
<p>Of the 100,000 people expected to attend the service in Liege's Saint Martin basilica, about one thousand will be accommodated inside the church. The others will be able to follow the mass on a large outside video screen.</p>
<p>Police meanwhile continued their investigation into Belgium's worst child-sex scandal, focussing on finding Marchal and Lambrecks. Thirty detectives were added to the team which has widened its searches to other countries, including Britain.</p>
<p>In Johannesburg South African police said on Wednesday there could be a link between the Belgian child sex scandal and the disappearance of five girls in Pretoria up to eight years ago.</p>
<p>British Detective Superintendent John Bennett, who led the investigation into the &quot;House of Horrors&quot; murders in Gloucester, western England, arrived on Wednesday to offer advice.</p>
<p>The hidden bodies of Fred and Rosemary West's victims were recovered with the aid of hi-tech heat-seeking and radar equipment, which Belgium has asked to Britain to supply.</p>
<p>Belgian police said more bodies could be found. &quot;We always expect it is possible to find more bodies. There are still people missing,&quot; Major Jean-Marie Boudin of the gendarmerie's missing children squad said.</p>
<p>In Belgium and the Netherlands police have re-opened cases of missing girls in the wake of the scandal. In Belgium at least 15 children vanished in the past six years. Seven have now been found dead. Six are missing. Only two have been rescued.</p>
<p>Belgian media have accused the police of incompetence in the 14-month search for Julie and Melissa, citing leaked police papers with tipoffs on Dutroux.</p>
<p>Belgian radio said police in Liege had authenticated the documents but denied they ever reached the investigators searching for the two.</p>
<p>Justice Minister De Clerck has promised that a judge from Liege will look into the matter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
