<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6499" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: African hunger strikers reject Paris concession.</title>
<headline>African hunger strikers reject Paris concession.</headline>
<byline>Alister Doyle</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>African immigrants fighting expulsion vowed on Wednesday to continue their 48-day-old hunger strike despite a government promise to have their cases reviewed by France's highest administrative court.</p>
<p>Representatives of the protesters said Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre told them during a one-hour meeting that he could not accept their demand that all 300 protesters, 10 of whom are fasting, be allowed to stay in France.</p>
<p>&quot;The hunger strike goes on. At this time, we don't consider there is a concession,&quot; a spokeswoman named as Madiguene said.</p>
<p>In a conciliatory move, Prime Minister Alain Juppe earlier called ministers to an emergency meeting and asked the Council of State to review the enforcement of controversial immigration laws.</p>
<p>&quot;The enforcement of these laws naturally takes account of individual cases in a humane way to which the government has always given importance,&quot; a statement from his office said.</p>
<p>But it ruled out redrafting the 1993 laws and insisted: &quot;Clandestine immigration must be combated with the greatest firmness because it is a violation of the law.&quot;</p>
<p>A few thousand people marched through Paris to the church on Wednesday evening in a demonstration of support for the protesters called by left-wing parties, trade unions and human rights groups.</p>
<p>Debre received a delegation of the protesters and told them the government would favourably review the most tragic cases and he hoped the hunger strike would end.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it can go on if these people are sensible and have humanitarian motives. If their motives were political, it would be another thing,&quot; he told Radio France Info.</p>
<p>The hunger strike has put the conservative government in a quandary. The protesters, who are mostly from Mali and include 110 children, are holed up in the Saint-Bernard church in the heavily immigrant Goutte d'Or district with a human shield of hundreds of sympathisers preventing police from seizing them.</p>
<p>The first opinion poll on the dispute, to be published on Thursday in the daily Le Parisien, said most French voters sympathised with the protesters but that most opposed giving them all an automatic right to stay.</p>
<p>The far-right, anti-immigration National Front has demanded that they be expelled.</p>
<p>The protesters say many of them who had enjoyed residence rights were plunged into illegality by the &quot;Pasqua laws&quot; pushed through by hardline former interior minister Charles Pasqua.</p>
<p>Officials admit a legal kink means some immigrants can be neither expelled nor granted residence permits.</p>
<p>Aides said Juppe, who cut short his summer holidays to tackle the embarrassing dispute, had consulted the speakers of both houses of parliament, leaders of the two parties in the ruling centre-right coalition, and Xavier Emmanuelli, junior minister for emergency humanitarian action.</p>
<p>Bruno Gollnisch, a leader of the National Front, was turned away from the interior ministry as Debre was having his first encounter with representatives of the protesters.</p>
<p>&quot;I wanted to express the French people's exasperation. The law must be enforced, &quot; Gollnisch told reporters. &quot;I note that the minister gives priority to people who are delinquents.&quot;</p>
<p>One of the 10 hunger strikers was taken to hospital with stomach pains on Tuesday night but his life was said to be in no danger.</p>
<p>Doctors monitoring the health of the hunger strikers at the church, where they have been drinking sugared tea and eating vitamins, said two others were in serious condition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
