<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6500" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Historic Dresden church rising from WW2 ashes.</title>
<headline>Historic Dresden church rising from WW2 ashes.</headline>
<byline>Lars Rischke</byline>
<dateline>DRESDEN, Germany 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dresden's Baroque Frauenkirche (Church of Our Lady) hosted its first service since it was destroyed in a 1945 bombing raid with the inauguration of its restored crypt on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Once the centrepiece of the Baroque centre that earned Dresden the name &quot;Florence on the Elbe&quot;, the Frauenkirche was bombed on February 13, 1945, in a British and U.S. air assault that killed some 35,000 civilians. The church tower stood, a smoking shell, for days after the raid before collapsing.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a moving moment,&quot; said the Bishop of Saxony, Volker Kress, who led the service attended by about 300 clerics, regional and city officials.</p>
<p>&quot;From now on, services will take place here to call out to God from the depths.&quot;</p>
<p>Kress said the ceremony was the high point so far in efforts to rebuild the church.</p>
<p>&quot;The number of donors is breathtaking. The church has found a global community,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kress has said he hoped the vaulted crypt, reconstructed from photographs, would inspire more donations. Restoration could cost a total of 250 million marks ($165 million) and take another 10 to 15 years.</p>
<p>But only 25 million marks have been raised so far, he said in a recent interview.</p>
<p>Guests at the ceremony included the premier of the regional state of Saxony, Kurt Biedenkopf, and other dignitaries who have supported the project, which got under way in 1993.</p>
<p>Britain's &quot;Dresden Trust&quot; and a U.S.-based foundation are also helping raise money for the project.</p>
<p>The inauguration marked the end of 50 years of debate over whether Dresden's famous Italianate church, which was completed in 1743, should be allowed to rise out of the ashes or be left as a permanent reminder of the futility of war.</p>
<p>&quot;For Dresdeners the Frauenkirche will remain a symbol for peace and reconciliation,&quot; said Matthias Oelke, a spokesman for the church. &quot;Once again the Frauenkirche will be the spiritual centre of Dresden,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DRESDEN, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
