<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6502" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Paris plays conciliatory card on hunger strike.</title>
<headline>Paris plays conciliatory card on hunger strike.</headline>
<byline>Alister Doyle</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Prime Minister Alain Juppe played a conciliatory card on Wednesday to try to end a 48-day-old hunger strike by African immigrants fighting an expulsion order, delaying its enforcement by seeking a court review.</p>
<p>Officials said after Juppe chaired an emergency ministerial meeting that the centre-right government had asked the highest administrative court to review &quot;as fast as possible&quot; the enforcement of controversial immigration laws.</p>
<p>&quot;The Interior Minister (Jean-Louis Debre) has appealed to the Council of State to demand an opinion so as to have all the information at his disposal,&quot; a Juppe statement said. It was a concession to 300 protesters holed up in a Paris church supporting nine hunger strikers there and another in hospital.</p>
<p>&quot;The enforcement of these laws naturally takes account of individual cases in a humane way to which the government has always given importance,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>But it ruled out redrafting the 1993 laws and insisted: &quot;Clandestine immigration must be combated with the greatest firmness because it is a violation of the law.&quot;</p>
<p>In another sign of a new conciliatory stance, Debre received three representatives of the protesters in their first meeting since the hunger strike began.</p>
<p>The nine Africans fasting at the Saint-Bernard church had earlier pledged to continue their hunger strike after a 10th protester was taken to hospital with stomach pains.</p>
<p>An official said that the court review would also focus on a legal kink which means some immigrants can be neither expelled nor granted residence permits.</p>
<p>Aides said Juppe, who cut short his summer holidays on Tuesday, had consulted the speakers of both houses of parliament, leaders of the two parties in the ruling centre-right coalition, and Xavier Emmanuelli, junior minister for emergency humanitarian action.</p>
<p>Bruno Gollnisch, a senior member of the far-right and anti-immigrant National Front, turned up unannounced at the interior ministry demanding to see Debre but was turned away.</p>
<p>&quot;I wanted to express the French people's exasperation. The law must be enforced, &quot; Gollnisch told reporters. &quot;I note that the minister gives priority to people who are delinquents.&quot;</p>
<p>At the church, a spokesman for the protesters said 29-year-old Moussa Keita, taken to hospital on Tuesday, was in no danger.</p>
<p>&quot;He is tired but his condition is not worrying. He has not been put on a drip,&quot; Keita told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that one of the hunger strikers was taken to hospital shows that this is a real hunger strike and that they are determined to continue until the end.&quot;</p>
<p>Doctors monitoring the health of the hunger strikers at the church, where they have been drinking sugared tea and eating vitamins, said two others were in serious condition.</p>
<p>Around the church in the heavily immigrant Goutte d'Or district, protesters including 110 children are surrounded by hundreds of sympathisers ready to attempt to prevent police seizing them by chaining themselves together.</p>
<p>In eastern Paris, demonstrators who heeded a call from left-wing parties, human rights associations and trade unions gathered for a march through the capital to the church to show support for the immigrants.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFRICA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
