<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6503" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Grief-stricken Belgium to mourn child sex victims.</title>
<headline>Grief-stricken Belgium to mourn child sex victims.</headline>
<byline>Bert Lauwers</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tens of thousands of grief-stricken Belgians will attend the funeral on Thursday of two eight-year-old children starved to death by a paedophile gang which abducted at least four other girls.</p>
<p>The outpouring of grief since the bodies of Melissa Russo and Julie Lejeune were unearthed last weekend revived memories of the display of mourning that followed the death of Belgium's much-loved King Baudouin three years ago.</p>
<p>The government has called for one minute's silence at 11 a.m (0900 GMT) on Thursday, the start of the memorial service which will also be broadcast on television.</p>
<p>Of the 100,000 people expected to attend the service in Liege's Saint Martin basilica, only about 1,000 can be accommodated inside the church. The others will be able to follow the mass on a large outside video screen.</p>
<p>Thousands of weeping mourners have filed past the white coffins with the bodies of the two close friends over the past three days.</p>
<p>Mountains of flowers covered the lawns at the girls' homes. Most of the bouquets were laid by mothers with young children, some of whom left behind their favourite toy.</p>
<p>Black ribbons or banners were put on cars and some bars displayed a picture of the dead girls next to a lit candle.</p>
<p>In Liege, a number of factories and shops were due to close temporarily on Thursday to allow workers to attend the funeral.</p>
<p>Belgium has been in a state of shock since the weekend when convicted child sex offender Marc Dutroux, 39, led police to the girls' bodies in the garden of a house he owned near Charleroi, southern Belgium.</p>
<p>The girls, abducted in June 1995, starved to death early this year.</p>
<p>Dutroux, who served time between 1989 and 1992, also told police of two other abducted girls -- Laetitia Delhez, 14, and Sabine Dardenne, 12.</p>
<p>They were found alive in a makeshift dungeon in another of his houses. Both had been sexually abused.</p>
<p>The whereabouts of An Marchal and Eefje Lambrecks -- kidnapped by Dutroux and his accomplices a year ago -- remains a mystery.</p>
<p>Parents and the public prosecutor in charge of the case are hopeful they can be found alive.</p>
<p>Three other people, including Dutroux' second wife, have been charged in the case, Belgium's worst-ever child-sex scandal.</p>
<p>Police continued their investigation into the scandal, focussing on finding Marchal and Lambrecks. Thirty detectives have been added to the team which has widened its searches to other countries, including Britain.</p>
<p>British Detective Superintendent John Bennett, who led the investigation into the &quot;House of Horrors&quot; murders in Gloucester, western England, arrived on Wednesday to offer advice.</p>
<p>Public prosecutor Michel Bourlet said after a meeting with Bennett and investigators he would hold a news conference on Thursday but added there was no news on the case.</p>
<p>At least 15 children have vanished in Belgium in the past six years. Seven have now been found dead. Six are missing. Only two have been rescued. Police said more bodies could be found.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
