<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6504" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Africans keep up Paris fast for residence permits.</title>
<headline>Africans keep up Paris fast for residence permits.</headline>
<byline>Francois Raitberger</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ten African immigrants fighting expulsion went into the 48th day of a hunger strike in a Paris church on Thursday, buoyed by government concessions and bent on winning more.</p>
<p>In a marked softening, Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre said he would put to France's highest administrative court the problem of the 300 immigrants holed up with the hunger strikers.</p>
<p>But the hunger strikers, boosted by a support march towards the Saint-Bernard church which attracted 5,000 demonstrators, reaffirmed their determination to fast until winning residence permits for all of the 300.</p>
<p>&quot;The hunger strike goes on...We reject bids to divide us, we are united,&quot; their spokeswoman Madiguene Cisse told reporters.</p>
<p>There was a distinct feeling among the protesters that victory was at hand after Prime Minister Alain Juppe cut short his holiday for an emergency ministerial meeting and Debre received their representatives for the first time.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a turning point,&quot; one of them said.</p>
<p>Debre went on radio and television to explain that the government would review distressing cases favourably.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is holding out its hand...I believe reason will prevail. I believe all this is going to end,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he said there was no legal way of allowing all the protesters to stay in France, including those whose requests for political asylum had been turned down.</p>
<p>The protesters say they are all entitled to stay. They say many of them enjoyed residence rights until they were plunged into ilegallity by 1993 laws tightening residence and citizenship regulations to drastically curb immigration.</p>
<p>Debre ruled out redrafting the laws and insisted: &quot;Clandestine immigration must be combated with the greatest firmness because it is a violation of the law.&quot;</p>
<p>The hunger strike has divided the ruling centre-right coalition between those who favour strictly enforcing he law and those who call for concessions.</p>
<p>The government risks a public relations disaster if one of the hunger strikers dies, or if it tries to evict the protesters.</p>
<p>One of the hunger strikers returned to the church after being treated in hospital. Doctors say two others were in serious condition.</p>
<p>The church, in the heavily immigrant Goutte d'Or district, Juppe's former constituency, is surrounded by hundreds of sympathisers, including media celebrities, determined to prevent a police bid to seize the protesters.</p>
<p>The first opinion poll on the dispute, published on Thursday in the daily Le Parisien, said most French voters sympathised with the protesters but most opposed giving them all an automatic right to stay.</p>
<p>The opposition Socialists welcomed the government's call to the Council of State but said it was insufficient and tantamount to an admission that the &quot;Pasqua laws&quot; had led to an intolerable legal imbroglio.</p>
<p>The laws were pushed by former interior minister Charles Pasqua in the wake of the Socialists' 1993 election rout. Officials admit a legal kink means some immigrants can be neither expelled nor granted residence permits.</p>
<p>Former Socialist culture minister Jack Lang said the Council of State could not consider every individual case. He asked Juppe to declare a moratorium on expulsions and appoint an independent mediator to look into each of the protesters' legal status.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
