<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6506" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Corsican separatists say truce over.</title>
<headline>Corsican separatists say truce over.</headline>
<dateline>AJACCIO, Corsica 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Corsican separatists said on Wednesday they were ending a shaky seven-month truce, accusing the Paris government of reneging on secret commitments.</p>
<p>The truce had already been broken by 10 bombings over the past week on the French Mediterranean holiday island.</p>
<p>&quot;The end of a peace process&quot;, was the headline of an article in Ribombou, the newspaper of the nationalist movement Cuncolta Naziunalista which is regarded as the political arm of outlawed Corsican National Liberation Front (FLNC) separatist guerrillas.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has betrayed all its commitments, made in negotiations with the FLNC,&quot; Cuncolta leader Francois Santoni wrote.</p>
<p>It has been widely reported that the government held secret talk with the FLNC since the ceasefire began but the government has never confirmed it and the outcome has not been disclosed.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe, visiting the island last month after judges on the island complained the state was too lax on guerrilla violence, announced a policy of economic aid twinned with toughness to restore law and order.</p>
<p>Santoni accused Juppe of despising Corsicans and dismissed the promised economic aid as charity.</p>
<p>&quot;Threats against outlawed groups have no effect on the determination to continue a fight which began more than 20 years ago,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A crackdown on the guerrillas would fail and &quot;could even hasten (Juppe's) political demise,&quot; Santoni said.</p>
<p>Ten bombs have exploded on the island in the past week, mostly targetting public buildings in an apparent resumption of two-decade-old separatist violence.</p>
<p>The Justice Ministry said last week it was &quot;determined to seek out and and punish the perpetrators of terrorist acts&quot;.</p>
<p>In a new escalation, suspected separatists planted a bomb on Monday on the Ajaccio doorstep of former French industry minister Jose Rossi, who heads Corsica's elected council.</p>
<p>Police defused the bomb, but Rossi warned that Corsica was headed for new violence which could spread to the French mainland.</p>
<p>He said the flare-up may stem from confusion after secret talks and urged both the government and the separatists to clearly say what they wanted.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AJACCIO, Corsica"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
