<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6512" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Hedge fund reduces Montedison stake -source.</title>
<headline>Hedge fund reduces Montedison stake -source.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Codelouf &amp; Co hedge fund headed by Luca Padulli has reduced its stake in Italian agri-chemical group Montedison to 0.12 percent, a source close to Montedison said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>An announcement on the change is due to be published in newspapers on Thursday, the source said. At Montedison's June annual general meeting, Codelouf held a stake of just under four percent.</p>
<p>Padulli was reported in May to be dismayed at Montedison's low share price and to have called in a letter to its chairman for the company to break up.  </p>
<p>Montedison managing director Enrico Bondi in June brushed aside calls for a break-up and Padulli said he had no accord with other stockholders to force the company's hand.</p>
<p>Montedison stocks closed 0.08 percent up at 999.4 lire on Wednesday, slightly below the blue-chip Mib30 index. Earlier, a block of 60 million Montedison shares, equal to a stake of 1.52 percent, changed hands at 998 lire a share.</p>
<p>Financial sources said the block had been sold by U.S. investment house Merrill Lynch, although no official confirmation from Merrill's was available.</p>
<p>The bank bought a 3.8 percent stake in Montedison in January 1996, which was then reduced to 2.17 percent.</p>
<p>Italian industrial holding Compart, formerly Ferruzzi Finanziaria SpA, has 33 percent of Montedison's ordinary capital.</p>
<p>-- Milan bureau +392 66129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
