<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6514" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: 45 Africans ejected by Spain start hunger strike.</title>
<headline>45 Africans ejected by Spain start hunger strike.</headline>
<byline>David Brough</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forty five African immigrants deported to Guinea-Bissau have begun a hunger strike to press for their return to Spain, a human rights official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Their deportation from Spain was illegal. They want to go back to Spain,&quot; Leopoldo Amado, a spokesman for the Guinea-Bissau League for Human Rights, said in a telephone interview from the West African state.</p>
<p>He said the ejection of the Africans by Spain in June was illegal because some of them had filled in papers at a centre for immigrants in the Spanish enclave of Melilla in north Africa requesting travel to Spain before they were deported.</p>
<p>One hunger striker, a Nigerian called Azeez Mohammed, told Reuters authorities in Melilla had handcuffed the group and later put them on military planes where they were served with drinking water containing sedatives.</p>
<p>Spain's decision to sedate the Africans expelled from Melilla was criticised this month by U.N. High Commissioner for Human Rights Jose Ayala Lasso.</p>
<p>Azeez said the planes had flown to Senegal and Cameroon where authorities had turned them away before Guinea Bissau, a former Portuguese colony, accepted them on June 22.</p>
<p>Amado said Spanish authorities had bribed the Guinea Bissau government to take them.</p>
<p>The Africans were presently housed in a cramped police prison in the capital Bissau, sleeping on the floor and served just two meals a day, Azeez said.</p>
<p>The hunger strikers could leave the prison by bribing the guards, he added, speaking from the human rights office.</p>
<p>&quot;The hunger strikers want to be transferred to a hotel in Bissau from the prison. They are not criminals,&quot; Amado said.</p>
<p>He added that the hunger strikers were demanding medical treatment during their stay in Bissau.</p>
<p>Guinea Bissau officials have said they planned to send the immigrants back to their countries of origin -- Nigeria, Liberia, Cameroon, Togo, Central African Republic and Rwanda.</p>
<p>The Africans had ended an earlier hunger strike lasting four days this month after Guinea-Bissau Interior Minister Amaro Correia assured them he would mediate a solution with Spain.</p>
<p>But when Bissau officials later changed their position and said they would repatriate the men, the Africans decided on Tuesday to start an indefinite hunger strike.</p>
<p>&quot;They are taking nothing -- no water or salt,&quot; Amado said.</p>
<p>Guinea-Bissau authorities had already repatriated five of the original group of 50 to neighbouring Guinea, he said.</p>
<p>The group are among hundreds of Africans who try to cross the narrow Strait of Gibraltar into Spain from north Africa every year in search of a better life in Europe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUBI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
