<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6519" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bonn commission to look into Libya weapons deal.</title>
<headline>Bonn commission to look into Libya weapons deal.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Bonn parliamentary commission will examine the failure of Germany's BND intelligence service to prevent the export of chemical weapons-making technology to Libya, the commission chairman said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Authorities this week revealed that 3.2 million marks' ($2.15 million) worth of state-of-the-art equipment to mix poison gases was sent to Libya from Germany between 1990 and 1993 in defiance of German arms control laws.</p>
<p>The BND conceded on Tuesday that it interviewed one of the suspects at length four years ago without discovering the deals. It denied reports that the man, Lebanese-born businessman Berge Balanian, had worked as a BND informer.</p>
<p>Parliamentary control commission chairman Wilfried Penner of the opposition Social Democrats (SPD) told German Radio the commission would &quot;examine this matter intensively, probably next week&quot;.</p>
<p>He said there was no evidence the government had acted wrongly in the matter. But Manfred Such, the opposition Greens member of the control commission, said the BND's version of events was implausible.</p>
<p>&quot;The BND's account that it had for years been speaking to Balanian about Libya in general but failed to find out about the poison gas deal...is hard to imagine.</p>
<p>&quot;And if the BND really had no idea about a deal of this importance, this would again call into question the quality of its insight and the value of the BND,&quot; Such said in a statement.</p>
<p>The BND has recently had to battle allegations of incompetence on several fronts.</p>
<p>In particular, it was accused of luring smugglers into bringing highly radioactive plutonium to Germany from Russia in 1994, and was forced to investigate its own staff for pocketing money intended to buy the services of Russian officers.</p>
<p>The Libyan affair is also embarrassing for the government, which clamped down on the arms trade after German firms in the 1980s equipped a plant at Rabta in Libya suspected of making chemical weapons.</p>
<p>Prosecutors believe Balanian also tried to supply equipment for Rabta, which burned down in 1990.</p>
<p>SPD arms control expert Herbert Bachmaier said it was possible his party would try to call a special parliamentary inquiry into the Libyan affair, similar to one currently examining the plutonium smuggling incident.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LIBYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
