<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6520" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: FORECAST-Engil seen reporting profit flat.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Engil seen reporting profit flat.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Construction company Engil-SGPS is expected to report a consolidated net profit of 600 to 650 million escudos ($4.0-4.3 million) in the first half, flat on last year but below initial forecasts, analysts said.</p>
<p>But they said that the company, which is expected to announce six month figures within a few days, was still on target to reach a full-year profit of 1.5 billion escudos, compared with 1.18 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;I am looking for close to 650 (million escudos), below the 750 million that were being forecast at the start of the year,&quot; said Pedro Andrada of brokers Fincor.</p>
<p>First half profit in 1995 was 586 billion escudos.</p>
<p>But Andrada said the company could still reach the 1.5 billion profit target for the whole year.</p>
<p>&quot;The 1.5 billion seems reasonable...because the second half is usually better,&quot; added Joao Pereira of Gesfinc. &quot;We have been recommending it as a buy for some time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The construction sector got off to a slow start in 1996 because of heavy winter rains and the fact that the 1996 budget only came into effect in April because of the change of government at the end of the previous year.</p>
<p>Most analysts expect that the construction sector will outperform the overall economy in 1996 and from the stock market perspective Engil had the advantage of being one of the most liquid construction stocks.</p>
<p>It is quoted on Wall Street as American Depositary Receipts (ADR).</p>
<p>($1=152.4 escudos)</p>
<p>---Sergio Goncalves, Lisbon bureau 3511-3150035</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
