<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6523" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALTA: Maltese shares rise in higher turnover.</title>
<headline>Maltese shares rise in higher turnover.</headline>
<dateline>VALLETTA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Malta Stock Exchange share index was up by 7.897 points on Wednesday as business picked up in the once weekly trading session.</p>
<p>Turnover reached just over Lm 333,100 ($926,018), almost double last week's total. There were 80 deals, of which 51 were in equities and 29 in fixed income securities.</p>
<p>Business in equities amounted to just over Lm90,100 ($250,470) from the previous week's Lm 40,500 ($113,400) with 68,062 shares being traded. Of these, 29,322 were Bank of Valletta shares which were sold in 27 deals for an average of 125.9 cents, up four mils.</p>
<p>There were 12 deals in Mid-med Bank, with 25,000 shares selling for an average price of 145.1 cents, up from 143 cents last week.</p>
<p>Middle Sea Insurance, shares remained unchanged for the second week, with 7,740 shares changing hands in three deals for an average 121 cents each.</p>
<p>Lombard Bank Malta also traded, with 7,740 shares selling an average 139.4 cents, up from 137.2 when last traded on August 7.</p>
<p>In Simons Farsons Cisk, 1,000 ordinary shares changed hands for 62 cents per share, unchanged.</p>
<p>In the government bond market, 10 issues were dealt in, turnover reaching Lm241,591, up steeply from last week's Lm125,700. Business was mainly in the 6.5 percent MGS 2001 (II).</p>
<p>In corporate bonds, there was one deal in Mid-Med Bank 7.25 percent unsecured loan stock 2005 amounting to Lm1,387.40 at 99.1 cents. (Lm1=$2.78)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALTA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VALLETTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALTA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
