<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6525" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy CPI must hold below 3.5 pct for rate cut - ABI.</title>
<headline>Italy CPI must hold below 3.5 pct for rate cut - ABI.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian inflation must consolidate below the 3.5 percent level before the Bank of Italy will cut its official discount rate again, the head of the Italian Banking Association (ABI) told Reuters.</p>
<p>Italian consumer prices are estimated to be rising at 3.3/3.4 percent year on year in August, according to analysts' estimates based on preliminary data released earlier on Wednesday. Inflation in July stood at 3.6 percent.</p>
<p>ABI chairman Tancredi Bianchi said he expected inflation to fall again in September.</p>
<p>&quot;For a further fall in the discount rate, we will need at least one more month's confirmation (of the August data). If CPI consolidates under 3.5 percent things will be looking better,&quot; Bianchi said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>He said the preliminary August data confirmed a continuing downward trend for inflation &quot;even though there is concern that the fall in inflation is in part tied to the slowdown of the economy,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Bank of Italy cut its official discount rate to 8.25 percent last month, after holding its key rate unchanged for over a year at nine percent. -- Alma Davanzo, Rome newsroom +396 6782501</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
