<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6530" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German industry urges Bonn to tone down tax debate.</title>
<headline>German industry urges Bonn to tone down tax debate.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>German industrialists on Wednesday urged Chancellor Helmut Kohl's centre-right coalition government to tone down a debate over tax cuts that has become the issue to fill a summer lull in news.</p>
<p>During parliament's recess, politicians from Kohl's coalition of Christian Democrats and liberal Free Democrats (FDP), joined by the main opposition Social Democrats (SPD), have kept up a steady chorus calling for cuts in income tax.</p>
<p>For weeks, hardly a day has passed without a leading member of the FDP restating the party's demands for a sweeping reform of the income tax system before the general election in 1998.</p>
<p>At the same time, Kohl recently fuelled the summer debates from his Austrian vacation home by suggesting a rise in value added tax to finance a cut in income taxes.</p>
<p>But as the sultry Rhineland summer fades and politicians gear up for their return to Bonn, Germany's main industry association took the opportunity to remind the political establishment that the issue was more than summer theatre.</p>
<p>In a statement, Hans-Olaf Henkel, president of the Federation of German Industry (BDI), said he &quot;appealed to the government to steer the discussion in a clear direction and quieter waters&quot;.</p>
<p>In order to benefit industry, and lay the foundation for job creation, broad tax reform must lower the total share of taxes and levies on basic pay to 40.7 percent by the year 2000 from around 43.7 percent now, he said.</p>
<p>It must also lower tax burdens for companies, eliminate taxes on trading capital and lend a hand to mid-sized companies, many of which are family-owned, by easing inheritance taxes, he added.</p>
<p>At issue is the second phase of a government plan to lower tax burdens. The first step is to take place next year and will involve lowering a so-called solidarity tax, which was put in place to finance German unification.</p>
<p>It also aims to scrap taxes on wealth, delay a rise in child benefits and change taxes on vehicles to be based on emissions instead of horsepower.</p>
<p>The second phase will deal directly with income tax and the costs of labour but the government coalition has been divided over when and how to implement this step.</p>
<p>Kohl's CDU and the FDP have been at odds over details of the planned tax reform and when it should take effect.</p>
<p>The FDP wants the second phase of tax reform to take effect ahead of the next election, which must take place before the end of 1998. Kohl prefers to wait until 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;The dramatic situation with four million jobless demands quick action,&quot; said FDP general secretary Guido Westerwelle.</p>
<p>But Hansgeorg Hauser, state secretary in the Finance Ministry, has rejected the FDP demand to bring forward the tax reform.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be impossible to carry out the necessary changes to the law so quickly,&quot; Hauser told the weekly Wirtschafts Woche business magazine.</p>
<p>Economic experts and industry representatives say high taxes are one of the main reasons why businesses are not investing.</p>
<p>Members of Germany's &quot;Five Wise Men&quot;, a panel of independent economic advisers to the government, urge lower corporate taxes, with one, Rolf Peffekoven, warning: &quot;Germany as a centre of industrial production is in danger.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
