<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6534" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Nightmare for kidnapped Belgian girl's parents.</title>
<headline>Nightmare for kidnapped Belgian girl's parents.</headline>
<byline>Bert Lauwers</byline>
<dateline>HASSELT, Belgium 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paul and Betty Marchal have lived a nightmare since their eldest daughter An disappeared along with a female friend exactly one year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;You wonder whether they are still alive, where they are, what happened to them...&quot; An's father Paul Marchal told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Part of the mystery was solved when convicted child rapist Marc Dutroux confessed last weekend that he had kidnapped An, then aged 19, and her friend Eefje Lambrecks, 17, in Ostend on August 21, 1995.</p>
<p>But the nightmare continues as the fate of the girls remains unknown.</p>
<p>Dutroux had earlier led police to the bodies of two eight-year-old girls after two other children were rescued from one of his houses. Both had been sexually abused.</p>
<p>&quot;We discussed every possibility of what could have happened (to An),&quot; Betty Marchal told Reuters. &quot;But we never expected this. This is totally inhuman,&quot; husband Paul added.</p>
<p>The arrest of Dutroux and his accomplices and the discovery of the four other girls rekindled hopes in recent days that An and Eefje could be found.</p>
<p>&quot;The prosecutor says there is a possibility (of finding them) and if he says so he must have some facts to prove this... I just hope it will not be a matter of weeks any more,&quot; Paul said.</p>
<p>Media reports the girls were in the Czech Republic or the Netherlands fuelled hopes for an early breakthrough. But Michel Bourlet, the public prosecutor in charge of the case, said on Tuesday there was no real news.</p>
<p>Asked whether the tension now had become unbearable, he said: &quot;I've always suppressed my feelings. I have hardly had any time to let my feelings out.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There is not so much anger because we didn't have the time to absorb it all. This is not a man but a monster,&quot; he said of Dutroux.</p>
<p>He also appealed to anyone holding the girls to let them go.</p>
<p>&quot;If they do something more horrible, if they kill them, it will more difficult for (the abductors) too.. bring them back please,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Marchal was bitter about the lack of cooperation from police after his daughter went missing.</p>
<p>&quot;Police always said the girls had just run off. It took police 10 days to react,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He also attacked the lack of information. &quot;Sometimes we were without news for several months and even then we had to call them, to hear there was no news,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Marchals, who have four children, have quietly endured the barrage of media interest in the case, Belgium's worst child-sex scandal.</p>
<p>Their telephone and door bells ring almost constantly, but An's 16-year-old sister Karen and brothers Kris, 14, and Gert, 12, are undeterred.</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing they complain about is that we can give them so little attention now,&quot; Paul said.</p>
<p>He admitted he was more worried about the three than before An's abduction.</p>
<p>&quot;They have to stick to strict arrangements...but you cannot lock them up, can you? That's what we tried to do at first but they let us know that was out of the question.&quot;</p>
<p>The centrepiece of the living room is a big poster with An and Eefje's picture and the word &quot;missing&quot; in six languages. Stacks of newspapers and leaflets on the missing girls fill tables.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HASSELT, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
