<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6535" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: INSTANT VIEW-Italy Aug CPI seen at 3.3 pct yr/yr.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW-Italy Aug CPI seen at 3.3 pct yr/yr.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are analysts' comments on preliminary Italian consumer prices data from six sample cities showing inflation is likely to be 3.3/3.4 percent year on year in August and 0.0/0.1 percent month on month.</p>
<p>The rates are analysts' estimates after the data. Forecasts had been for 3.6 percent year on year and 0.1 percent month on month.</p>
<p>Luciana Trevisan, economist at Caboto, said &quot;In my opinion the Bank of Italy will cut interest rates at the end of the year because the target of three percent will be reached in November or December.&quot;  </p>
<p>Sharda Persaud, European economist at San Paolo bank in London, said so far on the data released she forecast consumer prices at 3.3 percent year on year for August.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very good data...We see inflation heading down possibly to 3.0 percent in October which would give enough room for Bank of Italy governor Antonio Fazio to cut rates again.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We see the discount rate coming down to about 7.0 percent by the end of the year so we see two more cuts in the discount rate,&quot; Persaud said.  </p>
<p>Riccardo Barbieri, Italian economist at Morgan Stanley in London said, &quot;Yes, the numbers are pretty good. I was expecting an increase of 0.1 percent on the month, and since the increase is actually on average slightly below that level, I think the inflation rate will probably decline to at least 3.4 percent if not 3.3 percent at the national level from 3.6 percent in July&quot;.</p>
<p>A further four Italian sample cities report their preliminary August CPI data tomorrow, while ISTAT will publish the official August Italian CPI figures on September 5.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
