<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6543" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish bonds slide with Europe, eye Buba meeting.</title>
<headline>Irish bonds slide with Europe, eye Buba meeting.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish government bonds lost ground across the curve in brisk trading on Wednesday afternoon as most European markets were nervy in advance of a possible repo rate cut at Thursday's Bundesbank meeting, dealers said.     &quot;Irish</p>
<p>bonds have been slipping gradually all day because of panicky European markets. Dealers are still divided on whether a German repo cut is on the cards,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>By 1515 GMT, the 8.00 percent bond due 2000 was down 37 pence from Tuesday's close at 103.55 to yield 6.85 percent.</p>
<p>The 8.00 percent bond due 2006 was down 35 pence from the close at 102.95 to yield 7.43 percent.  </p>
<p>The German Ifo business climate index came in stronger than expected at 94.1 and dealers said any repo rate cut tomorrow was now likely to be kept to a minimum.</p>
<p>&quot;The Irish market has fallen in anticipation of a small German repo cut on Thursday. Most analysts would now be expecting a minimum cut in the repo rate,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>In the UK, gilts made half-point losses across the curve at closing as dealers said the only thing that could stablise the market was a German repo cut.</p>
<p>Earlier, UK retail sales for July showed a surprise drop of 0.6 percent after a 1.4 percent jump in June, dealers said.</p>
<p>-- Senan Hogan, Dublin Newsroom +353 1 660 3377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
