<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6549" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Iraq oil seen on track for mid-September - diplomats.</title>
<headline>Iraq oil seen on track for mid-September - diplomats.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Western diplomats at the United Nations said Wednesday that the administrative arrangements necessary before first Iraqi oil can flow under the recent &quot;oil-for-food&quot; deal remain about two weeks away.</p>
<p>Four overseers, independent experts from the United States, France, Russia and Norway, who will approve oil sales contracts on a day-to-day basis are expected to be in place at the U.N. this week, said one diplomat on the U.N.'s Iraqi sanctions committee.  </p>
<p>Once in place, Baghdad must submit its pricing mechanism, a step which is expected to take place next week. This will consist of a pricing formula to be used for term contract sales based on three regional benchmark crudes - North Sea Brent for Europe, West Texas Intermediate for the Americas and Dubai for the Middle and Far East.</p>
<p>Iraq will also be permitted to sell its oil on the spot market, subject to sanctions committee approval, at market prices rather than formula prices, diplomats said.  </p>
<p>Diplomats said the process to complete the accord, reached on May 20 accord, is on schedule but would take more time and continue into September.</p>
<p>&quot;We're waiting for contracts to sign on the goods inspectors, and to put the oil monitors in place,&quot; said a Western diplomat. &quot;It's at least two, maybe three weeks (from completion),&quot; the diplomat said.</p>
<p>The United Nations named the four overseers on August 8, the date the sanctions committee adopted procedures for oil sales and aid purchases.  </p>
<p>Since procedures were adopted, U.N. officials have worked to finalize the last bits of the oil-for-food scheme. The plan allows Iraq to sell $2 billion worth of crude over six months on a renewable basis to ease effects of sanctions imposed after Iraq invaded Kuwait in August 1990.</p>
<p>U.N. Under-Secretary-General Chinmaya Gharekhan said last week that the United Nations wanted as many &quot;indispensible&quot; people on the ground in Iraq as possible before the secretary-general's report is finalized.  </p>
<p>This set of monitors would be recruited individually by the U.N. secretariat.</p>
<p>Another 32 independent inspection agents would be recruited through another company to monitor the import of humanitarian aid, a step later in the process.</p>
<p>Distribution of goods in the northern Kurdish regions of the country would remain under U.N. control.</p>
<p>The initial six-month period begins the day after Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali submits his report to the U.N. Security Council.</p>
<p>The Dutch company Saybolt has been signed to field 14 independent inspection agents to monitor the oil exports from Iraq.</p>
<p>Before oil sales can start, the U.N. must also hire 150 monitors to observe the distribution of supplies in central and southern Iraq, to ensure they reached all sections of the population and to report on the adequacy of supplies.</p>
<p>-Patrick Connole, +1 212 859 1828</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
