<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6550" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss bond market closing report.</title>
<headline>Swiss bond market closing report.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss bonds ended weaker, dropping as German bonds fell on news of Germany's latest Ifo economic institute report.</p>
<p>But Swiss prices may have gained some support from the Swiss franc's gains versus the dollar.</p>
<p>Two new 10-year corporate issues totaling 550 million Swiss francs weighed on prices early in the day.</p>
<p>The long end was seen pressured by rising swap rates.</p>
<p>Money market rates remained firm although the Swiss National Bank was said to have added funds this morning slightly below market rates.  </p>
<p>News that Germany's Ifo institute reported its July business climate index at 94.1, up from 90.4 in June, weighed on German bonds. The number was above expectations and was also seen as lessening chances for the Bundesbank to lower its repurchase rate at the central bank's meeting Thursday.</p>
<p>In the wake of the Ifo report, Swiss debt prices eased. The news also made for a less than ideal climate for launch of Canton Zurich's 250 million Swiss franc 10-year issue.</p>
<p>The issue, with a 4.25 percent coupon priced at 100.55, yielded 4.31 percent in late trade, only four basis points above 10-year Confederate bonds.  </p>
<p>Alongside Zurich, Credit Suisse also led a 10-year 300 million Swiss franc issue for Tokyo Electric.</p>
<p>Ten-year swap rates were quoted in late trade at 4.60 compared with 4.58 early in the day.</p>
<p>Swiss National Bank (SNB) 10-day reserves data showed sight deposits rising 96.3 million Swiss francs to a relatively high 3.07 billion Swiss francs in the mid-August period. An SNB spokesman said the level indicated continued demand for liquidity and also SNB willingness to meet this demand. Overnight money was quoted near 2-1/2 percent early in the day. The SNB was said to have added liquidity at 2-1/4 percent.  </p>
<p>Closing prices as follows:</p>
<p>--Futures:</p>
<p>Sept conf bond down 30 at 112.75.</p>
<p>Sept comi medium-term bond down 12 at 109.10.</p>
<p>Sept Euro Swiss francs down four at 97.65. -- Cash:</p>
<p>4-1/2 Apr 2006 bond 101.63/101.73 yld 4.274 pct</p>
<p>(Tuesday 101.72/82 yield 4.262 pct)</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial, +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
