<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6551" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Zimbabwe's Affretair to boost winter capacity.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe's Affretair to boost winter capacity.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwean cargo airline Affretair said it will expand capacity substantially on its Europe flights this winter to cope with increasing horticultural exports.</p>
<p>Ingo Zimmer, managing director of the airline's Germany general sales agent ATC Aviation Services, said the three summer flights to Amsterdam will be increased to four from October and five from January.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a massive upgrading in terms of space for the winter flower season,&quot; he told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>The introduction of a new McDonnell Douglas DC-10 aircraft will ease capacity limitations with the airline's two Douglas DC-8s on northbound legs, in particular, he added.</p>
<p>From October, Affretair will fly a separate Thursday DC-8 Amsterdam-Lusaka service which will allow a DC-10 service to Harare and Johannesburg on the same day, Zimmer said.</p>
<p>The existing Monday Harare flight and Saturday service to Harare and Johannesburg using DC-8 aircraft will be maintained.</p>
<p>From January, when the flower season peaks, Affretair will fly DC-10 services to Harare on Mondays, Tuesdays, Thursdays and Saturdays with extensions to Johannesburg on Thursdays and Saturdays.</p>
<p>Zimmer said distribution from Amsterdam through Germany is secured by direct trucking services to all major German airports.</p>
<p>Affretair horticulture sales manager Phil Clitchlow said in July the airline had not had enough capacity to cope with demand in the last few years.</p>
<p>The Zimbabwean Horticultural Promotion Council said in July it expects to export more than 48,000 tonnes of fresh-cut flowers and edible produce to Europe in the 1995/96 season. --Air Cargo Newsroom Tel +44 171 542 8982 Fax +44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
