<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6552" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian OLOs down on IFO but Bund spread narrows.</title>
<headline>Belgian OLOs down on IFO but Bund spread narrows.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian linear bonds lagged the decline in Bunds on Wednesday making the market seem even more expensive and raising the chances of a sharp move lower in the near future, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;I still see the market as overbought with room to come down,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>The decline was triggered by strong July German business climate figures from the IFO, dashing -- or at least heavily undermining -- high hopes for a cut in the repo rate at Thursday's meeting of the Bundesbank Council, traders said.  </p>
<p>The benchmark 2006 OLO ended the day yielding 6.64 percent, up from Tuesday's 6.59, and the spread over Bunds narrowed three basis points to 30.</p>
<p>The front-month futures contract fell 51 basis points to 115.95. Three-month Treasury certificates yielded 3.25/31 percent against Tuesday's 3.27/29.</p>
<p>The Belgian franc/mark rate was 20.6015/35 compared with 20.6010/30.</p>
<p>The IFO index rocketed to 94.1 from 90.4 in June, confounding expectations of a rise to 91.0 and sending a strong signal that the Bundesbank might feel reluctant to cut the repo.</p>
<p>The figures triggered a spate of selling, particularly in five year paper where the yield jumped to 5.48 percent from 5.39 overnight.</p>
<p>But traders added that yields among all the five to 10 year maturities climbed steeply.</p>
<p>Despite that, buying in the afternoon ensured that the bond market lagged by a comfortable margin the decline in Germany's Bunds. -- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
