<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6557" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital markets closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital markets closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>French bond futures settled lower, tagging Bunds, after German Ifo business climate data for July came out stronger than expected, dampening prospects of a rate cut in Germany on Thursday.</p>
<p>PIBOR three-month interest rate futures underperformed their German counterparts as the franc slithered back below 3.42 per mark in afternoon trading, adding to the weight of conviction against a rate cut by the Bank of France.</p>
<p>Traders said the afternoon slide came as primarily technical trading ahead of the Bundesbank and Bank of France meetings on Thursday pushed German, and French futures, through supports.  </p>
<p>In Germany, markets were more bearish about chances of a cut in the 3.30 percent repo rate.</p>
<p>Seven out of 10 economists polled by Reuters on Thursday said they now believed the chances of a cut had fallen. In a poll after weak M3 data on Tuesday, eight out of 10 had confidently predicted an easing in monetary policy.</p>
<p>On top of the Ifo data, an upward revision in Germany's June industry orders index by the Bundesbank to 96.3 from 95.7 also pointed to economic strength.  </p>
<p>&quot;One figure does not complete the picture for the German economy,&quot; he said, referring to the Ifo index. Jamet also noted that Buba members Edgar Meister and Otmar Issing had recently voiced concerns about German economic fundamentals and recent mark appreciation.</p>
<p>The September contract settled clinging to a major support level of 123.32/30, which had been breached earlier after the equivalent bund broke through support at 97.65.</p>
<p>Valerie Asselot, economist at Credit Lyonnais, said failure by the Bundesbank to move on Thursday could rekindle tensions in France to the extent that it would limit the French central bank's room for manoeuvre.</p>
<p>&quot;It will give the idea that the joinery in the Franco-German couple is not rock solid. The franc needs a helping hand on monetary policy from Germany,&quot; Asselot said, adding that this helping hand did not seem top priority for the Bundesbank.</p>
<p>Fimat analyst Damien Jamet said, however: &quot;Expectations of a small gesture will not fade completely.&quot; -- Brian Love, Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
