<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6558" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spanish olive oil industry set for 1997 revival.</title>
<headline>Spanish olive oil industry set for 1997 revival.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's olive oil market is set for a revival next year as consumers, hard-hit by two years of rocketing prices, benefit from the milder weather which is set to restore the olive harvest to 1993 levels.</p>
<p>Industry officials say last winter's abundant rains, combined with good weather all summer, have partly reversed the effects of a five-year drought which threatened to make the staple ingredient of the Mediterranean diet a gourmet luxury.</p>
<p>The Agriculture Ministry predicts the national harvest for the 1996/97 season will recover to 550,000 tonnes from a mere 350,000 tonnes in 1995/96, returning production to 1993/94 levels.</p>
<p>It said foreign analysts' forecasts of a 700,000 tonne crop were excessive, a position supported by other officials who placed the ceiling at around 600,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>But virgin olive oil was set to fall back to 400 pesetas a litre from 605 pesetas at present and a peak of 700 in December, a spokesman at the ministry said.</p>
<p>Industry sources say these forecasts are on the optimistic side, but agree that a drop to the 450-500 range is possible.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a long way to drop to 400,&quot; said a spokesman for the Young Farmers' Association (ASAJA).</p>
<p>It sees a harvest of 600,000 tonnes in the crop year which runs from November 1 to October 31, with prices falling to around 500 pesetas per litre.</p>
<p>&quot;In principle consumption will pick up,&quot; the spokesman said. &quot;But it's going to depend a lot on the promotion campaigns that are run.&quot;</p>
<p>Consumption fell 40 percent between January and June, down 23 percent on a annualised basis, due to rising prices, said a spokesman for the edible oil bottling and refining association.</p>
<p>&quot;There are many people who don't buy through the usual channels and go straight to the supplier, and we've seen an increase in fraud especially in Andalusia where some suppliers have been mixing in other oils,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But it appears that instead of switching to other types of oil, many cooks are simply using less.</p>
<p>Consumption of seed and sunflower oil has risen by only five to six percent this year, raising hopes of a swift recovery in olive oil sales once prices come down.</p>
<p>Export sales to countries where olive oil is generally considered a luxury could also rise.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very probable we will see a rise, not only in domestic consumption but also that of third countries like the U.S., Japan, Australia and Germany,&quot; the ASAJA spokesman said. --By Joelle Diderich, Madrid Newsroom +34 1 585 2161</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
