<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6559" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks close sharply down on weaker franc.</title>
<headline>French stocks close sharply down on weaker franc.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>French shares closed sharply lower on Wednesday due to a weaker franc amid evaporating hopes of a German rate cut on Thursday, but the market managed to remain above the 2,000 level and did keep some of Tuesday's gains.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index was down 18.62 points or 0.92 percent at 2,000.64 while the CAC-40 futures contract was down at 2,003 from 2,027 on Tuesday's close.</p>
<p>The share market was closely following the futures market which in turn eyed the bond and bund markets. Wall Street's lower start and losses on other European markets also weighed.  </p>
<p>Volume was a modest 3.43 billion francs.</p>
<p>The market had been deep in the red from the start after the Ifo west German business climate poll for July showed a stronger economy than expected, which was interpreted as a sign the Bundesbank will not cut its repo rate on Thursday.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, slower German monetary growth coupled with a decision by the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) not to raise U.S. rates had rekindled German rate cut hopes and pushed French shares up by a strong 1.66 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The German indicators suggest a strong economy and the market doubts that there will be a cut,&quot; a dealer said.  </p>
<p>Economists do not expect the Bank of France to follow any German rate cut due to the relative weakness of the franc ahead of the September presentation of the 1997 austerity budget.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe, who returned from holidays on Tuesday, will meet President Jacques Chirac this weekend. They are expected to set the main outlines of promised tax cuts as well as the spending cuts needed to reach the budget deficit criteria to qualify for European Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>The September budget could cause further social unrest with labour unions ready for a new battle after last December's strikes -- another factor keeping the franc and shares down.  </p>
<p>Half-way between the end of the season for first half sales figures and the start of publication of first half corporate results, financial analysts have further cut profit forecasts.</p>
<p>The Associes en Finance research institute said their August poll of 18 brokerages showed that French corporate forecasts had again been reduced for both 1996 and 1997.</p>
<p>The 1996 forecasts, on an earnings per share basis, were downgraded by an average 1.8 percent and those for 1997 by 0.8 percent compared to the July poll. These low forecasts explain the Paris market's inability to stay above 2,000 for long while other markets set record highs, analysts said.  </p>
<p>* Media group Pathe gained another 5.24 percent to 1,305 after earlier gains on Monday and Tuesday. The share was boosted by big increase in first-half sales, higher than expected full-year results of BSkyB -- in which it has a 17 percent stake -- and buy advice by NatWest.</p>
<p>* Promodes closed 0.33 percent lower at 1,212 after reversing earlier losses to a low of 1,171 on rumours it had downgraded its profit forecast after disappointing first half sales. Finance director Alexandre Roeser told Reuters the company still expects a 10 to 15 percent rise in 1996 net attributable profit.  </p>
<p>* Cap Gemini, up 3.1 percent to 211.90, reported its first half sales were up by 21.6 percent.</p>
<p>* Axime dropped 9.6 percent to 552 franc, in a volume of 96,721 shares, on the back of disappointing 1995/96 profit figures. It lost some 15 percent on Tuesday.</p>
<p>* Cie Generale des Eaux, down 1.17 percent to 505 francs, said it had won a 15-year U.K. rail franchise for the South Eastern network. CGEA unit will invest 400 million stg to replace the train fleet.</p>
<p>* Bouygues down 2.5 percent to 507 francs in light volume of 37,356 shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
