<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6564" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Bangladesh lawmakers protest police raid on campus.</title>
<headline>Bangladesh lawmakers protest police raid on campus.</headline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bangladeshi opposition lawmakers walked out of parliament on Wednesday in protest against police raids on Dhaka University residential halls where violence erupted between student groups, parliamentary sources said.</p>
<p>Members of the opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and fundamentalist Jamaat-e-Islami staged the walkout after they were refused permission to open an unscheduled debate on the campus clashes, the sources said.</p>
<p>Home Minister Rafiqul Islam told the house in a statement later there was a &quot;sinister design&quot; to create chaos in the country and destabilise the new government.</p>
<p>Police denied any firing on the campus but said they had used teargas after violence broke out between the Chhatra League, the student wing of ruling Awami League, and Jatyatabadi Chhatradal (JCD) of the BNP.</p>
<p>Islam said police resorted to action only after JCD activists attacked them with guns. He said the JCD protesters were preventing students from attending class.</p>
<p>The JCD called a strike on campus after their supporters were driven out by rivals from a residential hall on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Hospital sources said Shahiduddin Chowdhury Ani, the president of JCD, was injured and admitted to Dhaka Medical College Hospital.</p>
<p>The JCD supporters, angered by the incident, set fire to the office of the provost of a university hall.</p>
<p>Police said they then raided university dormitories to flush out fighting students and found four guns. Two JCD students had been arrested, they said.</p>
<p>Nearly 20 students and one policeman had been injured since Monday in sporadic clashes between the rival student groups, police said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
