<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6566" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: OPINION - INDIA MARKET STRATEGY - BY KOTAK SECURITIES.</title>
<headline>OPINION - INDIA MARKET STRATEGY - BY KOTAK SECURITIES.</headline>
<text>
<p>An extract from Kotak Securities' latest market</p>
<p>strategy report. Kotak forecasts a negative short-term outlook for Indian stocks. It says foreign investment flows are likely to be low during the remaining part of 1996, with domestic institutions staying net sellers.</p>
<p>								 -----oOo-----</p>
<p>				 HIGHLIGHTS</p>
<p>**  BUY QUALITY - For the rest of 1996/97 investors are safer staying with non-cyclicals which are least affected by trend of government policy.</p>
<p>**  MULTINATIONALS - Multinationals with the favourable tilt of government policy towards them and a new found aggression will outperform the market in the next 12-months.</p>
<p>**  WHAT'S HOT - Banks, power generation utilities, power equipment suppliers, refining utilities, fast moving consumer goods (FMCG), pharmaceutical formulations, auto and auto ancillaries.</p>
<p>**  WHAT'S NOT - Synthetic yarn &amp; fibres, plastics, petrochemicals, textile intermediates, cement, steel, pharmaceutical bulk drugs.</p>
<p>			    BUDGETARY SIGNALS</p>
<p>The signals sent out by Finance Minister Chidambaram's budget are very clear: the government would rather let market forces dictate the growth of commercial enterprises.</p>
<p>It is important to recognise that this had more to do with the restricted options he had to balance the Budget than what is broadly referred to as &quot;political compulsions&quot;.</p>
<p>This is important to recognise because the course of future government policy in India appears inevitably set on a path that will ensure greater competition - both global and domestic - rather than on attempts to direct investment in to &quot;desirable&quot; areas.</p>
<p>Even if future governments are inclined to think differently they will face the same dilemma that Chidambaram faced: there are just not enough resources with the government for it to determine and guide allocation.</p>
<p>We can sense this from some of the measures that can be termed as budget surprises.</p>
<p>ONE, the fact that the finance minister reduced sharply the import duties on synthetic yarns and fibres, polyester and viscose intermediates, steel products and plastics despite the fact that these industries were already reeling under the impact of domestic over capacity and weak international prices.</p>
<p>The message, not delivered in as concrete terms appears to be, &quot;be competitive or perish&quot;.</p>
<p>SECOND, and equally significant, is the fact that the finance minister refrained from directing foreign investment away from &quot;non-priority&quot; areas.</p>
<p>THIRD, the willingness of the government to abolish zero tax status for companies providing only one significant exemption-export oriented units.</p>
<p>Even though the government has prolonged subsidies for the agricultural sector (fertilisers, irrigation systems, tractors &amp; tillers etc) we think this is clearly a temporary compromise than an important policy element.</p>
<p>We believe the Budget is the final proof, if any were required, that businesses that thrived on government subsidies and were more adept at raising and allocating resources rather than obtaining a market rate of return on them can no longer expect to be the star performers.</p>
<p>In the competitive environment that has emerged in India only those businesses that have accumulated real skills, and can leverage off them to compete effectively, will obtain above average returns.</p>
<p>The former type of companies will be the victims of the reforms programmes and the latter companies its creations.</p>
<p>			 CORPORATE OUTLOOK</p>
<p>While the measures that are being proposed in the Budget are by and large not unfavourable for the industrial economy or the corporate sector we believe that from a 12-month perspective many of the major industries will be negatively affected by the budgetary proposals.</p>
<p>There are two significant areas of impact:</p>
<p>**  The import duty reductions on a range of products in the plastics, the petrochemicals, synthetic textiles and steel products will squeeze margins for major players in these industries.</p>
<p>The steel and cement industries will also witness a squeeze in margins because of cost push due to increases in the cost of freight, power and fuel. While the lower prices could spur demand over a longer period of time the immediate impact is more likely to be reflected in company fundamentals and stock market prices.</p>
<p>While the performances of these companies has been relatively unaffected in the past despite sharp drops in the rates of duties since 1992, we think the performance has been helped by two other factors:</p>
<p>1.  The sharp depreciation of the rupee against the U.S. dollar in the past five years, and</p>
<p>2.  The general level of buoyancy in commodity prices in the international markets.</p>
<p>While the rupee-dollar rate is likely to continue to decline in the next 12-months, the decline will be nowhere as sharp as it has been in the preceding five years.</p>
<p>In addition, competitive pressures will be stronger for most commodities because weakness in global markets and also because of domestic oversupply situation in key textile products (polyester yarn, polyester fibre, viscose staple fibre, cement and flat steel products).</p>
<p>**  The introduction of changes in the direct tax laws requiring companies to pay minimum alternate tax on book profits will result in denying full tax benefits, available in the past, to companies that are investing in capital assets aggressively. Most of these are cyclicals.</p>
<p>As such there will be more earnings downgrades in these sectors than on many other sectors.</p>
<p>As the companies most likely to be affected are the large companies (in terms of sales and market capitalisation), the post-Budget reaction of the Sensex has been very negative.</p>
<p>We think this will also lead to a sharper focus on some sectors to the exclusion of others. The need to be more defensive will also lead to preference for non-cyclicals in portfolios.  </p>
<p>			     MARKET OUTLOOK</p>
<p>** SHORT TERM: NEGATIVE</p>
<p>While the sensex performance over the first seven months of the calendar year (upto 23/07/1996) shows positive gain of 19 percent as many as 40 percent of the stockist have shown negative returns and only 13 stocks out of 30 have outperformed the index.</p>
<p>The poorer performance of major stocks like Reliance, Tata Steel, Indian Rayon and Grasim is outweighed by the positive performance of the automobile companies (Mahindra &amp; Mahindra and Telco), the multinationals (Hindustan Lever, Glaxo, Nestle, Siemens, K.Cummins and ITC), Tata Power and Indian Hotels.</p>
<p>Given the relatively lower liquidity of the stocks that have been the most outstanding performers we think the overall market returns for FII investors would have been significantly lower than the 19 percent indicated by the sensex.</p>
<p>This is compounded by the fact that the outlook for the major sectors -- steel, cement, plastics, textiles etc. continues to be negative.</p>
<p>We do not therefore see any significant step up in Foreign Iinstitutional Investor (FII) investment which has already reached some $2.8 billion from January 1996 till date.</p>
<p>Earlier, investments into emerging markets for calendar year 1996 were estimated at $50 billion - of this, 8-10 percent was estimated to flow into India.</p>
<p>This would have placed FII inflows into Indian stocks at around $4-5 billion for calendar 1996. Although roughly 50 percent of this has already been invested, much of this went through the secondary market because of the small flow of GDR issues in the first half of the year.</p>
<p>Of the balance 50 percent a greater proportion is likely to go to the primary market with large GDR issues taking place/proposed for ICICI, SBI, TELCO, VSNL etc.</p>
<p>On the whole the last five months of the calendar year are likely to see very little FII investment flowing into the secondary market as compared to that in the first seven months.</p>
<p>We expect local institution to be net sellers in the domestic market over the same period. Our market oulook for the next five months is negative.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>		    SECTOR PERFORMANCE AND OUTLOOK</p>
<p>On a industry perference basis it is probably natural that certain sectors have dominated the sensex outperformance list in the past 12-months.</p>
<p>These are: Auto, auto ancillary (including tyres), power generation, power equipment, telecom services, fast moving consumer goods, banks, software, paints and multinational pharmaceuticals</p>
<p>The Budget, trend of government policy and industry specific factors indicate that these are likely to be the same sectors that will outperform the sensex over the next 12-months also. </p>
<p>To sum up, the following is the list of industries that we view as positive and negative respectively over the next 12-months.</p>
<p>** POSITIVE</p>
<p>Banks, power equipment suppliers, power generating utilities, oil refining utilities, FMCG, pharmaceutical formulations, telecom services, auto and auto ancillaries, hotels, and software.</p>
<p>We would also include aluminium and shipping along with the auto segment as the only cyclicals where the outlook is not too negative and valuations are attractive.</p>
<p>** NEGATIVE</p>
<p>Steel, cement, plastics, textile intermediates, synthetics fibres and yarns, petrochemicals, fertilisers and chemicals, pharmaceutical bulk drugs, consumer durables and paper.</p>
<p>We think investors will be more sharply focussed on short term earnings gwoth prospects (for half year ended September 96 to March 97) and will find that the industries identified as positive will have companies reporting above average earnings growth, whereas companies in industries categorised as negative will have below average earnings growth.</p>
<p>Overweighting the positive sectors and underweighting the negative sectors will be both a defensive and enterprising strategy.</p>
<p>Cyclicals where the industry cycle is currently down could be included in the portfolio only when a clear indication of a upturn in the commodity cycle is visible.</p>
<p>			  MULTINATIONALS</p>
<p>One class of companies that emerges as a clear winner in the current context is Indian companies &quot;owned&quot; by foreign multinationals.</p>
<p>This class of companies referred to in the past as &quot;FERA&quot; companies after the Foreign Exchange Regulation Act were always amongst the best managed Indian companies in terms of day-to-day operations.</p>
<p>Until 1991 however they were subjected to several government controls under the FERA (now scrapped), the Monopolies and Restrictive Trade Practices Act and the Industries (Development &amp; Regulation) Act which governed the issue of licenses for manufacturing. There was a fairly consistent anti-MNC stance in these laws.</p>
<p>Since 1991 however many changes have been made in these laws the principal thrust of which have been to:</p>
<p>**  Allow greater shareholding for foreign parents in the Indian company, and</p>
<p>**  Permitting capacity expansions/new prodcut introduction without the formality of a government license in most cases.</p>
<p>These factors combined with their altered view of the domestic market as a vigorously growing one has revived growth aspirations for many of these companies.</p>
<p>Whereas much of the management focus in the past was on &quot;maintenance&quot; in the face of the number of constraints they faced today many of these companies are focussed on growth by leveraging on their knowledge of the Indian market gained through presence over many years.</p>
<p>In their pursuit of growth these companies enjoy many advantages over Indian growth companies belonging to groups like Reliance, Essar, Jindal etc, such as:</p>
<p>**  Access to technology and a range of developed products under license from the parent.</p>
<p>**  Marketing skills and experience gained in other countries.</p>
<p>**  Management skills, particularly in the area of financial management and corporate strategy.</p>
<p>**  Strong balance sheets with under borrowed position, thanks partly to many years of low capital commitment to new products/expansions.</p>
<p>**  Relatively stronger ability of majority stakeholders to commit large financial reasons for long term growth.</p>
<p>The future of these companies will be more impacted by their ability to leverage global strengths.</p>
<p>Apart from their ability to achieve significant growth with minimal equity dilution MNCs also enjoy the following additional benefits:</p>
<p>**  The reduction in surcharge on corporate income tax from 15 percent to 7.5 percent with a promise to remove it totally next year will improve post-tax earnings by 11 percent in two years as most MNCs pay very high tax close to the 46 percent (40 percent plus 15 percent surcharge) rate.</p>
<p>**  Import duty reductions substantially benefit MNCs, rather than affecting them because they import raw materials and generally do not produce products that face threat from imports.</p>
<p>**  Excise duty reductions also benefit MNCs as most of them produce non-commodity goods and can atleast partially retain the benefit of reduced excise duty or leverage off it to increase sales faster.</p>
<p>For the equity investor, their attractiveness from the point of view of their ability to achieve credible, substainable growth with minimal equity dilutions has to be balanced off to some extent against lack of availability of stock easily in large volumes and their high discounting.</p>
<p>As a group of stocks MNCs trade at a significant premium to the market. We believe that despite being more expensive this group of stocks will outperform the market over the next twelve months.</p>
<p>(The opinions expressed in this article reflect the views of the author only. They should not be taken as reflecting the views of Reuters)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
