<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6572" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - August 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - August 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indian business and political stories in leading newspapers on Wednesday prepared for Reuters by Business News and Information Services Pvt Ltd, New Delhi. Telephone: 11-3324842, 11-3761233; Fax: 91-11-3351006</p>
<p>Internet: biznis.news@forums.sprintrpg.sprint.com</p>
<p>		   -------oo0oo-------</p>
<p>			TOP STORIES</p>
<p>The Hindustan Times</p>
<p>INDIA VETOES TEST BAN TREATY</p>
<p>India vetoed the draft text of the controversial Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty (CTBT), thus posing hurdles in sending the pact to the UN General Assembly. Indian envoy Arundhati Ghose said the draft CTBT did not serve the purpose of promoting the realisation of universal disarmament goals. The US and its allies reacted sharply to India's action and vowed to bring the pact to the UN General Assembly for signature somehow. Pakistani envoy Munir Akram condemned the Indian veto and expressed concern about what he called New Delhi's nuclear ambitions.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Times Of India</p>
<p>EXPELLED BHARATIYA JANATA PARTY LEADER LAUNCHES NEW PARTY</p>
<p>Expelled) leader Shankarsinh Vaghela of the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) has formed a new party, the Rashtriya Janata Party (RJP). The other new party formed by the BJP rebels, the Gujarat Janata Party, has declared its merger with Vaghela's RJP. The United Front coalition, meanwhile, continued parleys with Vaghela with a view to forming a non-BJP government in Gujarat with the Congress party's support.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Indian Express</p>
<p>SCRAP TELECOMMUNICATION LICENCES: COMMUNIST LEADER</p>
<p>Communist Party of India-Marxist Parliament member Ashok Mitra urged the Prime Minister to suspend all licences for basic and cellular telecommunications services issued in 1995. The demand followed recent raids on the residence of former Communications Minister Sukh Ram by the Central Bureau of Investigation which led to the recovery of about 36.6 million rupees. Mitra asked the Prime Minister to institute an inquiry into the procedure adopted for issuing the licences.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Economic Times</p>
<p>PLAN TO ABOLISH APPROVAL FOR POWER PROJECTS UP TO 250 MW</p>
<p>The Indian government plans to abolish the need for approval by the Central Electricity Authority of power projects of up to 250 megawatt capacity or investments of up to 10 billion rupees. Techno-economic clearance of the Central Electricity Authority would not be any more mandatory for such projects, junior power minister S. Venugopalachari said. The power ministry is preparing a comprehensive energy policy to this effect in consultation with the ministries of finance, power, petroleum and coal. There are plans to provide single window clearance for all power projects to speed up implementation of projects in this sector, the minister said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>GRASIM CAN PLACE UP TO 51 PCT EQUITY WITH FOREIGN INVESTORS</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry has allowed Grasim to place up to 51 percent of its paid-up capital with foreign institutional investors (FIIs). Granting approval to its $125 million global depository receipt (GDR) issue, the government clarified that FII investment in the company should not cross the 51 percent limit. Sources said the company would become yet another blue chip whose majority stake might be owned by foreigners in the event of its GDRs being converted.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>CENTRAL BANK TO TIGHTEN ACCOUNTING GUIDELINES FOR BANKS</p>
<p>Reserve Bank of India (RBI), the central bank, is working on fresh guidelines to tighten the accounting and provisioning norms of commercial banks. It is also working on uniform guidelines to calculate the non-performing assets (NPAs) of banks. Although a relook at the provisioning and accounting norms was expected this year, recent irregularities in Indian Bank and Vijaya Bank prompted the RBI to step up its momentum, sources said.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Financial Express</p>
<p>MAJOR REVAMP AT DCM-DAEWOO ON THE ANVIL</p>
<p>South Korea-based Daewoo plans to restructure DCM-Daewoo Motors Ltd once it is allowed to increase its stake in the joint venture (JV) to 75 percent. Daewoo's Indian partner DCM recently agreed to divest a chunk of its stake in the JV in favour of the former. Daewoo plans to revamp the JV's board of directors by easing out the DCM nominees. All DCM nominees along with the nominee of Toyota Motor Corp, another stake holder, may now resign from the board. The word DCM may also be dropped from the name of the company as well as the car.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>JAPAN EXIM BANK TO FUND HINDUJAS' POWER PLANT</p>
<p>The Japan Exim Bank and the Export Credit Agency of the UK have agreed to finance 75 percent of the 31.5 billion rupee debt component for the Hinduja National Power Corporation's power project. The rest of the fund for 1040 MW coal based thermal power station at Visakhapatnam is to be raised from financial institutions - the Industrial Development Bank of India and SBI Capital Markets Ltd.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business Standard</p>
<p>INVESTMENT NORMS TO BE RECAST FOR PROVIDENT FUNDS</p>
<p>The Union finance ministry may recast the investment norms of provident funds. The new norms are expected to facilitate release of about 100 billion rupees for investment in top-rated debt instruments of financial institutions, banks and public sector undertakings. The ministry's move is aimed at imparting greater flexibility in fund management to provident funds and, thereby ensure better returns to the trusts that manage them. The proposed changes are expected to enhance the returns from the funds to about 14-15 percent from the current rate of 11 percent, sources said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Observer</p>
<p>SMALL INVESTORS TO GET DISCOUNT ON SHARE SELL-OFF</p>
<p>The government plans to sell shares of public sector units (PSUs) this September at discounted prices to domestic small investors in the first tranche of disinvestment in the current fiscal. The finance ministry is waiting for book builders for to fix the final prices for the PSU shares. The move to offer discount to domestic small investors is aimed at creating a wider market for the PSU shares instead of banking on foreign and domestic institutional investors.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>COMMITTEE TO DRAFT NORMS FOR POWER PRODUCERS</p>
<p>The power ministry has set up a committee of financial institutions (FIs) to lay down new norms for payment guarantee to independent power producers. The committee is planning to make it mandatory for the state electricity boards, as buyers of power, to operate escrow accounts with payments from consumers. This is being contemplated following the decision not to offer sovereign counter-gaurantees to any more private power projects.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business Line</p>
<p>RUPEE LOAN FOR DABHOL POWER PROJECT MAY COST MORE</p>
<p>A consortium of Indian lenders to Enron's Dabhol power project is ready to revalidate the rupee loan agreement provided the disbursements are made at the highest end of the prevailing interest rate band. This means the earlier interest rate of 17.5 percent on the rupee loans, worked out in 1994, will now be over 20 percent. Bankers said this was in line with the interest rate being charged by the lenders for all term loans sanctioned to new projects in the last several months.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
