<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6574" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Mother Teresa has cardiac problems, fever - agency.</title>
<headline>Mother Teresa has cardiac problems, fever - agency.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mother Teresa, who founded a network of missions for the poor and the sick in India's most populous city, is being treated for heart problems in a nursing home, the Press Trust of India (PTI) reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The news agency said Mother Teresa, a Nobel Peace Prize Laureate who will be 86 on Tuesday, had been admitted to a nursing home in Calcutta with a fever, but was now being treated for cardiac problems.</p>
<p>PTI quoted a spokesman for the nursing home as saying she had some cardiac problems earlier in the day &quot;which the doctors are attending to on an emergency basis&quot;.</p>
<p>The health of the woman regarded by many as a living saint began to deteriorate in 1989, when she was fitted with a heart pacemaker. In 1991, Mother Teresa was treated at a California hospital for heart disease and bacterial pneumonia.</p>
<p>In May 1993, she fell in Rome and broke three ribs. In August the same year, while in New Delhi to receive yet another award, she developed malaria, complicated by her heart and lung problems.</p>
<p>The wrinkled nun of Albanian descent founded the Missionaries of Charity in Calcutta in 1949. The Roman Catholic religious order now has nearly 3,000 people ministering to the needy, dying and orphaned in the slums of 200 cities.</p>
<p>The work includes the care of nearly 7,000 children in 120 homes and arranging 1,500 adoptions each year. In 1988 nearly four million sick people were treated at her 629 mobile clinics.</p>
<p>PTI said Mother Teresa was now resting but gave no further details.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
