<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6575" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India, United States sign pact on energy sector.</title>
<headline>India, United States sign pact on energy sector.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>India and the United States signed an agreement on Wednesday to work jointly on various projects in the energy sector which could translate into huge American investments in India, officials said.</p>
<p>The agreement, signed after two days of talks between officials of both countries, includes plans to jointly develop policies for private investments in power projects in India's mainly state-controlled energy sector.</p>
<p>&quot;We focussed on certain suggestions made by our private sector,&quot; Dirk Forrister, assistant secretary in the U.S. Department of Energy, leader of the American delegation, told Reuters after a news conference.</p>
<p>The agreement was signed barely a month after India finally cleared a $2.1 billion power project planned by Enron Corporation after a year-long dispute.</p>
<p>Forrister said India has promised the United States faster clearances of power projects to facilitate investments in India's energy sector.</p>
<p>&quot;We will speed up clearances and lay down relevant policies,&quot; India's power secretary P. Abraham told reporters.</p>
<p>Energy officials say India's current installed capacity is 87,000 megawatts per year and it will rise to 142,000 mega watts by 2007.</p>
<p>Abraham said both countries would jointly lay down policies for greater private participation in hydro-electric projects and chalk out procedures to finance small and medium-sized power projects.</p>
<p>A joint advisory group on coal will be formed to accelerate utilisation of coal fly ash, Abraham said.</p>
<p>Officials of both countries will also jointly work on projects related to renewable energy, energy efficiency and reduction of green house gas emissions.</p>
<p>Forrister said the agreement would make it easier for international investors to set up power units in India.</p>
<p>&quot;I think its a very very exciting time. There are so many (potential projects) floating around there. They are all exciting in terms of size and scale,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The power sector is the story of the 90's with respect to Indo-U.S. relations,&quot; Forrister had said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>--Arindam Nag, New Delhi newsroom +91-11-301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I11000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
