<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6580" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian court declines to rescind Rao summons.</title>
<headline>Indian court declines to rescind Rao summons.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indian Supreme Court on Wednesday declined to overturn a lower court order summoning former prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao to appear as a co-accused in a cheating case.</p>
<p>But the court told Rao's lawyer that the former prime minister could ask another lower court magistrate to take up the case and reconsider the summons, which has cast a shadow over his future as head of the embattled Congress party.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court's decision appeared to be a partial setback to Rao's hopes of having the summons quashed, legal experts said.</p>
<p>The court left open the possibility that Rao would manage to have the summons rescinded by a lower court.</p>
<p>Rao, who did not appear during two days of hearings before the Supreme Court, has been exempted from appearing personally at the lower court trial until the Supreme Court decides whether the magistrate was justified in ordering him to testify as a co-accused.</p>
<p>The two-judge bench said it was &quot;not going to upset the order of the Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Prem Kumar summoning Mr Rao at this state. But the former prime minister is not without remedy&quot;.</p>
<p>The United News of India said Kumar, the magistrate who last month summoned Rao to appear as co-accused, had since been promoted, raising the possibility that the former prime minister could approach another magistrate.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court said it would take a final decision after hearing from Rao's counsel, Kapil Sibal, on Thursday morning. Sibal said he would consult Rao about the suggestion that he ask another lower court magistrate to take over the case.</p>
<p>At issue was a case filed by expatriate Indian businessman Lakhubhai Pathak, who alleged Rao and a Hindu guru conspired to cheat him of $100,000 in 1983.</p>
<p>Pathak says he paid the money to guru Chandraswami in a failed attempt to secure a state newsprint contract after Rao, then foreign minister, assured him at a meeting in a New York hotel that his &quot;work would be done&quot;.</p>
<p>Rao says he is innocent of the charge of criminal conspiracy to cheat, and has denied he was in New York on the dates mentioned by Pathak.</p>
<p>Analysts say Rao would probably be forced to relinquish leadership of the demoralised and squabbling Congress party if the court rejected his appeal and he was forced to testify.</p>
<p>The battered Congress party suffered a crushing defeat in April-May general elections, but is still the second largest party in parliament.</p>
<p>Its support is crucial to the survival of Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's 13-party coalition.</p>
<p>Rao's lawyers have argued that their client cannot be named as a co-accused if he was not mentioned in the initial police report.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
