<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6587" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Iran-Pakistan pipeline plan remains uncertain.</title>
<headline>Iran-Pakistan pipeline plan remains uncertain.</headline>
<byline>Raja Asghar</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iranian Oil Minister Gholamreza Aghazadeh returned home on Wednesday after signing a deal with Pakistan for a $1.2 billion refinery, but leaving a multi-billion-dollar gas pipeline plan threatened by U.S. sanctions in the doldrums.</p>
<p>Pakistani officials said Aghazadeh and Pakistani Production Minister Mohammad Asghar signed the long delayed refinery agreement on Tuesday night after several years of talks.</p>
<p>But the two sides seemed to be considering alternative ways to escape the U.S. sanctions that could hit the $3.5 billion to $4 billion project to lay a pipeline to bring Iranian gas to Pakistan and then on to India.</p>
<p>Pakistani officials said Iran and Pakistan would equally share the cost of the 120,000 barrels per day refinery, which is to be set up at Hub, in Baluchistan province, near the southern port city of Karachi. They declined to give further details.</p>
<p>State-run Tehran Radio said the refinery was estimated to cost $1.2 billion, &quot;75 percent of which will be met by international sources and the rest will be paid jointly by the two countries.&quot;</p>
<p>The radio said Iran's equity share in the project would be met by providing technical services and equipment for the refinery which will process Iranian crude.</p>
<p>The deal follows a controversial $23 billion accord last week with Turkey to supply it with Iranian natural gas to the year 2020.</p>
<p>On the gas pipeline, Aghazadeh and Pakistani Petroleum and Natural Resources Minister Anwar Saifullah agreed on Tuesday to &quot;facilitate the undertaking of a detailed feasibility...on fast track approach basis,&quot; a Pakistani government statement said.</p>
<p>They discussed &quot;various options available to implement this mega-project in the shortest possible time&quot; and stressed the need to finalise details speedily so the work could start without any further loss of time, it said.</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton signed a law early this month to penalise non-U.S. firms that invest $40 million or more a year in the oil and gas sectors of either Iran or Libya.</p>
<p>The Pakistani statement quoted Saifullah as saying a joint working committee had done &quot;excellent work&quot; on an alternative proposal, which seemed designed to beat the U.S. sanctions.</p>
<p>He said the proposal envisaged delivery of the Iranian gas at the Iran-Pakistan border &quot;under the exclusive arrangements of the Iranian government.&quot; Pakistan would buy gas &quot;from the point of delivery and make arrangements for its upcountry transmission and sale under its exclusive arrangements.&quot;</p>
<p>Saifullah said Islamabad's &quot;preference was to have the project completed on build, operate and own basis&quot; but it would readily explore all possibilities to make it a reality.</p>
<p>Pakistan and Iran earlier decided to invite bids in July for the pipeline project, but have not done so.</p>
<p>The 1,600-km (1,000-mile) pipeline would carry 1.6 billion cubic feet per day of Iranian gas to Pakistan and India.</p>
<p>U.S. Senator Alfonse D'Amato, an architect of the Iran-Libya Sanctions Act signed by Clinton on August 5, has warned foreign firms against getting involved in the project.</p>
<p>Washington accuses Tehran of sponsoring terrorism and seeking to develop nuclear arms. Iran denies the charges.</p>
<p>Several Western powers and other nations have strongly criticised the unilateral U.S. sanctions against Iran.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
