<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6589" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Asian neighbours regret India's nuclear veto.</title>
<headline>Asian neighbours regret India's nuclear veto.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's Asian neighbours criticised New Delhi's decision to block a global treaty banning nuclear tests and called its stance unrealistic.</p>
<p>&quot;It is highly regrettable that the Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty (CTBT) was not adopted at the Conference on Disarmament in Geneva because of opposition from some countries, including India,&quot; Japanese Foreign Minister Yukihiko Ikeda said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday India, which led opposition to the treaty, prevented the adoption of the pact at the disarmament negotiations and pledged to try to block it being forwarded to the United Nations General Assembly.</p>
<p>New Delhi said it had two main objections to the treaty.</p>
<p>It said the pact would allow the five declared nuclear powers -- Britain, China, France, Russia and the United States -- to retain their nuclear arsenals while the nuclear &quot;have-nots&quot; would be barred from obtaining the weapons.</p>
<p>India also opposed a provision that would require New Delhi, along with the five declared powers and the two other &quot;threshold&quot; states, Israel and Pakistan, to sign the agreement before it could become international law.</p>
<p>But U.S. disarmament negotiator Stephen Ledogar said India was shielding its real motive.</p>
<p>&quot;The real reason is that the current government in New Delhi wants to maintain the Indian nuclear weapon option,&quot; Ledogar said in Geneva on Tuesday.</p>
<p>India exploded a nuclear device in 1974 but says it has not built the bomb. However, the government's longstanding strategic doctrine has been to retain the option to equip itself with nuclear weapons if threatened.</p>
<p>New Zealand said India's professed goal of forcing the nuclear powers to commit to a disarmament timetable was unrealistic. Most countries believe the Geneva talks were never meant to be sweeping negotiations but rather a stepping stone towards eventual disarmament.</p>
<p>&quot;We certainly want to see progress to the goal of eliminating nuclear weapons,&quot; a New Zealand foreign ministry official said in Wellington.</p>
<p>&quot;So we share the same goal, but to seek in this treaty, which is about banning tests, a commitment to a timetable to achieve everything else, is unrealistic.&quot;</p>
<p>The New Zealand official said India's stand-alone stance threatened to scuttle 2-1/2 years of negotiations. &quot;By trying to get everything at once, you put at risk what has been achieved, the progress that's been made,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>New Zealand said it was working with other countries to try to forward the treaty to the U.N. General Assembly where it could be approved by a majority. At the Conference on Disarmament in Geneva, agreement requires a consensus.</p>
<p>&quot;The point has been reached where negotiations won't achieve anything more in Geneva,&quot; the New Zealand official said.</p>
<p>Indonesia joined in the generally muted criticism of India, saying it regretted New Delhi's stance.</p>
<p>&quot;We regret it because Indonesia is already in line with the concept of nuclear neutrality in this (Asia) region. Indonesia supports the Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty,&quot; a foreign ministry official in Jakarta said.</p>
<p>India's arch-foe Pakistan did not mince words, saying India's veto had exposed its &quot;nefarious designs&quot; to pursue nuclear and ballistic missile plans.</p>
<p>Pakistani disarmament ambassador Munir Akram said in a speech in Geneva: &quot;Today, the mask of the 'Smiling Buddha' has been torn off revealing the face of the Goddess of War.&quot;</p>
<p>Akram was referring to India's only nuclear blast in 1974, which was followed by the coded message &quot;the Buddha has smiled&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
