<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6590" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India says Pakistan must grant MFN for free trade.</title>
<headline>India says Pakistan must grant MFN for free trade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan must grant India Most Favoured Nation (MFN) status before a free trade zone can be created in South Asia, Indian Finance Minister P. Chidambaram said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Let Pakistan take a decision on MFN, then we can go forward,&quot; Chidambaram told reporters, adding that all other members of the South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation (SAARC) were keen to move forward towards a free trade zone.</p>
<p>In January, trade ministers of the seven-nation SAARC agreed to accelerate measures to create a regional free trade zone by cutting tariffs across the board.</p>
<p>Chidambaram, who was then India's trade minister, had said that Pakistan had indicated that it would shortly resolve the issue of granting MFN status to India.</p>
<p>Set up a decade ago, SAARC comprises India, Pakistan, Sri Lanka, Bangladesh, Nepal, Bhutan and the Maldives.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said at SAARC meetings India had offered a wide variety of initiatives to move towards the objective of SAFTA (South Asian Free Trade Association).</p>
<p>&quot;The pre-requisite for this is Pakistan giving us MFN,&quot; Chidambaram said.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said Pakistan had refused to offer India MFN, which is an undertaking by two countries to give each other the maximum tariff concessions on their mutual trade which they already grant to other countries.</p>
<p>&quot;We are open. They (Pakistan) are closed. We offer them MFN. They have not yet offered us MFN,&quot; Chidambaram said.</p>
<p>Sidestepping decades of political friction between its two largest members, India and Pakistan, SAARC launched a preferential trading accord last December with a goal of creating a free trade zone by the year 2000.</p>
<p>It granted mutual tariff cuts on 226 items, but members agreed it was not enough.</p>
<p>Chidambaram had in January proposed applying zero or near zero tariffs on primary commodities, which comprise 64 per cent of intra-SAARC trade. India is SAARC's largest member.</p>
<p>The seven-nation region is home to 1.2 billion people and has a combined gross domestic product of $300 billion.</p>
<p>SAARC countries' share of total world trade is not even 1.0 percent. Intra-SAARC trade, at 3.0 percent of its total foreign trade, is low compared with other regional groups, officials said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
