<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6599" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Calcutta shares rise on short-covering.</title>
<headline>Calcutta shares rise on short-covering.</headline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share prices staged a smart recovery to close higher on the Calcutta Stock Exchange on Wednesday on hectic short-covering, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said speculative sellers rushed to cover their positions anticipating prices to move up for technical reasons despite the absence of foreign institutional investors (FIIs) in the market,</p>
<p>Brokers said scrips like Reliance Industries and State Bank of India were expected to attract a stiff backwardation charge of about five rupees per share at close of current accounting period of the exchange on Thursday.</p>
<p>This prevented speculative sellers from forcing fresh sales, the brokers added.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not think that prices can move up very much as most blue-chips will face strong upside resistance,&quot; said a dealer with brokers Jet Age Securities.</p>
<p>He said most blue-chips lacked the momentum to break resistance in the absence of buying interest from foreign funds.</p>
<p>Brokers said most scrips opened much higher than their previous close and moved in a narrow range. Only blue-chips were able to maintain their initial gains, the brokers said.</p>
<p>It was not so much as fresh buying but the retreat of speculative sellers that promoted the market to stabilise at higher levels, they added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
