<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6602" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India call ends down, gilt yields continue to rise.</title>
<headline>India call ends down, gilt yields continue to rise.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian call money rates eased after opening high while gilt yields continued to firm up in moderate trade on Wednesday, dealers said.</p>
<p>Call money ended around 10 percent, down from the day's opening 10.50-10.75 percent, they said. Stray deals were also reported below 10.0 percent, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Call money rates eased on lack of demand,&quot; a dealer at a foreign bank said. Dealers said call money was likely to trade around the same levels for the next week.</p>
<p>&quot;Repos deals struck today were in the region of 10.15 percent,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;This may be an indication of the call money rates for the rest of the reporting fortnight.&quot;</p>
<p>Yields on government securities continued to move up in moderate trade, dealers said. &quot;At the moment, there are no buyers in the market,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;With call looking firm, market participants are unwilling to take positions.&quot;</p>
<p>The 13.50 percent 1997 government of India stock was traded on Wednesday at a yield of 13.45 percent, up from 13.38 percent on Tuesday, dealers said.</p>
<p>Yield on the 13.62 percent 1998 stock moved up marginally to 13.63 percent from 13.60 percent, they said.</p>
<p>Dealers said there were no trades in commercail paper or certificates of deposit on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Rates on inter-corporate deposits remained steady in the 17-19 percent range for top-rated borrowers.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
