<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6604" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India vows to defy pressure over nuclear treaty.</title>
<headline>India vows to defy pressure over nuclear treaty.</headline>
<byline>Nelson Graves</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>India on Wednesday dismissed international criticism of its decision to block a nuclear test ban treaty and vowed to resist pressure to sign the pact.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no question of a change in our stand,&quot; Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda told reporters at an atomic research centre near Bombay. &quot;There is no question of yielding to pressure.&quot;</p>
<p>On Tuesday, India singlehandedly prevented the Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty (CTBT) from being adopted at talks in Geneva.</p>
<p>New Delhi's stance, which effectively blocked 2-1/2 years of negotiations at the Conference on Disarmament, drew widespread but generally muted foreign criticism.</p>
<p>Japan called India's decision highly regrettable, while New Zealand said New Delhi's professed goal of global nuclear disarmament at the current Geneva talks was unrealistic.</p>
<p>Long-time foe Pakistan had the sharpest words, saying New Delhi had exposed &quot;nefarious designs&quot; to pursue nuclear and ballistic missile plans.</p>
<p>India exploded a nuclear device in 1974 but says it has never built the bomb.</p>
<p>However, the South Asian nation's longstanding strategic doctrine, reiterated by the new centre-left government, is to keep the option to build nuclear weapons if threatened.</p>
<p>New Delhi said it opposed the CTBT because it would not commit the five declared nuclear powers -- Britain, China, France, Russia and the United States -- to a timetable for dismantling their arsenals.</p>
<p>India said the nuclear powers would be able to fine-tune their weapons using laboratory techniques, not banned under the pact, while the nuclear &quot;have-nots&quot; would be permanently barred from obtaining the weapons.</p>
<p>Indian political parties quickly rallied behind the government's stance, which polls show was backed by a public that is wary of China and Pakistan's designs.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot afford to subscribe to any goal that is discriminatory, unfair and inimical to national interests,&quot; Deve Gowda said at a ceremony marking the 40th anniversary of Apsara, India's first nuclear reactor at the Bhabha Atomic Research Centre (BARC) near Bombay.</p>
<p>But U.S. disarmament ambassador Stephen Ledogar accused India of insincerity in its arguments against the draft treaty. &quot;The real reason is that the current government in New Delhi wants to maintain the Indian nuclear weapon option,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In Singapore, Indian Foreign Minister Inder Kumar Gujral shrugged off the U.S. criticism.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not going to respond to that,&quot; Gujral told a Foreign Correspondents Association lunch in Singapore. &quot;If we start questioning each other's motives, it may be a very dirty scene. I don't want that.&quot;</p>
<p>Gujral denied India was likely to resume testing its Agni intermediate-range missile after a two-year gap.</p>
<p>Indian officials said they did not think New Delhi's stand-alone stance at the Geneva talks would damage fledgling business ties with the rest of the world which have blossomed since the country launched free-market reforms five years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;I have been assured we don't expect any economic fallout and hope there would not be any economic fallout,&quot; Finance Minister P. Chidambaram told reporters in the Indian capital.</p>
<p>The treaty, which supporters would like to forward to the United Nations General Assembly over India's objections, includes a clause providing for eventual, unspecified measures to encourage countries to ratify the pact.</p>
<p>India has expressed concern that the measures could involve punitive sanctions aimed at forcing it to approve the treaty.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
