<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6625" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India HPCL says tie-up with Oman Oil on.</title>
<headline>India HPCL says tie-up with Oman Oil on.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's state-run refiner Hindustan Petroleum Corporation Ltd (HPCL) said it was proceeding with a proposed joint venture refinery on the west coast in partnership with Oman Oil Company.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no advice from Oman Oil on reconsideration (of the project),&quot; HPCL chairman H.L.Zutshi said when asked about reports in Indian media which said Oman Oil was reviewing its commitment to the joint venture.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as we know, their interest in the refinery continues,&quot; Zutshi said. &quot;They have already subscribed to a portion of their equity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>M.N. Advani, managing director of Hindustan Oman Petroleum Company Ltd, HPCL's joint venture with Oman Oil, told Reuters that land acquisition for the refinery on the western coast was proceeding smoothly.</p>
<p>&quot;We have full support of the Maharashtra government,&quot; he said. The proposed refinery is coming up at Deoghar on the Maharashtra coast.</p>
<p>The refinery will have a capacity to process six million tonnes of crude oil a year.</p>
<p>Zutshi said a preliminary feasibility report on another proposed joint venture refinery in partnership with Saudi Aramco Oil Company has been submitted to the Indian government for approval.</p>
<p>This refinery, also with a capacity to process six million tonnes of crude annually, is to come up in the northern state of Punjab.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
