<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6627" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian lawmaker wants phone licences suspended.</title>
<headline>Indian lawmaker wants phone licences suspended.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A communist lawmaker said on Wednesday that he has asked the Indian government to suspend all telecommunications licences awarded to private firms.</p>
<p>Ashok Mitra of the Communist Party of India-Marxist (CPI-M) told Reuters that he had written to Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda asking that the licences be suspended in view of an investigation into former communications minister Sukh Ram.</p>
<p>The Central Bureau of Investigation (CBI) has filed a corruption case against Sukh Ram, who oversaw India's ambitious telephone privatisation programme until the Congress party was defeated in April/May general elections.</p>
<p>Last week CBI agents recovered more than $1 million in cash during a raid on two of Sukh Ram's homes. A senior Department of Telecommunications civil servant has been arrested in the corruption case.</p>
<p>Sukh Ram remained untraced on Wednesday, five days after the CBI launched the raid on his homes.</p>
<p>Newspapers said Indian authorities had asked the nation's diplomatic missions in Britain and the United States to help find Sukh Ram. While the CBI has filed a corruption case against the former minister, no charges have been brought.</p>
<p>News reports said Sukh Ram may have gone to France or Belgium.</p>
<p>Mitra said his letter asking Deve Gowda to suspend the telecommunications licences was backed by the CPI-M.</p>
<p>Under the privatisation programme, the government has awarded licences to dozens of private joint ventures, involving both Indian and foreign companies, to operate both cellular and basic services.</p>
<p>A fourth round of bidding to grant basic services licences in the remaining zones has not yet been scheduled.</p>
<p>- New Delhi newsroom +91-11 301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
