<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6628" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India eases power project clearance requirement.</title>
<headline>India eases power project clearance requirement.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indian goverment has eased a guideline on private power projects to speed up construction of new plants, newspapers quoted junior Power Minister S. Venugopalachari on Wednesday as saying.</p>
<p>The newspapers quoted Venugopalachari as saying power project investments of up to 10 billion rupees would be exempt from a requirement to obtain authorisation from the Central Electricity Authority (CEA).</p>
<p>Currently all projects involving more than four billion rupees in investment need CEA clearance.</p>
<p>&quot;We have decided to raise the exemption limit for power projects from earlier four billion rupees to 10 billion for Central Electricity Clearance, in the wake of persistent demands from the states for faster clearance of projects,&quot; The Economic Times quoted Venugopalachari as saying.</p>
<p>Power Ministry officials could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>Power plants requiring a 10-billion rupee investment generate about 250 megawatts of electricity. Plants involving four billion rupees produce about 100 megawatts.</p>
<p>The move was expected to speed the construction of several power plants of up to 250 megawatts. But it fell short of the industry's demand for an increase in the clearance exemption for projects generating up to 400 megawatts.</p>
<p>Industry estimates say that India, which has an installed annual capacity of 87,000 megawatts, will have an additional demand of some 142,000 megawatts by 2007.</p>
<p>On Tuesday India said it would try to put 145 private power proposals in a &quot;fast track&quot; category for government approval, along the lines of seven units now in the pipeline.</p>
<p>Indian opened its power sector under an economic reform programme launched in 1991, but private power firms have complained that a cumbersome approval process has slowed the construction of new plants.</p>
<p>- New Delhi +91-11 301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020044">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
