<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6634" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-UK sales figures ease fears of runaway boom.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-UK sales figures ease fears of runaway boom.</headline>
<byline>Rosemary Bennett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>British retail sales suffered a surprise 0.6 percent drop in July, official figures showed on Wednesday, providing evidence that while high streets shops are busy there is no danger of a runaway spending boom.</p>
<p>The news was immediately welcomed by the government which is enjoying a sustained economic upturn with no sign of inflation, and raised the possibility of yet another interest rate cut.</p>
<p>But the opposition Labour Party said the drop in sales showed there was no room for complacency and &quot;demonstrated continuing feelings of insecurity and a lack of confidence&quot;.</p>
<p>The dip in July followed a bumper 1.4 percent rise in June, the Office for National Statistics said, taking the year-on-year growth rate to 2.2 percent.</p>
<p>Economists said the data showed British shoppers are clearly feeling the benefit of cheaper borrowing costs, tax cuts and rising incomes after years of tough pay restraint.</p>
<p>The Treasury said sales were &quot;on an upward trend&quot;, but the figures confounded City economists who had expected a small rise.</p>
<p>&quot;The figures will help to ease fears of a return to a 1980s -style consumer boom and will provide useful ammunition for Chancellor Clarke in the interest rate rebate,&quot; said Jonathan Loynes, UK economist at HSBC Markets.</p>
<p>British shares hit new highs this week as data underlined sturdy growth. The Financial Times index of 100 leading shares stood at 3884.9 points in afternoon European trade, just below its new trading high hit on Wednesday of 3894.4.</p>
<p>Analysts said the retail sales data will also help the government cut the cost of borrowing again in the run up to the general election, due to be held by next May.</p>
<p>British voters are particularly sensitive to the cost of borrowing as two-thirds of households own their homes.</p>
<p>The government is eager to restore a strong sense of national wellbeing, or the &quot;feel-good factor', and knows one more rate cut will give the economy an extra push.</p>
<p>Recent data has shown the government is leading a charmed existence with house prices and consumer spending on the up, but inflationary pressures domant.</p>
<p>High spending on expensive household items in particular, up 3.8 percent in the year to July, suggested voters are feeling more confident about the future, largely thanks to higher real incomes as tax and interest rate cuts hit home.</p>
<p>However, the ruling Conservatives are still trailing opposition Labour by over 20 points in the opinion polls and Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke may be under pressure to cut rates one more time.</p>
<p>If he does, he risks a full blown argument with the central bank. The two men clashed in June when rates were cut by a quarter-point to 5.75 percent, with the Bank warning that strong consumer spending may mean inflation picks up next year.</p>
<p>Some analysts said a rate cut on the back of one month's fall in shop sales would be a risky strategy and Clarke could come under pressure for a politically-unpopular rate rise before the election.</p>
<p>&quot;We are inclined to view the monthly drop in retail sales as an aberration,&quot; said Alex Garrard, UK economist at UBS.</p>
<p>&quot;The drop reflects a rebound from the extraordinary high level of retail activity in June which was somewhat artificially boosted by a weather-related jump in clothing and footwear sales and spending of overseas visitors here to watch the Euro 96 Football Championships.&quot;</p>
<p>And consumer spending will receive another boost if, as expected, the government cuts income tax again in the November budget, the last chance it has to prove its tax-cutting credentials before the polls.</p>
<p>This, on top of more cash handouts from building societies turning into banks, would mean disposable income will continue climbing next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
