<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6636" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British detective helping in Belgian sex case. [CORRECTED 12:45 GMT]</title>
<headline>British detective helping in Belgian sex case. [CORRECTED 12:45 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Merissa Marr</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The detective who led the investigation into Britain's &quot;House of Horrors&quot; serial murders will on Wednesday meet Belgian police investigating their country's worst child sex scandal, British police said.</p>
<p>Superintendent John Bennett travelled to Belgium to discuss the case as an international hunt widened for two teenage girls abducted a year ago by convicted child rapist Marc Dutroux.</p>
<p>&quot;At the request of the Belgian police, Superintendent John Bennett of the Goucestershire constabulary will attend a meeting in Belgium on Wednesday,&quot; said a police spokesman in Gloucester in the west of England where Bennett is based. Police could give no further details of the meeting.</p>
<p>Belgian detectives on Tuesday asked Bennett, who dealt with the 19-month investigation into serial killers Rosemary and Fred West, for advice in their search for further possible victims of an organised paedophile ring.</p>
<p>The sight of Belgian police digging for bodies at the weekend evoked memories of scenes at the house of the Wests, where British detectives excavated the remains of the couple's dismembered victims.</p>
<p>The Belgian investigation went international on Tuesday as Belgium grappled with revelations of deaths, abductions and imprisonment of children by paedophile kidnappers. Belgian police have spoken to a number of countries in their efforts to find two teenage girls who were abducted a year ago.</p>
<p>News reports have highlighted the Czech Republic, Germany, the Netherlands and France. Dutch police have now reopened a number of dormant dossiers on missing children.</p>
<p>The West case shares many characteristics the Belgian child-sex scandal in which two children have been found dead, two are missing and two have been rescued.</p>
<p>(Corrects numbers of dead, missing and rescued children)</p>
<p>Fred and Rosemary West sexually abused and killed young girls and women who were then chopped up and buried beneath the cellar, bathroom and garden of a house labelled Britain's &quot;House of Horrors&quot;.</p>
<p>Police became suspicious when they could not trace the Wests' daughter Heather and they dug up the garden in Cromwell Street in Gloucester in 1994.</p>
<p>In similar scenes, Belgian police at the weekend discovered the corpses of two eight-year-old girls thought to have been victims of an organised paedophilia ring who had been buried in a garden.</p>
<p>Convicted paedophile Dutroux and associate Michel Lelievre led police to the corpses on Saturday. The two men were charged on Friday after police rescued two abducted young girls from a house owned by Dutroux. Both girls had been sexually abused.</p>
<p>The murdered eight-year-olds had also been sexually abused, but starved to death and were buried in a garden after being kidnapped in June 1995. Dutroux has denied responsibility for the deaths on the grounds that he was serving a four-month jail sentence for theft at the time.</p>
<p>He has admitted killing accomplice Bernard Weinstein for letting the girls die.</p>
<p>Dutroux has now admitted kidnapping two other teenage girls but their subsequent fate is a mystery.</p>
<p>Against stern warnings from the prosecutor involved and his own mother, Dutroux was released 10 years early in 1992 from a 13-year sentence for multiple rape and child abuse.</p>
<p>Rosemary West continues to protest her innocence. She was found guilty in November 1995 of murdering 10 women. Fred confessed to killing 12 women and girls but hanged himself in prison before he could face trial.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
