<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6641" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Major sparks row by ennobling party adverts guru.</title>
<headline>Major sparks row by ennobling party adverts guru.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister John Major sparked a political row on Wednesday by making Maurice Saatchi, the advertising genius who has helped Britain's Conservative Party to win four successive general elections, a Lord.</p>
<p>The opposition Labour Party was furious because 50-year-old Saatchi is the man behind a controversial poster featuring a picture of its leader Tony Blair with demonic red eyes.</p>
<p>Its anger was increased by the fact that another of the six people Major nominated to sit as Conservatives in the upper House of Lords was a public relations expert who has also advised on this campaign, Peter Selwyn Gummer.</p>
<p>Gummer, brother of Environment Secretary John Gummer, is chairman of a public relations company.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is quite extraordinary,&quot; Labour's environment spokesman Frank Dobson told BBC radio.</p>
<p>&quot;Right in the middle of a row over what everybody...says is the dirtiest election campaign in history the government choose to give peerages to the two people who are putting this dirty, lying campaign together.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The only problem these two people have got when they get to the House of Lords is an argument as to which of them is going to take the title Lord of the Lies,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But defence secretary Michael Portillo accused Dobson of a &quot;disgraceful attack&quot;, saying the two had produced wealth for Britain by running highly successful companies.</p>
<p>He said political parties had for years nominated people to replenish their strength in the House of Lords. &quot;But never as far as I can remember before has one party sought to denigrate the people who have been elevated to this position.&quot;</p>
<p>Saatchi and Gummer were among 14 people - six Conservatives, six Labour members and two others -- whom Queen Elizabeth formally announced on Wednesday she planned to make life peers. The list followed nominations made by party leaders.</p>
<p>Saatchi and his elder brother Charles helped Margaret Thatcher to win power in 1979 when their Saatchi and Saatchi agency produced a poster showing a huge queue of people at an employment exchange under the slogan &quot;Labour isn't working&quot;.</p>
<p>Their &quot;Labour's Tax Bombshell&quot; poster at the 1992 general election was widely credited with scaring enough middle-income voters away from the opposition party to give Major a majority of 21 seats in the lower House of Commons.</p>
<p>Maurice Saatchi was ousted from Saatchi and Saatchi in a shareholder revolt in 1994, and set up his own agency, M&amp;C Saatchi, which the Conservatives almost immediately switched to.</p>
<p>It is now working on a &quot;New Labour, New Danger&quot; campaign designed to convince voters that despite their dropping of traditional socialist dogma, the Conservatives' principal opponents cannot be trusted.</p>
<p>One poster in this campaign shows a picture of Blair with red eyes which critics say portrays him as a demon.</p>
<p>After heavy criticism from church leaders and opposition parties, the Conservatives withdrew this poster, now under investigation by the Advertising Standards Authority watchdog, but reserved the right to use it again.</p>
<p>Nominations for honours have sparked political controversy in Britain for years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
