<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6644" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - Aug 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>-- BSKYB READY FOR 200 NEW CHANNELS</p>
<p>Satellite broadcaster BSkyB which today announced record profits of 257.4 million stg, has revealed that it is on target to launch between 200 and 300 new TV channels in Britain before the end of 1997. During the year the company signed up 900,000 new customers, bringing its total to 5.5 million in Britain and Ireland. For the first the company saw revenue exceed one billion stg. The company believes it has created a foundation from which it will be able to develop digital TV services in Britain.</p>
<p>-- BANKS NEAR ACCORD TO CUT CROSS-BORDER CREDIT RISKS</p>
<p>It is reported that British banks and their Japanese counterparts are close to announcing a deal that will govern the risks accepted by parties involved in the cross-border deposit market. Any such accord as well as helping to reduce costs borne by banks operating in the sector would also help to reinforce the position of London as an international financial centre. It would also help restore confidence in the Japanese market, where doubts have been voiced about the stability of the country's financial system.</p>
<p>-- HALIFAX MARKET SHARE SHRINKS</p>
<p>The Halifax Building Society has revealed that during the first half of the year it saw its share of the UK's mortgage market contract to 3.1 percent from a figure of 12.1 percent in the same period in 1995. Increased competition in the sector was blamed for the decline. During the six months the society achieved pre-tax profits of 649.1 million stg, down on the figure of 656 million stg for the same six months a year earlier.</p>
<p>-- MAURICE SAATCHI AMONG 14 NEW WORKING PEERS</p>
<p>The advertising tycoon behind the 'demonic eyes' poster campaign targeting New Labour, Maurice Saatchi, has been awarded a peerage by John Major, in a move that will cause a fresh storm over the ethics of political patronage and negative electioneering. Further angering the opposition, the Prime Minister has given a second 'working peerage' to another key Tory insider and brother of Environment Secretary Peter Gummer. However, it has also emerged that a key corporate donor to the Labour party, Swraj Paul, chairman of the engineering group Caparo, is also to become a lord.</p>
<p>-- UNIONS ARE 'LOSING APPEAL' FOR YOUNG WORKERS</p>
<p>A survey of attitudes carried out by the independent research institute Global Futures has found that many younger workers are losing their faith in the need for trade union membership, seeing them as marginal to their workplace interests. The poll found that workers were three times more likely to approach a manager with work problems than a trade union representative. The institute has noted that mass industrial action such as took place in Britain in the late 1970's is unlikely to reoccur.</p>
<p>-- FOREIGN BANKS WARN UK OVER OPT-OUT ON SINGLE CURRENCY</p>
<p>Writing to the Treasury, the Foreign Banks and Securities Houses Association has warned that the country's financial sector is being damaged by the continuing equivocal stance being adopted by the government over the planned single European currency. Representing some 180 firms, the association notes that preparations for the advent of the euro are being set back by uncertainty over whether or not the country will opt-out.</p>
<p>-- ROAD BUILDERS DEMAND COMPENSATION</p>
<p>A number of construction companies in Britain are reported to be seeking compensation from the government after road building programs worth some 110 million stg were cancelled only days before tenders were due to be submitted. The Federation of Civil Engineering Contractors is asking for 3 million stg in compensation to be paid to six companies involved and has expressed dismay at the timing of the decision. A similar dispute arose two years ago when a number of major roads projects were also cancelled at the last moment.</p>
<p>-- SCOTTISH COUNCIL SET TO REJECT POWERGEN SCHEME</p>
<p>It appears likely that Scottish officials with North Lanarkshire council will reject an application by PowerGen to develop the region's first gas-fired power station. Such a decision would lead to a public inquiry into the project being established, further delaying the company's plans. Local politicians are concerned that the plant, to be located at Gartoch near Glasgow, would lead to the loss of jobs in the coal mining sector.</p>
<p>-- DELAY IN ELECTRICITY REFORMS ATTACKED</p>
<p>An annual report from the Electricity Consumers Committees, representing consumers in the UK, has called on the government, industry and regulator, to ensure that the 1998 target for the introduction of full competition in the electricity sector is met. The call comes in the wake of a report from the industry which suggested that change be introduced gradually, prompting concern that a delay of 18 months could ensue. The industry is reported to be concerned about the costs involved in preparing for greater competition.</p>
<p>-- HOPES RISE FOR BUNDESBANK RATE CUT</p>
<p>It is reported that in advance of a meeting of the policy-making council of the Bundesbank there are increased hopes that there will be a cut in the country's securities repurchase (repo) rate. Any such reduction would have the effect of easing the pressure under which the French franc has been labouring of late. Interest rate cut hopes have been bolstered by the latest money supply figures from Germany which indicate that there was a slowing in growth during July.</p>
<p>For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
