<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6645" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Aug 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>-- BA PLAYS DOWN RISK OF 'OPEN SKIES' RIFT</p>
<p>British Airways remain confident of gaining regulatory clearance for a tie-up with American Airlines despite a rift between the British and American governments on an 'open skies' agreement. Chief executive of British Airways, Robert Ayling told a National Aviation Press Club lunch in Sydney that he was optimistic about the two governments settling differences. Shares in BA dropped 8p to 530p yesterday amid fears that the link-up with American could collapse.</p>
<p>-- THISTLE TO BEAR FRUITS FOR PEEL</p>
<p>The chief executive of Thistle Hotels, Robert Peel, is expected to make a profit of several millions pounds from exercising options granted after his Mount Charlotte hotel group was taken over six years ago by Brierley Investments. Thistle Hotels which formally unveiled its plans for an October flotation yesterday, is likely to be valued at between 1.0 and 1.5 billion stg.</p>
<p>-- TAKARE TRIMS NEW BUILDING TO FOCUS ON NURSING CARE</p>
<p>Britain's largest nursing home group, Takare, is to concentrate on premium-priced residential care, which it hopes to buy from other operators. This is an about-turn for Takare, whose previous strategy was to build low cost purpose-built nursing homes, and follows recurrent crises in local authority funding of residential care and a period of prolonged weakness in Takare's share price.</p>
<p>THE TIMES</p>
<p>-- INCENTIVES COST HALIFAX 300 MILLION POUNDS</p>
<p>Two years of discounted home loans and cash-back offers to attract borrowers has cost the Halifax Building Society nearly 300 million stg. They reported half year profits of 649.1 million stg, basically unchanged from the previous half year. Britain's largest mortgage lender said that although it had chosen not to compete aggressively in the housing market this year, special deals had taken 81 million stg off its bottom-line profits.</p>
<p>-- BSKYB HITS NEW HEIGHTS WITH PROFITS LEAP OF 66 PERCENT</p>
<p>The satellite television company, British Sky Broadcasting Group, reported a record 66 percent increase in full-year profits to 257 million stg yesterday. With total subscribers to BSkyB up 16 percent to 5.5 million and overall turnover increased 30 percent to just over one billion stg.</p>
<p>-- ORANGE STAYS BUOYANT DESPITE PLUNGING DEEPER INTO THE RED</p>
<p>Despite reporting first-half losses of 125 million stg, Orange, the mobile phone company, insisted yesterday that its industry remains in robust health. Confusion over complex pricing tariffs was blamed for the apparent slowdown in the rate of growth of the mobile phone industry.  </p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>-- LIFFE MAN IS BORROWED TO FOIL COPPER SCANDAL</p>
<p>The London Metal Exchange, has hired John Foyle, deputy chief executive of the London International Financial Futures and Options Exchange (LIFFE), to help it through the next six months. His secondment will coincide with an investigation by the Securities and Investments board after the Exchange was shaken by scandals in the copper market. The investigation may propose wide ranging reforms of the world's premier metal market and should be completed by Christmas.</p>
<p>-- BRITONS STRESSED FROM OVERWORK</p>
<p>Britons are being afflicted at work by extra hours, heavier workloads and greater responsibilities, without any extra pay. A survey published yesterday by Global Futures in London entitled Working Lives in the 1990s, suggests that stress, the complaint most often associated with the 1990s, is no more than a mask for more traditional problems.</p>
<p>-- CHINA OUSTS JAPAN AS US DEFICIT FOE</p>
<p>The American trade deficit with China last month surpassed the traditional deficit with Japan. This benchmark has been hailed over the past year as evidence that President Clinton's market-opening policy was working, but the White House was immediately confronted with a new problem with China, whose trade surpluses show little sign of slowing their breakneck growth.</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>-- SHARES SOAR AS LENDERS SIGNAL HOUSE MARKET BOOM</p>
<p>Share prices soared yesterday to another record high. By the end of trade yesterday the FT-SE 100 index closed 19.5 points, or 0.5 percent higher, at 3883.2. Traders believe the increase was based on high hopes for a continuing housing market boom and the regular monthly survey from the Building Societies Association showed that net mortgage lending in July was up 7.0 percent  on the previous month at 1.2 billion stg.</p>
<p>-- CONSUMERS CALL FOR POWER INVESTIGATION</p>
<p>A full-scale investigation into the operation of the power generation market by the Monopolies and Mergers Commission was called for yesterday by Electricity consumers' groups. The prices levied by generators was attacked by the Chairman's Group of Electricity Consumers' Committees, who also said National Power and PowerGen, should be broken up, as they are not passing on lower costs to consumers.</p>
<p>-- ACTIVE IMAGING'S SHARES PLUMMET BELOW PLACING</p>
<p>The high tech group, Active Imaging, who were floated on the Alternative Investment Market in April, warned yesterday that results would be short of market expectations and then saw its shares dive below the placing price. The resignation of its managing director was also announced. The price fell 18p to 110p, which compares with the 112p flotation.</p>
<p>--For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC</p>
<p>+44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
