<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6648" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Firm trend continues on UK grain futures market.</title>
<headline>Firm trend continues on UK grain futures market.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>UK grain futu their up-swing during Wednesday's session with prices supported mainly by short covering.</p>
<p>Traders said the market had been sold short recently and now people were trying to get cover on their books. &quot;The touble is a lot the sellers have disappeared,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The stop-go harvest was another factor underpinning prices.</p>
<p>&quot;The harvest is coming in slower this year giving farmers time to store it, unlike the last couple of years when the weather has been hot and dry and the market was faced a lot of grain all at once,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>However, some traders said prices could tumble again next week if the weather is good over the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;If the (UK) Bank holiday weekend is dry the market could fall sharply on Tuesday when faced with three days' grain,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Wheat futures closed 0.90 to 1.30 stg up after trading 519 lots while barley was 1.25 to 0.60 stg higher on a turnover of 128 lots.</p>
<p>Amsterdam milling wheat futures were mixed with closing values one mark down to three marks higher on a turnover of seven lots.</p>
<p>Trade was slow on the UK fob market with one 3,000-tonne load reported traded on the east coast at 109 stg a tonne for August.</p>
<p>Delivered trade was mainly for spot material with feed wheat fetching up to 107 stg in East Anglia, 109 stg in Liverpool and 106.50 stg on the south coast.</p>
<p>&quot;You can't find anyone willing to sell forwards while futures are going up,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>-- Jim Ballantyne, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8062</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
