<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6649" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: North Sea crudes slide as refiners trim runs.</title>
<headline>North Sea crudes slide as refiners trim runs.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea crudes slid on Wednesday as a handful of European refiners cut throughputs in response to poor margins and benchmark Dated Brent was pulled lower by a swaps-related deal, trading sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's looking a lot weaker today. There seem to be real run cuts and not just talk of them,&quot; said a North Sea producer.</p>
<p>An end-August Dated Brent cargo moved at a discount of 13 cents to Sept Brent paper in what traders described as a deal designed to benefit the seller's Contracts-for-Difference (CFDs) position.  </p>
<p>Sept Brent barrels fetched Sept flat early on Wednesday. One Brent cargo, loading Sept 5-7, was due to turn wet.</p>
<p>Other grades were also under pressure from reduced refinery demand. Refineries in France, Britain and Italy have already cut back crude throughputs, traders said.</p>
<p>A French oil company sold a Sept 17 cargo of Norwegian Ekofisk to a British refiner for about Dated Brent +37/+38 cents, down from trade last Thursday at Dated Brent +45 cents.</p>
<p>Oseberg and Statfjord cargoes were also said to have moved at lower prices but exact pricing details could not be confirmed.  </p>
<p>Brent intermonth paper spreads were steady after slipping a couple of cents in early talk, with Sep/Oct at +45/+48 cents and Oct/Nov at +38/+42 cents.</p>
<p>Next week's dates were also unchanged from early talk with Aug 26-30 valued at Oct Brent +27/+31 cents.</p>
<p>Demand for West African crudes perked up with barrels moving both to the U.S. and the East late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A second decade September VLCC of Bonny Light/Medium and Odudu moved to Korea, traders said. All the Bonny Light/Medium cargoes in September were now sold and the grades were valued at Dated Brent +50-53/25 cents, they added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
