<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6658" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: OPTIONS - Bund volatility stable after slight rise.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - Bund volatility stable after slight rise.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Implied volatility on Bund options traded on LIFFE stabilised after rising slightly on Wednesday in the run-up to Thursday's Bundesbank council meeting, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Volatility is pretty stable though it increased a little from yesterday,&quot; said one German trader in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>He said implied volatility levels on October, November and December contracts were all up by 10 basis points and that they now stood respectively at 4.6, 4.9 and 5.1 percent.</p>
<p>A French broker said the December contract was especially well bid ahead of the Wednesday's German Ifo business climate index for July, which came in at 94.1, up from 90.4 in June. The market had forecast only a small rise.</p>
<p>&quot;The FOMC meeting, German money supply and Ifo sent the market down through various levels which had the effect of making the market makers keep their offers high,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) on Tuesday left interest rates unchanged but the move was widely expected. Earlier this week, German M3 growth showed a fall but was not as low as some had speculated.</p>
<p>The French broker said the market was now in two minds whether the Bundesbank would cut its repo rate from 3.30 percent. He personally thought it would not.</p>
<p>At 1409 GMT, December Bund futures were at 96.60, down 0.57 from the prior close.</p>
<p>&quot;Volatility has firmed up in the last 24 hours but this morning it has come a litte bit off the top,&quot; said the French broker.</p>
<p>Volume was better than it had been but was still &quot;not brilliant&quot;. He said the Bundesbank meeting unusually coincided with the expiry of the September Bund option contract.</p>
<p>&quot;People are buying the gearing stocks which are the 1998 calls and puts,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The German bank trader said the October and December contracts were attracting most interest in a market which had become &quot;a bit nervous&quot; on Wednesday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;With current trading behaviour and overall market direction, I would still say investors should have an eye on looking for coverage and selling October calls.&quot;</p>
<p>--Steve Nisbet, International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6784</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
