<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6660" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Analysts offer mixed advice to Brit Gas.</title>
<headline>Analysts offer mixed advice to Brit Gas.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The jury is still out among analysts whether British Gas should reject or accept the final Ofgas proposals for a new TransCo pricing regime.</p>
<p>Those in favour of accepting argue the utility should forget about regulation for the moment and devote its energy to fighting increased competition and prepare for its planned split-up.</p>
<p>&quot;Following the easing of the Ofgas proposals the British Gas board should accept them at the earliest possibility and get on with their business,&quot; said Irene Himona at SG Strauss Turnbull.  </p>
<p>But BZW's Daniel Martin said British Gas should not give in as it has good reasons to believe it would find the Monopolies and Merger Commission (MMC) on its side.</p>
<p>The MMC will vet the Ofgas proposals if British Gas deems them unacceptable. British Gas has until October 7 to decide.</p>
<p>&quot;I advice them (British Gas) to reject,&quot; said Martin.</p>
<p>Ofgas is propoing that TransCo cut its charges to gas suppliers by 20 percent in 1997 and by 2.5 percent in the following four years.</p>
<p>The watchdog had initially demanded a one-off price cut of 20 to 28 percent and a drop of five percent in subsequent years.  </p>
<p>Ofgas arrived at its proposals by employing a new method, assuming adjusted depreciation rather than full depreciation of TransCo's assets.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no precedent for that. It is a new thing and no other regulator has ever tried that. It is worth a try at the MMC,&quot; said Martin.</p>
<p>British Gas said earlier it wanted further talks with Ofgas, but director general Clare Spottiswoode said only details were still open for negotiation.</p>
<p>She said she had taken a slightly more lenient stance in her final proposals after having received new data from British Gas.  </p>
<p>Another reason to soften the proposals was to prevent accusations that she aimed to mend any false generosity in the past.</p>
<p>Analysts, however, agreed that the final review had remained harsh overall, probably forcing British Gas to trim its 1997 dividend to around 10 pence from 14.50 pence in 1995. Some analysts predict a cut in the 1996 interim pay-out.</p>
<p>-- Hans de Jongh, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
