<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6661" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Br Gas, Ofgas relationship was always rocky.</title>
<headline>Br Gas, Ofgas relationship was always rocky.</headline>
<byline>Hans de Jongh</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ever since British Gas Plc was privatised in 1986 it has been under the microscope of industry regulator Ofgas, whose aim is to turn the former state monopoly into a lean and mean company and protect consumers.</p>
<p>Currently, Ofgas is not only reviewing the pipeline charges of British Gas' unit TransCo, but it is also taking a look at the utility's prices in the domestic market.</p>
<p>Besides Ofgas, the Office of Fair Trading and the Monopolies and Merger Commission have also helped shape the operational framework under which British Gas has faced increased competition, first in the industrial market and now in part of the domestic market too.</p>
<p>Here is a list of their involvement since British Gas was privatised:</p>
<p>1986: Privatisation of British Gas, the world's largest integrated gas company and monopoly supplier of gas in Britain at 135 pence per share.</p>
<p>1987: Annual rises in British Gas' transport and storage costs are capped by retail price inflation minus two percentage points (RPI-2).</p>
<p>1988: First Monopolies and Mergers Commission inquiry calls for greater competition, specifically to industrial customers, and transparent pricing on the shipment of gas.</p>
<p>April 1991: British Gas accepts Ofgas proposals for a new and tougher tariff formula: RPI-5.</p>
<p>March 1992: British Gas gives undertakings to the OFT to give up all but 40 per cent of the market to supply gas to industrial customers by 1995, to establish a separate gas transportation and storage section with separate accounts and to develop transparent pricing for transportation which does not discriminate against other users of its pipelines.</p>
<p>July 1992: Competition in the industrial market increased to customers using more than 2,500 therms a year. Previous threshold was 25,000.</p>
<p>July 1992: Second involvement of the MMC as Ofgas asks it to examine the transportation and storage of gas and decide whether BG's pipeline monopoly is against the public interest.</p>
<p>Michael Heseltine, Trade and Industry Secretary, orders the MMC to make a comprehensive review of the gas industry, asking it to report on the transportation and storage of gas in line with the Ofgas referral, and on the supply of gas to larger industrial users as well as domestic customers.</p>
<p>August 1992: Ofgas asks the MMC to also investigate the fixing of prices for domestic and small commercial users.</p>
<p>August 1993: Publication of two reports on the gas industry relating to the references to the MMC. The MMC recommends the introduction of full competition by 2002 and the divestment of the gas trading business.</p>
<p>December 1993: Government announces there is no obligation to divest and says domestic competition should be introduced in 1996-98.</p>
<p>April 1994: RPI-4 tariff formula takes effect for gas prices in the market below 2,500 therms per year, implementing MMC recommendations.</p>
<p>October 1994: New transportation charging methodology takes effect under the RPI-5 formula.</p>
<p>January 1995: The Department of Trade and Industry and Ofgas release a consultation documents on pilot areas for domestic competition.</p>
<p>April 1996: Pilot project for domestic competition starts in south west of England.</p>
<p>May 1996: Ofgas releases initial proposals for a new transportation charge formula.</p>
<p>June 1996: Ofgas releases initial proposals for a new domestic gas price formula, suggesting RPI-5 instead of RPI-4.</p>
<p>August 1996: Ofgas releases final proposals for transport charge formula. It wants a one-off 20 percent cut in 1997 and a price cap of RPI-5 from 1998 to 2001. A third MMC inquiry will follow if British Gas does not reach agreement with Ofgas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
