<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6670" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British royal revolution puts spotlight on cash.</title>
<headline>British royal revolution puts spotlight on cash.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Reaney</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>As Queen Elizabeth ponders changes to Britain's 1,000-year old monarchy including renunciation of state subsidies in exchange for a return of ancient estates, the spotlight is focused on the royal family's complicated finances.</p>
<p>Confusion has always surrounded the wealth of Britain's 70-year-old queen, one of the world's richest women, who is worth an estimated 158 million pounds ($244 million) according to Business Age Books.</p>
<p>But a Buckingham Palace spokeswoman said on Tuesday that the figure, modest by some estimates, is still grossly exaggerated.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as the queen's private monies are concerned an estimate is never given. People like Business Age tend to include inalienable items -- palaces and jewels -- which are not the queen's to sell,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Last year the queen received 8.6 million pounds ($13.4 million) in state subidies from the Civil List to meet her expenses as monarch and to cover the allowances of other family members.</p>
<p>In addition she received a grant-in-aid for the upkeep of the royal palaces totalling 20.5 million pounds ($31.7 million).</p>
<p>Travel costs and maintenance of the royal yacht and aircraft of the Queen's Flight boosted the overall public cost of keeping the royal family to at least 60 million pounds a year.</p>
<p>As private income, she also netted an additional 5.3 million pounds from The Privy Purse which gets its funding from the Duchy of Lancaster, an estate owned by the queen which has 50,000 acres (20,000 hectares) of land and commercial property in London, as well as an investment portfolio.</p>
<p>Since 1992, to placate critics of her wealth and the high-spending habits of some members of the royal family, the queen has paid tax on her personal income -- the revenue fromn the Duchy of Lancaster and from other assets.</p>
<p>Buckingham Palace has confirmed that the queen, Prince Charles and other royal family members are part of a strategic committee looking at ways of updating and improving the monarchy, tarnished by series of royal scandals and divorces.</p>
<p>One option they are reported to be considering is scrapping the Civil List and instead allowing the monarch income from the Crown Estate.</p>
<p>The estate, comprising land in England, Scotland, Wales and lucrative areas of London, was surrendered to the government by George III in 1760 in exchange for a fixed annual income.</p>
<p>With profits of the Crown Estate at 94.6 million pounds last year, the queen stands to profit from the deal and would no longer be at the mercy of members of parliament who must approve the Civil List each year.</p>
<p>But Phillip Hall, an expert on royal finances and author of &quot;Royal Fortune: Tax, Money and the Monarchy&quot;, said the queen has no right to the revenues of the Crown Estate.</p>
<p>&quot;It is unthinkable that any government will restore the Crown Estate to the queen or her successor,&quot; he said in a recent commentary.</p>
<p>If the queen and her family are sincere about improving their image and saving money, Hall suggested there are better ways to do it.</p>
<p>&quot;The most straightforward method is to spend less money,&quot; he said. &quot;Each of the monarchies on the continent costs well under half of the deluxe British version...they have fewer relatives living in publicly-funded palaces, less extravagant transport and fewer flunkies.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
