<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6673" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LME copper premium dwindles, but caution over Sept.</title>
<headline>LME copper premium dwindles, but caution over Sept.</headline>
<byline>Martin Hayes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Copper premiums have fallen on the London Metal Exchange (LME) as highly-visible warehouse inventories swell, but there is caution over September dates.</p>
<p>This month copper stocks have risen without interruption in the LME's warehouses, while the cash/threes backwardation has more than halved. But traders are unwilling to call &quot;time' on LME tightness, as August is a slow month industrially and total copper stocks are still very low.</p>
<p>&quot;As we get to the end of August we will see premiums rise and prices will go higher,&quot; said one senior trader.</p>
<p>Since the end of July LME warehouses stocks have grown from 224,100 tonnes to the current 266,000 tonnes, cutting the cash premium over three months from $110 to the current $35/$40.</p>
<p>Analysts were unsure whether the trend reflected fundamental oversupply -- long anticipated after high prices throughout the 1990s encouraged a whole host of low-cost new production.</p>
<p>Or, analysts said, copper may have been lent to the LME during the summer slowdown to take advantage of high premiums.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, end-users looking to book requirements after the seasonal shutdowns said there was reasonable availability for the remainder of this month. But September is a different story.</p>
<p>&quot;It is early days yet, but a lot of people are starting to look around, and there is not that much there,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>On the LME there are several likely tight dates in early September all relating to the massive sell-off seen on the market in June when the extent of the Sumitomo Corp scandal unravelled.</p>
<p>September 5/6 is one hurdle, as this is three months after Sumitomo said it found evidence of unauthorised trading by its former head trader Yasuo Hamanaka. In a $500 price-slide, over one million tonnes of copper was cleared on the LME.</p>
<p>Another sensitive area will be September 12 through to the September &quot;third Wednesday&quot; date (September 18), as this will be three months after Sumitomo announced its $1.8 billion of unauthorised losses, prompting another heavy sell-off.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a lot of short-selling then. Some of those (shorts) will cover, but a lot may be rolled forward. If so, we will have a backwardation for much longer,&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>Outside the LME, the stock picture shows total inventories falling, with levels of some 805,000 tonnes equating to between 3.6 and four weeks consumption, dangerously close to a historically critical level of 3.5 weeks.</p>
<p>There have been reports of up to 100,000 tonnes of copper being held in China's bonded warehouses in Shanghai with the threat of these being sold on to the market.</p>
<p>But traders and analysts are doubtful of this occurring  as China is expected to be a net importer of copper metal and ore during the final quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>And the copper from the new projects and expansions in North and South America and the Far East may take some time to show up in statistics.</p>
<p>&quot;With some of the SX-EW (solvent extraction-electrowon) and start-up metal probably off-grade, it is likely that a lot of the new metal will not be put on warrant, but used to alleviate the likely shortage in scrap,&quot; analyst William Adams of LME trader Rudolf Wolff and Co said.</p>
<p>Although the metal is in the system, sentiment will focus on the visible inventory on the LME, with prices likely to react accordingly, others said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is tightness in September, which could continue through Ocober and even into November,&quot; the senior trader said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom, +44 171 542 8080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
