<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6675" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Mark climbs as markets ponder German rates.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Mark climbs as markets ponder German rates.</headline>
<byline>Abigail Levene</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The mark clawed gains from other European currencies on Wednesday after a robust business climate survey from Germany's influential Ifo institute forced the market to re-examine its predictions of credit easing.</p>
<p>The market had been pricing in a cut of 10 to 15 basis points in the main money market &quot;repo' rate from the Bundesbank at its council meeting on Thursday, but the July Ifo reading of 94.1, far above the forecast 91.0 and June's 90.4, made many think again.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything is looking quite good for the real economy...the Bundesbank won't want to rock the boat by tinkering with the repo this time,&quot; said Ian Amstad, international economist at Bankers Trust in London.</p>
<p>Speculation of a repo reduction had been fuelled by Tuesday's release of key German money supply data which showed M3 growth slowed to 8.6 percent in July from 9.6 in June. But But Wednesday's Ifo data destroyed any consensus among analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;I still stick with a five basis point cut -- though it's a very, very fine decision,&quot; said David Brickman, European economist at Yamaichi International.</p>
<p>Stuart Thomson, chief international economist at Nikko Europe, saw the Bundesbank moving to a variable rate repo after having set fixed 3.3 percent tenders since February.</p>
<p>But &quot;the market will be well aware that such moves will be a token gesture and any movement in the repo rate will be strictly limited,&quot; Thomson said.</p>
<p>That, said analysts, was the key issue. Whatever the Bundesbank decided on Thursday, the market would try to extrapolate the longer-term implications for German interest rates -- and thereby the outlook for the mark, analysts said.</p>
<p>While the currency was seen likely to firm initially if rates stayed put, analysts said its strength should be capped by the feeling that easing is still just a matter of time.</p>
<p>By holding rates steady this time, the Bundesbank would retain the easing weapon. It could be spurred into using if the mark climbed or if the German economy displayed weakness in the second half.</p>
<p>&quot;The chances of the mark moving higher in the autumn are pretty good -- that might force the Bundesbank's hand in getting rates down,&quot; said Amstad at Bankers Trust.</p>
<p>A small reduction on Thursday will nurture hopes of a softly-softly easing approach, with many analysts expecting the repo to ratchet down to 3.0 or even 2.8 percent. That should rein in the mark and boost peripherals as other countries in dire need of easing -- such as France -- follow Germany's lead.</p>
<p>But any hopes of restraining the mighty mark were likely to fly out of the window if a hefty cut emerged this week.</p>
<p>&quot;The danger is that if they do 30 basis points in one go, people will think (the easing cycle) is all over,&quot; said Yamaichi's Brickman.</p>
<p>However, some said the Bundesbank would be most unwilling to sow the idea of higher rates in market minds.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think they're in any mood to indicate to markets that they want to see rates going up,&quot; said Stephen King, deputy chief economist at HSBC James Capel.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Bundesbank wants to prevent excessive mark strength because of its harmful effect on the domestic economy.</p>
<p>A rising mark is also bad news for satellite currencies such as the French franc, currently suffering from market butterflies ahead of the government's 1997 budget proposals.</p>
<p>&quot;The one thing the French do need at the moment is lower interest rates. If the Germans can deliver and help them on that then so much the better,&quot; said Capel's King.</p>
<p>&quot;But I don't think they want to be put in a position where they are seen to be helping out the French in any way and consequently no move tomorrow will be damaging for the franc.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
