<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6681" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK Labour attacks govt over jobs, feelgood factor.</title>
<headline>UK Labour attacks govt over jobs, feelgood factor.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The opposition UK Labour party, thrust on the political defensive by recent economic figures suggesting a return of the feelgood factor, fought back on Wednesday by publishing statistics showing unemployment is still a major problem.</p>
<p>Ian McCartney, Labour's chief employment spokesman, said 3.2 million or 18 percent of Britain's 17.7 million households with adults of working age had no one in paid employment.</p>
<p>McCartney said the figures, compiled by the House of Commons library from the government's own Labour Force Survey, showed why job insecurity continued to plague every area of Britain.  </p>
<p>&quot;Even if you yourself have a job, there is a one in five chance that no one at all is working next door,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>McCartney said in a statement the statistics exposed what he called the &quot;dreadful reality of mass unemployment&quot; that ministers were trying to hide.</p>
<p>&quot;For so many households to have no adult in a job is not only a tragedy for the families concerned, it puts a massive burden on the taxpayer and has worrying long-term consequences for society at large.</p>
<p>&quot;These figures show that Tory policies are cutting off entire families from the world of work. The UK cannot afford the economic and social costs of allowing unemployment to become an inherited way of life,&quot; McCartney said.</p>
<p>Another Labour spokesman, Alistair Darling, said a 0.6 percent drop in July retail sales reported on Wednesday also showed that the Conservatives were unjustified in claiming a return of the feelgood factor.</p>
<p>&quot;These figures show there is no room for complacency on the economy and bear out people's misgivings over the strength of the recovery,&quot; darling, who was promoted last month to the post of shadow Chief Secretary to the Treasury, said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7767</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
