<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6682" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Energy Intensive Users &quot;disappointed&quot; by UK Ofgas.</title>
<headline>Energy Intensive Users &quot;disappointed&quot; by UK Ofgas.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The UK's Energy Intensive Users Group (EIUG) said on Wednesday it was &quot;extremely disappointed&quot; by gas industry regulator Ofgas's final price proposals for British Gas unit TransCo.</p>
<p>&quot;Energy intensive companies need internationally competitive energy prices to maintain their global market position,&quot; said EIUG chairman Ian Blakey in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;They have made an excessive contribution to British Gas' undeserved profitability since privatisation, and this control will continue to allow TransCo to charge over the odds for their monopoly pipeline&quot;.</p>
<p>EIUG combines 10 industry trade federations.</p>
<p>Ofgas published its final price proposals on Wednesday morning. According to Ofgas data, large firms -- defined as those using more than 300,260 therms a year -- now face an average annual gas bill of 567,000 stg.</p>
<p>TransCo's share of this, based on a notional transport route from Bacton in Norfolk to the West Midlands, is 25 percent.</p>
<p>In the first year of price controls, this bill will fall to 539,104 stg, a saving of 27,896 stg, if the Ofgas proposals are accepted. And in the year 2001/2002, the average bill for this group will be 511,835 stg, a saving from current levels of 55,165 stg, according to Ofgas.</p>
<p>While EIUG complains that the proposed cuts are too weak, British Gas argues that they are too draconian.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 6412</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
