<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6684" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Talk of trend to longer Eurodollar debt overblown.</title>
<headline>Talk of trend to longer Eurodollar debt overblown.</headline>
<byline>Aline van Duyn</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top-notch 10-year Eurodollar debt has been selling briskly lately and bankers have been touting this as evidence of a widespread investor move up the curve.</p>
<p>But the strong demand -- noticeable for recent $1.0 billion 10-year global bonds from Canada and the World Bank -- is based on a number of factors such as current asset swaps and does not represent a new trend, some dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;There has not been a sweeping change in demand, but increases are due to a combination of specific situations,&quot; said the head of the Eurobond trading desk at a U.S. bank here.</p>
<p>Canada tapped the 10-year area on Monday, with a bond yielding 29 basis poinnts over comparable Treasuries, via joint lead managers Goldman Sachs, Morgan Stanley and Scotia Capital Markets. That followed a World Bank bond last week through Merrill Lynch and SBC Warburg.</p>
<p>Syndicate officials at these banks have been speaking of the deals as part of a shift towards longer-dated paper.</p>
<p>There has undoubtedly been an extension of the duration of portfolios as U.S. interest rate rises are considered less likely. On Tuesday the Federal Open Market Committee meeting left rates unchanged.</p>
<p>But swap market plays have also contributed by creating synthetic demand for dollar paper, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Selected Asian investors and some others are extending maturities. But the shape of the yield curve has not changed. There is no reason for a sudden rush to 10 years,&quot; the U.S. bank Eurobond trading head said.</p>
<p>Instead, the World Bank and Canada issues also benefited from the rallying Canadian dollar bond market.</p>
<p>&quot;Asset-swapping has gone on,&quot; said another Eurobond trader. &quot;As Canadian bonds rally, swap spread levels create a bid for dollar-based securities from Canadian investors.&quot;</p>
<p>These institutions can only buy Canadian credits or international bonds issued by bodies of which Canada is a member, such as the World Bank, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;A synthetic bid for one part of the fixed-income market is created by swap rates. These are the kinds of factors that are driving the recent deals,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Issuance in the dollar sector has been centred on maturities of five years or less for most of 1996. That sector was considered popular because of market volatility and at the same time there was a dearth of supply elsewhere on the curve.</p>
<p>&quot;Part of the reason why we have seen mostly five-year dollar issuance is because this has been the most attractive area for borrowers from a swap point of view,&quot; said a syndicate manager.</p>
<p>&quot;Usually, 10 years is a more popular part of the curve but the swap market is relatively tight,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Historically tight spreads due to excess liquidity in the banking system -- a classic case of demand exceeding supply -- have made investors reluctant to buy bonds at all, holding onto their cash instead.</p>
<p>&quot;When issuance slows it is not because the market is saturated but it is just hard for investors to rationalise paying the prices asked,&quot; said a European bank syndicate head.</p>
<p>&quot;Cash is available, and (investors) will jump in as soon as there is relative spread widening or rises in absolute yields. There is money to be spent,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7748</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
