<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6697" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Russia MinFins hit by freeze talk, Yeltsin health.</title>
<headline>Russia MinFins hit by freeze talk, Yeltsin health.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian debt prices were hit first by market rumours, since denied, that some MinFin bonds had been frozen and then renewed fears over President Boris Yeltsin's health, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a selloff in Russian debt after the nervousness caused by the MinFin talk,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Renewed fears over Yeltsin's health, after Security Chief Alexander Lebed issued a statement casting doubt over the authenticity of recent presidential orders on Chechnya, also hit prices.</p>
<p>&quot;It raised concerns about a power vacuum in Russia,&quot; said BankAmerica analyst Richard Gray.</p>
<p>Both MinFins and dollar-denominated debt paper were under pressure on Wednesday. MinFins 3 were off 0.375 at 75.875/76.625, MinFin 4 down 0.500 at 48.875/49.250 while MinFins 5 and 7 were down 0.625 at  32/32.625 and 1.125 at 27.250/28.00, respectively.</p>
<p>Dollar-denominated Vnesh paper was off 0.375 at 60.250/60.750 in London trade.</p>
<p>In other debt markets, action in Mexican and Brazilian paper on Wednesday highlighted positive economic prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;On Mexico, we have had some good GDP numbers and the Cetes auction showed yields down by 230 basis points (to 24.33 percent,&quot; said Gray.</p>
<p>This came on the heels of second quarter GDP figures showing 7.2 percent growth.</p>
<p>&quot;The Mexican success story rolls on,&quot; said Gray.</p>
<p>Mexican Pars on Wednesday were up 0.125 at 67.500/67.875.</p>
<p>Brazilian debt was also active with analyts citing improved economic prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;Recently, Brazilian data has been more positive...It points to stronger growth and less inflation. This is good news for Brazil,&quot; added Gray.</p>
<p>Brazil Pars on Wednesday were at 56.750/57.125, whith IDUS paper at 95.750/96.00.</p>
<p>--Julia Meehan, London newsroom +4471 542 2734</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
