<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6705" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Rail union votes against London tube deal.</title>
<headline>Rail union votes against London tube deal.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Members of the Rail, Maritime and Transport union (RMT) have voted by a majority of four to one against a pay and hours deal proposed by management, the union said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The ballot result means that a one-day strike by RMT drivers scheduled for Friday and next Tuesday will still go ahead.  </p>
<p>Aslef, the other union involved in the dispute that has paralysed the London underground railway system with a series of 24-hour strikes in recent months, has also balloted its members, and the results should be known shortly.</p>
<p>RMT officials said 354 members had rejected the deal and 102 had acceptred it. Fifty-one percent of the drivers had voted.</p>
<p>RMT leaders had urged the 900 drivers in their union to reject the deal. Aslef is the bigger of the two unions amongst the tube drivers. The deal would give drivers a 35-hour week in 1998, down from 38.5 hours now, but it would be paid for by an effective cut in pay, with annual wage rises below the rate of inflation over three years.  </p>
<p>The RMT union said its scheduled strikes would go ahead whatever Aslef decides.</p>
<p>&quot;What Aslef decides to do is an independent decision by them,&quot; RMT assistant general secretary Bob Crow told reporters.</p>
<p>Aslef said it would announce the results of its ballot at about 1300 GMT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
