<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6707" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: WORLD BONDS - Europe at risk if Bundesbank sticks.</title>
<headline>WORLD BONDS - Europe at risk if Bundesbank sticks.</headline>
<byline>Kate Kelland</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>European debt markets, pushed and pulled by German economic data this week, are at risk of deeper losses if the Bundesbank fails to cut interest rates at its meeting on Thursday, analysts said.</p>
<p>A key business survey on Wednesday showing an upbeat German economic climate wiped out earlier money supply data showing the opposite. Now analysts say speculation on the fate of the repo rate ahead of Thursday's Bundesbank meeting is at fever pitch.</p>
<p>&quot;It's on a knife edge,&quot; said Adrian Owens, European economist at Julius Baer Investments in London.</p>
<p>&quot;After the M3 data, I though we might get a small cut in the repo rate,&quot; Owens said. &quot;But with the strong Ifo index -- that could be enough to prompt them to hold off.&quot;</p>
<p>The Ifo West German business climate index rose to 94.1 in July -- far above market forecasts for a rise to 91.0 from 90.4 in June. September Bund futures skidded 30 basis points lower.</p>
<p>Huw Roberts, European economist at NatWest Capital Markets in London, said he too thought the Bundesbank would not move on interest rates on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The consensus yesterday was probably 55-to-45 that they would move, but I should think that has probably swung round completely to say that 55-to-45 they won't,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>If the Bundesbank were to be dissuaded from easing monetary policy, analysts said there were more losses ahead in Europe  -- particularly in French and high-yielding debt markets.</p>
<p>Recent weakness in the franc against the mark has left the OAT market already vulnerable, analysts said.</p>
<p>But the Bank of France has had its own dilemma -- whether to ease monetary policy unilaterally -- risking further pressure on the franc but providing a boost to a sluggish economy -- or wait for the Bundesbank to move first.</p>
<p>With a strong mark posing a slight threat to an already shaky German economic recovery and a weak franc undermining France's monetary union prospects, analysts said the Bundesbank will be keenly focused on currency concerns. But its &quot;charity begins at home&quot; remit is unlikely to be contravened.</p>
<p>&quot;They are obviously worried that if the mark strengthens it might derail a recovery -- and at the back of their minds will be France's problems. But the Bundesbank has shown on numerous occasions that domestic considerations come first,&quot; said Owens.</p>
<p>NatWest's Roberts also noted foreign exchange arguments affecting the Bundesbank, but said the council did not seem to the feel the risk of a powerful mark was high enough to warrant looser monetary policy.</p>
<p>If the bank does take this view and holds its repo rate at 3.30 percent on Thursday, Roberts picked out France and Italy as the two debt markets likely to take some pain.</p>
<p>&quot;When there is a crisis in the extrernal prop of weak deutschmark/strong dollar, it always causes problems,&quot; he said. &quot;And Italy and France are the pick of the bunch.&quot;</p>
<p>Within Europe, analysts said core Bunds were likely to outperform other debt markets if the Bundesbank remains on hold.</p>
<p>The spread between 10-year French OATs and Bunds was likely to widen, analysts said, maybe heading into the 20 basis point area in the medium term from its current six basis point level.</p>
<p>&quot;We could probably hit double digits on that spread tomorrow if we get no (repo) move,&quot; said Phyllis Reed, European bond strategist at BZW in London. &quot;Then we'd be looking for a widening to 20/25 basis points in the next few months.&quot;</p>
<p>Reed also said European high-yielders Spain and Italy were hanging in the balance, with the risk of more underperformance if German rates are left unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;A lack of action by the Bundesbank would push those spreads out to 275 basis points for Spain and 350 basis points for Italy,&quot; she said. These yield gaps were 265 and 330 basis points respectively on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Kate Kelland, International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 8682</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
