<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6718" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dollar slips as German rate cut hopes damped.</title>
<headline>Dollar slips as German rate cut hopes damped.</headline>
<byline>Peter Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar edged down against the mark on Wednesday and German stocks suffered after a respected German business climate survey dampened expectations that the Bundesbank would ease credit this week.</p>
<p>The Ifo institute said its West Germany business climate index for July jumped to 94.1 from 90.4 in June -- far exceeding economists' expectations for a figure of around 91.0.</p>
<p>The index had been hotly awaited in financial markets, with many players looking for a weak figure. That would have made it more likely the German central bank would cut its main money market interest rate, the repo, at its regular council meeting on Thursday.</p>
<p>The news boosted the mark against the dollar and also stengthened the German currency against other European currencies. The dollar later steadied at lower levels of around 1.4850 marks, having earlier approached the 1.49 level.</p>
<p>Weaker expectations of a German rate cut also hit the Frankfurt bourse, where the main Dax index lost about 15 points or half a percentage point in early floor trading.</p>
<p>London, Europe's largest bourse, which closed on Tuesday at a record high, rose a few points in lacklustre early trading after British retail trade figures provided Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke with further ammunition if he wants to cut lending rates again.</p>
<p>British retail sales fell 0.6 percent in July after a bumper 1.4 percent rise in June, data from the Office for National Statistics showed.</p>
<p>The blue chip FTSE 100 index ended at a record 3,883.2 points on Tuesday and was further underpinned at its opening as the market breathed a sigh of relief that U.S. monetary authorities refrained from raising U.S. interest rates overnight.</p>
<p>In New York the Dow Industrial Average ended with a 21.82 point gain at 5,721.26.</p>
<p>French shares started lower and fell further after the stronger than expected Ifo survey. Weaker expectations of a German rate cut also dimmed prospects that the Bank of France would trim its own rates, particularly in view of recent French franc weakness.</p>
<p>On the foreign exchanges damage to the dollar/mark was limited by the sentiment that, on balance, the Bundesbank will still opt for a credit easing despite the Ifo survey, and by Tuesday's news of a sharp narrowing of the U.S. trade gap.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar is doing well and holding in,&quot; said David Coleman, chief eocnomist at CIBC Wood Gundy.</p>
<p>&quot;OK, it's not making any progress above 1.49 but you can't expect it to with the Bundesbank overshadowing everything.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said that while any German credit easing would be small in terms of the whole economy, it would have an important psychological impact on the foreign exchange market and be taken as a sign that the Bundesbank wants to take some of the steam out of the mark.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 0930 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.4850 marks and 108.30 yen compared with 1.4884 marks and 108.28 yen at the London close on Tuesday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 0930 GMT</p>
<p>The London FTSE 100 index was up 5.3 at 3888.5</p>
<p>The German Dax index was down 14.41 at 2545.85</p>
<p>The Paris CAC-40 inded was down 12 at 2007.26</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold fixed at $387.45 versus $387.55 at its close in London on Tuesday. Silver was down one cent at $5.22.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
