<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6731" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's SFA expels three, reprimands another.</title>
<headline>UK's SFA expels three, reprimands another.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>British financial markets' regulator the Securities and Futures Authority (SFA) said on Wednesday it had expelled three people and reprimanded and fined another in four unrelated cases.</p>
<p>The SFA, which regulates all the organised markets in London, said it had expelled Robin Sim Jenkins, a former financial controller at the head office of Barclays Stockbrokers Limited in Glasgow, from its register of managers.</p>
<p>The SFA said Jenkins had caused 176,525 stg to be paid by the company into his own accounts and said he was &quot;no longer fit and proper to be SFA registered.&quot;  </p>
<p>Jenkins was also required to pay 1,000 stg towards costs.</p>
<p>It said it also expelled former Bear Stearns International employee Karim Robert Tabet from its register of traders and Simon James Burch form its register of directors.</p>
<p>The SFA said Tabet had entered fictitious trades to conceal losses incurred through unauthorised trading along with other trading irregularities.</p>
<p>He was required to pay 3,000 stg towards costs.</p>
<p>It claimed Burch had attempted to deceive a potential employer through tampering with a dismissal letter on his home computer to conceal the reasons for his departure.</p>
<p>Burch was required to pay 6,500 stg towards costs.</p>
<p>The SFA further reprimanded John Paul Ludlam for irregularities over trading in Belgian shares while he was employed by Salomons between October 1994 and February 16, 1995.</p>
<p>He was fined 5,000 stg and required to pay costs of 4,000 stg.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
