<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6749" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bradford &amp; Bingley new home loans jump 90 pct.</title>
<headline>Bradford &amp; Bingley new home loans jump 90 pct.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Bradford and Bingley Building Society said on Wednesday that new residential mortgage advances leapt almost 90 percent to 1.29 billion stg in the first half of the year compared to the same period last year.</p>
<p>The company said this showed that borrowers were attracted by its new initiatives' package and &quot;were seeking the more competitive rates which mutuality provides&quot;.</p>
<p>The group earlier said that pretax profits in the period had slipped about 17 million stg to 62.7 million stg because of the initiative, which it introduced in March.  </p>
<p>The package gives borrowers and savers better interest rates funded by around one million pounds per week from profits.</p>
<p>&quot;First half performance reflects the society's continuing policy of incorporating the cost of mortgage cashbacks fully into the accounts in the year which they are granted,&quot; the building society said in its results statement.</p>
<p>The Halifax Building Society, Britain's largest mortgage lender, said on Tuesday its usual 20 percent share of the home loans market had slipped as it had avoided getting involved in re-mortgaging, which made up around 30 percent of the market.  </p>
<p>Bradford and Bingley said that despite the fall in profits, reserves had been increased to 888 million stg against 848 million at the end of 1995.</p>
<p>The building society currently offers a mortgage direct rate of 5.99 percent, that it sells over the telephone, which it says is the lowest variable home loan rate available from a bank or building society.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7972</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
