<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6753" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British Gas seen higher after price review.</title>
<headline>British Gas seen higher after price review.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in British Gas Plc are expected to open higher after the publication of the latest price proposals for its transportation arm Transco from industry regulator Ofgas, traders said.</p>
<p>The proposal for a 20 percent reduction in transportation charges in 1997/98 and 2.5 percent thereafter compare with initial proposals for cuts in a range of between 20 and 28 percent in 1997/98 followed by five percent cuts thereafter.  </p>
<p>Ofgas said the proposals could lead to a cut in average domestic gas bills of almost 30 stg in 1997, rising to over 50 stg in 2001.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a bit of a curate's egg. British gas have clearly lost out in year one. However, Spottiswoode has made significant concessions in subsequent years which gives British gas a far better chance of holding their dividend,&quot; said Yamaichi analyst Nigel Hawkins.</p>
<p>In early pre-market trading British Gas shares were 11-1/2p higher at 209-1/2p.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the initial 20 percent cut was as good as could have been expected, with most not having expected any concessions from Ofgas director Clare Spottiswoode.</p>
<p>But on the whole the review was seen as beneficial with the better-than-expected change in the RPI-minus formula for later years slightly outweighing the hefty year one cuts.</p>
<p>&quot;Spottiswoode has moved quite significantly on the RPI-minus number (for) subsequent years and it is a well-enough pitched proposal conceivably to split the British Gas board on how to respond to it,&quot; said Hawkins.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
