<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6757" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Ofgas proposes 20 pct cut in TransCo charges.</title>
<headline>Ofgas proposes 20 pct cut in TransCo charges.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Industry regulator Ofgas on Wednesday proposed that British Gas Plc's pipeline operator TransCo cut its charges to gas suppliers by 20 percent in 1997/98 and by 2.5 percent in the years thereafter.  </p>
<p>The final proposals follow an initial draft released in May when the watchdog said TransCo, which is British Gas biggest moneymaker, should cut charges between by 20 to 28 percent in the year from April 1997, and by five percent thereafter.</p>
<p>Ofgas said on Wednesday that its final proposals could lead to a cut in average UK domestic gas bills of almost 30 stg per year in 1997, rising to to over 50 stg in 2001.</p>
<p>&quot;If the prosals are accepted (by British Gas), TransCo's customers will benefit from substantial price cuts from April 1997 and continuing real price reductions in the following years,&quot; Ofgas director general Clare Spottiswoode said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are confident that these final proposals offer TransCo a realistic target for the next price control period and an appropriate incentive to improve effciency and earn reward,&quot; Spottiswoode said.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope British Gas will accept the proposals,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Spottiswoode dismissed fears that the Ofgas proposals would jeopardise safety. She said that the Health and Safety Executive had found that the assumptions underpinning the proposals would not hit safety.</p>
<p>British Gas will be able to opt for a review of its price control after three or four years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
