<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6762" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Key closing stock market indices, Aug 20.</title>
<headline>Key closing stock market indices, Aug 20.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here is how major stock markets outside the United States ended on Tuesday.</p>
<p>LONDON - Britain's FTSE 100, which sank to its lowest year level a month ago, chalked up a record closing high led by improving sentiment in the retail sector. The blue chip index closed 19.5 points higher at 3,883.2, surpassing the 3,872.9 record level set just last week.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Shares were rangebound in bourse trade, with the highlight of the day a shifting of interest from the chemical sector into utility stocks. The 30-share DAX ended the day down 2.50 points at 2,560.26 points after sticking in a seven-point range. The IBIS-DAX, tracking electronic trading during the day, closed slightly better at 2,562.12 points.</p>
<p>PARIS - Shares extended earlier gains to close over one percent higher, outshining most other European centres, as fresh talk of rate cuts allowed the market to claw back some of its recent chronic underperformance. The blue-chip CAC-40 index closed up 33.05 points or 1.66 percent at 2,019.26.</p>
<p>ZURICH - Shares closed higher in active trade. Dealers said buying from abroad was one of the main factors leading the market higher. The main focus of interest were future Ciba and Sandoz, which plan to merge as pharmaceuticals giant Novartis, as well as CS Holding and Elektrowatt. The broad SPI was up 16.60 to 2,365.68.</p>
<p>TOKYO - Stocks closed slightly higher, after drifting in tight ranges in mostly directionless trade for most of the day. Investors remained on the sidelines, and brokers expected the sluggish trend to continue for a while. The key 225-share Nikkei average ended up 20.60 points or 0.10 percent at 21,127.01.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - A rally in the utilities sector lifted stocks to a higher close, with the Hang Seng index closing above 11,300 points for the first time since March. The index closed 99.03 points higher at 11,312.51. Turnover was HK$3.44 billion compared to HK$3.71 billion on Monday.</p>
<p>SYDNEY - The share market ended just firmer and well off its highs as cautious players cashed in gains ahead of the Federal budget. The All Ordinaries index closed up 3.2 points to 2,264.7 Brokers said few investors were willing to hold courageous positions ahead of the budget, allowing a wave of caution to wash over the market in the afternoon session.</p>
<p>JOHANNESBURG - Industrial shares recouped some losses in afternoon trade on the back of short-covering and bargain hunting while golds ended little changed after taking a mild knock in early trade. At the close, the industrial index ended off its worst level, tumbling 88.4 points to 7,650.4. The gold index inched up 0.4 points to 1,731.2, which left the overall index 75.7 points lower at 6.445.8.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
