<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6763" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - High IQ society celebrates 50th anniversary.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - High IQ society celebrates 50th anniversary.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Reaney</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than 1,000 of some of the most intelligent people from around the world gathered in London this week to mark the 50th anniversary and update the public image of the high-IQ society Mensa.</p>
<p>A three-year old boy, 90-year old pensioner and Oscar- winning actress Geena Davis may seem to have little in common but they are the youngest, oldest and arguably the most famous members of the international organisation.</p>
<p>The private club, which admits only people with intelligence quotas at the genius level of 148 or above, is hosting a series of lectures, tours, trips and a gala dinner to celebrate its founding in Oxford, home of the prestigious British university, a half century ago.</p>
<p>Apart from the week-long festivities in London and the northern city of Manchester, the group will also be trying to show that its members are just ordinary people and not a club of eccentric, stodgy and bespectacled intellectuals.</p>
<p>&quot;It is important that we do show ourselves in the real light,&quot; said Mensa member Bronagh Miskelly who is organising the celebrations.</p>
<p>&quot;Lots of people have pre-conceived ideas that Mensa is about middle-aged men in anoraks sitting around talking about obscure mathematical problems. Mensa isn't about that at all. It is about ordinary people who have joined either to prove something to themselves...or because have discovered they can do the puzzle in the paper.&quot;</p>
<p>The puzzle published in newspapers and magazines was the initial introduction for many of the group's 110,000 members in countries ranging from Britain and the United States, which have the largest memberships, to Hungary, Argentina and the Philippines.</p>
<p>Only after solving it and passing two rigorous IQ tests were they invited to join the group whose members' intelligence is in the top two percent of the general population. For a 30 pound ($46) annual fee members receive a monthly newsletter listing the group's activities and events.</p>
<p>Miskelly likened Mensa (the Latin word for table) to clubs where people share common interests or talents.</p>
<p>&quot;In this case it is people who are good at IQ tests,&quot; she said, disputing claims that the group is elitist.</p>
<p>&quot;One in 50 people is that really elitist? I can't play tennis so a tennis club to me is fairly elitist.&quot;</p>
<p>When Briton Dr Lancelot Lionel Ware, who at 81 is still a member, and Australian Roland Berrill formed Mensa in 1946 to promote contact with people of similar intelligence they had no idea it would grow into an international organisation spanning the globe.</p>
<p>&quot;I found that I got on well with people with high intelligence and I wanted (to start) a club with an objective criteria,&quot; Ware said, adding that Mensa now has members in 100 countries.</p>
<p>&quot;We are a lot of human beings who have something in common.&quot;</p>
<p>Mansa's detractors have described it as a singles club for nerds and a society of eggheads.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a sad place, designed for people with good minds who do not know how to use them,&quot; said a report in Britain's Independent newspaper, adding that &quot;most clever people are clever enough not to need such a club.&quot;</p>
<p>The group weathered a storm of criticism last year after its Los Angeles chapter published a newsletter which appeared to support a master race and suggested that the &quot;mentally infirm&quot; should be &quot;humanely dispatched&quot; and said homeless people &quot;should be done away with, like abandoned kittens.&quot;</p>
<p>The editor of the newsletter was ousted following pressure from American Mensa after members expressed outrage, but not before the group became the butt of jokes on American talk shows.</p>
<p>&quot;Like all organisations it has growing pains and isn't perfect yet,&quot; Ware said.</p>
<p>There have also been complaints that IQ tests which form the basis for Mensa membership measure nothing more than a person's ability to do intelligence tests, a fact that Miskelly and Ware both acknowledged.</p>
<p>&quot;Having a high IQ does not make you a kind or a very competent person nor does having a Rolls Royce engine in your car make you a good driver,&quot; Ware said.</p>
<p>Geena Davis, who won an Academy Award for best supporting actress in 1989 for her performance in &quot;The Accidental Tourist&quot;, said she took the Mensa test on a whim.</p>
<p>Benjamin Woods, at three Mensa's youngest member, already reads bedtime stories to his parents. Both, Mensa says, show the cross-section of its membership.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got to do a lot more to show what Mensa is all about,&quot; said Miskelly. &quot;I think the celebrations help because they enchance the reputation of Mensa. It's about people getting together.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
