<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6766" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: PRESS DIGEST - Canada - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Canada - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are top headlines from selected  Canadian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE GLOBE AND MAIL:</p>
<p>- Take charge, provinces urged: 'We can and we will' shape new national standards on social policy, Ontario Premier Mike Harris says. Alberta Premier Ralph Klein wants to go beyond merely stripping the federal government of control over medicare, suggesting an end to the enforcement of national standards altogether.</p>
<p>- Doctors tiptoe toward reforms. After an impassioned warning from their president that support from doctors for private medicine would help the government destroy medicare, delegates at the Canadian Medical Association conference yesterday took a few cautious steps toward a two-tiered health system.</p>
<p>- Lebed attacks Kremlin; security chief questions decree. In a bizarre new attack on his political enemies, Russian security czar Alexander Lebed has alleged that the Kremlin is controlled by a clique of faceless officials who write their own presidential decrees and sign them with Boris Yeltsin's name.</p>
<p>- Canadian Chief of Defence General Jean Boyle blames his subordinates: 'They lacked moral fibre,' general says of officers who altered Somalia files.</p>
<p>- Blame me for blood scandal, former federal health minister Monique Begin says; appears to waive immunity in letter to the Commission of Inquiry on the Blood System in Canada.</p>
<p>Report on Business Section:</p>
<p>- Talisman Energy bets on North Sea: Calgary company pays over C$100-million for controlling stakes in three offshore oil fields.</p>
<p>- AGF, Citibank team up to offer bank products: Fund's trust unit, bank expected to unveil new service today.</p>
<p>- Belzberg crows about deals: Harrowston's purchases biggest step since First City's fall.</p>
<p>- CAW alters strike plan as battle with GM looms.</p>
<p>THE FINANCIAL POST:</p>
<p>- CIBC to revisit real estate. The bank was burned badly by property deals in the recession, but CIBC Wood Gundy comes back to test the strength of the office market in a C$200 million fund set up with Oxford Properties.</p>
<p>- Canada a hot prospect for foreign water firms. Water companies from Britain, the U.S. and France are streaming into Canada in the hope of benefitting from the fiscal problems of local municipalities.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
