<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6770" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>TUNISIA: Arafat rejects Israel's condition for Hebron pullout.</title>
<headline>Arafat rejects Israel's condition for Hebron pullout.</headline>
<byline>Abdelaziz Barrouhi</byline>
<dateline>TUNIS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat on Wednesday rejected any linkage between an Israeli troop redeployment in the West Bank city of Hebron and stopping PLO activity in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Israel said on Tuesday it would not redeploy the troops until the Palestinian Authority closed PLO offices in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>An Israeli official quoted Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Tuesday as telling a closed-door session of Israel's Foreign Affairs and Defence Committee that there would be no progress until the offices were closed.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Netanyahu) has to abide by what was agreed on, and not add new conditions,&quot; Arafat told reporters in Tunis following talks with President Zine al-Abidine Bin Ali.</p>
<p>&quot;I briefed President Ben Ali on our suffering from Israel's non-commitment to the (peace) deal and on the dangers of the (Jewish) settlement policy,&quot; Arafat said.</p>
<p>Arafat, who left Tunis on Wednesday, also urged Arab states to join efforts to overcome the obstacles facing the peace process between Israel and its Arab neighbours.</p>
<p>&quot;I insisted on the importance of action (to overcome the hurdles), not only by the Palestinians alone, but by all the Arabs,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Senior PLO official Mahmoud Abbas known as Abu Mazen was also quoted as saying on Wednesday: &quot;This logic is unacceptable to us. In fact we reject it completely because the obligations must be fulfilled in time.&quot;</p>
<p>Under a peace accord with the PLO, Israel was due to have redeployed its troops by the end of March in Hebron, the last major Arab West Bank city still under Israeli control.</p>
<p>Israel delayed the redeployment in Hebron after Moslem militants killed 59 people in Israel in a spate of suicide bombings in February and March.</p>
<p>Abu Mazen said the two sides had made preparations to revive the activities of a joint economic committee, including naming heads of the two delegations.</p>
<p>&quot;There is hope to complete other circles. I mean to revive the higher committee and hold summit meetings between Arafat and Netanyahu,&quot; Abu Mazen, secretary of the PLO's executive committee, was quoted as saying by the London-based Arabic newspaper al-Hayat.</p>
<p>But he said the situation was still difficult and uncertain. &quot;What I am sure about is that we are not going to allow things to go backwards,&quot; Abu Mazen said.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's government this month cancelled a new settlement building freeze imposed by the previous Labour Israeli government which made peace deals with the Palestinians.</p>
<p>Israel's Housing Ministry on Tuesday said it was drafting a plan to approve construction of 5,000 new homes in the Palestinian occupied West Bank.</p>
<p>In Algiers, PLO official Farouq Kaddoumi discussed with President Liamine Zeroual the troubled peace process and the &quot;dangers wrought by the latest developments following the Israeli elections,&quot; the official Algerian News Agency APS said.</p>
<p>APS said President Zeroual pledged to Kaddoumi that his North African country would throw its weight behind the Palestinians and rally worldwide support for their cause.</p>
<p>&quot;President Zeroual underlined that Algeria intends not only to support the Palestinian cause but it is also ready to do its utmost in order to mobilise all the countries to back the Palestinians in their just cause&quot;, APS added.</p>
<p>Kaddoumi, who arrived in Algiers on Monday, said Netanyahu's &quot;proposals have no meaning and convey no wish to make peace.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TUNIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TUNIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TUNISIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
