<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6774" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli army raids Palestinian offices.</title>
<headline>Israeli army raids Palestinian offices.</headline>
<dateline>AIZARIYEH, West Bank 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli security forces on Wednesday raided two PLO offices in West Bank villages and Palestinians protested this was against self-rule accords.</p>
<p>But Israeli army spokesman said the offices belonged to Palestinian security forces operating in the area in violation of Israeli-PLO self-rule deals.</p>
<p>&quot;Security forces this morning raided offices that were used by the Palestinian security forces in the villages of Aizariyeh and Abu Dis in Area B...that were operating in contravention to the agreement,&quot; an army spokesman said.</p>
<p>The Palestinian governor of Abu Dis and Aizariyeh, Jamil Othman Nasser, said the Israelis actually raided civilian complaints offices attached to the Palestinian Authority.</p>
<p>Nasser said Israelis searching the offices did not find any weapons or military personnel but seized some files and a computer diskette found in an employee's briefcase.</p>
<p>&quot;The Israelis are in control of overall security in this area. These offices had nothing to do with security. They were simply there to receive complaints that would be handed to us,&quot; Nasser told reporters at his office.</p>
<p>Israel handed over its civil administration headquarters in Abu Dis in January to the Palestinians under the 1995 deal that expanded Palestinian self-rule in the West Bank. The accord gave Palestinians control of civilian affairs in rural areas such as Aizariyeh and Abu Dis but left security responsibility in Israeli hands.</p>
<p>&quot;We consider this a violation of the agreement,&quot; Nasser said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AIZARIYEH, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
