<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6775" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: New efforts to reduce tension in Cyprus. [CORRECTED 15:50 GMT]</title>
<headline>New efforts to reduce tension in Cyprus. [CORRECTED 15:50 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>There were fresh diplomatic efforts to damp down explosive tensions in the divided island of Cyprus on Wednesday with Iran (corrects from Iraq) asked to mediate in the long-standing dispute and Turkey calling for dialogue.</p>
<p>Tehran radio reported that visiting Greek Foreign Minister Theodoros Pangalos asked Iran to mediate.</p>
<p>It said Pangalos made the request during talks in Tehran with Iranian Foreign Minister Ali Akbar Velayati who said Iran was ready to help ease tensions between feuding NATO members Greece and Turkey.</p>
<p>In Ankara, Turkish foreign ministry spokesman Omer Akbel told a news briefing:&quot;The latest incidents in Cyprus show once more that dialogue is necessary between the two sides.&quot;</p>
<p>The potential dangers of the 22-year-old Cyprus problem were underlined last week when Turks beat to death a Greek Cypriot protester inside the U.N. buffer zone dividing the island into Greek Cypriot and Turkish Cypriot areas. Three days later a Greek Cypriot trying to tear down a Turkish flag was shot dead.</p>
<p>Iran's Velayati said during a news conference that &quot;solving the Cyprus problem is on the agenda in talks between Iran and Greece and Iran supports the idea of mediating in order to resolve this dispute,&quot; the radio added.</p>
<p>Iran has recently improved its ties with its neighbour Turkey since the new Islamist Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan came to power. He visited Tehran earlier this month.</p>
<p>Iran and Greece have good ties. They have cooperated to mediate between Bosnia's Moslem-led government and Bosnian Serbs who have close ties with fellow Christian Orthodox Greece.</p>
<p>Turkey's Akbel  said the basic condition for a just and lasting solution in Cyprus was creating an atmosphere of mutual confidence between the Greek and Turkish sides on the island.</p>
<p>Akbel blamed the Greek side for provoking unrest on the island and said Greek Cypriot leader Glafcos Clerides was refusing to meet Turkish Cypriot leader Rauf Denktash.</p>
<p>He said the basic condition for a just and lasting solution in Cyprus was creating an atmosphere of mutual confidence between the Greek and Turkish sides on the island.</p>
<p>&quot;You cannot expect agreement between two communities whose leaders do not meet,&quot; Akbel said.</p>
<p>Cyprus party leaders were reported split over whether Clerides should make a joint statement with Denktash after a five-hour meeting of the National Council on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Cyprus has been divided since Turkish troops invaded in 1974 following a coup engineered by the military junta then ruling Greece.</p>
<p>Only Ankara recognises the self-declared Turkish Republic of Northern Cyprus created in 1983.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
