<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6776" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Iraqi Kurd group says 100 hurt in Iran shelling.</title>
<headline>Iraqi Kurd group says 100 hurt in Iran shelling.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Iraqi Kurdish militia group said on Wednesday that Iranian artillery units have pounded its positions in northern Iraq in support of a rival Kurdish group, killing or wounding around 100 people.</p>
<p>&quot;The Iranian Islamic regime has entered the war on behalf of its (Patriotic Union of Kurdistan) PUK quisling,&quot; the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) said in a statement.  </p>
<p>&quot;This Iranian aggression has caused the death and injury of nearly 100 people and the displacement of tens of families,&quot; the group said. Its statement was faxed to Reuters in Ankara. The PUK was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Fighting between the two Kurdish groups broke out last weekend, shattering a ceasefire brokered by the United States early last year.</p>
<p>The KDP, led by Massoud Barzani, said Iranian forces had been shelling northern Iraq from inside Iran since August 18. It appealed to the Western allies, who protect northern Iraq's Kurds against any attack by Baghdad, to halt the shelling.</p>
<p>A small number of Iranian troops briefly entered northern Iraq last month and killed around 20 members of an Iranian Kurdish group based there.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
