<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6778" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares climb on selective demand.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares climb on selective demand.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish shares rose by 1.47 percent on Wednesday amid selective demand and improved market mood, brokers said.</p>
<p>The IMKB-100 stood at 64,302.67, up 932.98 points from Tuesday. Gains so far this week have totalled 3.12 percent. Daily volume rose to 7.8 trillion lira from Tuesday's 5.0 trillion.</p>
<p>&quot;The market pierced resistance at 63,500 and 64,000 today amid demand for state shares. The market can rise to 65,000 tomorrow but there may be profit-taking sales after that,&quot; said Cenk Akyoldas from Yatirim Finansman.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the buying came in the afternoon because share prices are cheap and there was nothing to spoil market mood,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Brokers said buying in state-sector shares towards the end of the session had spilled over to the rest of the market, dragging the index higher.</p>
<p>They said there was still no fresh cash entry to the market in the lack of fresh expectations or market-moving news but they said cheaper prices after last week's 4.16 percent drop spurred selective activity.</p>
<p>The session's most active shares were those of the utility Cukurova Elektrik which gained 1,000 lira to 70,000. Shares of Aktas Elektrik, also a utility, also gained 15,000 lira to 465,000.</p>
<p>The 85-share industrial index rose by 1.22 percent to 71,185.61 and the 15-share financial index surged by 2.14 percent to 55,623.47.</p>
<p>Of the 217 shares traded, gainers outdid losers by 118 to 45 and 54 shares were stable.</p>
<p>-- Istanbul Newsroom, +90-212-275 0875</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
