<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6780" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>YEMEN: Saudi defence minister to visit Yemen.</title>
<headline>Saudi defence minister to visit Yemen.</headline>
<dateline>SANAA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yemen said on Wednesday Saudi Arabian Defence Minister Prince Sultan will visit Yemen, a sign of improving ties between the two neighbours after years of tension and brief border clashes.</p>
<p>Upon his return from a visit to the kingdom, Yemeni parliamentary speaker Sheikh Abdullah al-Ahmar told Saba news agency that Prince Sultan would come to Sanaa on August 28.</p>
<p>The visit would be the first by a senior official and a key member of the Saudi royal family since ties soured in 1990 when Cuba and Yemen, then members of the United Nations Security Council, were the only two of 15 states to vote against the use of force in the 1990-91 Gulf crisis.</p>
<p>Prince Sultan is one of King Fahd's six full brothers and is also second deputy prime minister.</p>
<p>Wealthy Saudi Arabia, once a crucial financial and political supporter of impoversihed Yemen, cut off all financial aid to Sanaa and expelled hundreds of thousands of Yemeni workers during the crisis over Iraq's occupation of Kuwait.</p>
<p>Tension rose again when Saudi Arabia and some Arab states appeared to back a bid to revive the southern Yemeni state which Sanaa crushed in the 1994 Yemeni civil war.</p>
<p>After months of minor border clashes, Saudi Arabia and Yemen signed a memorandum of understanding in 1995 to settle a 60-year -old dispute over border areas potentially rich in oil and gas.</p>
<p>Ties have been steadily improving since and the two states in July signed a security accord to combat crime, drug smuggling and allow the extradition of suspects.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANAA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YEMEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
