<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6783" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli shares mixed, Teva surges.</title>
<headline>Israeli shares mixed, Teva surges.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli shares closed mixed in dull, thin trading as only a sharp rise in blue chip Teva Pharmaceutical Industries prevented the market from falling, traders said.</p>
<p>The benchmark Mishtanim index of the top 100 shares fell 0.16 points, or 0.09 percent, to 172.15 on an all-share turnover of only 46 million shekels against 58 million on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Maof 25 index gained 0.14 percent to 182.67.</p>
<p>&quot;Trading was mixed and dull today and only Teva's rise prevented the market from falling,&quot; said Doron Tsur at Sahar Securities.</p>
<p>Teva, the most active share, surged 5.0 percent to 112,147 on volume of 4.7 million shekels after its shares traded on Nasdaq rose 5.2 percent on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Many shares were not traded at all and activity was concentrated in very few stocks. The crisis in the bond market continues and there is no end in sight yet,&quot; Tsur added.</p>
<p>Africa Israel Investments rose 5.25 percent to 362,559 following the resignation of its managing director, Shlomo Grofman. He resigned over a disagreement concerning the proposed spin-off of Migdal, Africa's insurance subsidiary.</p>
<p>Traders said Grofman's resignation removes an obstacle to the plan to sell a controlling stake in Migdal to Italian insurer Generali Spa, which will benefit shareholders.</p>
<p>Africa's parent company Bank Leumi rose 1.0 percent to 346.</p>
<p>Discount Investments fell 0.75 percent to 17,072 after it reported that net profit in the second quarter of 1996 rose to 49.7 million shekels from 38.7 million shekels in the same quarter in 1995. During the first half net profit was 101.8 million shekels against 71.1 million shekels in the first six months of 1995.</p>
<p>Discount's parent company IDB Holdings lost 1.25 percent to 1,030.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is very boring and we have simply nothing to do. Total turnover was simply a joke,&quot; said a trader at Leahva Investments.</p>
<p>Other active shares included Tadiran, which lost 0.5 percent to 1,206 on turnover of 3.0 million shekels and its parent company Koor Industries, which fell 1.25 percent to 27,258 on volume of 2.5 million shekels.</p>
<p>- Dan Gerstenfeld, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
