<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6789" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Morocco sells four mines to ONA at $75 mln.</title>
<headline>Morocco sells four mines to ONA at $75 mln.</headline>
<dateline>RABAT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Morocco agreed to sell four mines, including a silver and copper mine, to the country's largest private conglomerate ONA Group for the equivalent of $75 million, Privatisation Minister Abderrahman Saaidi said.</p>
<p>&quot;After we reached an agreement in principle...we decided to sell the four mines to the ONA Group at 648.8 million dirhams,&quot; Saaidi told Reuters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Morocco launched an international tender in March to sell four mines -- silver, copper, fluorite, cobalt -- in one lot at a minimum price of 648.8 million dirhams.</p>
<p>It also offered to sell a foundry and a manganese mine in two separate tenders.</p>
<p>An official statement would be issued as soon as the &quot;commission of transfer&quot; put its stamp on the accord, Saaidi added.</p>
<p>The biggest mine is Societe Metallurgique d'Imiter (SMI), in which the state offered its majority 69 percent holding or 668,380 shares. It valued the stake at a minimum 448.9 million dirhams.</p>
<p>SMI, in southeast Morocco, has a capital of 96.7 million dirhams and produced 234 tonnes of silver in 1994 out of the country's total output of 259 tonnes.</p>
<p>Upline Securities stockbrokers said they had expected the ONA Group, which already has 31 percent of SMI and varying stakes in the other mines, to purchase the four mines.</p>
<p>&quot;ONA's strategy in the mining sector culminated in 1992 when the company started operating the Guemassa mine, one of the world's lowest cost producing zinc mines. It merged all its mining participations in a holding company called Compagnie Miniere du Maroc, prior to the privatisation of the four mines,&quot; Anas Alami, an analyst at Upline Securities, said.</p>
<p>The other mines are copper producer Societe Miniere de Bou-Gaffer (SOMIFER), fluorite mining company Societe Anonyme d'Entreprise Miniere (SAMINE) and cobalt mine companie de Tifnout Tiranimine (CTT).</p>
<p>The state sold 40 percent of CTT, 35 percent of SAMINE and 34 percent of SOMIFER.</p>
<p>The latest available figures for 1994 showed that Morocco produced 36,010 tonnes of copper, of which SOMIFER accounted for 22,932 tonnes, and 85,000 tonnes of fluorite extracted entirely from the SAMINE mine. Manganese production was estimated at at 30,700 tonnes.</p>
<p>The mines were on a list of 114 state enterprises slated for privatisation by end 1998.</p>
<p>($1= 8.6 dirhams)</p>
<p>-- Ali Bouzerda, Rabat newsroom (212-7) 726518</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RABAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
