<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6790" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey may boost exports by $4.5 bln to Asia - PM.</title>
<headline>Turkey may boost exports by $4.5 bln to Asia - PM.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan said on Wednesday Turkey could increase its exports by $4.5 billion through bilateral deals agreed to during his recent 10-day visit to five Asian countries.</p>
<p>Erbakan who returned home late on Tuesday from a tour of Iran, Pakistan, Singapore, Malaysia and Indonesia, said he had agreed to trade deals worth a total $9 billion during his trip.</p>
<p>&quot;If half of that amount is made up of exports, that makes $4.5 billion of exports,&quot; Erbakan told a news conference.</p>
<p>He said Turkey could &quot;easily&quot; raise its exports to $40 billion through similiar trade deals.</p>
<p>Turkey set its 1996 exports target at $25 billion after $21.6 billion last year. It seeks a 1996 the foreign trade deficit of $16 billion, slightly up from $14.1 billion in 1995. But economists feared the deficit could exceed $20 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;This visit has been realised to solve the chronic problem in our foreign trade balance,&quot; Erbakan said.</p>
<p>Turkey signed a $23 billion natural gas deal with Iran and both countries agreed to raise the two-way trade volume to $2.5 billion from $958 million in 1995, Erbakan said.</p>
<p>He said Pakistan and Turkey had also agreed to begin joint projects in defence and production of transport aircraft. Turkey will sell engine and farm tractors to Pakistan, he said.</p>
<p>He said the bilateral trade volume with Pakistan could jump to $1.5 billion from around $100 million last year. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Turkey and Malaysia agreed to cooperate in aviation and the manufacturing of armoured combat vehicles, frigates and submarines, he said. Erbakan said Malaysia's petroleum company Petronas will invest in Turkey, but he gave no details.</p>
<p>He said Malaysia and Turkey would increase trade volume to 1.5 billion from around $300 million last year.</p>
<p>Erbakan said Turkey and Indonesia would cooperate in aviation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
