<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6792" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Africa Israel chief resigns over Migdal sale.</title>
<headline>Africa Israel chief resigns over Migdal sale.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Africa Israel Investments' managing director said in a letter that he was resigning over a disagreement concerning the planned spin-off of Migdal, the conglomerate's insurance subsidiary.</p>
<p>&quot;At an Africa Israel board of directors' meeting held yesterday Bank Leumi said that as the major shareholder it disagreed substantially with me, the managing director, about the spin-off of Migdal from Africa Israel,&quot; Shlomo Grofman wrote in a letter to the acting chairman of Africa Israel.</p>
<p>He said that after this disagreement, he could not continue to perform as managing director of the company and in all his other roles within the group. Grofman is also chairman of Migdal Insurance.</p>
<p>Earlier on Wednesday Africa Israel notified the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange that Grofman had resigned and that the board of directors had accepted his resignation.</p>
<p>Bank Leumi has to reduce its 52 percent stake in Africa to 25 percent by the end of the year to comply with Israeli banking law.</p>
<p>Press reports stated that Grofman favoured selling the Africa Israel stake with Migdal remaining part of it but Leumi believes it could get more money if its sells Migdal, Israel's largest insurance group, separately.</p>
<p>Bank Leumi has signed a letter of intent to sell control of Migdal to Italian insurer Generali Spa, which already owns 27.1 percent of Migdal. Currently, Bank Leumi and Africa Israel together control 68.1 percent of Migdal.</p>
<p>Africa, one of Israel's largest congolomerates, has holdings in the hotel, construction, tourism and real estate sectors as well as insurance.</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
