<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6798" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Creeping inflation seen keeping Egypt's rates high.</title>
<headline>Creeping inflation seen keeping Egypt's rates high.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A gradual increase in the Egyptian inflation rate bodes ill for the government's commitment to cut interest rates, widely seen as an essential element in stimulating the economy, bankers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The cabinet office said on Wednesday that 1996 inflation to the end of June rose to 8.3 percent, from 8.1 percent at the end of May but down from 9.9 percent a year ago.</p>
<p>Inflation hit a 30-year low of 4.9 percent at the end of last November but has since crept up almost every month.</p>
<p>The yield on six-month treasury bills, a benchmark figure, has been moving lower, from 10.835 percent at the end of November to 10.245 percent this week. And businessmen had hoped interest rates would continue to fall.</p>
<p>But a banker said &quot;The inflation is going to keep interest rates up. There isn't much room for cutting them now.&quot;</p>
<p>The treasury could face a major interest-rate decision within the next few weeks if it decides to issue a second batch of five-year and seven-year bonds worth four billion pounds ($1.5 billion), the bankers said.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Mohieddin el-Gharib was quoted last week as saying the bonds would pay interest at 11 percent, but bankers differed on Wednesday on whether this rate would be high enough.</p>
<p>The state-owned Arab Land Bank plans to offer seven-year bonds next month at 1.5 percent below the central bank's discount rate, which now stands at 13.5 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the treasury will have to offer 12 percent if they want to attract all those funds,&quot; one banker said.</p>
<p>But another banker said the government would be reluctant to go above 11 percent for fear of diverting funds from the stocks, which have just hit a 17-month high.</p>
<p>Whatever the treasury decides, the bond issue will probably push up the price of short-term money, bankers said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm concerned that the issue will absorb a lot of funds. Maybe the central bank will cut down on treasury bills, otherwise interbank rates could go up to 11, 12 or 13 percent for a time,&quot; one banker said.</p>
<p>Higher interest rates were also seen boosting the Egyptian pound, which foreign economists already see as overvalued.</p>
<p>-- Jonathan Wright +20 2 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
