<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6799" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Greece asks Iran to mediate in Cyprus crisis.</title>
<headline>Greece asks Iran to mediate in Cyprus crisis.</headline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Visiting Greek Foreign Minister Theodoros Pangalos on Wednesday asked Iran to mediate in the Cyprus crisis to reduce tensions between Greece and Turkey, Tehran radio reported.</p>
<p>It said Pangalos made the request during talks in Tehran with Iranian Foreign Minister Ali Akbar Velayati who said Iran was ready to help ease tensions between Greece and Turkey.</p>
<p>Velayati also said during a news conference that &quot;solving the Cyprus problem is on the agenda in talks between Iran and Greece and Iran supports the idea of mediating in order to resolve this dispute,&quot; the radio added.</p>
<p>Tension between Greece and Turkey has mounted after two Greek Cypriots were killed on the island last week during protests against Turkey's 22-year military presence in northern Cyprus.</p>
<p>Iran has recently improved its ties with its neighbour Turkey since the new Islamist Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan came to power. He visited Tehran earlier this month.</p>
<p>Iran and Greece have good ties. They have cooperated to mediate between Bosnia's Moslem-led government and Bosnian Serbs who have close ties with fellow Christian Orthodox Greece.</p>
<p>Pangalos, who arrived in Tehran on Tuesday, also proposed a meeting between Iran, Greece, Bosnia and Serbia to establish peace and stability in the Balkan region, the radio said.</p>
<p>Velayati agreed that contacts between the four countries had been positive, the radio added.</p>
<p>In Ankara a Turkish foreign ministry spokesman called for dialogue on Cyprus to calm renewed tension on the island.</p>
<p>&quot;The latest incidents in Cyprus show once more that dialogue is necessary between the two sides,&quot; spokesman Omer Akbel told a news briefing.</p>
<p>He said the basic condition for a just and lasting solution in Cyprus was creating an atmosphere of mutual confidence between the Greek and Turkish sides on the island.</p>
<p>Akbel blamed the Greek side for provoking unrest on the island and said Greek Cypriot leader Glafcos Clerides was refusing to meet Turkish Cypriot leader Rauf Denktash.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
