<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6802" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel shekel rises against dollar, falls vs baske.</title>
<headline>Israel shekel rises against dollar, falls vs baske.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Israeli shekel rose slightly against the dollar but weakened against the basket of foreign currencies following the dollar's decline against the mark, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Trading continues to be very quiet and the shekel moved today in a very tight range,&quot; said a dealer at United Mizrahi Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The shekel weakened against the basket following the mark's rise against the dollar abroad. The basket (exchange rate) is now around 6.8 percent below the slope,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The shekel can fluctuate in a trading band of 7.0 percent above or below a slope designed to devalue the Israeli currency at six percent a year against the basket of key currencies.</p>
<p>If the shekel-basket exchange rate reaches the lower trading band the market believes the central bank would intervene by buying foreign currency.</p>
<p>The representative rate for the dollar was 3.1470 against 3.1480 on Tuesday. The basket, composed of the dollar, mark, pound sterling, French franc and yen, closed at 3.5418 shekels against 3.5388 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>On the crosses the shekel traded against the yen at 2.9037 shekels per 100 yen against 2.9164 on Tuesday and against the mark at 2.1215 shekels per mark against 2.1128 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In late afternoon the dollar was trading at 3.1475 shekels.</p>
<p>- Dan Gerstenfeld, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
