<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6807" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: U.N. envoy to Cyprus says received threats.</title>
<headline>U.N. envoy to Cyprus says received threats.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cyprus's top U.N. official said on Wednesday he had received several threats from outraged Greek Cypriots after the death of two protesters during demonstrations against Turkey's occupation of the island's north.</p>
<p>Gustave Feissel, the United Nations secretary-general's permanent representative in the divided island, said the threats were aimed at his personal safety and ...&quot;were not invitations to a birthday party&quot;.</p>
<p>Asked if he took the threats seriously, Feissel told Reuters: &quot;You never know. We have taken extra precautionary security measures at (U.N.) headquarters, some posts along the (green) line and private personal protection for myself.&quot;</p>
<p>He said emotions were &quot;understandably&quot; running high after the death of the two Greek Cypriot protesters last week during demonstrations inside the U.N.-controlled buffer zone.</p>
<p>But Feissel said &quot;flamboyant statements and ridiculous accusations&quot; in the Greek Cypriot press led people into making wrong conclusions.</p>
<p>&quot;People were fed various things in newspapers which were inaccurate about what was said, what the U.N. did or did not do,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Greek Cypriot press highlighted a statement by Feissel in which he blamed the Cypriot police for allowing demonstrators into the buffer zone on August 11, triggering clashes with troops and counter demonstrators on the Turkish Cypriot side.</p>
<p>The press also charged U.N. peacekeepers with standing by while a Greek Cypriot protester -- Tasos Isaac -- was clubbed to death during that protest at Dherinia.</p>
<p>Feissel said the press &quot;took out one sentence&quot; of his statement and ignored his critical comments of the Turkish Cypriot side.</p>
<p>He said a U.N. investigation proved his men &quot;were not standing around looking at the moon but actively involved in trying to save him (Isaac).&quot;</p>
<p>On August 14, a Greek Cypriot man -- Isaac's second cousin -- was shot dead by security forces on the Turkish Cypriot side when trying to take down a Turkish flag.</p>
<p>The buffer zone clashes were the most serious since Turkish forces occupied the northern third of Cyprus in 1974 after a coup in Nicosia engineered by the military then ruling Greece. Turkish Cypriots later proclaimed their own republic, recognised only by Turkey.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
