<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6813" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan relaxes curfew in riot town, arrests go on.</title>
<headline>Jordan relaxes curfew in riot town, arrests go on.</headline>
<byline>Rana Sabbagh</byline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan's army further eased a curfew on Karak on Wednesday allowing free passage into the riot-hit southern town for the first time in four days.</p>
<p>Armoured vehicles continued to patrol Karak, the centre of weekend unrest that shook the kingdom after the government doubled bread prices, and security forces were still rounding up pro-Iraqi activists and other suspects, residents said.</p>
<p>Some government departments and private sector enterprises opened their doors with skeleton staff as life returned to a semblance of normality.</p>
<p>&quot;They told us today we can move freely from seven (0400 GMT) until two (1100 GMT) and we will be given more time in the afternoon,&quot; said Hana Salam, a school teacher from Karak.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot wait until they end it.&quot;</p>
<p>The curfew, imposed late on Saturday after King Hussein vowed an &quot;iron fist&quot; policy to face unrest and sent in army units, allowed people up to four hours to buy food.</p>
<p>&quot;For the first time in three or four days I could come to my work,&quot; said hotel receptionist Mohammad Ramzi who lives near Karak. &quot;Officers at the army checkpoint on the entrance asked me for identity papers, but did not search the car.&quot;</p>
<p>Officials said they will continue a gradual lifting of the curfew before removing it after ensuring law and order.</p>
<p>Karak residents have said the government failed to address their severe economic harship and its heavy-handed use of force could precipitate more trouble once the army leaves.</p>
<p>&quot;We really have to be assured before the curfew is lifted,&quot; one official told Reuters. &quot;So far, citizens have been cooperating and we are responding by relaxing the curfew.&quot;</p>
<p>He said security forces had detained 190 people, including over 100 in Karak, since Friday. Many were released while others will be sent to court for trial, he said.</p>
<p>Karak residents said 300 people had been detained but many had already been freed. They said some were tortured.</p>
<p>An official said arrests included a local reporter, Fouad Hussein, on charges of &quot;direct involvement in the unrest&quot; and three journalists in a pro-Iraqi weekly for violating press and publication laws by &quot;carrying inaccurate and misleading reports&quot; on the riots.</p>
<p>King Hussein has blamed the Jordanian Arab Socialist Baath Party, a pro-Iraqi organisation, for the riots. But the party, which has one deputy in the 80-seat lower house, denied any involvement in unrest it blames on rising poverty.</p>
<p>King Hussein, seeking to show his authority, invited deputies and royally appointed senators from the south to his palace on Wednesday for talks and demanded a meeting with all parliament members on Thursday to help contain the crisis.</p>
<p>He angered many Jordanains on Saturday when he suspended the summer session of parliament, where a majority of deputies opposed the bread price rises and were angered when Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti ignored their views.</p>
<p>Some 23 deputies, including those of the Islamic Action Front (IAF), the single largest party in parliament, have vowed to oust Kabariti. They refused to attend a meeting at the prime ministry with other southern deputies and senators on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Riots began in Karak, famed for its towering Crusader castle, and quickly spread to nearby centres after main noon Moslem prayers. By Saturday night there were clashes in Amman.</p>
<p>The violence was the most serious in Jordan since 1989 when price rises also sparked off riots. The king responded then by sacking his prime minister and starting democratic reforms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
