<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6814" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwaiti convert leaves Kuwait to United States.</title>
<headline>Kuwaiti convert leaves Kuwait to United States.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Kuwaiti convert to Christianity who said he feared for his life after an Islamic court declared him an apostate has gone to the United States despite Kuwaiti guarantees of his safety, residents said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I am in the Unted States, in a place of safety,&quot; Robert Hussein said in a recent telephone call to Reuters in Kuwait from what he said was a location in the United States.</p>
<p>Hussein declined to elaborate on why he had gone to America or say whether he would return to try to overturn the declaration in an appeal due to be heard in September.</p>
<p>Residents in Kuwait on Wednesday confirmed Hussein had left Kuwait on Friday evening and had arrived in the United States.</p>
<p>A Shi'ite Family Court, ruling on a private civil suit brought against Hussein by three Islamist lawyers, declared Hussein an apostate on May 29 in the first such finding by a court in the conservative Gulf Arab state.</p>
<p>Public abandonment is rare in the Arab world.</p>
<p>Hussein, who annnounced his conversion to newspapers a year ago, said the court ruling could be interpreted by Moslems as permission to kill him.</p>
<p>Hussein's interpretation has been greeted with incredulity by officials and lawyers and also by several expatriate Christians who say he is grossly exaggerating the situation.</p>
<p>The Kuwaiti government issued a statement in July guaranteeing Hussein's safety. Hussein said his old Kuwaiti passport was &quot;confiscated&quot; after his conversion but residents said he had just lost it. He has been issued with a new one.</p>
<p>Kuwaitis say Hussein appears bent on fanning prejudice and misunderstanding among Western commentators unfamiliar with the variety of expatriate religious practice in Gulf Ara states.</p>
<p>Unlike neighbouring Saudi Arabia, Kuwait allows Christians to worship publicly in a variety of churches and its constitution guarantees freedom of religious belief.</p>
<p>Kuwait also has a small and long-established Kuwaiti Christian community.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
