<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6815" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Africa Israel chief resigns.</title>
<headline>Africa Israel chief resigns.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The managing director of Africa Israel Investments, Shlomo Grofman, has resigned from his post, the company said in a statement to the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The board of directors has accepted the resignation, the statement said, without giving further details.  </p>
<p>Grofman will continue in his post until September 24. Mordechai Meir will stand in as acting managing director.</p>
<p>Company officials were not immediately available for comment. But it has been widely reported in the press in recent days that Grofman would resign due to his opposition to the proposed spin-off of Migdal, Africa's insurance subsidiary.</p>
<p>Bank Leumi, Africa's parent company, has reached a preliminary agreement to sell control of Migdal to Italian insurer Generali Spa.</p>
<p>Leumi, which has to reduce its 52 percent stake in Africa by the end of the year to comply with Israeli banking law, believes Migdal is worth more sold separately from Africa, newspapers said.</p>
<p>They reported on Wednesday that Grofman had approached Generali and told them they were overpaying for Migdal. Generali's offer valued Migdal at about $1 billion.</p>
<p>Africa, one of Israel's largest conglomerates, has holdings in the hotel, construction, tourism and real estate sectors as well as insurance.</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
