<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6821" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Hydro-Quebec says to produce cobalt 60 at Gentilly.</title>
<headline>Hydro-Quebec says to produce cobalt 60 at Gentilly.</headline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hydro-Quebec said on Wednesday that it agreed with Nordion International Inc, a unit of MDS Health Group Ltd, for the production of cobalt 60 at its Gentilly-2 nuclear power station.</p>
<p>The five-year agreement, which runs from 1997 to 2002, provides for the production of between 15 and 20 million curies of cobalt 60 and will generate millions of dollars a year in revenues for Hydro-Quebec, the Quebec government-owned utility said.</p>
<p>A previous five-year agreement with Nordion (1985-1989) for the production of 18 million curries of cobalt 60 had not been renewed because of an oversupply situation. Cobalt 60 is a radioactive isotope of cobalt 59 that results from the irradiation of cobalt 59 in a nuclear reactor. The production of cobalt 60 has no effect on the output or safety of the reactor, Hydro-Quebec said.</p>
<p>Cobalt 60 is used for treating cancer, sterilizing medical and surgical products, preserving food, combating food-borne illness and decontaminating waste. Nordion supplies more than 80 percent of the global demand for cobalt 60, Hydro-Quebec said.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Montreal bureau (514) 985-2434</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I1610107">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
