<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6851" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RESEARCH ALERT - Goldman lowers Oracle. [CORRECTED 15:40 GMT]</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - Goldman lowers Oracle. [CORRECTED 15:40 GMT]</headline>
<text>
<p>-- Goldman Sachs analyst Rick Sherlund took Oracle Corp off its priority list and moved it down to its recommended list, his office said.  </p>
<p>-- Oracle had been on the brokerage's priority list for approximately one year.</p>
<p>-- In published comments, Sherlund said he had lowered Oracle's rating due to its sharp price appreciation.  </p>
<p>-- The stock closed at 39 Tuesday (corrects from Monday), near its year high of 42-1/8. Oracle shares were trading in the vicinity of 25 when Sherlund added the stock to Goldman's priority list last fall.</p>
<p>-- In his comments, Sherlund said Oracle's quarter ending later this month &quot;appears to be a bit tighter than expected as new sales territories are assigned and quotas are established in Europe,&quot; a change he noted may not have gone smoothly.</p>
<p>-- Stll, he said he believes &quot;a strong end-of-quarter push will likely permit the company to acheive our estimates for the quarter.&quot; The analyst's estimate for the first quarter ending in August stands at $0.17 per share currently.  </p>
<p>-- Sherlund said his rating change reflects the absence of a near-term catalyst for the stock, but he added that he remains very bullish on Oracle's prospects as dominant supplier of database management software and other products.</p>
<p>-- The analyst said he believes there is likely to be an upside to his full year earnings estimates as the seasonally stronger second half results arrive.</p>
<p>-- Sherlund's earnings estimate for the fiscal year ending in May 1997 is $1.25 per share.</p>
<p>-- Oracle stock had fallen 1-1/2 points to 37-1/2 just after the opening of trading Wednesday (corrects from Tuesday).</p>
<p>-- E. Auchard, Wall Street bureau, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
