<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6889" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Minnesota Power to buy balance of ADESA.</title>
<headline>Minnesota Power to buy balance of ADESA.</headline>
<dateline>DULUTH, Minn. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Minnesota Power &amp; Light Co said Wednesday it agreed to acquire a remaining 17 percent minority interest in ADESA, the company's Indianapolis-based auto auction business.</p>
<p>The 17 percent stake will be acquired at undisclosed terms from shareholders, who include managers of ADESA. Minnesota Power acquired an 83 percent stake in ADESA in 1995.</p>
<p>ADESA operates 17 auto auction centers in the U.S. and four in Canada.</p>
<p>Minnesota Power also said James Hallett, 43, ADESA executive vice president and president of ADESA's Canadian operations, has been named president and chief executive officer of ADESA.</p>
<p>Hallett succeeds D. Michael Hockett, former chief executive officer and founder, who is retiring from ADESA and Minnesota Power's board of directors. Larry Wechter, president of ADESA, and a few other executives who had been part of a group that formed ADESA, are also leaving the company, the company said.</p>
<p>Besides ADESA, Minnesota Power's businesses include electric utility operations in Minnesota and Wisconsin, water utilities in Florida and the Carolinas.</p>
<p>-- Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DULUTH, Minn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
