<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6921" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Central Tractor sees higher Q4 results.</title>
<headline>Central Tractor sees higher Q4 results.</headline>
<dateline>DES MOINES, Iowa 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Central Tractor Farm &amp; Country Inc said Wednesday it expects stronger same-store sales, net sales and earnings comparisons in the fiscal fourth quarter compared with a year gao.</p>
<p>&quot;With a higher store count and an increase in farming activity generated by moist ground conditions compared with the drought that affected 1995's fourth quarter, sales and earnings should be substantially higher than last year's relatively weak results,&quot; James McKitrick, president, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>In the year-ago fourth quarter Central Tractor earned $0.03 a share on sales of $56.2 million.</p>
<p>Central Tractor today reported earnings for the fiscal third quarter ended July 27 of $0.36 a share, down from $0.40 a year ago. Sales rose to $86.2 million from $74.4 million.</p>
<p>&quot;We are encouraged by the sales momentum generated in the latter part of the third quarter after a slow start related to unfavorable weather,&quot; McKitrick said.</p>
<p>Central Tractor said its gross margin in the third quarter fell to 29.5 percent from 30.3 percent a year ago due to product mix changes related to weather conditions and the elimination of central product lines.</p>
<p>Selling, general and administrative (SG&amp;A) costs as a percentage of sales increased in the third quarter compared with a year ago due to the cost of opening new stores and the conversion of Big Bear stores.</p>
<p>SG&amp;A expenses in the quarter totaled $18.2 million, up from $15.0 million a year ago.</p>
<p>McKitrick said SG&amp;A as a percentage of sales is expected to moderate in subsequent quarters.</p>
<p>Central Tractor, an agricultural specialty retailer, operates 108 stores in 16 states.</p>
<p>-- Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DES MOINES, Iowa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
