<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6934" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cable modem start-up (At)Home signs content deals.</title>
<headline>Cable modem start-up (At)Home signs content deals.</headline>
<dateline>MOUNTAIN VIEW, Calif. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>(At)Home Corp, a developer of high-speed interactive Internet services via the cable TV infrastructure, said it had signed partnership deals with more than 60 TV, print media and Web content providers.  </p>
<p>(At) Home, with the backing of several top U.S. cable companies and Silicon Valley venture fund Kleiner, Perkins, Caufield &amp; Byers, plans to introduce a proprietary Internet delivery network running over existing cable infrastructure.</p>
<p>The company said it had signed up suppliers of news, sports and entertainment programming, including CNET Inc , CUC International, Wired Ventures Inc, Knight-Ridder Inc, New York Times Co, SportsLine USA Inc, Gannett Co Inc Dow Jones &amp; Co Inc and Softbank Corp's Ziff-Davis.  </p>
<p>&quot;We feel these news services are the harbingers of a new wave of breakthrough offerings on the Internet,&quot; said Charles Moldow, (At)Home's vice president of media developer.</p>
<p>The (At)Home network would connect personal computer users to the Internet using high-speed cable modems running over this network, unlocking the possibilities of a high-speed, graphics-intensive programming delivered via the Internet.</p>
<p>Current modems running at slower speeds are capable of transmitting text and simple graphics, but this method is ill-suited for more data intensive voice, video and graphics.</p>
<p>To date, however, the closely watched Internet technology pioneer has experienced substantial engineering difficulties in attempting to overlay its Internet network on the existing cable infrastructure, resulting in service roll-out delays.</p>
<p>The company now says it plans to introduce its service in selected markets later this year through its three cable service operator partners, Tele-Communications Inc, Comcast Corp and Cox Communications Inc.</p>
<p>-- Eric Auchard, New York Newsdesk, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOUNTAIN VIEW, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
