<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6937" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. stocks seen facing mild profit-taking at open.</title>
<headline>U.S. stocks seen facing mild profit-taking at open.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street stocks are expected to open steady to lower, with the Dow industrials facing mild profit-taking after their recent run-up.</p>
<p>Blue chips are expected to pause for a breather after pushing higher late Tuesday, but analysts do not expect serious selling to develop.</p>
<p>&quot;We may see some profit-taking here,&quot; said Peter Cardillo, director of research at Westfalia Investments. &quot;But closing above 5700 yesterday was positive from a technical standpoint and I expect the Dow to ultimately wiggle to new highs.&quot;  </p>
<p>In recent weeks, blue chips have outperformed the market as investors have turned to large-cap top name companies. Analysts said investors were unlikely to shake off their recent aversion to small-cap stocks on a day offering little in the way of economic data and with market participation depressed by the summer doldrums.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no economic numbers of great importance today,&quot; said Larry Wachtel, market analyst at Prudential Securities. &quot;The only excitement could be a resurgence of the Dow kind of stocks.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
