<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6939" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Agouron's cancer drug trials cleared by FDA.</title>
<headline>Agouron's cancer drug trials cleared by FDA.</headline>
<dateline>LA JOLLA, Calif. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Agouron Pharmaceuticals Inc said on Wednesday it has received clearance from the U.S. Food and Drug Administration to start clinical studies of its anti-cancer drug AG2034 in the United States.  </p>
<p>The company said that under an Investigational New Drug Application filed with the FDA in July 1996, it will now proceed to conduct clinical studies of the intravenous formulation of AG2034 in the United States.</p>
<p>In this first study of AG2034 in cancer patients, physicians are seeking to establish parameters of the compound as the basis for determining an optimal dose and schedule for administration of the drug in subsequent efficacy studies, the company said.</p>
<p>AG2034 is a small synthetic chemical compound using an approach described as &quot;protein structure-based drug design.&quot; The drug was designed specifically to inactivate an enzyme known as GART (glycinamide ribonucleotide transformylase) required for the rapid proliferation of cancer cells.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LA JOLLA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
