<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6985" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. municipal bond and tax ballot proposals.</title>
<headline>U.S. municipal bond and tax ballot proposals.</headline>
<text>
<p>BALLOT PROPOSALS</p>
<p>AUG 27</p>
<p>--$18.5 million Franklin Cty, N.C., GO bonds for schools.</p>
<p>SEPT 3</p>
<p>--$37 million Hollywood, Fla., GO bonds for parks and other capital projects.</p>
<p>--Hillsborough County, Fla., votes on proposed sales tax hike for schools, roads and football stadium.</p>
<p>--Westin, Fla., residents vote whether to incorporate as new city.</p>
<p>SEPT 7</p>
<p>-- $184 million Richland Cty, S.C., schools bonds.</p>
<p>-- $25 million Stokes Cty, N.C., general obligation bonds.</p>
<p>-- $1.870 million Martinville Ind Sch Dist, Texas, school g.o. bonds.</p>
<p>SEPT 10</p>
<p>--$4.2 million issue, Loup City School District, Neb.</p>
<p>SEPT 14</p>
<p>--$14.8 million Mount Vernon Ind Sch Dist, Texas, school g.o. bonds.</p>
<p>SEPT 17</p>
<p>--$215 million King Cty, Wash., new park bonds.</p>
<p>SEPT 28</p>
<p>--$174.6 million Richardson Ind Sch Dist, Texas, school g.o. bonds.</p>
<p>OCT. 5</p>
<p>--$66.8 million LaPorte Ind Sch Dist, Texas, school g.o. bonds.</p>
<p>OCT 8</p>
<p>--$94.5 million Tulsa Ind Sch Dist, Okla., g.o school bonds.</p>
<p>OCT. 12</p>
<p>--$20 million Jasper Ind Sch Dist, Texas, g.o. school bonds.</p>
<p>NOV 5</p>
<p>--$2 billion Los Angeles Unified School District, Calif., school bonds.</p>
<p>--$1.8 billion North Carolina GO bonds for schools.</p>
<p>--$1.75 billion New York Clean Water, Clean Air Bond Act.</p>
<p>Would fund a variety of environmental projects through-out the state.</p>
<p>--$995 million, California Proposition 204 - Safe, Clean, Reliable Water Supply Act. Would authorize the issuance of general obligation bonds to finance water programs.</p>
<p>--$950 million North Carolina GO bonds for highways.</p>
<p>--$750 million Los Angeles, Calif., park bonds.</p>
<p>--$700 million, California Proposition 205 - Youthful and Adult Offender Local Facilities Bond Act of 1996. Would authorize the issuance of general obligation bonds to construct, renovate, remodel and replace county juvenile and adult correctional facilities.</p>
<p>--$550 million West Virginia GO bonds for roads.</p>
<p>--$400 million, California Proposition 206 - Veterans' Bond Act of 1996. Would authorize the issuance of general obligation bonds to fund a program of farm, home and mobilehome loans.</p>
<p>--$319 million Los Angeles Cty, Calif., greenbelt, zoo improvement bonds.</p>
<p>--$300 million New Jersey port dredging bonds.</p>
<p>--$225 million Sacramento Unif Sch Dist, Calif., school g.o. bonds.</p>
<p>--$200 million Dade County, Fla., general obligation bonds for parks.</p>
<p>--$174.8 million Chesterfield Cty, Va., GO bonds for schools.</p>
<p>--$100 million San Francisco, Calif., general obligation bonds.</p>
<p>--$98.4 million Charlotte, N.C., GO bonds for streets and drainage.</p>
<p>--$43.8 million Arlington Cty, Va., county government g.o.bonds.</p>
<p>--$37 million Greensboro, N.C., general obligation bonds.</p>
<p>--$34 million Chesterfield Cty, Va., GO bonds for public safety.</p>
<p>--$30 million Cobb County, Ga., GO bonds for recreation.</p>
<p>--$29.1 million Arlington Cty, Va., g.o. school bonds.</p>
<p>--$25 million Greensboro, N.C., GO bonds for public safety.</p>
<p>--$13.5 million Chapel Hill, N.C., GO bonds for parks, streets and sidewalks.</p>
<p>--$12 million Sante Fe, N.M., bond measure to fund public works projects.</p>
<p>--$11.5 million Wilmington, N.C., GO bonds for stormwater drainage, parks and roads.</p>
<p>--$10.3 million Chesterfield Cty, Va., GO bonds for libraries.</p>
<p>--$10 million Greensboro, N.C., GO bonds for housing.</p>
<p>--$9.3 million Chesterfield Cty, Va., GO bonds for parks.</p>
<p>-- $6 million Apex, N.C., general obligation bonds.</p>
<p>--$1.5 million Albany, N.Y., issue.</p>
<p>--Louisiana parishes vote whether to keep gambling legal.</p>
<p>--Florida referendum on proposal requiring two-thirds voter approval for statewide tax increases.</p>
<p>--South Carolina referendum on amendment allowing state pension money to be invested in equities.</p>
<p>--Knoxville and Knox County, Tenn., vote on proposal to consolidate government.</p>
<p>--North Carolina amendment to give governor veto powers.</p>
<p>--Georgia referendum on proposal to end intangibles tax.</p>
<p>--Prince George's County, Md., vote on proposal to repeal property tax cap.</p>
<p>--Leon Cty, Fla., two-year extension of one-percent local option sales tax.</p>
<p>--California Proposition 210 - Minimum Wage Increase. Increases the current state minimum wage of $4.25 per hour to $5.00 per hour on March 1, 1997 and then to $5.75 per hour on March 1, 1998.</p>
<p>--California Proposition 217 - Top Income Tax Brackets. Continues highest tax rates of 10 percent and 11 percent on residents with taxable income over $100,000 and $200,000 respectively.</p>
<p>--California Proposition 218 - Voter Approval for Local Government Taxes. Limits authority of local governments to impose taxes and property-related assessments, fees and charges. Requires majority of voters approve increases in general taxes and reiterates that two-thirds must approve special taxes.</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
