<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6986" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Husband of Kevorkian patient disputes coroner.</title>
<headline>Husband of Kevorkian patient disputes coroner.</headline>
<byline>Michael Ellis</byline>
<dateline>PEMBROKE, Mass 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The husband of a Massachusetts woman who committed suicide in the presence of Dr. Jack Kevorkian disputed on Tuesday a Michigan medical examiner's autopsy, calling him &quot;insensitive&quot; and accusing the examiner of pursuing &quot;his own agenda.&quot;</p>
<p>Psychiatrist Franklin Curren, the husband of Judith Curren, said at an impromptu news conference on his front lawn that the coroner was &quot;insensitive and does a disservice. He's got his own agenda. Some people are, highly illogically, trying to deal with the issue by saying my wife wasn't sick.&quot;</p>
<p>Oakland County, Michigan, medical examiner Dr. Ljubisa Dragovic, a longtime Kevorkian critic, said on Monday an autopsy on Judith Curren showed she was overweight and depressed, but showed no signs of chronic fatigue syndrome or other significant disease process.</p>
<p>The medical examiner's conclusions and police reports showing that Franklin Curren allegedly assaulted his wife raised troubling questions about Kevorkian and renewed debate over assisted suicide.</p>
<p>Curren said Dragovic's suggestion his wife's judgment was jarred by painkillers and she took her life because she was overweight belittled people who suffer from chronic fatigue syndrome.</p>
<p>&quot;How can he diagnose depression on a cadaver?&quot; he asked reporters. &quot;The premise behind that is that anyone who takes medication is irrational or drug-addicted. She was not incompetent because she took medication.&quot;</p>
<p>Curren said his wife suffered from fibromyalgia and chronic fatigue for 20 years and in recent years was unable to read, watch television or even spend more than 20 minutes a day with their daughters, aged 10 and 7.</p>
<p>In Southfield, Michigan, meanwhile, Kevorkian's attorney Geoffrey Fieger Tuesday produced medical records, some of Judith Curren's handwritten letters and a new eyewitness to her final moments.</p>
<p>A statement from Dr. David Bell of Harvard University, one of the medical records Fieger produced, said, &quot;I do not feel that mental illness is the cause of her activity limitation or her symptom pattern. I would rather see this as a complication of chronic fatigue syndrome.&quot;</p>
<p>Fieger said Curren called him almost daily for a year begging him to refer her to Kevorkian.</p>
<p>In a letter after making contact, Curren told the retired pathologist: &quot;For that one evening you put a happy smile on my face because I felt secure in knowledge you would help me die. On that night I was confident in the belief that you would assist me to reach the goal I have prayed for, longed for and been too incapacitated to accomplish on my own.&quot;</p>
<p>Janet Good, a longtime Kevorkian supporter who was present at Curren's death on Aug. 15, said Curren kissed her husband, Franklin, goodbye before she died. Good said Curren's last words were, &quot;Thank you, Dr. Kevorkian.&quot;</p>
<p>Last week the Currens flew from Pembroke to Detroit, where Judith Curren, a 42-year-old registered nurse, became the 35th person to die in Kevorkian's presence. She weighed 260 pounds and was 5 feet 1 inch tall.</p>
<p>Curren said his wife first told him she planned to commit suicide four years ago, and his refusal to help her led to arguments, particularly during emotional phases of her illness.</p>
<p>She filed domestic assault charges against him in late July and sought a restraining order against him three years ago, according to police reports. News reports said police responded to at least eight 911 calls from Judith Curren asking for help or from neighbours who complained of fighting at their earlier residence in Winchester, Massachusetts, from 1989 to 1994.</p>
<p>Curren was facing a court hearing on Oct. 5 on the assault charges, according to Boston media reports.</p>
<p>&quot;The stress of the family situation was that I wasn't going along with the decision to take her life ... It wasn't family stress leading her to not want to be here,&quot; he said. &quot;Every time she made these accusations she retracted them and never went to court.&quot;</p>
<p>Curren said he finally agreed to honour her decision to die in March when she said she would divorce him, if necessary, to keep him from interfering.</p>
<p>&quot;As time went on, she would say to me, 'Frank, why are you making me suffer?' And I would say, 'I'm not, I'm your husband, I'm trying to help you.' She said, 'Don't you realise that by keeping me alive, you're making me suffer. There's no help available. And I can't stand my life of lying in bed,'&quot; Curren said</p>
<p>Curren said on rare occasions, once every six to 12 months, he would prescribe drugs for her in accordance with medical treatments supervised by &quot;one of the world's pre-eminent psychopharmacologists&quot; in New York. He declined to name the New York doctor.</p>
<p>He said he met Tuesday for about two hours with members of the state medical board, who questioned him about doctors' allegations he improperly prescribed narcotics with other patients.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PEMBROKE, Mass"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
