<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="6996" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Reliance to form new property insurer.</title>
<headline>Reliance to form new property insurer.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reliance National and an African-American insurance executive said they plan to form a new property-casualty company to insure public utilities and corporations with commitments to buy products and services from minority-owned business enterprises.</p>
<p>Onyx Insurance Co will be capitalized at more than $5 million and will be jointly owned by Aaron Richardson as the majority common shareholder and Reliance National, a unit of Reliance Group Holdings Inc.</p>
<p>Reliance declined to disclose the size of its or Richardson's stake.  </p>
<p>Richardson, a 29-year veteran of the insurance industry, will serve as the chairman and chief executive of Onyx.</p>
<p>Upon approval by the California insurance department, Onyx Insurance Co will be the only African-American owned property-casualty insurance company in the United States.  </p>
<p>&quot;There is clearly a great opportunity for a minority-owned company with sufficient capacity to participate in the insurance programs of public entities and large corporations,&quot; said Dennis Busti, chief executive of Reliance National.</p>
<p>Onyx will retain a small portion of each risk and reinsure the remainder through Reliance National, enabling Onyx to spread its risk and quickly establish a broad customer base.</p>
<p>&quot;There are more than 2,600 property-casualty insurance companies in the United States with a combined net income of over $20 billion and assets of nearly $232 billion,&quot; Richardson said.</p>
<p>&quot;Yet not one of these companies is African-American owned. The formation of Onyx Insurance Company is an important step toward African-American participation in the economic mainstream of America,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Richardson is the founder and owner of ARISCO (Aaron Richardson Insurance Services Corp), a San Francisco-based property-casualty insurance brokerage that he formed in 1990.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1716</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
