<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7005" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hedge funds beat equity funds in July - analyst.</title>
<headline>Hedge funds beat equity funds in July - analyst.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. and offshore hedge funds dropped about two percent in July, compared to an average decline of five percent for equity mutual funds, according to Van Hedge Fund Advisors.</p>
<p>The top peforming hedge fund style in July was short-selling, as U.S. funds that primarily bet securities prices will fall gained 12 percent and similar offshore funds rose 14 percent.</p>
<p>Hedge funds are private investment partnerships with wide latitude to invest across a variety of financial markets, frequently using borrowed money and derivatives.  </p>
<p>&quot;Hedge funds tend to serve as buffers during periods of market correction,&quot; said George Van, chairman of the advisory firm.</p>
<p>Hedge funds also beat equity funds over the first seven months of the year, Van said. U.S. hedge funds rose nine percent and offshore funds gained eight percent through the end of July, compared to an average gain of four percent for mutual funds and the S&amp;P 500's five percent rise, Van said.</p>
<p>Over the first seven months, the most successful U.S. hedge fund style was emerging markets, up over 16 percent.  </p>
<p>The most successful offshore fund style was special situation investing, up almost 12 percent.</p>
<p>Short-seller's stellar July performance offset declines earlier in the year, Van reported. For the year to date, U.S. hedge fund short seller were up six percent and offshore funds rose almost five percent.</p>
<p>The worst performing U.S hedge fund style in July was aggressive growth funds, down over six percent. For offshore funds, emerging market funds came in last, falling five percent.</p>
<p>U.S. macro funds, which make bets on large-scale economic moves, declined over four percent in July and remained the worst performing U.S. fund style for the year-to-date, down over two percent for the first seven months.</p>
<p>The worst performing offshore fund style year-to-date was market timers, up one percent through the end of July.</p>
<p>--Aaron Pressman, 202-898-8312</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
