<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7006" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Aug 1 pork belly stocks seen at nine-year low.</title>
<headline>US Aug 1 pork belly stocks seen at nine-year low.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Frozen pork belly stocks in U.S. warehouses as of August 1 likely remain at a nine-year low, analysts said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Agriculture Department will release its monthly Cold Storage Report at 1400 CDT Friday and analysts forecast the data will show August 1 stocks between 35.1 million and 38.7 million lbs versus July 1 stocks of 56.767 million and August 1, 1995, stocks of 47.055 million.</p>
<p>Continued demand from the fast food sector through the month of July kept the flow of frozen bellies strong and stocks at low levels, analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The drawdown during the month as a percentage to the stocks that we had, was a little larger than average and as a result the 38.5-million-lb figure that we have on hand as of August first is the lowest number we've had for that date since 1987,&quot; said Chuck Levitt, senior livestock analyst for Alaron Trading Corp.</p>
<p>Levitt noted that the larger percent of usage came despite wholesale bacon prices that are double the price of last year.</p>
<p>Expectations following the June 1 USDA Hogs and Pigs Report pointed to increased hog numbers. Users gambled that fresh production would jump late this summer and used frozen stocks to fill needs.</p>
<p>However, hog slaughter has not risen to expectations and usage of frozen product continues large.</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
