<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7007" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. fed cattle numbers seen low but placements up.</title>
<headline>U.S. fed cattle numbers seen low but placements up.</headline>
<byline>Jerry Bieszk</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Agriculture Department is expected to report that fed cattle supplies at major U.S. feedlots in the seven key states remained at low levels during July despite more cattle moving into feedlots during the month, analysts said.</p>
<p>The average of analysts' estimates for the number of cattle on feed as of August 1 was 86.2 percent of a year ago, in a range of 84.0 to 88.0 percent while July placements averaged 110.5 percent of a year ago in a range of 100.0 to 116.0 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;On-feed numbers out ahead will remain friendly and the front end supplies will get very tight during the next 30 to 90 days,&quot; said Andy Gottschalk, LFG senior vice president and livestock analyst. &quot;Then we will start to see the impact of the larger placements.&quot;</p>
<p>USDA will release its feedlot cattle supply data at 1400 CDT Friday in its monthly Cattle-On-Feed report. This is the eighth time for the new 12-state report, but analysts continue to only estimate data for feedlots in the seven key states with capacities of 1,000 head or more as historical data continues to build.  </p>
<p>Gottschalk noted that heavier July placement numbers partly reflected improved fed cattle prices. An abundance of feeder cattle and higher prices for fed cattle sparked a flow of feeder cattle into feedlots.</p>
<p>Drought conditions in some regions also forced feeders off of pastures and declining feed costs further encouraged placements on feed, analysts said.  </p>
<p>Although estimates on marketings at first glance appeared friendly for the market, averaging 102.4 percent of a year ago in a range of 100.5 to 106.0 percent, marketings may be perceived as disappointing considering there were two additional slaughter days this year that added 10 percent to the marketing total for July, sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;The (estimated) marketing number in fact, given the number of slaughter days that we had, was somewhat disappointing,&quot; Gottschalk said.</p>
<p>The trend shown during July, larger placements and smaller marketings, was expected to continue for the next few months. The larger placements will likely start to impact cash cattle prices around or after the latter part of November, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;From here on out we will be seeing much bigger placements and smaller marketings - we'll grow this on-feed number pretty quickly from here on out,&quot; said Bob Price, senior livestock analyst for Cargill Investor Services.</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
