<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7009" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Jewell polygraph expert once cleared guilty man.</title>
<headline>Jewell polygraph expert once cleared guilty man.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A polygraph expert who declared Richard Jewell innocent of the Olympic park bombing once used a lie detector to defend a man later convicted of ordering his wife's murder, an Atlanta newspaper said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Richard Rackleff, a former FBI agent, told a news conference on Tuesday that Jewell had passed a lie detector test in which he denied any involvement in the bomb attack on the Centennial Olympic Games. The polygrapher was hired by Jewell attorneys as part of a public campaign to clear the security guard's name of suspicion.</p>
<p>The Atlanta Journal-Constitution said Rackleff in 1992 gave a similar lie detector test to a prominent lawyer accused of murdering his wife and said he was convinced of the man's innocence. But the lawyer was later convicted of racketeering for hiring a business associate to carry out the murder.</p>
<p>The newspaper said Rackleff also used a polygraph test to defend a man who later admitted to being a child molester. Rackleff, a retired 27-year FBI veteran, was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Two people died and more than 100 were injured on July 27 when a homemade pipe bomb exploded at an outdoor concert in Atlanta's Centennial Olympic Park. Jewell, 33, a security guard at a nearby pavilion, was initially hailed as a hero for finding the green knapsack that carried the bomb and helping to clear crowds from the area.</p>
<p>But days later he became the only named suspect in a federal investigation and has remained under FBI and media surveillance, although he has not been charged with any crime.</p>
<p>Jewell has steadfastly maintained his innocence. Using the polygraph results provided by Rackleff, his lawyers have demanded that the FBI either arrest him or apologise to him.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
