<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7017" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tour finds Ohio, Indiana corn, soy behind 1995.</title>
<headline>Tour finds Ohio, Indiana corn, soy behind 1995.</headline>
<byline>Emily Kaiser</byline>
<dateline>LAFAYETTE, Ind. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crop scouts on day one of a four-day U.S. tour projected Ohio and Indiana corn yields below last year's tour estimates after late planting left crops vulnerable to dry weather, disease and insect damage.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the latest planting season we've had since we started keeping records in 1951,&quot; said Ralph Gann, Indiana State Statistician. &quot;With a (late) frost and good moisture for the next three weeks, (the crops) might make it.&quot;</p>
<p>The tour pegged Indiana corn output at 105.0 bushels per acre (bpa), against last year's tour estimate of 119.6 bpa.  </p>
<p>Ohio's production was estimated at 103.0 bpa, compared with last year's tour prediction of 119.2 bpa.</p>
<p>Participants on the ProFarmer tour -- including more than 50 agronomists, farmers, crop analysts, and USDA officials -- sampled corn from 48 fields in Ohio and 122 fields in Indiana.</p>
<p>They reported soybean progress also well behind average and pod counts were below last year's tour estimates.</p>
<p>In Ohio, pod counts taken in three-foot by three-foot areas showed an average of 721.5 pods, down from last year's tour estimate of 1,147 pods.  </p>
<p>In Indiana, a sample of 111 fields produced an average of 933.4 pods per three-foot square. Last year's tour estimate was 1,119.8 pods.</p>
<p>Plant population counts in most counties were low with few corn fields sampled containing more than 45 pollinated ears per 30-foot row, the crop scouts reported.</p>
<p>Soybean stands were also spotty and several fields had not begun podding. Other plants had produced only a handful of pods and were still blooming.</p>
<p>Corn borer damage was noted in eastern and northern sections of Indiana.  </p>
<p>Second generation borers had drilled into ears and stalks in some regions, the scouts said. In a few fields, stalks broke off when pushed, indicating corn borers had weakened the stem.</p>
<p>Grey leaf spot was reported in some central Indiana counties and there were also isolated cases of smut in north-central areas of the state, the scouts reported.</p>
<p>There were also widespread reports of Japanese beetle in soybean fields across Indiana and Ohio, but agronomists said leaf damage was not heavy enough to justify spraying.</p>
<p>The biggest problem in most areas was lack of moisture, the scouts said.  </p>
<p>While Indiana and Ohio were plagued by heavy rains during spring planting, a dry August followed, leaving many fields parched and further stalling development.</p>
<p>&quot;It's critical we get some moisture shortly,&quot; said Ellsworth Christmas, agronomist at Purdue University.</p>
<p>But even with timely rains, Christmas said Indiana's soybean yield average would not top the U.S. Agriculture Department's 35 bpa estimate.</p>
<p>&quot;It cannot go over 35 bushels because of delayed planting,&quot; Christmas said. &quot;I'm looking at that to be the absolute max.&quot;  </p>
<p>Crop conditions have improved in the western third of Indiana with samples taken from some counties indicating potential corn yields of more than 160 bpa, said Joe Miller, analyst at the Indiana Farm Bureau.</p>
<p>&quot;Our good counties look good but our counties that typically don't produce as well don't look as good,&quot; Miller said. &quot;In north-central Indiana (the crops) are late, but they look great.&quot;</p>
<p>Tour participants reported the highest Indiana corn yield estimates in White, Carroll, Cass and Clinton counties. Those, along with Benton and Montgomery counties, produced more than 10 percent of Indiana's crop last year, Miller said.</p>
<p>The tour will scout Illinois corn and soybean fields on Wednesday and Minnesota and Iowa fields on Thursday and Friday.</p>
<p>(Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8720)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAFAYETTE, Ind."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
