<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7027" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: California guards stage prisoner cockfights - report.</title>
<headline>California guards stage prisoner cockfights - report.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Los Angeles Times newspaper said on Wednesday that Guards in a California prison arranged &quot;cockfights&quot; between inmates, betting on the men and shooting several of them.</p>
<p>The newspaper, citing prison officials, said California's toughest maximum-security jail, Corcoran State Prison, ranked highest in the United States for inmate killings with routine reports of torture and cover-ups by prison guards.</p>
<p>&quot;It was common practice, they say, for guards to pair off rival inmates like roosters in a cockfight, complete with spectators and wagering, then sometimes shoot those who wouldn't stop fighting,&quot; the newspaper said.</p>
<p>There was no immediate comment from the state Department of Corrections. The Los Angeles Times said its director declined to be interviewed, citing pending lawsuits. Located in the San Joaquin Valley, the high-tech prison houses convicted killers Charles Manson and Sirhan Sirhan, who murdered presidential candidate Robert Kennedy in 1968.</p>
<p>The Los Angeles Times said the accusations of brutality came not from inmates or prisoner rights groups but from &quot;Corcoran's captains, lieutenants and guards who said they no longer could stay quiet about abuses their brethren inflicted on prisoners&quot;.</p>
<p>The newspaper said the accounts by several officers were bolstered by internal memos and confidential documents.</p>
<p>It said that since the prison was built eight years ago seven inmates have been shot dead by guards and more than 50 have been wounded -- the most killings of any U.S. prison.</p>
<p>While the state Department of Corrections routinely cleared officers of wrongdoing in the killings, the newspaper said the Federal Bureau  of Investigation (FBI) and a federal grand jury are investigating the shootings.</p>
<p>The former warden George Smith, who retired in July, was quoted in the article as saying some of his staff &quot;have gone crazy&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;But it was only a few who screwed up. We've got 1,700 good employees&quot;.</p>
<p>The newspaper said the troubles began in 1989 when guards shackled a prisoner who had put up a fight, took his trousers off and fired a stun gun into his genitals.</p>
<p>Despite a &quot;wall of silence&quot; from guards, the officers in the incident were later convicted when one supervisor helped prosecutors.</p>
<p>Still, the brutality escalated, including the placing of rival gangs in small yards where fights erupted on which guards bet, according to one official quoted in the article.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
