<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7030" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ten powerful high-tech companies are investing in a venture fund to support startups developing Internet software using Java as a programming language, The Wall Street Journal reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>International Business Machines Corp, Tele-Communications Inc, Sun Microsystems Inc, Compaq Computer Corp, U S West Communications Group, Netscape Communications Corp and Oracle Corp are among the investors in the $100 million Java Fund. It will be administered by venture-capital firm Kleiner Perkins Caulfield &amp; Byers.</p>
<p>The widespread endorsement for the Java Fund, which also includes investments from Cisco Systems Inc, Comcast Corp and Japan's Itochu Corp, marks an unprecedented rate of adoption for a single technology across a wide range of high-tech industries.</p>
<p>The newspaper also reported:</p>
<p>* V. John Goodwin has quit as National Steel Corp's president and chief operating officer less than a week after the company's majority shareholder, NKK Corp, took away his chief executive's title.</p>
<p>* Britain and France have told the European Commission that a joint missiles venture between British Aerospace Plc and France's Lagardere SCA affects both countries' security interests and that they oppose an EU investigation of the deal.</p>
<p>* Arizona and Kansas join parade of states suing the tobacco industry to recoup health care costs, and Michigan announces it plans to become the 13th state to do so.</p>
<p>* Slower growth, higher costs put CompuServe Corp deeply in the red.</p>
<p>* United Auto Workers walk out of contract talks over Chrysler Corp's Latin American plans.</p>
<p>* Champion Enterprises Inc to buy Redman Industries Inc in a stock swap valued at about $367.6 million.</p>
<p>*  Huntsman Corp drops bid to acquire Rexene Corp.</p>
<p>* Netscape Communications Corp asks the Justice Department to investigate Microsoft Corp for anti-trust violations.</p>
<p>* Shares in British Airways fall after a report that &quot;open sky&quot; talks between Britain and the United States were stalled.</p>
<p>* Consumer Reports magazine says two sport utility vehicles, Isuzu Motors Ltd's Trooper and Acura SLX, can overturn during quick turns at low speed and demands a recall.</p>
<p>* Federal Reserve leaves interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>* The Dow Jones Industrial Average rises 21.82 to 5,721.26. The Nasdaq composite index falls 6.24 to 1,124.67.</p>
<p>* Sprint Corp will start offering Internet services to its customers.</p>
<p>* Leading retailers report gains in profits.</p>
<p>* U.S. trade deficit shrinks in June, but gap with China surges.</p>
<p>-- New York newsroom, (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
