<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7034" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Missouri executes convicted U.S. double-murderer.</title>
<headline>Missouri executes convicted U.S. double-murderer.</headline>
<dateline>POTOSI, Mo. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A man who murdered a rural farm couple and then abandoned their decomposing bodies in the trunk of a car was executed on Wednesday by the state of Missouri, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>Tim Kniest, a spokesman for the Missouri Department of Corrections, said Richard Oxford was injected with a lethal combination of drugs and was pronounced dead at 12:06 a.m. CDT (0506 GMT) at the Potosi Correctional Centre.</p>
<p>Oxford, 39, was convicted of the 1986 murders of Howard and Melba Wampler, a southwest Missouri farm couple who had seven children.</p>
<p>The Wamplers' bodies were discovered a few weeks after Oxford escaped from an Oklahoma prison.</p>
<p>Oxford was originally scheduled to die in June, but the U.S. Supreme Court temporarily halted the execution while it considered the case of a Georgia death row inmate. The court subsequently cleared the way for the execution to proceed.</p>
<p>Oxford's final words were marked with a penitent tone.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel remorse for what I did to the victims' family,&quot; Kniest quoted Oxford as having said. &quot;I love my wife and children and I'll see them on the other side.&quot;</p>
<p>Oxford was the fifth person to be executed in Missouri in 1996 and the 22nd since the state resumed executions in 1989.</p>
<p>Kniest said a crowd of 14 death penalty supporters and 10 opponents had demonstrated quietly outside the correctional centre in the hours leading up to Oxford's death.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="POTOSI, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
