<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7035" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Kevorkian participates in 36th assisted suicide.</title>
<headline>Kevorkian participates in 36th assisted suicide.</headline>
<dateline>PONTIAC, Mich. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dr. Jack Kevorkian attended his 36th suicide late on Tuesday night, hospital officials said, even as controversy continued to rage over the death of his previous patient last week.</p>
<p>Kevorkian brought the body of Louise Siebens, 76, of McKiney, Texas, into the emergency room at Pontiac Osteopathic Hospital at 10:11 p.m. Tuesday night (0311 GMT Wednesday), said Dr. Robert Aranosian, the hospital's emergency room director.</p>
<p>He told doctors there that Siebens had been suffering from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, or Lou Gehrig's disease, which is considered to be terminal.</p>
<p>The 68-year-old retired pathologist briefly provided some information about Siebens, then left. &quot;This is the usual routine -- he arrives, he's here briefly, then he leaves,&quot; Aranosian said.</p>
<p>Kevorkian's attorney, Geoffrey Fieger, could not be reached for comment early Wednesday morning.</p>
<p>The death of Kevorkian's last patient, Judith Curren, a 42-year-old registered nurse from Pembroke, Mass., has stirred controversy because she allegedly suffered from chronic fatigue syndrome, which is not considered a fatal disease.</p>
<p>The Oakland County coroner said Monday that an autopsy produced no evidence of disease, leading Kevorkian's critics to raise questions about his methods and standards in helping patients commit suicide.</p>
<p>Curren had filed an assault charge against her husband, Franklin, a psychologist, but he has denied ever assaulting her, and maintains that she filed the charge because he had refused to take her to see Kevorkian.</p>
<p>Siebens' death is the 36th that Kevorkian has acknowledged attending since he began his crusade for doctor-assisted suicide in 1990, and the eighth since he was acquitted of assisted suicide charges for a third time in May.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PONTIAC, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
