<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7039" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Washington Post carried the following stories on its front page on August 21:</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - Teenage drug use has doubled since 1992, according to a federal survey that Republicans seized upon to bolster their claims that President Bill Clinton has presided over a return to permissiveness.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - Washington DC's elected officials have stood nearly mute in the face of a continuing crisis in the public school system over the past three weeks.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>MOSCOW - Russian troops prepared to launch a risky new offensive against Chechen separatists in Grozny even as a high-stakes Kremlin power struggle escalated among top aides of an absent President Boris Yeltsin.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - The homicide rate in Prince George County, Maryland, the area's most crime-ridden suburb, has fallen nearly 25 percent so far this year.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>MORRISTOWN, N. J. - The pastoral communities of central New Jersey that were the prime beneficiaries of the great flight from cities are today laboratories where the old suburban ideal is adapting to downsizing and the new economy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
