<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7041" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ValuJet faces delay on resuming flights - report.</title>
<headline>ValuJet faces delay on resuming flights - report.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>ValuJet Airlines, which stopped flying two months ago because of U.S. regulators' concerns about its flight safety, will not get approval to resume operations by Friday, its target date, the Washington Post reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Quoting unidentified sources at the Transportation Department, the newspaper said the airline might have to wait until at least early September to begin flying again.</p>
<p>The Atlanta-based carrier voluntarily grounded its fleet on June 17 after the Federal Aviation Administration found &quot;serious deficiencies&quot; in its maintenance program.</p>
<p>The FAA inspections followed the May 11 crash of Flight 592 in the Florida Everglades.</p>
<p>The discount carrier began two days of federal safety &quot;proving runs&quot; on Tuesday and ValuJet executives had set the end of this week as their target for resuming operations.</p>
<p>ValuJet first must obtain clearances from the FAA, which is reviewing the airline's aircraft and safety procedures, and the Transportation Department, which is reviewing its financial health and management.</p>
<p>The Post said the Transportation Department, which oversees the FAA, appeared to be at least 10 days away from issuing the airline a &quot;certificate of fitness.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
