<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7044" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE - Horseshoes and Hoover balls hallmarks of presidents.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Horseshoes and Hoover balls hallmarks of presidents.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kenen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Presidential politics may be a horse race but they can also be a brisk sunrise walk.</p>
<p>An exhibit called &quot;Flexing the Nation's Muscle: Presidents, Physical Fitness and Sports in the American Century&quot; traces the athletic ventures of U.S. presidents and the ways they promoted an image of strength and vigour.</p>
<p>&quot;That's probably always been a part of American politics,&quot; said Clay Bauske, curator at the Harry S. Truman Library in Independence, Missouri, who helped put together the summertime exhibit at the White House Visitors Centre. &quot;But it probably got more important with television. Before that presidents kept fit to keep fit.&quot;</p>
<p>Many of the mementos are familiar -- George Bush's horseshoes, ostrich cowboy boots Ronald Reagan wore astride his horse, photos of John Kennedy sailing with his young family, President Bill Clinton's &quot;Razorback Hoops&quot; T-shirt and his New Balance running shoes.</p>
<p>Other images have fallen into oblivion. &quot;Hooverball,&quot; involving a 10-pound (4.5 kg) medicine ball heaved over a volleyball net, never quite caught on despite Herbert Hoover's endorsement that &quot;it requires less skill than tennis.&quot;</p>
<p>Some presidents were true athletes and outdoorsmen. Teddy Roosevelt, for instance, personifed &quot;vigor and fitness&quot; at the start of the 20th century, said Bauske, who was unable to get his curatorial hands on any big game trophies or other &quot;TR&quot; relics for this display.</p>
<p>The most outstanding athlete among modern presidents was probably Gerald Ford, despite his popular image as a bumbler, fed by his unfortunate habit of hitting spectators with golf balls at celebrity tournaments. A University of Michigan football star, Ford was still running three or four miles a day -- and sometimes up to 12 miles -- well into his 60s.</p>
<p>For some presidents, sports ceased to be pure pleasure and became part of a struggle for physical survival. Known for his intellect more than his sportsmanship, Woodrow Wilson was a reasonably fit man who played golf and took walks until his stroke in 1919. After that, on those occasions when he could walk at all, he needed a walking stick, shown in the exhibit.</p>
<p>Franklin Roosevelt, a one-time country club golf champion, was stricken by polio as a young man. Although he tried to hide the extent of the damage from voters, the leg braces on display are a poignant reminder of his atrophied limbs.</p>
<p>But not even polio stopped him from fishing and swimming. &quot;I have been swimming three times a week -- first in the Astor pool and lately in the pond on our place,&quot; he wrote a friend in 1923. &quot;The legs work wonderfully in the water and I need nothing artificial to keep myself afloat.&quot;</p>
<p>Dwight Eisenhower, enough of an athlete to get his picture in Sports Illustrated, relished his time on the golf course and was even known to wear golf shoes in the Oval Office, where he left cleat marks on the wooden floor. But he had a heart attack, so he fitted a shoe with a 12-pound (5 kg) weight to do leg exercises in his office while he recuperated.</p>
<p>For some presidents, physical regimens or outdoor hobbies became part of their image, almost an extension of their personality. Bush, who learned tennis at age five, was known for hyper-competitiveness and hyper-speed as he rushed from one sport to another.</p>
<p>Harry Truman's brisk early morning walks, one to two miles (.6 to 1.2 km) a day at a military gait of 120 paces per minute, came to symbolise his no-nonsense management style. He was also an avid swimmer, if a stubborn one, insisting on keeping his head above water so he could wear his glasses.</p>
<p>For Jimmy Carter, who made a virtue out of his common man modesty, good old-fashioned softball was the game of choice -- like touch football for the Kennedys. Carter often joined impromptu games with his family, staff, even reporters, and his display is brimming with baseball paraphernalia such as engraved &quot;his and hers&quot; bats for him and wife Rosalynn and a softball given to daughter Amy by the &quot;Purple Panda Girls&quot; team at an elementary school in Ohio.</p>
<p>Not every winning politician is a jock. Richard Nixon's space is virtually empty, although there is a photograph of him playing golf. &quot;When he was Eisenhower's vice president, I'm not sure if he had any choice in the matter,&quot; Bauske said.</p>
<p>But Nixon was still a step ahead of Hoover. An ardent football fan, Hoover managed the team while a student at Stanford. He went down in history for remembering to organise the ticket sales but forgetting to buy the ball.</p>
<p>The exhibit is on through Sept. 7 at the Visitors Centre, just southwest of the White House, from 7:30 a.m. to 4 p.m. Admission is free.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
