<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7046" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pop artist Lichtenstein designs DreamWorks logo.</title>
<headline>Pop artist Lichtenstein designs DreamWorks logo.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hollywood mogul David Geffen's new record company has hired pop artist Roy Lichtenstein to design his first corporate logo.</p>
<p>The design for DreamWorks Records incorporates a musical note in a dream balloon against a background of blue diagonal stripes. It made its debut on the company's second release, &quot;Beautiful Freak,&quot; from Los Angeles-based trio, the eels.</p>
<p>DreamWorks Records is the music arm of DreamWorks SKG, the fledgling entertainment company formed by Geffen with filmmaker Steven Spielberg and movie studio executive Jeffrey Katzenberg.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Geffen declined to say how much Lichtenstein, 72, was paid for his work. However, he will be supplied with compact discs from such artists as Peter Gabriel, Nirvana and Beck, she added. Lichtenstein retains some control over the logo's use, she added.</p>
<p>Lichtenstein, one of the originators of the American Pop Art movement, said in a statement: &quot;I'm not in the business of doing anything like that (a corporate logo) and don't intend to do it again.&quot;</p>
<p>He made an exception because of his friendship with art collector Geffen and with Mo Ostin, the veteran music executive who runs DreamWorks Records.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
