<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7047" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US WCoast prods decline on refinery returns, APIs.</title>
<headline>US WCoast prods decline on refinery returns, APIs.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast product prices declined on late Tuesday, with traders convinced refineries were doing better after last week's blackout.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there's plenty of gasoline around and with the majors out of the market it'll soften a bit,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>The American Petroleum Institute (API) reported a drop in refinery use last week, despite company denials of problems. Utilisation dropped a hefty 7.8 percent to 81.3 percent.</p>
<p>But prices sagged today with fewer refiners needing to buy and cargoes expected by week's end.  </p>
<p>Conventional-grade gasoline in Los Angeles fell one cent from midday to 64/65 cents a gallon, with premium quality seven cents higher.</p>
<p>CARB-grade gasoline was notionally a half cent higher at 68.50/69.50 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>API data showed gasoline held in secondary storage out west fell 1.21 million barrels to 28.8 million, but traders noted it remained 764,000 barrels above year-ago.</p>
<p>Low sulphur diesel in L.A. slipped a half cent to 68.50/69.50 cents, in line with trader predictions that the market was overvalued after refinery unit problems.  </p>
<p>With problems resolved, EPA was seen falling to its usual five-cent discount to CARB, traders said.</p>
<p>The API also reported a 643,000 barrel rise in West Coast distillate stocks.</p>
<p>Jet fuel sagged, falling between two and 2.50 cents to 69.50/70 cents on forecasts of foreign cargoes and inventory data.</p>
<p>And business shifted from August to September after two quiet sessions when traders attended a golf tournament.</p>
<p>August gasolines were seen 1.50 below September.</p>
<p>-- David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles Bureau 213 380-2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
