<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7051" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. killer of German tourist agrees to life term.</title>
<headline>U.S. killer of German tourist agrees to life term.</headline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Miami man avoided a possible death sentence on Tuesday by agreeing to serve life in prison for the 1993 shotgun murder of a German tourist during a highway robbery.</p>
<p>Recondall Wiggins, 22, who was convicted of first-degree murder, agreed to a deal worked out by prosecutors and defence attorneys just before a jury was to hear testimony on whether he get life in prison or death in Florida's electric chair.</p>
<p>He agreed to a life term with no possibility of parole for 25 years for the slaying and 50 years on unrelated charges.</p>
<p>Wiggins was convicted in the Sept. 8, 1993 death of Uwe-Wilhelm Rakebrand, 33, of Adendorf, Germany, who was fatally shot as he and his pregnant wife tried to flee robbers who bumped their rental car with a truck on a highway between Miami International Airport and Miami Beach.</p>
<p>When Rakebrand refused to pull off the highway, the assailants fired at his rented Toyota Corolla, killing him.</p>
<p>Two other defendants in the case, Patsy Jones -- known by the nickname &quot;Gangsta Bitch&quot; -- and Alvan Hundson, pleaded guilty to murder charges under an agreement that spared their lives.</p>
<p>The killing was one of several highly publicised attacks on foreign visitors that sent shockwaves through Florida's $31 billion-a-year tourism industry.</p>
<p>The state has since removed identifying markings from rental cars, improved highway signs in resort areas and deployed special tourism police to safeguard visitors.</p>
<p>Prosecutor Michael Band said Rakebrand's widow had been consulted and was satisfied with the sentence.</p>
<p>&quot;Germany does not have a death penalty. We discussed that with her,&quot; Band said. &quot;She is very satisfied that this thing now will be closed.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
