<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7055" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Juppe gropes for way out of African hunger strike.</title>
<headline>Juppe gropes for way out of African hunger strike.</headline>
<byline>John Follain</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Prime Minister Alain Juppe summoned nine ministers on Wednesday to try to break out of a damaging impasse as African immigrants fighting expulsion orders vowed to continue a 48-day hunger strike.</p>
<p>A day after one of the fasters was taken to hospital, the government hinted at a more conciliatory line and Juppe called round-table talks attended by heads of the justice, foreign, interior, and social affairs ministries.</p>
<p>The nine remaining hunger strikers pledged to continue their fast after one was taken to hospital on Tuesday night with stomach pains. They are flanked by about 300 other protesters occupying the Saint-Bernard church in Paris.</p>
<p>An official said the government would as part of a solution ask the highest administrative court, the Council of State, to review the enforcement of immigration laws, and a kink which means some immigrants cannot be expelled nor granted permits.</p>
<p>Aides said the premier, who returned early from his summer holidays on Tuesday, had consulted the speakers of both houses of parliament, leaders of the two parties in the ruling centre-right coalition, and Xavier Emmanuelli, junior minister for emergency humanitarian action.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre, in a letter to actress Marina Vlady who is among protesters, said he shared her concern at the expulsion of illegal immigrants with children legally in France, and pledged not to separate mothers from their children.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe it is essential that the necessary enforcement of republican law takes the human aspect into consideration,&quot; Debre wrote. His conciliatory tone contrasted with earlier vows to strictly apply the law.</p>
<p>At the church, a spokesman for the protesters said 29-year-old Moussa Keita, taken to hospital on Tuesday, was in no danger. &quot;He is tired but his condition is not worrying. He has not been put on a drip,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that one of the hunger strikers was taken to hospital shows that this is a real hunger strike and that they are determined to continue until the end,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Doctors monitoring the health of the hunger strikers at the church, where they have been drinking sugared tea and eating vitamins, said two others were in serious condition.</p>
<p>Around the church in the heavily immigrant Goutte d'Or district, protesters including 110 children are surrounded by hundreds of sympathisers ready to prevent police seizing them by chaining themselves together if necessary.</p>
<p>Personalities who have called at the church include Danielle Mitterrand, widow of President Francois Mitterrand, anti-poverty campaigner Abbe Pierre, and sacked bishop Jacques Gaillot. Film star Emanuelle Beart has spent several nights sleeping there.</p>
<p>Short of achieving their main aim, the hunger strikers have managed to divide the ruling coalition, and to unite the fractious left several weeks into their protest.</p>
<p>&quot;The right is on the verge of a nervous breakdown,&quot; headlined the left-leaning newspaper Liberation.</p>
<p>Left-wing parties, human rights associations and trade unions have called a march from Republique Square in eastern Paris to the church for later in the day (1600 GMT) to show support for the immigrants.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFRICA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
