<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7058" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: African protesters in France vow to continue fast.</title>
<headline>African protesters in France vow to continue fast.</headline>
<byline>John Follain</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>African immigrants on the 48th day of a hunger strike to fight French expulsion orders pledged to continue their protest on Wednesday as the government refused to back down, even though one of them was rushed to hospital.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the fasters, who are flanked by 300 supporters occupying a Paris church, said Malian Moussa Keita, 29, was in no danger after complaining of severe stomach pains late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;He is tired but his condition is not worrying. He has not been put on a drip,&quot; the spokesman told reporters as Keita rested at the Lariboisiere hospital in the capital.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that one of the hunger strikers was taken to hospital shows that this is a real hunger strike and that they are determined to continue until the end,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Doctors monitoring the health of the hunger strikers at the Saint-Bernard church, where they have been drinking sugared tea and eating vitamins, said two were in serious condition.</p>
<p>Around the church in the heavily immigrant Goutte d'Or district, protesters including 110 children are surrounded by hundreds of sympathisers committed to preventing police seizing them by chaining themselves together if necessary.</p>
<p>Personalities who have called at the church include Danielle Mitterrand, widow of President Francois Mitterrand, anti-poverty campaigner Abbe Pierre, and sacked bishop Jacques Gaillot. French film star Emanuelle Beart has spent several nights sleeping in the church.</p>
<p>Short of achieving their main aim, the hunger strikers have managed to divide the ruling centre-right coalition as it struggles to find a way out of the impasse, and to unite the fractious left several weeks into their protest.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe's first move on his return from a holiday he had cut short was to receive late on Tuesday centrist parliamentarian Gilles de Robien, who broke with the official line to meet representatives of the hunger strikers earlier.</p>
<p>Officials said Juppe met Xavier Emmanuelli, junior minister for emergency humanitarian action, on Wednesday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;The right is on the verge of a nervous breakdown,&quot; headlined the left-leaning newspaper Liberation. &quot;For a long time the affair was left in the clumsy hands of the interior minister,&quot; it said in an editorial.</p>
<p>&quot;He has succeeded in turning a simple police case into a national issue,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The centrist UDF, junior coalition partner, is in two minds on an attempt by its National Assembly floor leader de Robien to launch negotiations between the protesters and the government.</p>
<p>Agriculture Minister Philippe Vasseur gave the initiative of his UDF colleague the thumbs-down. &quot;My friend's move was untimely, not sufficiently concerted or thought out,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Several left-wing leaders have urged President Jacques Chirac to intervene, and Juppe is due to stay with him at the presidential retreat of Bregancon on the Riviera this weekend.</p>
<p>Both Juppe and Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre, anxious not to lose face in the eyes of supporters of the far-right and anti-immigrant National Front, have repeatedly ruled out any compromise.</p>
<p>Left-wing parties, human rights associations and trade unions have called a march from Republique Square in eastern Paris to the church for Wednesday afternoon (1600 GMT) to show support for the immigrants.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
