<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7066" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: U.N. court boosts war crimes awareness-Goldstone.</title>
<headline>U.N. court boosts war crimes awareness-Goldstone.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.N. tribunals trying war crimes suspects from ex-Yugoslavia and Rwanda have at least raised public awarness of the atrocities committed even if the goal of meting out justice quickly has been thwarted, the top prosecutor for both was quoted on Wednesday as saying.</p>
<p>Chief Prosecutor Richard Goldstone, who is stepping down next month, told the German weekly Die Zeit that the court for former Yugoslavia in The Hague remained hamstrung by the NATO-led IFOR peacekeping force's reluctance to arrest indicted war criminals.</p>
<p>But the South African judge gave an optimistic assessment of the court's achievements in the past two years.</p>
<p>&quot;An important result for both tribunals is without doubt the educational effect on the international level,&quot; he said in an interview released ahead of publication on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Newspapers in many countries, above all in Europe and North America, write about war crimes almost daily in a way that would have been inconceivable a few years ago. I believe this has a deterrent effect on certain political and military leaders.&quot;</p>
<p>He criticised the IFOR force for not apprehending Bosnian Serb leader Radovan Karadzic and his military commander, General Ratko Mladic, under arrest warrants issued by the tribunal.</p>
<p>&quot;This is highly unsatisfactory. The two may well never be arrested if this goes on. The latest IFOR inspection in the Republika Srpska (Serb entity in Bosnia) made clear that IFOR did not want to cross Mladic's path,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He was referring to an incident this month when a lightly armed IFOR inspection team decided not to try to arrest Mladic when he offered to escort them through a site in Bosnia.</p>
<p>To date the tribunal in The Hague has indicted 75 suspects: 54 Serbs, 18 Croats and three Moslems. But all but a handful remain at large.</p>
<p>Goldstone said the Bosnian government was cooperating fully with the tribunal, but Croatia was not helping as he would like.</p>
<p>&quot;We know that indicted suspects are moving about freely in Croatia without being arrested,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cooperation with rump Yugoslavia is minimal, he added, and limited by Belgrade's demand that any witnesses the tribunal finds must be questioned in the presence of a Serb judge.</p>
<p>The tribunal for Rwanda is based in Arusha, Tanzania.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
