<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7073" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: EU urges test ban treaty draft to meet timetable.</title>
<headline>EU urges test ban treaty draft to meet timetable.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union, reacting to India's veto of a global treaty banning nuclear tests, said on Wednesday that urgent efforts were needed to get the document adopted and ready for signature.</p>
<p>Ireland, the current EU president, issued a statement in Dublin on behalf of the 15-nation bloc recalling an August 7 EU declaration urging all states to accept and adopt a draft treaty outlawing nuclear bomb tests.</p>
<p>&quot;The draft treaty text represents the outcome of 2-1/2 years of intensive negotiations and embodies a large number of delicate and balanced compromises,&quot; Wednesday's EU statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the EU view, it offers an historic opportunity to have a treaty which bans all nuclear test explosions for all time.&quot;</p>
<p>The statement was issued a few hours after the Indian government prevented the adoption of the pact at disarmament negotiations and pledged to try to stop it being forwarded to the United Nations General Assembly.</p>
<p>India says the pact would allow the five declared nuclear powers -- Britain, China, France, Russia and the United States -- to retain their nuclear arsenals while the nuclear &quot;have-nots&quot; would be barred from obtaining such weapons.</p>
<p>India also opposed a provision that would require New Delhi, along with the five declared powers and the two other &quot;threshold&quot; states, Israel and Pakistan, to sign the agreement before it could become international law.</p>
<p>India exploded a nuclear device in 1974 but says it does not have a nuclear bomb. It is regarded as a threshold state and says it retains the right to develop such arms if threatened.</p>
<p>The EU said members of the European Free Trade Association, Central and East European countries associated with the EU and associate states Cyprus and Malta backed its stance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
