<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7075" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France warns Israel on peace accord.</title>
<headline>France warns Israel on peace accord.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>France, voicing concern at Israel's delay in redeploying troops in Hebron and plans to develop West Bank settlements, warned the Jewish state on Wednesday against breaching its peace accord with Palestinians.</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry spokesman Yves Doutriaux said the French government was closely monitoring developments.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope that no step contrary to the Israeli-Palestinian accord will be carried out,&quot; he told a regular news briefing.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no alternative to the peace process...and respecting the accords which have been signed is a necessary condition to the region's stability, to which we are particularly attached,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Doutriaux said the development of settlements, the closure of borders with Palestinian-controlled territories and failure to redeploy troops in the West Bank city of Hebron raised tension and caused problems for the Palestinian Authority.</p>
<p>Israel's housing ministry is drafting a plan to build 5,000 new homes in the West Bank.</p>
<p>Israel has said it would not redeploy its troops in Hebron, the last major Arab West Bank city still under Israeli control, until the Palestinian Authority closed its offices in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Under the peace accord the troops were due to have been redeployed at the end of March.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
