<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7081" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Paris opera, age seven, is losing its facade.</title>
<headline>Paris opera, age seven, is losing its facade.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paris' flagship Bastille opera house has a new embarrassment to add to the litany of troubles since it opened seven years ago -- the facade of the building is starting to crumble.</p>
<p>Nets have been strung over parts of the white front of the opera house as a crude safety precaution to catch any falling masonry from the high-tech building that cost three billion francs ($590 million).</p>
<p>&quot;The netting has been put up wherever there's a risk. Nothing has fallen off yet,&quot; an opera official said on Wednesday. &quot;We've ordered a study of the problem to see what can be done.&quot;</p>
<p>Part of the steel tubing running down glass panels set into the facade has buckled, but the official said there was no threat to the audience.</p>
<p>Managers of the opera said in March they hoped the opera had finally shaken off a jinx that saw it plagued by labour disputes, financial losses and artists' rows since it opened in 1989 to mark the 200th anniversary of the French revolution.</p>
<p>Critics' reaction at its opening was mixed, with many feeling the cavernous auditorium sterilised vocal performances despite all the high-tech wizardry built into the monolith.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
