<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7082" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France calls for end to Chechnya fighting.</title>
<headline>France calls for end to Chechnya fighting.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>France on Wednesday urged Russian forces and rebels in the breakaway region of Chechnya to stop fighting and seek a negotiated solution to their conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;We urge all parties in the conflict to stop fighting. There will be no military solution to the Chechnya conflict,&quot; Foreign Ministry spokesman Yves Doutriaux said in a statement.</p>
<p>He said France was &quot;extremely concerned&quot; by the fighting and urged both sides to start talks based on existing ceasefire accords and promises of peace.</p>
<p>Russian forces pounded the Chechen capital Grozny on Wednesday, seeking to drive out separatists who captured the city two weeks ago. Much of Grozny is in ruins from Russian raids at the start of Moscow's 20-month military campaign to crush Chechnya's independence bid.</p>
<p>In Strasbourg, the president of the parliamentary assembly of the Council of Europe, which seeks to uphold democracy and human rights, urged all parties to set up a planned commission to supervise a ceasefire.</p>
<p>&quot;The current fighting scuttles all efforts to bring about a ceasefire,&quot; Leni Fischer said in a statement.</p>
<p>She reminded Moscow that Russia was allowed to join the 39-member Council in February partly because it had pledged to avoid violence in settling the Chechen conflict.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
