<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7087" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Becalmed Danish shares consolidate ahead of Buba.</title>
<headline>Becalmed Danish shares consolidate ahead of Buba.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish share prices closed lower on Wednesday, taking a breather to consolidate on top of five days of record highs, with dealers seeing Thursday's Bundesbank council meeting and a possible German repo rate cut shaping trade in the days ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;The stock market will stay within a quarter point range ahead of the first Buba meeting after the summer break with a German repo rate very much on the cards,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The KFX top-20 index closed 0.73 point down at 119.86 while the KFX September future fell 0.25 point to 120.25 with 80 contracts each worth 100,000 crowns traded.  </p>
<p>KFX paper suffered across the board losses while lesser shares swept up in the wake of the ongoing stream of 1996 first-half results.</p>
<p>NKT put on four percent to close at 305 crowns on its decision to stop unprofitable production of motors for its troubled Nilfisk vacuum cleaner manufacturing unit.</p>
<p>Unidanmark bank shod seven crowns to 265 after a good 1996 interim result, while the biggest bank Den Danske finished unchanged at 396 on the eve of its first-half 1996 result.</p>
<p>Overall turnover for the day was 593 million crowns.</p>
<p>--Chris Follett, Copenhagen newsroom +45-33-969650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
