<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7090" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norwegian shares edge higher as buyers emerge.</title>
<headline>Norwegian shares edge higher as buyers emerge.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwegian shares inched higher on Wednesday as bargain hunters emerged for some blue chips. Brokers said the positive trend was expected to remain for the rest of the week.</p>
<p>The Total share index edged up 2.45 points to 822.63 points, a rise of 0.3 percent. Turnover was a good 819 million crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;We're still in this consolidation phase but there is growing buying interest for some of the blue chips that have recently been lagging, such as Hydro,&quot; said one broker.</p>
<p>Norsk Hydro, which accounted for 56 million crowns of the day's trade, climbed three crowns to 292.50 crowns.  </p>
<p>Insurance group UNI Storebrand also attracted activity, gaining 0.60 crowns to 35 crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a lot of foreign interest in UNI. Many overseas investors are looking at financial shares in Norway because they are cheaply priced compared with abroad,&quot; said another dealer.</p>
<p>But shipping company Bergesen fell three crowns to close at 132 crowns in the A share after it forecast a mixed outlook for its businesses for the rest of the year despite a more than two-fold rise in operating profits in the first six months.</p>
<p>&quot;You don't make money from just being an operator in the tanker market without asset play,&quot; said the broker.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
