<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7091" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Millions of ballot papers ready for Bosnia poll.</title>
<headline>Millions of ballot papers ready for Bosnia poll.</headline>
<byline>Steve Pagani</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Millions of ballot papers for Bosnia's first post-war election have been printed in Vienna and are ready to go to Sarajevo and scores of other polling stations nationwide, the body organising the vote said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Roughly 20 to 25 million ballot papers have been printed for the five elections which will be taking place on September 14,&quot; a spokesman for the the Vienna-based Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) said.</p>
<p>Around 3.2 million ballots will also be sent off to 55 countries where arrangements are in place for hundreds of thousands of Bosnian refugees to vote.</p>
<p>The OSCE was charged under the Dayton peace accords on Bosnia to coordinate and supervise the nationwide polls.</p>
<p>&quot;All the ballot papers have already been packaged here in Vienna and should leave by the end of August, beginning of September,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The exact date of departure is confidential for security reasons. The papers were scheduled to leave in trucks and will be given a military escort by soldiers of the NATO-led international peace implementation force (IFOR) at the Croatian border. Ballot boxes and election information in several languages have also been prepared.</p>
<p>The ballots were printed by the Austrian state printing company which had to keep its presses running round the clock on some days to meet the deadline, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>OSCE officials were reluctant to disclose where the ballot papers will be stored in Bosnia before distribution to the 4,400 polling stations across the country.</p>
<p>The polls were logistically the most complex in history with an unprecedented 50 percent of eligible voters either displaced from their homes or living abroad as refugees, the OSCE said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expected around 200,000 to 400,000 refugees registering to vote. But the returns are beyond wildest expectations at 641,010 so far,&quot; the OSCE spokesman said.</p>
<p>Ballots for refugees should be received no later than August 28 and returned to Vienna by September 3. Votes for the nationwide elections such as the Bosnian presidency and the Bosnia-Herzegovina House of Representatives will be sent to Sarajevo for counting.</p>
<p>Elections will also be held for a Bosnian Moslem-Croat federation assembly and an assembly for Bosnian Serb territory. Votes received in Vienna for municipal and cantonal elections will be despatched to local centres for the count by September 14 or 15, the OSCE said.</p>
<p>U.S. envoy Robert Frowick, who heads the OSCE election mission in Bosnia, briefed ambassadors of the forum's permanent council in Vienna on Wednesday on the current state of play in the election campaign.</p>
<p>Frowick told reporters the OSCE was under no illusions over the difficulties ahead of the election and the potential arguments over the poll following the results.</p>
<p>Frowick said OSCE staff had problems in nine municipalities across Bosnia and had taken action against clear irregularities.</p>
<p>&quot;In Doboj (in Bosnian Serb territory) for example, there was an effort to tell individual voters that if they didn't register to vote as the authorities wished they would be denied humanitarian aid,&quot; Frowick said.</p>
<p>The OSCE demanded an end to the practice and got a public apology from the local Serb Democratic Party, which was also fined $25,000, he added. The fine will be deducted from the cash the OSCE is making available to all parties for campaigning.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
