<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7099" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Better 2nd half '96 seen for Europe paper industry.</title>
<headline>Better 2nd half '96 seen for Europe paper industry.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The second half of 1996 is likely to be better for Europe's pulp and paper industry than the first six months, according to the Confederation of European Paper Industries (CEPI).</p>
<p>&quot;However, whether the recovery in the second half will be sufficiently strong to produce satisfactory volume growth for the year as a whole is still open to question,&quot; said Michael Kessener, CEPI Director for Statistics and Market Analysis.</p>
<p>&quot;The consensus of opinion is that 1996 will be another year of marginal change, plus or minus, and a very challenging year for the industry,&quot; he added in the CEPI publication &quot;Annual Statistics&quot; for 1995.</p>
<p>He said this year was expected to be a mirror image of 1995, a year which was disappointing for the industry despite a good start.</p>
<p>In contrast to last year, 1996 got off to a weak start with a drop of 6.4 percent in paper and of 9.7 percent in pulp production in the first quarter, due largely to destocking.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition to the inadequate operating rates because of lack of orders, profitability was affected by the collapse in the price of market pulp and softening of paper prices,&quot; Kessener said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the basic growth in consumption for most grades of paper remains good and most of the destocking is over, there is some concern about the impact of instability in the global pulp market, some large increases in capacity and the potential for economic and political stagnation in Europe,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Brussels newsroom, Fredrik Dahl +32 2 287 68 11</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
