<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7110" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy bank rates should come down - Treasury source.</title>
<headline>Italy bank rates should come down - Treasury source.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian inflation is falling but bank interest rates are at a standstill and there is no economic reason why they should not fall, an Italian Treasury source said.</p>
<p>&quot;The struggle against inflation is directed at making bank interest rates fall,&quot; a Treasury source said.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment there is a sort of unnatural standstill in banking rates compared to inflation which is indisputably getting better, in line with the efforts being made to bring it down to 3.0 percent by the year end,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are currently no economic reasons why banking rates shouldn't fall,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>Italian data showed consumer prices grew 3.6 percent year on year in July but fell 0.2 percent on a month on month basis and have been coming down gradually for several months.</p>
<p>The source was speaking before preliminary CPI data from six out of 10 sample cities is released at 1530 GMT.</p>
<p>He said he did not want to anticipate the figures, which analysts forecast will show a year on year rate of 3.4 percent and a monthly rise of 0.1 to 0.2 percent.</p>
<p>But he said, &quot;The (recent) fall in prices does not automatically signify recession but can be considered a consequence of wages policy and the recovery of the lira after a 1995 penalised by political instability.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Without that (instability effect) the fall in prices would be more marked,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>The lira has strengthened and stabilised considerably since last year when it hit historic lows against the mark.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +39 2 66129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
