<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7112" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Buba rate decision key for German share outlook.</title>
<headline>Buba rate decision key for German share outlook.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Short-term prospects for German shares hinge almost entirely on the outcome of the Bundesbank's council meeting on Thursday, dealers said Wednesday afternoon.</p>
<p>Dealers warned of a knee-jerk reaction downwards should the meeting fail to yield a cut in the securities repurchase rate, or repo, or a move to a variable repo.</p>
<p>In late trading Wednesday, the IBIS DAX index which tracks electronic trade was down 22.95 points at 2,539.17, undermined by a stronger-than expected Ifo business climate report which shook the market's faith that a repo cut was imminent.  </p>
<p>The report showed the July Ifo index soared to 94.1 from 90.1 in June, sharply exceeding expectations and signalling a level of confidence about business prospects that might stall the Bundesbank from cutting rates.</p>
<p>Although a majority of economists said the report made a rate easing less likely, many dealers remained hopeful that a repo cut of five to 10 basis points was in the offing.</p>
<p>&quot;The Ifo is of course a negative but if I had to flip a coin, I would still say a move is likely,&quot; said a Frankfurt dealer.  </p>
<p>Should the Bundesbank decide against cutting the repo, the DAX risks a drop as low as 2,480 points over the coming days via a support around 2,510, one Duesseldorf dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has been overbought for several weeks now and I think if we got back to those lower levels people would start to buy back in,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>Dealers also warned that a small five-basis-point cut in the repo might not have a positive impact, and that the market would really prefer a move to a variable rate repo -- which few observers expect -- as this would leave more scope for further rate declines in the future.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the fact that more investors returned to the market on Wednesday, when prices were falling, indicated that a downward trend was in place.</p>
<p>Trading had been lacklustre earlier in the week.</p>
<p>Among shares under pressure was utility Viag AG, which was down 9.35 marks at 560 marks in IBIS trade after reporting a 21 percent drop in its first-half pre-tax profit, which dealers said was at the low end of expectations.</p>
<p>Retail stocks also remained under pressure, which dealers suggested may be linked to the stalemate in talks to agree a wage and work hours deal to cope with liberalised shop hours.  </p>
<p>The market overall will remain strongly vulnerable to the Bund market, always a strong leader for shares, and a major factor in their weakness on Wednesday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've already seen Bunds fall through several supports today. Whatever they do on the Bundesbank, we are likely to follow,&quot; said a Frankfurt dealer.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
