<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7113" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek markets welcome early elections talk.</title>
<headline>Greek markets welcome early elections talk.</headline>
<byline>George Georgiopoulos</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek Premier Costas Simitis is set to call early elections this week aiming to focus more closely on European economic and monetary union with a new mandate, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Financial markets have welcomed the elections talk.</p>
<p>&quot;It is better to hold elections now rather than later because political cost will weigh less in economic and foreign affairs decision-making,&quot; said Panos Panayiotopoulos, chief money market dealer at private Alpha Credit Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The reaction of the markets has been positive so far judging from the behaviour of the stock market, the drachma and interbank rates,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He forecast a fall in interest rates based on a receding political risk premium. Markets were bound to discount a fall in inflation and an improvement in the budget deficit.</p>
<p>The Athens bourse climbed 2.3 percent on Tuesday when the hint of elections came from the government. Trading resumed firmer on Wednesday with stocks gaining a further 0.96 percent.</p>
<p>A cabinet meeting scheduled for Friday was moved up to Thursday when Simitis was expected to make the official announcement for early polls.</p>
<p>Officials said the prime minister could choose to make the announcement on Friday after a joint meeting of his PASOK socialist party parliamentary group and central committee.</p>
<p>The constitution requires that polls must be held within a month after they are announced and the most probable dates are September 22 or 29. Elections are now scheduled for October next year.</p>
<p>&quot;The market prefers a compressed pre-election period rather than a prolonged one, as planning in the public and private sectors will not have to deal with a short 12-month horizon but look longer term,&quot; said broker Dimitris Paparistidis at Kappa Securities.</p>
<p>A decision to go to the polls early would end a period of uncertainty that has led Athens's battered bourse to very low levels. The benchmark index had turned south, below 900 points, with a negative year-to-date performance.</p>
<p>&quot;The run-up in equities is starting from very low levels. Couple this with improved macroeconomic indicators as we get closer to the implementation phase of key infrastructure projects and you have three reasons for the rise,&quot; Paparistidis said.</p>
<p>This echoes well with other market watchers as well. Senior dealers at foreign banks are bullish on early elections since a renewed mandate will make it easier for the government to take tough economic measures.</p>
<p>Simitis and his Finance Minister Alexandros Papadopoulos are in the final stages of putting together next year's budget which includes cuts of $1.2 billion in state spending and the restructuring of public companies to boost growth.</p>
<p>&quot;I think elections is the best solution. It will help clear up the political front ahead of tough economic decision making,&quot; said fund manager Alexandros Sarrigeorgiou at Allianz Mutual Funds.</p>
<p>&quot;What is the most positive is the fact that it is the first time that no matter which party wins the elections in Greece, it will be a one-way street in terms of economic policy,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
