<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7118" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: More bodies not ruled out in Belgian sex scandal.</title>
<headline>More bodies not ruled out in Belgian sex scandal.</headline>
<byline>Lorrayne Smith</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police working on Belgium's worst child-sex scandal were to meet on Wednesday with a British detective who specialises in finding buried bodies, but hopes flickered that two abducted Belgian girls could be found alive.</p>
<p>Superintendent John Bennett, who led the investigation into the &quot;House of Horrors&quot; serial murders in Gloucester, western England, came to Belgium following contacts between the two countries' police forces, Belgian police said.</p>
<p>&quot;We always expect it is possible to find more bodies. There are still people missing, so it is always a possibility,&quot; Major Boudin, a spokesman for the gendarmerie's missing children squad, told Reuters.</p>
<p>He declined to say where the meeting with Bennett would take place or how long he would stay in the country.</p>
<p>The sight of Belgian police digging for bodies at properties owned by chief suspect Marc Dutroux evoked memories of scenes at the Gloucester house where British detectives excavated the remains of Rosemary and Fred West's dismembered victims.</p>
<p>The Wests' victims were buried beneath a cellar, bathroom and in the garden of the house.</p>
<p>The whereabouts of the missing girls, An Marchal and Eefje Lambrecks, remains a mystery. Dutroux, a convicted child sex abuser who served time in prison between 1989 and 1992, has admitted kidnapping the pair in the port of Ostend last August.</p>
<p>Dutroux, arrested last week, stunned the nation by leading police to the bodies of two eight-year-olds, Julie Lejeune and Melissa Russo, buried in the garden of a house he owns near Charleroi in southern Belgium.</p>
<p>The girls, abducted in June 1995, starved to death early this year while Dutroux was in prison for theft and violence.</p>
<p>Dutroux also told police of two other abducted girls -- Laetitia Delhez, 14, and Sabine Dardenne, 12 -- who were subsequently found alive in a makeshift concrete dungeon in another of his houses. Both had been sexually abused.</p>
<p>Some newspapers likened the outpouring of public grief over Russo and Lejeune's deaths to the national display of mourning after the death of the much-loved King Baudouin three years ago.</p>
<p>Mountains of flowers carpeted the lawns at the girls' homes. Thousands have signed condolence registers around the country.</p>
<p>At a local funeral home the bodies of the two friends lay side by side in white coffins with brass plaques inscribed simply &quot;Julie&quot; and &quot;Melissa&quot;. Weeping mourners have been filing past from morning till night at a rate of 500 an hour.</p>
<p>The two girls are to be buried in a private ceremony on Thursday, to be followed by a televised public memorial service in Liege at which police expect up to 100,000 people.</p>
<p>Justice Minister Stefaan De Clerck and Public Services Minister Andre Flahaut are to represent the government at the funeral.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in renewed efforts to find Marchal and Lambrecks, 30 more detectives are to join the team which has widened its searches to a number of other countries, including Britain.</p>
<p>Neufchateau public prosecutor Michel Bourlet told a news conference on Tuesday that there were indications that the girls might still be alive.</p>
<p>At least 15 children have disappeared in Belgium in the past six years. Seven have now been found dead, six are still missing and only two have been rescued.</p>
<p>Dutroux was sentenced to 13 years in jail in 1989 for multiple rape and child abuse, only to be released 10 years early in 1992 despite stern warnings from the prosecutor involved and from his own mother.</p>
<p>Belgian media have accused the judicial authorities of incompetence in handling the investigation, citing a lack of cooperation between the authorities involved and adding that investigators had ignored warnings about Dutroux's practices.</p>
<p>Justice Minister De Clerck has promised that a judge from Liege will look into whether mistakes were made.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
