<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7121" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>VATICAN: Pope appears in good form at post-illness audience.</title>
<headline>Pope appears in good form at post-illness audience.</headline>
<dateline>VATICAN CITY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pope John Paul, who underwent a hospital checkup last week after complaining of abdominal pain, appeared in good form at his weekly Vatican audience on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The spiritual leader of the world's 960 million Catholics presided at the 75-minute audience without any signs of fatigue or discomfort as he read greetings in more than 10 languages to some 10,000 people in the Vatican's modern audience hall.</p>
<p>This was in marked contrast with some of his public appearances last week, when he had looked tired and in pain.</p>
<p>At the end of the audience the 76-year-old Polish Pontiff chatted with pilgrims and smiled as he greeted sick Ukrainian children.</p>
<p>Concern for the Pope, who has had a spate of health problems in recent years, was raised last week when abdominal pains forced him to skip morning mass at his summer residence south of Rome and enter hospital for a checkup.</p>
<p>The Vatican said a CAT (Computed Axial Tomography) scan showed nothing seriously out of order, particularly in relation to a 1992 operation to remove an intestinal tumour that was starting to turn malignant.</p>
<p>The Pope has been taking antibiotics for the unspecified abdominal problem, characterised as a mild infection, which also caused him to suffer a mild fever last week, officials said.</p>
<p>The Vatican has said Papal visits to Hungary and France in September would go ahead as planned.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VATICAN CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VATICAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
