<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7124" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain's Pryca boosted by H1 results talk.</title>
<headline>Spain's Pryca boosted by H1 results talk.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Spanish retail store chain Pryca were sharply higher at midday on talk that first half results will be strong, dealers and analysts said.</p>
<p>At 1125 GMT, Pryca was up 80 pesetas to 3,105, off a high of 3,160 pesetas. The Ibex-35 index was up 17.23 points, 0.43 percent, to 4,005.00.</p>
<p>&quot;Relatively low sales growth in the first half will still mean (first half) profits increase by around 25-30 percent,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>A second analyst said Pryca was expected to benefit from a more aggressive business strategy in the same period.</p>
<p>In the first quarter Pryca posted a 42 percent year-on-year profit increase on the back of an around six percent sales increase.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the company said: &quot;This is a typical month which invites this kind of talk. This year consumption is not advancing very well. And as regards results, we'll see what they're like at the beginning of September.&quot;</p>
<p>Rumours were also doing the rounds that Carrefour, which controls around 60 percent of Pryca, was to buy out the Spanish retailer.</p>
<p>These were dismissed as groundless by analysts.</p>
<p>One who requested anonymity said: &quot;Every now and again this rumour is bandied about, but it doesn't make any sense. All is does is send the price up. Someone is trying to send the price up,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom +341 585 2160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
