<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7127" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Thousands rush to beat Spain immigration deadline.</title>
<headline>Thousands rush to beat Spain immigration deadline.</headline>
<byline>Joelle Diderich</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of people are rushing to beat a Friday immigration deadline and long queues have formed at Spanish police stations while more people head for Spain's southern coast in makeshift boats.</p>
<p>Immigrants who have temporary residence and in some cases work permits have until late on Friday to claim papers allowing them and relatives and dependents to stay in Spain legally.</p>
<p>Although this applies only to those who arrived in Spain before January 1, 1996, hundreds of North Africans are risking life and limb crossing the narrow Strait of Gibraltar in makeshift boats in the belief they too can profit from it.</p>
<p>They head for Spain's south coast in groups as small as four or as large as 30, lured by false promises of guaranteed work and residence permits from ruthless middlemen out to line their own pockets, immigration associations say.</p>
<p>Coastal police say it is customary to see a sharp increase in the number attempting the crossing in the summer, when weather conditions are optimal, but this year numbers are even higher than usual.</p>
<p>More than 380 illegal immigrants have been plucked from the seas near Gibraltar since the beginning of August, according to police officials in Algeciras. Around 1,100 have been caught trying to cross the Strait so far this year, compared with a total of 1,563 in 1992.</p>
<p>For many, their only time on Spanish soil will be in police stations where they face a swift return to their country of origin with a probable prison sentence on arrival. They also lose the black market fare for the crossing, which can run up to 150,000 pesetas ($1,200).</p>
<p>There are currently 461,000 foreigners legally living in Spain, 82,600 of them Africans, the Interior Ministry said.</p>
<p>This year's scheme attracted 13,090 applications between its launch in April and early July.</p>
<p>Moroccans were the largest group applying for legalisation, closely followed by Latin Americans, in particular from Peru, the Dominican Republic and Argentina.</p>
<p>On Wednesday morning, the queues stretched around the block at a Madrid police station charged with handling applications.</p>
<p>But unions say that many of those entitled to documents will miss out, while experts warn that illegal immigrants will keep arriving even after the Friday's deadline expires.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately, this will not end on August 23,&quot; said Rafael Lara, spokesman for the Cadiz Solidarity Platform, an organisation which helps immigrants.</p>
<p>&quot;There are very powerful mafia interests which are earning a lot of money, the government of Morocco is blatantly turning a blind eye and is thus encouraging the poorest people to have false illusions,&quot; Lara told state television.</p>
<p>Spain's unions have asked for the deadline to be extended, saying the scheme's conditions are too strict and many people will miss out because they do not fufill one of them.</p>
<p>Francisco Soriano, immigration secretary at Workers' Commissions, says up to 50,000 foreigners who have lost their work permits in the last few years are eligible but up to 70 percent could be rejected.</p>
<p>Other unions said the scheme should extend to those working in the black economy, who are often scared of declaring themselves to authorities for fear their situation will get worse, not better.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
