<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7132" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Banisadr to testify on Iran ties in Berlin court.</title>
<headline>Banisadr to testify on Iran ties in Berlin court.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Iranian president Abolhassan Banisadr will testify in a heavily-guarded German courtroom on Thursday that a 1992 gangland-style killing of Kurd opposition leaders was backed by the Iranian government.</p>
<p>Banisadr was expected to repeat before the Berlin court accusations made in June that Iran's president and religious leader knew of and blessed the assassination of three Iranian Kurdish leaders and their translator at a Berlin restaurant.</p>
<p>Tehran has denied the allegations.</p>
<p>Banisadr, 63, has warned the German authorities that two teams of Iranian-backed assassins were planning to pursue him in Germany, Parvis Dastmalchi, a survivor of the 1992 attack, told Berlin television station B1 on Tuesday evening.</p>
<p>&quot;I talked with Banisadr on the telephone and he told me that...two teams of assassins are on the way,&quot; Dastmalchi said in the interview.</p>
<p>&quot;One is a five-man team from Tehran and the second team consists of non-Iranians and they will be coming to Germany via Sweden. Their aim is clear. They want to frighten Banisadr.&quot;</p>
<p>Banisadr will be the prosecution's star witness in the court on Thursday and Friday when he elaborates on his allegations that Iranian President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani and Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, Iran's religious leader, backed the attack.</p>
<p>His testimony looks certain to be the high point of the 33-month trial that has been full of cloak-and-dagger revelations and characterised by secret service involvement.</p>
<p>Two masked men armed with machine guns burst into the Mykonos restaurant on September 17, 1992 and fired at dozens of Iranian dissidents seated at a table.</p>
<p>Three leaders of the Iranian Democratic Party of Kurdistan (DPK-I) and their translator were killed in a hail of bullets.</p>
<p>One Iranian, Kazem Darabi, and four Lebanese nationals are standing trial on charges of murdering the dissidents.</p>
<p>The case has strained relations between Bonn and Tehran, particularly after prosecutors issued an arrest warrant in March for Iranian Intelligence Minister Ali Fallahiyan, accusing him of masterminding the attack.</p>
<p>Tehran has denied his involvement and said there was no evidence the Iranian defendant and his four suspected accomplices on trial were acting as its henchmen.</p>
<p>Tehran has also cast doubt on the credibility of Banisadr's remarks, saying that he is a fierce opponent of Iran's Islamic fundamentalist government and that 14 years have passed since his government was toppled and his ties to Iran severed.</p>
<p>Banisadr also alleged in a pre-trial interview in Paris in June that the Iranian defendant Darabi was a confidant of Fallahiyan.</p>
<p>Security at the Berlin criminal court has been extremely tight during the trial, where the defendants are sealed off behind bullet-proof glass and the judges and attorneys are provided with bodyguards.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
