<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7138" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Spring barley in east France seen good for malting.</title>
<headline>Spring barley in east France seen good for malting.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spring barley in eastern France came off the fields in excellent shape for malting this year but winter barley suffered excess protein, analysts said.</p>
<p>A crop analyst at regional capital Dijon said on Wednesday that spring barley was giving test weights of around 66 kilos per hectolitre and protein of 11 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We have the volume, the weight and the weak protein we need for malting. It's looking very good,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A dry spring had pushed winter barley protein levels up to around 12.5 percent, a level usually rejected by the malting industry as too high, he said.</p>
<p>Forecast spring barley yields of 4.8 tonnes per hectare could be revised up slightly and winter barley yields were seen near 5.2 tonnes, he said.</p>
<p>The Dijon region is France's second spring barley producer by area and the has the country's biggest winter barley sowings.</p>
<p>National cereals office ONIC last month predicted regional yields of 4.5 and 5.0 tonnes respectively for spring and winter barley this year. Last year's yields were 4.48 tonnes for spring barley and 5.79 tonnes for winter barley.</p>
<p>ONIC estimates published in July show the area of land sown to spring barley by the region's farmers fell to 49,000 hectares from last year's 51,400 hectares.</p>
<p>Winter barley sowings rose to 142,000 hectares from 130,350.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5146</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
