<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7144" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Guilder deposits up on Ifo, Treasury buys back DTCs.</title>
<headline>Guilder deposits up on Ifo, Treasury buys back DTCs.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch money market rates edged up on Wednesday after a much higher than expected German Ifo business climate index dimmed hopes of a repo rate cut by the Bundesbank on Thursday.</p>
<p>Three-month deposits rose two basis points to 2.98 percent, but near-term guilder interest rates remained stable.</p>
<p>The Dutch Treasury was buying five- and seven-day guilders, running between August 22 and August 29 as it needed to cover liquidity shortages. But excess cash in September also prompted repurchasing offers for Dutch Treasury Certificates (DTCs) between August 30 and September 30.</p>
<p>&quot;Our cash position looks good in September, so we can withdraw DTCs from the market and save the state some interest payments,&quot; a Finance Ministry debt agency spokesman said.</p>
<p>There was no one big reason for the September cash pile.</p>
<p>Prices for the DTC repurchase were not very competitive and the Finance Ministry had executed few deals, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The DTC repos were quoted at 2.85/90 percent whereas one-month guilder deposits were trading at 2.89/97 percent.</p>
<p>The spread with German money remained stable and the guilder was steady at 112.16 per 100 marks.</p>
<p>Dealers expect the guilder to underperform the mark if the Bundesbank does not cut the repo rate.</p>
<p>-- Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000, Fax +31 20 504 5040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
