<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7145" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German court set to give verdict on U.S. neo-Nazi.</title>
<headline>German court set to give verdict on U.S. neo-Nazi.</headline>
<byline>Susanne Frank</byline>
<dateline>HAMBURG, Germany 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Hamburg court will deliver its verdict on Thursday on U.S. neo-Nazi leader Gary Lauck, accused of running a worldwide propaganda network which has pumped extremist material into Germany for two decades.</p>
<p>Lauck, dubbed the &quot;farm-belt Fuehrer&quot; by U.S. Nazi watchers, has maintained a defiant silence during the three-month trial.</p>
<p>He left his lawyer to argue that the court has no right to try him and that his extradition to Germany last year was illegal. But the attorney held out little hope of an acquittal.</p>
<p>&quot;I assume the court will convict him because it has rejected several objections I have raised during the trial and that is the only explanation for the judges' actions,&quot; defence lawyer Hans-Otto Sieg told Reuters.</p>
<p>Publishing and distributing neo-Nazi material is illegal in Germany but Sieg insists Lauck broke no laws in the United States and prosecutors have not proved he was deliberately smuggling material into Germany.</p>
<p>Prosecutors have demanded five years' jail for the 43-year-old from Lincoln, Nebraska, who heads the National Socialist German Workers' Party Foreign Organisation (NSDAP-AO) -- a name derived from the full German title of Hitler's Nazi party.</p>
<p>Lauck is charged with inciting racial hatred by producing anti-Semitic and rightist publications and propaganda including posters, badges and stickers, and distributing them to Germany and the rest of the world from his home in the United States.</p>
<p>Investigators say Lauck, who sports a thick Hitleresque moustache, was the main source of neo-Nazi material in Germany for about 20 years. But prosecutors have concentrated on the last few years in a bid to secure a quick conviction.</p>
<p>Lauck's only remarks to the court came on the opening day of his trial in May, when he gave flippant answers in fluent German to a judge's questions about his personal details.</p>
<p>He said he was &quot;not sure&quot; if he was still married and, when asked if he had any children, he replied: &quot;Not as far as I know. I have a dog and two cats.&quot;</p>
<p>Lauck's conviction would be a major coup for Nazi-busting prosecutors, who have been trying to get him extradited to Germany for trial for years. Their chance finally came when the U.S. citizen visited Denmark in March last year.</p>
<p>Police detained him there on an international arrest warrant and the courts decided he could be extradited as, although neo-Nazi propaganda is not illegal there, his material was so extreme it violated Denmark's racial hatred laws.</p>
<p>Lauck is also accused of portraying violence and disseminating insignia and propaganda of anti-constitutional organisations in his publications produced in ten languages.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
