<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7148" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German call money steady, repo hopes dampened.</title>
<headline>German call money steady, repo hopes dampened.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>German call money rates were unchanged at 3.25-3.30 percent on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Several money dealers said the news of a sharp rise in the Ifo institute's west German business climate index had dampened hopes of a repo rate cut at Thursday's Bundesbank council meeting.</p>
<p>The Ifo index rose to 94.1 in July from 90.4 in June, well above economists' expectations for 91.0.</p>
<p>Neither the Ifo index nor Tuesday's news of an M3 growth slowdown to 8.6 percent in July suggested that the Bundesbank would cut the 3.30 percent repo rate tomorrow, dealers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We don't expect a cut tomorrow,&quot; one money dealer at a major German bank said. But he added that he would not rule out a cut.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, this week's bank bids for 14-day repos were unusually low at 80 billion marks, suggesting that some banks had been expecting a cut and had refrained from bids because they hoped to obtain cheaper repo funds next week.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank allocated 69 billion marks of repo funds today. A repo pact totalling 69.9 billion marks expired today so a net 900 million marks was drained from the money market.  </p>
<p>Banks held 39.7 billion marks in deposits at the Bundesbank on Tuesday, up from 39.1 billion marks on Monday. The monthly average was at 38.4 billion marks, up from 38.3 billion marks.</p>
<p>Bank borrowing from the Bundesbank's Lombard lending facility was negligible on Tuesday after totalling about 100 million marks on Monday.</p>
<p>The Frankfurt Interbank Overnight Average rate was 3.31983 percent on Wednesday, up from 3.31417 percent on Tuesday.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
