<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7152" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bonn sells 3.16 bln dmk Bobls at 99.11 and over.</title>
<headline>Bonn sells 3.16 bln dmk Bobls at 99.11 and over.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German government issued 3.16 billion marks in five percent, Series 119 five-year government bonds, or Bobls, in an auction on Wednesday at a price of 99.11 and above, the Bundesbank as issuing agent said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The average yield on the paper was 5.20 percent and the weighted average price was 99.12, the Bundesbank said.  </p>
<p>Tap issuance of Series 119 Bobls to non-banks ceased on Tuesday August 20.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank said 2.36 billion marks of the issue was sold to non-banks via tap issuance. A total of 2.48 billion marks of the issue was retained by the Bundesbank for market-smoothing purposes.</p>
<p>Together with the auction tranche of 3.16 billion marks, the total volume of the Series 119 issue comes to eight billion marks, the Bundesbank said.</p>
<p>The auction tranche of the Series 119 will be bourse-listed on Monday, August 26. The pay date for the tranche is Friday, August 23.</p>
<p>Bank bids for the auction tranche totalled 11.49 billion marks, the Bundesbank said.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
