<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7172" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's Bossi hits out ahead of &quot;independence day&quot;.</title>
<headline>Italy's Bossi hits out ahead of &quot;independence day&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Philip Pullella</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Umberto Bossi, firebrand leader of the separatist Northern League, on Wednesday hit back at magistrates who want to probe him for violating political ethics, saying he does not answer to judges of &quot;colonial Italy&quot;.</p>
<p>Magistrates in three northern cities sent documents to parliament on Tuesday seeking a green light to continue probes that could lead to Bossi being tried on charges of making threatening comments against political adversaries.</p>
<p>Bossi, who on September 15 is set to lead a big demonstration at which the League has threatened to declare an independent northern &quot;state&quot;, said the action by the judges was part of a plot to stop the movement.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't give a damn. We know what the magistrature is. This is just a manoeuvre by colonial Italy,&quot; he told the Turin newspaper La Stampa in an interview.</p>
<p>The magistrates want a parliamentary commission to decide if remarks Bossi made at rallies in 1995 are punishable as a crime or whether he has protection as a member of parliament under Italy's constitution. The commission is due to rule next month.</p>
<p>They have accused Bossi of inciting people to commit crimes and making threatening remarks at political rallies last year, where he threatened that League members would seek out and punish those who voted for the far-right National Alliance.</p>
<p>Ironically, the latest moves against Bossi -- who has hurled invectives against nearly everybody in the political spectrum -- came from magistrates in the north, his political stronghold.</p>
<p>The cigar-smoking Bossi was not intimidated by the latest judicial moves against him.</p>
<p>&quot;It's clear by now that there is a war of nerves between Rome and Padania,&quot; Bossi told an interviewer, referring to the name the League would give to an independent north.</p>
<p>&quot;Either Padania wins or Rome and Italian colonialism wins. It will be a very tough battle because they have the police and the magistrates on their side.&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are Padanians. We prefer to die rather than live without freedom,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In another irony, Bossi is being probed in connection with a law that forbids the reconstitution of the Fascist party. Provisions of that law forbid &quot;anti-democratic&quot; methods or threats of violence as means to a political end.</p>
<p>Commentators said it was the wrong way to stop Bossi. &quot;Evidently, there is no limit to the ridiculous in Italy,&quot; Piero Ostellino wrote in Milan's Corriere della Sera.</p>
<p>Bossi's supporters immediately attacked the magistrature.</p>
<p>&quot;These initiatives smack of pure fascism because they try to limit freedom of expression and thought,&quot; said Roberto Maroni, a former interior minister and leading member of the League.</p>
<p>For most of an otherwise politically quiet August, Italians have been treated to a string of Bossi's outbursts.</p>
<p>He accused the secret services of plotting to discredit him, branded the speaker of parliament a fascist and called for supporters to destroy relay stations of state broadcaster RAI.</p>
<p>The League took root in the 1980s as a protest movement against the excesses of Rome central government and was instrumental in helping bring about the collapse of the old, corrupt political guard at the start of the 1990s.</p>
<p>Its support has grown steadily and at the April election it polled 10 percent of the vote nationwide and over 30 percent in parts of the rich north of Italy.</p>
<p>Since the vote, Bossi has dropped his calls for a federalist state, saying the only way forward was outright secession.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
