<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7177" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Hopes up for missing Irish tourists after call - RTE.</title>
<headline>Hopes up for missing Irish tourists after call - RTE.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hopes that three Irish tourists feared missing in Australia were alive and well rose when a friend in Ireland said he had received a telephone call from one of them, Irish national broadcaster, RTE, said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Sandra Mahon, Stuart Gamble and Neil Hewson, all aged 25, who were on a working holiday in Australia, were last seen in Cairns on the state's far north coast on Saturday.</p>
<p>Concerns for the safety of the three backpackers mounted when Sandra Mahon called her father in a &quot;distressed and upset state&quot; in Ireland last Saturday and the line went dead.</p>
<p>A friend of Sandra Mahon said Sandra called him at her old workplace in Ireland on Tuesday night and he was satisfied it was her, the RTE report said.</p>
<p>A cash withdrawal on Sandra Mahon's bankcard took place at a bank machine at 10:30 a.m. local time on Wednesday at Mission Beach south of Cairns in Queensland.</p>
<p>Local witnesses said someone matching Mahon's description was seen in the vicinity of Mission Beach and Australian police said it would concentrate its search in that area, the RTE report said.</p>
<p>Australian police told RTE that although it was strange that the three had not contacted the authorities to say they were safe it was possible they were not listening to the radio.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
