<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7178" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: INSTANT VIEW - July west German Ifo index 94.1.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - July west German Ifo index 94.1.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are analysts reaction to the west German Ifo business confidence index for July, which rose to 94.1 from 90.4 in June. The June figure was a three-month low. Economists in a Reuter survey had on average predicted the index at 91.0 for July.</p>
<p>Karen Kricks-Brunnlieb, Trinkaus &amp; Burkhardt</p>
<p>&quot;The figure is much higher than expected, but it doesn't change our expectations because we do not expect a repo rate cut.&quot;  </p>
<p>Armin Kayser, Swiss Bank Corp, Frankfurt:</p>
<p>&quot;I think the Ifo numbers have been quite in contrast to economic reality during the last few months. The assessment of the business situation, which is one part of the Ifo business sentiment figure, has been deterioriating while the real data, such as industrial production, has been trending upward.</p>
<p>&quot;I still don't expect any move tomorrow. My view has not changed because of this data. The upward revision of new orders data and the improvement in the Ifo data do not favour a rate cut. There is no strong reason for the Bundesbank to stimulate the economy.</p>
<p>Rainer Veit, DB Research, Frankfurt:</p>
<p>&quot;This is very difficult to assesss. June was a very difficult figure and saw it as an abberation to the trend. The July figure is again somewhat an abberation figure. One sector may have contributed to the data, the energy sector.  </p>
<p>&quot;The overall picture of the economy is that it slowed down considerably. The overall perception will definitely not change because of this figure.</p>
<p>&quot;We still see a 60 percent probability of a repo rate cut tomorrow, of about five to 10 basis points. It would keep the interest rate hopes alive.</p>
<p>&quot;We still see potential for a (discount) rate cut two percent.&quot;</p>
<p>Fritz Engelhard, Bayerische Vereinsbank, Munich:</p>
<p>&quot;It is an improvement over last month but we have to take the figures as they are. The rebound is from a very weak reading and, of course, I think the trend must continue to that extent.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that this number doesn't change much in the Bundesbank's view to cut the repo rate by about 10 basis points. Even if they don't do it tomorrow, the expectations should be very high that they do it soon. They focus very much on credit growth.</p>
<p>&quot;A second thing is that the Bundesbank is focusing very much on the forex market. The mark is not at the level that they would like. They would prefer a weaker mark.&quot;</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
