<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7181" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian/U.S. bond spread sliced on S&amp;P.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian/U.S. bond spread sliced on S&amp;P.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p> AUD VS   3-YR	   10-YR	* AUD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p> USD	 84 (- 12)   126 (- 14) * FUTURES   71.5 (- 01.5)</p>
<p> CAD	123 (- 10)    61 (- 12) * CASH	85   (- 01)</p>
<p> NZD     -114 (- 09)   -22 (- 08) *</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The Australian/U.S. 10-year bond yield spread tumbled after Standard &amp; Poor's said it had revised Australia's outlook to positive from stable, traders said.  </p>
<p>The spread sunk to around 125 basis points (b.p.), breaching the pre-budget 130 b.p. resistance low seen on Tuesday and to its lowest level in over two years.</p>
<p>The spread had firmed to 140 b.p. late on Tuesday as the local market took profits on its recent strong rally after Treasurer Peter Costello's budget, while tough, did not provide any surprises.</p>
<p>In the space of just four months the spread to the U.S. has been halved on Australia's positive inflation outlook, combined with last month's cut in official interest rates, and analysts see scope for a further spread tightening.  </p>
<p>&quot;With clear evidence of a softening economy, in the context of easily the most fiscally aggressive budget ever providing a sound basis for future surpluses and the recent explict commitment from the RBA to target underlying inflation in a 2-3 percent band, the margin between Australian and U.S. ten-year is now set to test 100 basis points,&quot; economists at Westpac said in a report.</p>
<p>S&amp;P said it had revised the outlook to positive from stable and affirmed Australia's long-term AA and A1-plus short-term foreign currency ratings.  </p>
<p>&quot;The outlook change reflects the substantial fiscal tightening implied by the Commonwealth Government's budget statement released yesterday (Tuesday) and Standard and Poor's expectation that Australia's net public external debt burden could decline markedly if this fiscal stance is maintained medium term,&quot; the ratings agency said.</p>
<p>Local bond yields dropped to their lowest level since March 1994 on the S&amp;P news, while U.S. Treasuries remained stable in Tokyo trading after the Federal Open Market Committee left policy unchanged.</p>
<p>-- Colin Brinsden 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
