<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7182" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ shares end firmer, FCL Forest gains after sale.</title>
<headline>NZ shares end firmer, FCL Forest gains after sale.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>* New Zealand share prices ended firmer</p>
<p>* Fletcher Forest gains after sale of Forestry Corp</p>
<p>* Natural Gas at year high after result</p>
<p>---------------------------(Aug 21)---------------------------</p>
<p>Price movements at close</p>
<p>	    LAST CHG</p>
<p>141  nil  * NZSE-40 cap index +7.97 at 2,175.76</p>
<p>317  + 2  * NZSC cap index +5.81 at 4,368.56</p>
<p>286  + 1  * NZSE-10 cap index +5.83 at 1,097.62</p>
<p>373  + 1  * Volume NZ$30 million. Futures +8 at 1,112</p>
<p>674  + 6  * Other movers - +4 +50</p>
<p>New Zealand share prices ended firmer on Wednesday after a moderate session, with Fletcher Forest enjoying a modest re-rating after Tuesday's news that it been successful in its bid for Forestry Corp of NZ.</p>
<p>The NZSE-40 Capital Index ended 7.97 points higher at 2,175.76 on turnover of around NZ$30 million.</p>
<p>Fletcher Forest ended four cents higher at NZ$1.86 while Brierley Investments, its partner in the consortium buying Forestry Corp, gained one to $1.42.</p>
<p>BIL is also expected to soon stage a partial withdrawal from its majority ownership of British hotels giant Thistle.  </p>
<p>Yield-sensitive stock Telecom gained six cents to $6.74 after a mild rally in the bond market.</p>
<p>Fisher and Paykel was steady on NZ$4.71 but Campbell Johnstone at Hendry Hay McIntosh said decision by discount retailer The Warehouse to sell AEG appliances may have a negative impact on F&amp;P.</p>
<p>There was weakness in Wilson and Horton before its first half result, expected on Thursday, the publisher falling eight cents to NZ$9.30.</p>
<p>Analysts expect a net profit of NZ$21-22 million.  </p>
<p>Property stocks have been quite strong, particularly St Lukes and Kiwi Income. &quot;Maybe there are some investors who are looking to get themselves into interest rate-sensitive stocks, those two and Telecom,&quot; Johnstone said.</p>
<p>Natural Gas Corp, which earlier reported a solid improvement in annual profit to NZ$28.0 million from $22.2 million, gained five cents to a high of NZ$2.90 but on light volume.</p>
<p>-- James Gray (64 9 302 1253)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
