<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7183" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-CANBERRA WATCH - Colston exaggerates Senate fluidity.</title>
<headline>RTRS-CANBERRA WATCH - Colston exaggerates Senate fluidity.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Perrett</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senator Mal Colston's resignation from the Labor Party on Monday makes the Senate much more fluid than one would imagine.</p>
<p>One of the powerful, yet rarely mentioned, dynamics of the Senate is the Democrats' urgent need to keep the limelight.</p>
<p>The Democrats can exist only while their leader, Cheryl Kernot, continues to appear in the media as a powerbroker, &quot;keeping the bastards honest&quot;, as their slogan goes.</p>
<p>The Democrats are players in the Senate or they are nothing.</p>
<p>Looking like players was not hard in the last parliament, where the Labor government had to get the votes of all but one of the 11 balance-of-power senators: the eight Democrats, the two Greens and Independent Brian Harradine.</p>
<p>So the Democrats were always involved. (And so were the Greens for that matter, but they really do not chase publicity in their Senate tactics, believe it or not.)</p>
<p>But the Liberal-National government needs just two of the new Senate's 10 balance-of-power senators to get legislation through.</p>
<p>The Democrats can supply those two votes, and be seen gaining concessions from the government, but so can the two Greens or either of the Greens plus Harradine.</p>
<p>To remain relevant the Democrats must back a government bill before the Greens. If the Greens supply the two votes, it is their concession that the government grants. This has been a more fluid situation than the in previous Senate, but only to the extent that the Greens might cave in on something before the Democrats -- which would happen only occasionally.</p>
<p>Now, with Colston in play, there is a second and far, far more likely source of two votes: Colston plus Harradine, who is conservative but unpredictable.</p>
<p>Imagine a budget bill coming before the Senate in these circumstances. The government talks to the Greens (probably getting nowhere), and to the Democrats and to each of the Independents.</p>
<p>If the Independents back the bill, the Democrats become as sidelined as the Labor Party and risk being seen, as electoral analyst Malcolm Mackerras says, part of a Laborcrats Party.</p>
<p>So Kernot must give ground, so the public see the government meeting Democrats concessions.</p>
<p>Now that is a much more fluid situation.</p>
<p>-- Canberra bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
