<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7192" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: FCL has offers for Hikurangi forest.</title>
<headline>FCL has offers for Hikurangi forest.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fletcher Challenge Ltd chief executive Hugh Fletcher on Wednesday said FCL Forest Division had received three unsolicited offers for its 20,000 hectare Hikurangi forest in New Zealand's North Island.</p>
<p>He said he expected the company to cover the cost of the purchase of state-owned Forestry Corporation and the purchase of the $100 million solid wood processing assets of Fletcher Building from the sales of forests.  </p>
<p>Fletcher Forest leads a consortium with Brierley Investments Ltd and China's Citic which is buying Forestry Corporation for NZ$2.026 billion. Its equity share is NZ$240 million.</p>
<p>Fletcher said the company should realise &quot;several hundred million dollars&quot; from the forest sales, but would be interested in swapping forest to create contiguous blocks.</p>
<p>Answering questions about the tax position of Fletcher Forest, he said with about $300 million of tax losses available, Fletcher Forest would have a tax liability but the bulk of it would be deferred.  </p>
<p>&quot;Somewhere out there in the future, Forests has significant cash paying liability,&quot; Fletcher said.</p>
<p>The contract for managing the Forestry Corp assets had the potential to return between nil and $20 million, Fletcher said.</p>
<p>He said the deal would &quot;improve the prospects of Fletcher Forest paying a dividend&quot; but noted that like Fletcher Energy the stock tended to be attractive for capital gain rather than its dividend stream.  </p>
<p>He said there was no transfer of value between the forest and paper division as a result of the cancellation of the government's obligations under a long term supply contract between Forestry Corp and FCL's Tasman subsidiary. The board had been careful to ensure Fletcher Paper was receiving fair compensation. -- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
