<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7193" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Australia govt urges Senate pension approval.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Australia govt urges Senate pension approval.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Treasurer Peter Costello said on Wednesday the government's workers' retirement savings plan should be approved by parliament as a package and not be changed by the Senate.</p>
<p>&quot;My argument to the Senate is that this is a balanced package, this is an economically responsible package, this ought to go ahead as a package and that you will in fact unbalance it if you start changing it in this area or the other area and there could be knock on effects all over,&quot; Costello told the National Press Club in Canberra.  </p>
<p>&quot;Of course ... there are going to be consequences if the Senate mucks around with this,&quot; Costello said.</p>
<p>The five-month-old Liberal-National government said on Tuesday it would review how to contribute money to employee's retirement savings (superannuation).</p>
<p>Costello said on Wednesday it did not need to cut the money to achieve its fiscal plans.</p>
<p>&quot;The co-payment is budgeted for in ... the forward estimates, they are ready to be spent, and if it were spent in full we would still be producing surplus in 1998 and a larger one in 1999/2000,&quot; Costello said.  </p>
<p>&quot;So it's there we don't need to touch a dollar of that to produce our bottom line.&quot;</p>
<p>Costello said an announcement would be made later this year about whether the current arrangements were the best way to pay for the plan -- a public contribution equal to three percent of each employee's earnings.</p>
<p>The 1996/97 budget papers, issued on Tuesday, show the programme costing A$1.1 billion in 1998/99 and A$2.4 billion in the following year.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
