<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7197" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Mine group say tax in budget to hurt industry.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Mine group say tax in budget to hurt industry.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Western Australian mining industry said an effective new tax on the sale of mining tenements contained in the 1996/97 Federal budget was counterproductive for the mining industry.</p>
<p>&quot;For a budget aimed at increasing growth and investor confidence in the Australian economy, this tax is counterproductive as it will change the dynamics of the most productive areas of the economy,&quot; Adrienne Wright, an analyst for the Association of Mining and Exploration Companies (Inc) of Western Australia, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Under the budget, propsectors lost long-held tax-exempt status for income from the sale or transfer of rights to mine for minerals.</p>
<p>&quot;The new tax on the sale of tenements will reduce the incentive to apply risk capital to the search for prospective areas that can be used in the formation of new companies,&quot; Wright said.</p>
<p>&quot;This will produce an unspecified but certainly negative effect on the mining industry as a whole,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>The exemption was introduced in the 1940s to provide an incentive for prospectors lacking development funds to search for gold and other minerals.</p>
<p>AMEC also said that while it welcomed the retention of the diesel fuel rebate in the budget, it voiced concern that the government's expectation of saving about A$440 million over four years through modifications would be at the expense of legitimate mining claims.</p>
<p>Miners, farmers and other off-road business diesel users receive a rebate on a tax on diesel intended as a road tax.  </p>
<p>&quot;Government's fixation with the supposed rorting (cheating) of the scheme has created an unrealistic perception of the savings to be had from eliminating this alleged practice,&quot; Wright said.</p>
<p>&quot;Suggestions that the scheme can be capped and that other savings will return them A$440 million over four years is nothing more than a cover for what will inevitably evolve into government inspired back-door procedures to eliminate legitimate claimants from the scheme,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
