<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7198" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian dollar firms on samurai talk, S&amp;P.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian dollar firms on samurai talk, S&amp;P.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar was marching higher Wednesday afternoon, cheered by a surge samurai-related demand and a positive outlook for Australia's foreign currency rating from Standard &amp; Poor's.</p>
<p>&quot;That (S&amp;P action), combined with the capacity for a further dual currency issue (out of Tokyo) to be going through the market has squeezed a market that was probably a little bit short...post-budget,&quot; one Sydney-based trader said.</p>
<p>At 4.30 p.m. (0600 GMT), the local currency was at US$0.7909/13 above Tuesday's US$0.7860/63 level after the delivery of the 1996/97 Federal budget.  </p>
<p>The unit also has gained ground on the crosses at 85.64/5.74 yen against Tuesday's late 85.09 level and 58.0 in trade-weighted terms verses 57.8 previously.</p>
<p>The dollar flopped to a low of US$0.7854 in early morning dealings as stale longs sold on comments by Prime Minister John Howard that he was hopeful of a further cut in official interest rates.</p>
<p>But solid demand, including fund interest, backed by widespread talk of more samurai issues saw the currency shrug off the rate cut comments and chart steadily higher over the afternoon.  </p>
<p>The move also set off a round of stop-loss buy orders, said one trader, who saw the Australian dollar trading in a US$0.7900-40 range for the remainder of the afternoon.</p>
<p>He noted there was some selling interest at US$0.7925.</p>
<p>S&amp;P's positive outlook for Australia's offshore ratings and affirmation of domestic ratings was widely unexpected but has helped set a bullish tone, traders said.</p>
<p>Economists, too, backed the S&amp;P move as a boon for the currency.  </p>
<p>&quot;It probably tends to alleviate any concerns that (Federal government) policies may lead eventually to a pick up in the current account...so it does look as if we're going to have a reasonably robust Australian dollar over the course of the near term,&quot; UBS Australia Ltd economist Stephen Roberts told Reuters.</p>
<p>However, budget policies, inflation optimism and sober growth forecasts meant economists still saw pressure on the dollar emerging in the medium term.  </p>
<p>Opposition party statements during the day that the budget was likely to pass through the senate mostly intact was welcomed by market participants as helping underpin the Australian dollar in the near term.</p>
<p>&quot;At the end of the day, that was the concern with the budget over the next couple of weeks, whether or not the budget would go through the senate, and it looks like it might go through pretty unadulterated&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>-- Melbourne bureau 61-3 9286-1435</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
