<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7200" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Consumer group lobbies vs NZ electricity rules.</title>
<headline>Consumer group lobbies vs NZ electricity rules.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand's Consumer Coalition on Energy on Wednesday called on the anti-monopolies Commerce Commission to decline authorisation for the proposed New Zealand electricity market rules, due to take effect on October 1.</p>
<p>The Commerce Commission today concluded a three-day conference on the proposed market rules and is due to give its decision on September 13.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're going into a brave new world, and what the Commerce Commission is being asked is to give blanket approval to these rules, and we feel that that is pretty dangerous,&quot; said David Russell, chief executive of the Consumers Institute.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got to see how things work and make sure that it's well monitored.&quot;</p>
<p>The Coalition, which comprises the Consumer Institute, the New Zealand Manufacturers Federation, Federated Farmers and the Major Electricity Users Group, said authorisation of the rules would make them immune to future legal challenge, even if in they emerged to be anti-competitive.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Commerce Commission, while it is confined by the Commerce Act, must look at the broader issues,&quot; Russell said.</p>
<p>He said there was a real risk of &quot;gaming&quot; under the proposed market rules and structure. Gaming is the practice of generators acting unilaterally to push market prices above a competitive level.</p>
<p>If the Commerce Commission gave its stamp of approval to the proposed rules, there would be no restraint on generators from forcing up the market price. &quot;And then of course the consumer is going to pay that price. The potential is certainly there for that,&quot; Russell said.  </p>
<p>He was critical of the complexity of the proposed market.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to have a computer system, I'm told, that's going to be more complicated and have a larger capacity than the New York Stock Exchange. Again, this is going to reflect back on the end price that the consumer pays, because it's going to cost a lot to play the market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;You do have to ask the question, does New Zealand need such a complicated market to develop a competitive electricity industry?&quot;  </p>
<p>He said that under the current prudential requirements, the amount that market participants had to initially lodge against default was so large it acted against smaller companies.</p>
<p>&quot;On the one hand they're saying we want competition, and yet you have the prudential requirement to play the market acting against the small company, therefore acting as an incentive for the smaller companies to get together, and hence reduce the number of retailers, therefore reducing the competition,&quot; he said. &quot;Again it's going to be the consumer that's going to pay.&quot;</p>
<p>In a worse-case senario, Russell said electricity prices could rise by a third.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are certainly pro a competitive market and it is our contention that that is going to serve the consumers of New Zealand best,&quot; Russell said.</p>
<p>&quot;Eventually, yes, the market will look after itself. (But) until you get competition, we think that there is still a need to be very, very careful about the freedoms that are given to the market.</p>
<p>&quot;There must be some monitoring of what happens to ensure that the consumer in the short term is protected against the potential abuses that are there.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
