<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7201" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FOCUS - Pioneer still acquisitive.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FOCUS - Pioneer still acquisitive.</headline>
<byline>Michael Stapleton</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Building materials group Pioneer International Ltd said on Wednesday it was still sniffing out a major purchase more than a year after merging its downstream petroleum business Ampol with Caltex Australia Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of medium and larger acquisitions, I would have to say we are pursuing a large number of possibilities at this stage,&quot; managing director John Schubert said at a press conference to announce the company's end of year results.</p>
<p>Pioneer has said it has debt funding capabilities of around A$1 billion to fund any acquisition.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have ample gearing capacity - the balance sheet is not an impediment to a sensible large acquisition,&quot; said Pioneer's chief finance officer, Robert Elstone.</p>
<p>The company also initiated a programme last year to spend A$750 million of its cashflow over three years expanding its building materials operations.</p>
<p>Earlier, Pioneer said its net profit after preference but before abnormals and in the year to June 30, 1996 rose by A$2 million to A$252.2 million.  </p>
<p>The company said the geographic spread of its building materials operations along with sound earnings from its Ampol joint venture had allowed it to maintain its net earnings.</p>
<p>Pioneer said it faced another tough year with uncertain market conditions, especially in Australia and Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;Significant improvement in profitability will be depend on success in the group's growth initiatives,&quot; the company said in a statement accompanying its 1995/96 year results.</p>
<p>Pioneer said its 1995/96 earnings were held back by the poor showing of its Australian building materials business which declined in tandem with Australia's depressed housing sector.  </p>
<p>Schubert said he expected improving housing affordability, higher employment and wages would aid the housing industry.</p>
<p>&quot;My view is we will see a recovery in the first half of (calendar) 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earnings from the group's U.S. operations would improve in 1996/97, Schubert said. He said the Texas operation was seen maintaining strong performance, with a new cement joint venture in Houston planned to begin operations in October.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect activity in Hong Kong to slow as major infrastructure projects draw near to completion,&quot; he said, &quot;But generally, we see good growth prospects in Asia.&quot;  </p>
<p>Schubert said the company was satisfied with the performance of its European operations with the exception of Spain, which he said had shown over time time to be very volatile.</p>
<p>The Ampol-Caltex merger had achieved all targets and was now expected to exceed forecast net present value of A$500 million in synergy benefits, Pioneer said.</p>
<p>Ampol's net profit after tax for 1995/96 was A$138.1 million compared to A$23.4 million in the previous corresponding period, which was the first six month period of the merger.  </p>
<p>Pioneer said the substantial increase in profitability was mainly due to asset rationalisation and lower operating costs following the merger.</p>
<p>Pioneer said it expected petrol refiner margins to remain tight during 1996/97 due to strong competition from Asian refineries but saw margin improvements for jet and diesel fuel.</p>
<p>&quot;Offsetting tight margins will be continuing savings from merger synergy benefits and other operating improvements,&quot; it said. Schubert said Pioneer was happy with Ampol's Australian market share of about 30 percent for petrol and jet fuel.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
