<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7205" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Australian SFE wheat options overtake futures.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Australian SFE wheat options overtake futures.</headline>
<byline>Michael Byrnes</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trading in wheat futures options has overtaken wheat futures on the Sydney Futures Exchange (SFE), heralding the birth of a new market in Australia.</p>
<p>Last week, 73 wheat futures options traded against only 60 futures trades.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the start of a new market,&quot; said Brett Stevenson of Agrisk Management, a consultant working with the SFE.</p>
<p>Traders agree. &quot;Absolutely,&quot; Phil Lindsay of Ord Minnett Jardine Fleming Futures Ltd said when asked if options were opening a new chapter in futures trading.  </p>
<p>&quot;The options market appears to be more liquid than the actual futures,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Stevenson said options were capturing attention on the fall in wheat prices, with the key January 1997 futures contract down from A$255.00 a tonne in recent months to A$192.50 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Wheat buyers, key wheat users, many growers and others were all buyers of A$200.00 and A$195.00 call options, he said.</p>
<p>In the cross-roads of the Australian winter crop and the U.S. harvest, people were more comfortable buying options than futures, he said.  </p>
<p>Option activity on the SFE has been entirely in call options, signalling an anticipation of a rising market, Stevenson said.</p>
<p>Call options give the buyer the right to convert the option into a bought futures contract. A A$200.00 call option carries the right to convert to a bought futures contract at A$200.00 a tonne. If the option costs A$10.00, the futures market needs to rise beyond A$210.00 before the option buyer makes money.</p>
<p>A put gives the right to turn the option into a sold futures contract at the strike price.  </p>
<p>&quot;Only three weeks ago we did not have a January option on the books. So it's all happened pretty quickly,&quot; Stevenson said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the commencement of options trading in wheat in Australia -- there's been interest in those options almost every day,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At Ords, Lindsay said Australian wheat and canola growers were historically greater users of options than of futures.</p>
<p>Options were being quoted at fairly realistic premiums by several different trade bodies, with grantors of the options happy to do them in 500 tonne lots.</p>
<p>This was looked on favourably by growers, Lindsay said.  </p>
<p>&quot;People are seeking them (options) all the time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Twenty January call options traded on the Sydney Futures Exchange on Wednesday, against three futures trades.</p>
<p>The SFE contract size is 50 tonnes of Australian Standard White (ASW) wheat.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
