<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7212" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Over 200 whales beached on remote Australian.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Over 200 whales beached on remote Australian.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH, Australia 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>coast</p>
<p>Australian wildlife officials on Wednesday made repeated attempts to rescue up to 300 long-finned pilot whales after about 200 of the mammals beached themselves on a remote part of Australia's west coast.</p>
<p>Fourteen of the pod of over 300 whales died after the beaching was discovered by residents at Dunsborough, 200 km (124 miles) south of Perth, late on Tuesday night, officials said.</p>
<p>Wildlife services and up to 500 volunteers worked overnight after a local radio station appealed for help to rescue the stranded mammals.</p>
<p>&quot;The animals were thrashing around and the water was red with blood. It was rather a horrible sight,&quot; Western Australia state wildlife official Charlie Broadbent told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;They were definitely in distress. They were thrashing around and throwing themselves on the rocks, causing cuts and bruises, which led to extensive bleeding,&quot; Broadbent said.</p>
<p>Officials and volunteers successfully moved the stranded whales into deeper water after the initial discovery was made.</p>
<p>About 50 of the whales later returned to the beach and again had to be led out to sea. Another large part of the pod was later seen near the shoreline several kilometres east of Dunsborough.</p>
<p>Broadbent said the position of the pod was being monitored because there were fears all 300-odd whales might attempt to beach themselves. &quot;We are trying to guide them into deeper water, where they are more comfortable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
