<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7218" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Sale of NZ ForestCorp may spell end of 06 issuance.</title>
<headline>Sale of NZ ForestCorp may spell end of 06 issuance.</headline>
<byline>Catherine McCaw</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The sale of New Zealand's state-owned Forestry Corporation may spell the end of issuance of 11/06 government bonds, dealers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the government announced it would sell Forestry Corp to a consortium led by Fletcher Challenge Ltd, for NZ$2.026 billion.</p>
<p>The Treasury's Debt Management Office (DMO) immediately confirmed that the nominal bond programme for 1996/97 would be halved to NZ$1 billion by reducing issuance at the eight remaining tenders to $100 million each.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the long end of the curve had rallied on news of the forest sale, particularly as the price tag was above market expectations of around $1.8-1.9 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The thought pattern in the market now is obviously what mix the remaining tenders will have. The general consensus seems to be at this stage they are probably more likely to be all 01s and no 06s at all,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Another agreed: &quot;The market is now focusing on the lack of supply, and the potential non-issuance of 06 bonds.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said with $2.8 billion worth of 11/06 bonds currently in the market, that maturity was nearing the top of the optimal range of issuance, of between $2.5 and $3.0 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;It is likely that there will be one more issue, or possibly no more issues, of 06 bonds. That's why the market has rallied, with any further issuing likely to be done in the 01 maturity.&quot;</p>
<p>One Wellington dealer said 11/06s were highly regarded by foreign investors as &quot;the longer bonds to buy in New Zealand&quot;.  </p>
<p>&quot;They may become a little more popular in terms of people needing a few on board because they can't get any more in the tender. The curve could stretch out a little bit just on supply and demand in that back end in particular.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the Reserve Bank's initial concern would be that it needed more 02/01s in the market, as currently there are only $1.7 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;If they only started chipping out $50 million of each in each tender, it's going to take them a long time to get to plus $2 billion in the 01s. To get it up to scratch maybe they will issue more 01s for the majority of the year, and maybe issue a  </p>
<p>few last tenders of the 06s to top them up.&quot;</p>
<p>He said while the DMO had the option of issuing $75 million of 01s and $25 million of 06s at tender, $25 million was &quot;nothing&quot; in the New Zealand market.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a bit of an embarrassment nit-picking with that sort of size, so credibility-wise they might as well just issue $100 million 01s and worry about topping the 06s up at a later day.&quot;</p>
<p>A DMO official would not comment on the possibility of no further 11/06s being issued. He said a decision on retiring the 12-month Treasury bill and/or repurchasing the 07/97 bond in the light of the Forestry Corp sale would be announced after  </p>
<p>Treasury's December Economic and Fiscal Update.</p>
<p>Dealers said that announcement could precipitate a rally in the short end, but its impact would not be huge.</p>
<p>&quot;We think they'll probably do a mixture of both...it could flatten the curve a little bit, but once again it's reasonably well anticipated in the market,&quot; one dealer said, adding he doubted the Reserve Bank would be aggressive in its pricing.</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
