<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7223" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Genetic cane seen transforming sugar industry.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Genetic cane seen transforming sugar industry.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Genetically-engineered plant varieties currently under test will change the face of the sugar industry within five years, an Australian biotechnologist said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Current (gene) technology will profoundly change the face of the sugar industry,&quot; Robert Birch, head of the University of Queensland's biotechnology department, told the Sugar 2000 conference here.</p>
<p>The new technology to produce transgenic sugarcane only emerged in 1992 and new plant varieties would be in Australian cane fields by 2000, Birch said.  </p>
<p>&quot;All future sugar varieties will be transgenic and may well change the competitive efficiencies between sugar-producing countries,&quot; Birch said.</p>
<p>He said varieties of genetically modified plants currently under investigation were to control cane grub and leaf scald.</p>
<p>Factors limiting sucrose accumulation in sugar cane could also now be investigated as well as genes to reduce flowering and fibre accumulation in cane varieties.</p>
<p>Controlling maturation of cane varieties also could now be achieved &quot;to allow sugar cane to mature on cue,&quot; Birch said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Our capacity to introduce new genes into sugar cane plants no longer limits our ability to use transgenic sugar cane,&quot; Birch said.</p>
<p>He said more than 1,000 agricultural plant field trials were being conducted worldwide with sugar cane only one of many varieties.</p>
<p>&quot;None of these field trials has shown any harmful or hazardous or unexpected behaviour,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result public perceptions are becoming more positive towards transgenic plant material,&quot; Birch said.  </p>
<p>Birch warned that new gene technologies were eligible for patent protection allowing control of the technology for at least 20 years by the patent owners.</p>
<p>&quot;(Sugar) industries must therefore consider whether to participate as creators of key technologies which they will need to access for continued profitability,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100136">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
