<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7225" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian euthanasia law faces new challenge.</title>
<headline>Australian euthanasia law faces new challenge.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The world's first voluntary euthanasia law faced a new challenge on Wednesday when a motion to repeal legal assisted suicide was introduced in Australia's Northern Territory parliament.</p>
<p>The 25 members of the Northern Territory's Legislative Assembly began debating the &quot;Right to Human Life&quot; bill, with opinion divided on whether the euthanasia law would be repealed.</p>
<p>The territory's assisted suicide law, allowing terminally-ill patients to end their life by lethal injection or pill if they meet strict conditions, came into force on July 1 but has not yet been used.</p>
<p>Opposition backbencher Neil Bell said he expected his bill to be debated well into Wednesday night in a marathon session and said the assembly was evenly divided on the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;I can be no more definite than saying it is line ball,&quot; Bell told Reuters by telephone from the territory's capital Darwin. &quot;I think it could go either way.&quot;</p>
<p>Eric Poole, the territory's Asian Relations and Industry Minister, has proposed amendments to the euthanasia law to shore up support.</p>
<p>Poole hoped to have euthanasia disallowed in public hospitals and health clinics to allay fears and misconceptions about the existing law among remote area Aborigines.</p>
<p>Recent government research showed aboriginal opposition to euthanasia was widespread and had resulted in people not seeking medical treatment because of fears they may be killed.</p>
<p>The Northern Territory Supreme Court last month rejected a challenge brought by a coalition of doctors, church and aboriginal leaders, ruling the law was within the territorial parliament's power.</p>
<p>A challenge was expected in Australia's peak court, the High Court, with euthanasia opponents asking for a ruling on its constitutional validity, legal sources have said.</p>
<p>Euthanasia is illegal in Australia's six states and one other territory, but doctors admit it occurs unofficially.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
