<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7229" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-S&amp;P says affirms Australia, outlook positive.</title>
<headline>RTRS-S&amp;P says affirms Australia, outlook positive.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard and Poor's Corp said on Wednesday it has affirmed Australia's AA long term and A1-plus short term foreign currency ratings and revised the outlook to positive from stable.</p>
<p>However, S&amp;P said an upgrade of the rating would be dependent on the maintenance of a tight fiscal policy stance.  </p>
<p>S&amp;P also affirmed the AAA long term rating and the A1-plus short term ratings on Australian dollar denominated debt.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook change reflects the substantial fiscal tightening implied by the Commonwealth Government's budget statement released yesterday (Tuesday) and Standard and Poor's expectation that Australia's net public external debt burden could decline markedly if this fiscal stance is maintained medium term,&quot; the ratings agency said.  </p>
<p>S&amp;P said that both the foreign and local currency ratings balanced Australia's diverse and increasingly competitive economy and narrowing fiscal imbalances with a high net public external debt burden, which was about 78 percent of exports last fiscal year, relative to similarly rated sovereigns.</p>
<p>It said the local currency rating reflects a stronger capacity to service Australian dollar debt than foreign currency debt, as a result of moderate inflation, manageable public finances, the Commonwealth's taxation powers and control of the domestic financial system.  </p>
<p>S&amp;P said the package of spending cuts and revenue measures announced by Prime Minister John Howard's Liberal-National government should yield a reduction in the government's underlying budget deficit by 1.8 percent of gross domestic product over the next two years and surpluses in ensuing years.</p>
<p>The state government sector's underlying financial position was expected to be in near balance over the same period, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>It said reductions in public sector debt will be boosted further by planned privatisations by the federal and some state governments.  </p>
<p>S&amp;P said the foreign currency rating outlook was positive, but it added: &quot;An upgrade of the commonwealth's foreign currency rating over the medium term is contingent on the maintenance of a tight fiscal policy stance, leading to a reduction in Australia's net public external debt position, more in line with that of similarly rated sovereigns.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
