<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7232" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia Opposition sees minor budget change.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia Opposition sees minor budget change.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian opposition treasury spokesman Gareth Evans said the opposition in the senate will seek only marginal changes to the 1996/97 budget.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want to be taken for a moment to suggest the budget will survive intact,&quot; Evans told Reuters Financial Television (RFTV) in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;I am saying it is a reasonable anticipation that the overall shape of the budget and its general flavour will remain intact.&quot;  </p>
<p>Evans said the changes sought by the Opposition would amount to &quot;a few hundred million dollars&quot; and would focus on cuts to higher education, labour market programs and aboriginal funding.</p>
<p>Evans said the fact that most of the contentious items in the budget were spending rather than revenue measures made it difficult for the opposition to force changes.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll be trying hard to get a reconsideration, but we're not holding our breath in terms of actual outcomes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Labor Opposition, combined with minor parties and independents, has the numbers to frustrate government legislation in the Senate.  </p>
<p>In 1993, the then Labor government's budget was delayed in the upper house, leading to a major sell-off in the Australian dollar.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Newsroom 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
