<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7236" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-S&amp;P affirms Fletcher, Brierley ratings.</title>
<headline>RTRS-S&amp;P affirms Fletcher, Brierley ratings.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard and Poor's Corp said it has affirmed its BBB long-term rating of Fletcher Challenge Ltd and the BBB-minus long term and A-3 short term ratings of Brierley Investments ltd.  </p>
<p>S&amp;P said the rating action follows the announcement that a consortium comprising Fletcher Challenge, Brierley Investments Limited (Brierley), and Citifor consortium was the successful bidder for New Zealand Forestry corporation.</p>
<p>For an immediate net cash outlay of about NZ$300 million, Fletcher Challenge has a 37.5 percent share in the consortium, which has acquired all the shares in NZFC for about NZ$2.0 billion.</p>
<p>S&amp;P said the investment would not materially impact Brierley's diversified investment portfolio from a credit quality perspective.  </p>
<p>Brierley has a 25 percent share in the consortium. Citifor is a subsidiary of China International Trust &amp; Investment Corporation, rated BBB/A-2 .</p>
<p>S&amp;P said Fletcher Challenge's rating reflected satisfactory market positions in its geographically diverse core forestry, paper, energy, and building businesses.</p>
<p>These businesses were cost-competitive, generating substantial operating cash flows.  </p>
<p>Fletcher Challenge exhibited moderate debt leverage and satisfactory financial flexibility to pursue strategic growth initiatives while maintaining prudential measures consistent with its rating.</p>
<p>&quot;Fletcher Challenge's rating outlook is stable. While operating cash flow will remain cyclical, Fletcher Challenge's business diversity and moderately conservative financial policies should ensure stable credit quality over the next two to three years,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
