<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7240" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ First would launch state home-equity scheme.</title>
<headline>NZ First would launch state home-equity scheme.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Opposition New Zealand First leader Winston Peters on Wednesday pledged to launch a state-sponsored &quot;home-equity&quot; scheme to help superannuitants fund their retirement.</p>
<p>Releasing his party's senior citizens policy, Peters said the scheme would allow superannuitants who were reliant on New Zealand superannuation and without additional assets or income to raise money from their homes for personal use.  </p>
<p>He said the state would organise and run the scheme and would allow, for example, superannuitants to borrow up to 20 percent of the value of their homes up to a maximum limit so they could upgrade their car, repair their houses or take a holiday.</p>
<p>Loans would not need to be repaid immediately but could be &quot;parked&quot; against the home until it was sold.</p>
<p>Interest payments would be flexible depending on circumstance and could also be &quot;parked&quot; against the loan, Peters said.  </p>
<p>He said Housing New Zealand would administer the scheme which would be fiscally neutral for the government, although New Zealand First would put aside $150 million in its first term in government to support it.</p>
<p>He said New Zealand First would give a &quot;categorical assurance&quot; family trust legislation would stay in place. Inland Revenue and Social Welfare were looking at ways to wind back family trust law, Peters said.</p>
<p>His party would not re-introduce estate, death or capital gains taxes, he said.  </p>
<p>Peters reiterated New Zealand First would abolish the superannuation surcharge, inflation-index superannuation six monthly, compared with annually now, and introduce a compulsory savings scheme from July 1, 1997 initially at three percent of income above $5000 and rising to eight percent.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150214">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
