<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7244" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Pioneer sees difficult year ahead.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Pioneer sees difficult year ahead.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Building products and petroleum group Pioneer International Ltd said on Wednesday it faced another difficult year due to uncertain economic and market conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;Significant improvement in profitability will be depend on success in the group's growth initiatives,&quot; the company said in a statement accompanying its 1995/96 year results.</p>
<p>&quot;The group faces another difficult year with uncertain economic and market conditions, especially in Australia and Europe,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>Pioneer also said it was assessing a wide range of acquisition opportunities, including add-on acquisitions, new country entries and larger acquisitions.</p>
<p>Pioneer was commenting after reporting a nine percent rise in operating profit pre-tax of A$332.5 million for the year to June 30. It also posted a net profit of A$258.3 million, down on the A$413.5 million recorded in 1994/95, which was itself boosted by an abnormal gain of A$140 million.</p>
<p>It posted an unchanged nine final dividend.  </p>
<p>Pioneer said that most of the European economies in which it operated were expected to be under pressure and that volumes could fall further.</p>
<p>It said a highly competitive trading environment was forecast in Australia in 1996/97, given a very depressed level of housing starts.</p>
<p>&quot;The efficiencies achieved through the integration and rationalisation of building products should lead to an improved earnings outlook for these businesses,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;The company is more optimistic about growth of non-residential construction in Australia,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>&quot;There are also early indications that selling prices for building materials and products are firming in some of the group's Australian markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Pioneer said it expected the group's U.S. operations to further improve their results in 1996/97.</p>
<p>The Texas operation was expected to maintain strong performance, with a new joint venture cement terminal in Houston planned to begin operations in October 1996.</p>
<p>Pittsburgh sand and gravel assets recently acquired were expected to improve results from Pioneer's Davison operations.  </p>
<p>&quot;Some slowing of activity is forecast for Hong Kong,&quot; Pioneer said, adding however, that it was confident the changeover to Chinese rule in June 1997 would be smooth.</p>
<p>&quot;Some easing of monetary conditions is expected in China during 1996/97, with a positive impact on group results during 1997/98,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Pioneer's refining and marketing operations were expected to remain competitive during 1996/97, with refining margins forecast to remain tight.  </p>
<p>&quot;Offsetting these tight margins will be continuing savings from merger synergy benefits and other operating improvements,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Pioneer's share price was down one cent at A$3.72 at 12.30 p.m. (0230 GMT).</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
