<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7254" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia f'casts said based on world growth.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia f'casts said based on world growth.</headline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE 1996-08-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 1996/97 Australian budget lays the foundation for sustainable growth but its forecasts rely on continued strong global growth, economist David Chessell of Canberra-based Access Economics said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Chessel told reporters after a BankSA budget briefing in Adelaide that measures in the budget were designed for the medium term both for interest rates and unemployment.</p>
<p>Asked how he would score the budget out of 10 points, he said: &quot;Nine.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;I think the budget will help lay the foundation for sustainable growth in Australia, though overall in terms of delivering the A$8 billion cut, it is about 90 percent of the way,&quot; Chessel he said.</p>
<p>Referring to the interest rate outlook, Chessell said cuts in public spending were helpful but passage of measures through the Senate was still uncertain and budgetary forecasts were very dependent on the rest of the world growing strongly.</p>
<p>&quot;If the rest of the world lets us down, the the budget strategy will be under strain,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The main risks to the budget strategy - and to lower interest rates - are a slowdown in the world economy, a wages breakout at home, or an impasse in the Senate,&quot; he said in the BankSA Budget Brief.</p>
<p>Chessel told reporters the government's economic forecasts were realistic, &quot;if anything ... probably pessimistic&quot; with the government setting a series of hurdles which were relatively easy for it to clear.</p>
<p>&quot;Part of the strategy of the budget will be in 12 months time when the numbers come home to roost,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The government will be able to say 'we have exceeded the budget estimates' and that could well be true of inflation and unemployment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he said the forecast of a 14 percent growth in business investment was &quot;a reasonably brave one&quot; which assumed a pickup in the mining industry and improving commodity prices.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
