<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7262" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RBNZ survey respondents see lower growth.</title>
<headline>RBNZ survey respondents see lower growth.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Respondents to the Reserve Bank of New Zealand's latest survey of expectations believe monetary conditions have tightened since May but expect them to ease by the end of the year, the RBNZ said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The bank also said year-ahead inflation expectations have risen, while one and two-year-ahead GDP growth expectations have fallen. The survey does not reflect the bank's own views.  </p>
<p>A net 89 percent of respondents believe monetary conditions are tighter than neutral, up from 85 percent in May. A net 66 percent expect them to be tighter than neutral by year-end, while 36 percent have a similar expectation for June 1997.</p>
<p>The 90-day bank bill rate is seen at 9.8 percent, slightly below Wednesday's level, by the end of September, and is expected to fall to 8.7 percent by the end of June 1997.</p>
<p>Government 10-year bond yields are expected be 7.8 percent by the end of June from just above 8.0 percent now.  </p>
<p>Respondents expect the Consumer Price Index to rise by 0.6 percent in the September quarter and by 0.5 percent in the December quarter (2.3 percent and 2.4 percent respectively on an annual basis).</p>
<p>For the year to June 1997, CPI inflation is picked at 1.9 percent, up from a 1.8 percent expectation in May's survey.</p>
<p>Underlying inflation is seen at 1.8 percent in the year to June 1997 and 1.6 percent in the following year, compared with 1.6 percent and 1.5 percent in the May survey.  </p>
<p>Respondents expect real GDP to increase by 0.5 percent in both the June and September quarters and by 2.4 percent in the year to June 1997, down from the 2.6 percent expected for the year to March 1996 in the last survey.</p>
<p>A 3.0 percent increase in GDP is expected for the year to June 1998.</p>
<p>Unemployment, now 6.1 percent, is expected to rise to 6.6 percent in the June 1997 quarter and fall back to 6.4 percent by the June 1998 quarter.  </p>
<p>Respondents expected a slight decrease in the current account deficit and a government financial surplus of NZ$2.8 billion in the year to June 1997, falling to $2.5 billion in the following year.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
