<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7265" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK democrats face pressure to compromise with China.</title>
<headline>HK democrats face pressure to compromise with China.</headline>
<byline>Dominic Lau</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's main pro-democracy party on Wednesday faced mounting pressure to compromise and support Beijing's efforts to set up transitional political institutions for the British colony's 1997 handover to China.</p>
<p>Half of Hong Kong wants the popular Democratic Party to end its boycott of a China-controlled body that will pick a leader and a provisional legislature, Hong Kong government radio said.</p>
<p>The findings were in an opinion poll conducted by the party to ask the public whether party members should try to join a Selection Committee being formed by China to appoint a post-colonial leader and legislature.</p>
<p>The radio quoted Democratic Party secretary-general Lo Chi-kwong as saying the survey showed about 50 percent of those polled wanted party members to join the 400-member panel.</p>
<p>Lo declined to give further details of the poll, saying the findings were meant for internal use by the party. The poll was originally intended to be secret but word leaked out.</p>
<p>China hinted last week that it would tolerate having the democrats on the transition body, if they would accept plans to appoint a provisional legislature.</p>
<p>But party leader Martin Lee has flatly rejected the idea, saying the provisional body has no legal base in the Sino-British treaties that govern Hong Kong's conversion next July 1 into a Special Administrative Region of China.</p>
<p>He has said China's dismantling of the present, fully elected Legislative Council will be anti-democratic.</p>
<p>Lee's party, a vocal critic of Beijing's communist rulers, is under mounting pressure from public opinion, however, to moderate its stand. Analysts have predicted the issue could split the democratic movement.</p>
<p>Tam Yiu-chung, a member of the Beijing-appointed Preparatory Committee, said it was strange that the Democratic Party was ignoring public sentiment on the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm surprised that they do not follow public opinion,&quot; Tam said. &quot;All along, the Democrats say they place importance on public opinion,&quot; Tam told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they are not interested in making arrangements for the Special Administrative Region,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another committee member, university professor Lau Siu-kai, said the Democrats had &quot;no alternative&quot; but to refuse to join.</p>
<p>&quot;Public opinion may change after it decides to join the Selection Committee, when the party comes under attack from the pro-democracy camp and pro-China politicans for bending its principles,&quot; Lau said. &quot;The party may also face a split.&quot;</p>
<p>Lo defended his party's decision not to sit on the Selection Committee.</p>
<p>&quot;There are other issues when we do not follow the opinion poll, like the death penalty, like the cancelling of the first port of asylum for Hong Kong,&quot; Lo told the radio.</p>
<p>&quot;The most important thing is, what should be our principle,&quot; he said. &quot;The reason we are doing the poll is not that we want to do the poll so that we can follow public opinion.</p>
<p>&quot;What we are trying to do is to understand what's behind, and what sort of people answer 'yes' and what sort of people answer 'no,'&quot; Lo said.</p>
<p>The independent Ming Pao newspaper last week also published opinion poll results that suggested there was considerable public demand for a compromise by the Democratic Party.</p>
<p>That poll, quizzing 525 respondents, found 64.6 percent believed the Democrats should join the committee.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
