<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7268" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - August 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - August 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indonesian political and business stories in leading newspapers, prepared by Reuters in Jakarta. Reuters has not checked the stories and does not guarantee their accuracy. Telephone: (6221) 384-6364. Fax: (6221) 344-8404.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>KOMPAS</p>
<p>The Indonesian government said it would not interfere in an investigation by the official National Comission of Human Rights' into the July 27 riots in Jakarta in which at least four people were died.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>JAKARTA POST</p>
<p>The three sanctioned political parties contesting next year's general election vowed to make the event a success and promised not to launch maneuvers which would harm each other. Indonesia allows the ruling Golkar party, the Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI) and the Moslem-based United Development Party (PPP) to take part in the polls every five years.</p>
<p>Indonesian and Turkey have agreed to look into establishing closer cooperation in trade, investment and strategic industries, especially in the aerospace sector.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>REPUBLIKA</p>
<p>The Attorney General's office allowed the parents of Budiman Sudjatmiko, leader of the leftist People's Democratic Party (PRD) to visit him after one week in detention. The paper said Sudjatmiko was in a good condition. The government blames the PRD for being behind the July 27 riots.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MEDIA INDONESIA</p>
<p>A Catholic priest accused of publicly insulting President Suharto was questioned by the police on Tuesday. Father Ignatius Sandyawan is also accused of harbouring Budiman Sudjatmiko and two other activists from the PRD.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
