<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7277" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore shares end higher, second liners lead.</title>
<headline>Singapore shares end higher, second liners lead.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Singapore stock market closed sharply higher on Wednesday, pushed by advances in second line stocks and modest gains for blue chips, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said second liners were active on various rumours and strong July trade figures had prompted institutions to buy selected blue chips. Singapore posted a better-than-expected 6.4 percent growth in non-oil domestic exports on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;But the rally will probably tail off by the end of the week with profit taking setting in,&quot; said a dealer in a foreign bank.</p>
<p>The key Straits Times Industrials Index surged 31.79 points, or 1.50 percent, to 2,155.60.  </p>
<p>Market volume was a high 153.79 million shares with gainers leading losers by 278 to 110.</p>
<p>Property concern Guthrie GTS took centre stage in mid afternoon, with 7.00 million shares traded on the open market as an old takeover rumour by an Indonesian tycoon resurfaced. It closed Singapore $0.055 up at S$0.70 after hitting an earlier high of S$0.72.</p>
<p>Blue chip property stocks DBS Land and City Development gained 16 and 10 cents respectively. OCBC foreign led the bank stocks, rising 70 cents to S$16.70 on a volume of 1.11 million shares traded. --Seah Beng Nah (65 8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
