<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7288" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai T-bill repo rates end down, spots up.</title>
<headline>Shanghai T-bill repo rates end down, spots up.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Contracts on the treasury bill repurchase market in Shanghai closed mostly down on Wednesday on a rumour that the People's Bank of China would shortly cut bank interest rates, traders said.</p>
<p>Central bank officials declined to comment.</p>
<p>The annual rate for the three-day contract dropped to 12.18 percent from 18.60 percent and the most active seven-day contract ended lower at 10.50 percent from 11.54.</p>
<p>Turnover fell to 6.79 million lots from 8.43 million. One lot is 1,000 yuan face value of treasury bills.  </p>
<p>Despite the day's falls, traders said the rates were unlikely to fall sharply in the next few days due to new domestic A share issues in the short term, which are likely to suck liquidity out of repo market, pushing up the rates.</p>
<p>Most contracts on the T-bill spot market in Shanghai closed up on the bank interest rate rumour, with the most active 10-year bond that matures in June 2006 soaring to 124.76 yuan from 118.97 yuan, traders said.</p>
<p>Combined volume of the nine-contract market surged to 6.65 million lots from 2.26 million.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
