<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7289" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: India adamant on blocking nuclear test treaty.</title>
<headline>India adamant on blocking nuclear test treaty.</headline>
<byline>Michael Battye</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>India stood adamantly by its decision to block a nuclear test ban treaty on Wednesday, denouncing the proposed pact as not even fulfilling its United Nations mandate.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Inder Kumar Gujral also shrugged off forthright U.S. criticism of India over its veto of the Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty (CTBT) in Geneva.</p>
<p>U.S. disarmament ambassador Stephen Ledogar told reporters in Geneva on Tuesday that the real reason India vetoed the pact, which 44 nations had spent months negotiating, was to keep its own nuclear option open.</p>
<p>Gujral refused a direct response, but said strongly that India wanted a test ban treaty.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not going to respond to that,&quot; Gujral told a Foreign Correspondents Association lunch in Singapore. &quot;If we start questioning each other's motives, it may be a very dirty scene. I don't want that.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are in favour of a genuine, honest test ban treaty, but we feel that the treaty, as presently drafted and presented in Geneva, falls short of this,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;It does not even meet the mandate given to it by the United Nations General Assembly.&quot;</p>
<p>Indian officials said another reason Gujral did not want to get into a slanging match with Washington was that New Delhi did not wish the dispute to turn into a bilateral U.S.-India issue.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a matter of principle, not bilateral relations,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>In Bombay, Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda reaffirmed India's commitment to nuclear disarmament, vowing not to be a party to any &quot;discriminatory&quot; goals along the way.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe nuclear disarmament is vital for the future of humanity and would like to work towards this goal. However, till the goal is accepted by all, we cannot afford to subscribe to any goal that is discriminatory, unfair and inimical to national security interests,&quot; Deve Gowda told a gathering of scientists.</p>
<p>India vetoed the treaty, saying the draft merely froze the status quo, did not commit the nuclear powers to disarmament and allowed them high-technology ways of improving their arsenals.</p>
<p>New Delhi set off a nuclear explosion in 1974 but insists it has never produced a nuclear weapon, although it is widely believed to be capable of assembling one at short notice.</p>
<p>It has produced missiles capable of delivering nuclear warheads, but Gujral denied India was likely to resume testing its Agni long-range missile after a two-year gap.</p>
<p>The International Herald Tribune said on Wednesday he had suggested that in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;What I said quite clearly several times was that this was not on the cards, but that we keep our options open,&quot; Gujral told reporters at the lunch.</p>
<p>India last tested the Agni, designed to hit targets 2,500 km (1,500 miles) away, in 1994, three years after launching radical market reforms to its tightly-controlled economy that included a search for foreign, especially U.S., investment.</p>
<p>The United States had urged New Delhi to halt missile testing permanently, fearing a major arms race between India and Pakistan, which have fought three wars since independence from Britain in 1947.</p>
<p>U.S. officials say Washington fears that another war between the two old enemies could turn nuclear with Pakistan, like India, believed capable of assembling a nuclear warhead quickly.</p>
<p>India never admitted that its suspension of missile tests followed U.S. pressure or the search for U.S. investment, but diplomats in Delhi say they believe those were the reasons.</p>
<p>Gujral would not say when, or if, missile testing might resume. &quot;It is not on the agenda,&quot; he told Reuters Television.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
