<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7292" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: OPINION - Ivan Wong comments on Malaysian palm oil.</title>
<headline>OPINION - Ivan Wong comments on Malaysian palm oil.</headline>
<text>
<p>KUALA LUMPUR, Aug 21 - CPO production in July was a disappointment. PORLA reported an output figure of 721,900 tonnes or a mere 349 tonnes more than June. An increase of 32,100 tonnes or 5.7 percent in Peninsular Malaysia was offset by an unexpectedly sharp decline of 31,800 tonnes or 20 percent in East Malaysia. There were more mills reporting declines in production of 20 percent or more than we had estimated. Nevertheless, when compared to July last year production in the country still posted a growth of 6.6 percent.  </p>
<p>For the first seven months this year, production amounted to 4.42 million tonnes. This is 252,100 or six percent more than the same period of last year. Latest indications for this month pointed to a continued modest seasonal increase in Peninsular Malaysia while East Malaysia would see a moderate recovery. Rainfall has increased since last week with coverage of up to 80 percent in some crop areas on some days. Tentatively we estimate a seasonal rise in production of around seven percent to 772,000 tonnes this month. In contrast to the anaemic production, palm oil exports in July were most impressive.  </p>
<p>At 646,000 tonnes, they were 66,600 tonnes more than month earlier and also exceed our estimate of 630,000 tonnes. The July exports were the second highest monthly figure ever reported by PORLA, exceeded only by the 658,200 tonnes exported in January '94, an all-time high. The poor production but excellent exports resulted in a drawdown of 19,300 tonnes in end-July stocks of palm oil to 754,800 tonnes. While exports this month may see a modest decline, they remain at a highly satisfactory level. More importantly, we expect the healthy exports to be sustainable up to October or till the end of the peak crop period.  </p>
<p>Refiners are also likely to enjoy good processing margins during these four months. There is thus less likelihood of palm oil stocks rising to or exceeding the one million tonne mark in the last three months of this year. Stocks will not reach worrisome levels as long as palm oil price remain competitive in relation to other major oils and fats. The palm oil market was firm last week driven mostly by advances in CPO futures which posted gains of 76-66 ringgit in the September and October contracts during the six days ended August 15.  </p>
<p>Thereafter futures retreated 12-16 ringgit on heavy profittaking activities but rebounded 19-22 ringgit yesterday with October settling at 1,155 ringgit and November at 1,167 ringgit. October RBD palm olein was quoted at $550.</p>
<p>(The opinions expressed in this article represent the views of the author only. They should not be seen as necessarily reflecting the views of Reuters).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
