<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7306" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Asian Metals - Japan aluminium premium deals near.</title>
<headline>Asian Metals - Japan aluminium premium deals near.</headline>
<byline>Edmund Klamann</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese aluminium traders said on Wednesday that premiums in fourth quarter ingot contracts would likely be set midway between $60 and $65 a tonne over London Metal Exchange cash prices, as they negotiated deals with Western producers.</p>
<p>No deals were confirmed as of mid-afternoon on Wednesday, but decisions were expected soon.</p>
<p>Australian aluminium producers who arrived in Japan this week initially called for premiums of $65, trade sources said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Sixty-five dollars is a bit high,&quot; said one trader, although he added, &quot;I don't think we're that far apart.&quot;</p>
<p>He noted that a recent rise in domestic ingot inventories would help the Japanese bargain for a slight decrease from last quarter's $63 to $65 level, although he conceded the trade houses were unlikely to get premiums below $60.</p>
<p>Regarding recent figures showing a rise in Japan's rolling and extrusion mill output, he argued that ingot supplies were plentiful and domestic demand was still not strong enough to justify firmer premiums.  </p>
<p>Data released last week by the Japan Aluminium Federation said July output at Japan's seven largest mills rose 2.5 percent from the same month last year, reflecting strong demand from the beverage can and construction sectors.</p>
<p>Data from the first half of 1996 had shown a slight dip in mill output from the year-ago period.</p>
<p>Japan's negotiations will set the tone for South Korean and Taiwanese premiums, which are typically about $10 a tonne over Japan, traders said.  </p>
<p>In the copper market, traders said physical supplies remained tight and premiums for South American metal firmed modestly to around $85 a tonne over LME.</p>
<p>One trader also noted offers of small amounts of cathode from China, although premiums were said to be too high to interest local buyers.</p>
<p>Trade sources in Europe and Singapore recently noted talk that up to 100,000 tonnes of copper was believed to be in Shanghai bonded warehouses and that China National Non-Ferrous Metals Import and Export Corp (CNIEC) arranged meetings with European houses at which the metal was offered for sale.  </p>
<p>The zinc market remained quiet, although traders kept a wary eye on Korea Zinc Co following rumours, denied by the company, of shipment delays. Facilities at its Onsan smelter were scheduled to shut down from August 1 to 29 for regular maintenance, a company spokesman told Reuters last Friday.</p>
<p>Latest Japan indications of premiums in US$/tonne over LME cash prices on a CIF basis were as follows:</p>
<p>		   August 21    August 14</p>
<p>    Copper	$80-$90	$75-$85</p>
<p>    Aluminium   $60-$65	$60-$65</p>
<p>    Zinc	  $70-$80	$70-$80</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
