<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7318" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: In dull car market, rental firms boom in Shanghai.</title>
<headline>In dull car market, rental firms boom in Shanghai.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Business for Shanghai's rental car firms is booming on the back of rising local demand at a time when China's car market is in a slump and inventories on the rise, industry officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The city boasts nine rental-car companies with more than 900 vehicles, including BMWs, Mercedes and Lincolns, up from just one at the end of 1992 with 30 Santanas, the locally produced model that accounts for most cars on the city streets.</p>
<p>Working in favour of rental companies is the high price of cars, low individual incomes and an undeveloped private car market, a surfeit of drivers and the dream of thousands of people to travel in a private car.</p>
<p>&quot;We had fewer than 100 cars at the end of 1995 but now (have) more than 200,&quot; an official of Zhenlang Rental Car company said.</p>
<p>&quot;Within one or two year, we will have 500 cars, at which level we can make a stable profit,&quot; he said. The cheapest daily rate is 300 yuan ($36) for a Santana, while renting a Lincoln for eight hours will cost you 2,800 yuan.</p>
<p>&quot;People rent cars because of the high cost of purchasing one and finding a parking space,&quot; an official of Anji Rental Car Companye said. &quot;Married couples like to use an expensive imported car on their wedding day as a special treat.&quot;</p>
<p>The main customers were local institutions and foreign companies but the proportion of private individuals would increase greatly in the next few years, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;About seven percent of customers were local individuals in 1995, up from four percent in 1994,&quot; said an official of Shanghai Dazhong Rental Car, a unit of Shanghai Dazhong Taxi.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the figure to reach 25 percent in one or two years, the same proportion as that of foreign firms or companies from provinces next to Shanghai,&quot; the Dazhong official said.</p>
<p>Most individuals rent cars for weddings, but more and more want to rent them for weekend trips to cities and tourist spots near Shanghai, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;Shanghai people have already started to dream of buying a car, which ranks second after buying an apartment,&quot; the Zhenlang official said. &quot;But the car-buying day is far in the future&quot;.</p>
<p>In 1995, the average urban Chinese earned 3,893 yuan, while the cheapest four-seat passenger car cost at least 100,000 yuan. A car licence in Shanghai -- paid on top of the price of the car -- costs 140,000 yuan.</p>
<p>At the end of June, there were about 116,000 cars stockpiled in China, up from 88,000 in January. In the first half of 1996, China's manufacturers produced 758,000 cars but sold only 720,000.</p>
<p>Industry officials blame the slump in sales on a three-year austerity policy, tight credit and restrictions on spending by government institutions.</p>
<p>In Shanghai, more than 450,000 people have a driving licence but the city had less than 400,000 vehicles in 1995, official figures show.</p>
<p>Each year 50,000-60,000 Shanghai people spend at least three months to obtain a driving licence, even though most will not have the opportunity to own a car.</p>
<p>Officials said the idea of rental cars came to China during the 1990 Asian Games in Beijing, when reporters from abroad complained they would not work without rented cars.</p>
<p>($US1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I84801">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
