<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7320" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: India missile tests &quot;not on cards&quot; - minister.</title>
<headline>India missile tests &quot;not on cards&quot; - minister.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Foreign Minister Inder Kumar Gujral said on Wednesday a resumption of testing of the long-range Agni missile was not on the cards, although New Delhi was keeping its options open.</p>
<p>Gujral, in Singapore on a visit, was speaking the day after India vetoed a draft nuclear test ban treaty and said it would block its transmission to the United Nations.</p>
<p>Asked about remarks he made in a newspaper interview that indicated India was likely to resume missile testing after a halt of more than two years despite pressure from the United States for a permanent cessation, Gujral said:</p>
<p>&quot;What I said quite clearly several times was that this was not on the cards but that we keep our options open.&quot;</p>
<p>He was speaking at a press luncheon.</p>
<p>Gujral told the International Herald Tribune that India had developed its own cryogenic rocket engines, which Western experts fear could be used to power ballistic missiles.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now trying to test it (engine),&quot; Gujral told the newspaper, adding: &quot;It is not for a missile. It is for a spacecraft.&quot;</p>
<p>The United States, concerned over tensions in South Asia, has urged India to scrap the Agni as well as the short-range Prithvi, but India has said sophisticated weapons in neighbouring Pakistan and China require it to remain on guard.</p>
<p>The United States is worried that such missiles could be used to carry nuclear warheads.</p>
<p>On Tuesday in Geneva, U.S. disarmament ambassador Stephen Ledogar said India had blocked the Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty (CTBT) because &quot;New Delhi wants to maintain the Indian nuclear weapon option&quot;.</p>
<p>The Indian Defence Ministry said in an annual report on Monday that global pressures had mounted on India to scrap its missile programmes and abandon its option to build a nuclear bomb.</p>
<p>The ministry said it would keep a constant watch on the development and stockpiling of missile weapons systems in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;India will continue with its indigenous missile development programmes and also keep its options open on their deployment as warranted by our national security interests,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>India, along with Pakistan and Israel, is a nuclear threshold state that has the capability to build nuclear weapons swiftly. New Delhi exploded a nuclear device in 1974, but has not undertaken any nuclear tests since then.</p>
<p>India has said it wants the test ban treaty to include a time-bound commitment by the five declared nuclear powers -- the United States, China, Britain, France and Russia -- for total nuclear disarmament.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
