<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7323" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Hanoi begins evacuating homes as flood waters rise.</title>
<headline>Hanoi begins evacuating homes as flood waters rise.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Edwards</byline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of residents evacuated their flooded homes in Hanoi on Wednesday as waters on Vietnam's Red River rose to their most dangerous levels in years.</p>
<p>In districts bordering the river, entire neighbourhoods were submerged beneath several metres of swirling red-brown water washed down from flooded areas further upstream.</p>
<p>Rafts made from bamboo, wood, packing cases or anything that could float were being used to ferry families and their belongings away from the river to the relative safety of the city's main protective dike.</p>
<p>Boats and barges navigated city streets normally used by motorbikes and cars, cashing in on a lucrative waterborne removals and taxi business. Residents were being charged around 40,000 dong ($3.60) a trip.</p>
<p>As waters continued to rise, local authorities ordered access points on the centuries old main Hanoi dike sealed as an emergency measure to protect the city of 2.2 million people from widespread damage.</p>
<p>The threat to Hanoi -- the worst since 1971 -- follows a series of devastating storms across northern Vietnam over the past 10 days.</p>
<p>In provinces southeast of the capital, efforts were continuing to account for hundreds of missing people after a whirlwind storm tore through fishing fleets and coastal areas a week ago.</p>
<p>In mountain provinces in Vietnam's remote northwest thousands of families were said to be without sufficient food supplies after flooding and landslides caused by torrential rains at the weekend.</p>
<p>Vietnam's Red Cross issued figures on Wednesday saying 153 people had been killed, 293 were missing and nearly seventy thousand families had been affected across the north over the past week.</p>
<p>The figures differed from those given in a newspaper interview a day earlier by Agriculture Minister Nguyen Cong Tan, who said 635 people were still unaccounted for.</p>
<p>While an accurate casualty toll may not be known for some time, it is already clear the damage to northern Vietnam -- one of the poorest areas of the country -- is some of the worst in years.</p>
<p>According to preliminary estimates, more than 105,000 hectares (259,457 acres) of rice fields have been flooded. Damage to property was put at $68.72 million and the figure was expected to rise over the next few days.</p>
<p>Officials at the Central Weather Bureau were quoted by the English-language Vietnam News on Wednesday as saying tropical storm Niki, packing winds of up to 120 kph (75 mph), was expected to strike land in Vietnam before the end of the week.</p>
<p>The party mouthpiece Nhan Dan newspaper said Prime Minister Vo Van Kiet had issued instructions calling on local authorities and the armed forces to be ready to help protect sea-walls and dikes against further damage.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
