<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7325" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korean president attacks pro-Pyongyang students.</title>
<headline>S.Korean president attacks pro-Pyongyang students.</headline>
<byline>Lim Yun-suk</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean President Kim Young-sam on Wednesday accused radical students of waging urban guerrilla warfare in support of Pyongyang and vowed to sternly punish North Korean supporters.</p>
<p>Kim was addressing the heads of 292 colleges a day after riot police stormed Seoul's Yonsei University to end a seven-day occupation by students calling for reunification with North Korea and the withdrawal of U.S. troops stationed in the South.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a violent anti-government revolution that supports North Korea and can be considered as urban guerrilla warfare,&quot; a presidential statement quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;The violent forces that challenge government authorities will not be forgiven under any circumstances,&quot; Kim said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government will never accept violent students who believe in communism and (will) thoroughly punish anachronistic pro-North Korean forces,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>About 3,225 students were arrested after riot police stormed a teaching block at Yonsei, smashing through burning barricades of desks and chairs and lobbing stun grenades to dislodge mostly female undergraduates.</p>
<p>&quot;The government will deal with all violent pro-North Korean demonstrations strictly by law,&quot; said Kim.</p>
<p>It was the harshest denunciation so far of the student demonstrators, whose leaders have been branded by authorities as Pyongyang stooges intent on using the issue of Korean unification to destabilise the government.</p>
<p>The campus violence was the worst since Kim, a former dissident under the military-backed government, took office in 1993. Students were armed with iron bars and petrol bombs, and hundreds of riot police, as well as dozens of students, were injured.</p>
<p>More than 5,500 students were arrested in more than one week of unrest at Yonsei.</p>
<p>Authorities have sought to distinguish between what they described as naive students caught up in the protests and the ringleaders who meticulously planned the violence.</p>
<p>Most of the arrested students were expected to get off lightly, but the masterminds face prosecution, possibly under national security laws designed to protect South Korea against North Korea.</p>
<p>The two Koreas have been technically at war since the 1950-53 Korean conflict ended with a truce.</p>
<p>South Korean newspaper editorials also advocated stern punishment for the student leaders. &quot;The masterminds and those behind the violence must be shown that the law will be strictly enforced,&quot; said the Dong-Ah Ilbo.</p>
<p>The public, once supportive of student demonstrators fighting for democracy in the 1980s, have now turned hostile.</p>
<p>Police say they suspect the Yonsei protests were led by Namchongnyon, a federation of student university councils based in southern Cholla province.</p>
<p>North Korea's Committee for the Peaceful Reunification of Fatherland on Tuesday denounced the South for the crackdown.</p>
<p>&quot;While calling for dialogue with the North, the Kim Young-sam group are suppressing activists for reunification. If they truly want to negotiate with the North, they must stop the suppression and ensure free discussion of reunification,&quot; it said in comments carried by the Korean Central News Agency and monitored in Tokyo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
