<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7326" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Okinawa unlikely to refine oil for Taiwan in 1996.</title>
<headline>Okinawa unlikely to refine oil for Taiwan in 1996.</headline>
<byline>Miho Yoshikawa</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Okinawan refineries are unlikely to enter new crude processing pacts with Taiwan's state-owned Chinese Petroleum Corp (CPC) this year due to a dispute over refining costs, Japanese industry sources said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The sources said that both Nansei Sekiyu KK and Okinawa Sekiyu Seisei Co Ltd have broken off their respective negotiations over new refining arrangements with CPC. The Japanese companies and CPC were unable to reach a compromise and narrow the gap over the processing fee, they said.</p>
<p>The Japanese companies declined to provide official comment on the issue. A CPC source said on Tuesday that negotiations were being kept on hold until the issue of the cost was resolved.</p>
<p>&quot;It's highly unlikely that Okinawa Sekiyu will forge a new processing contract with CPC for this year,&quot; said a Japanese source close to the discussions.</p>
<p>The Japanese industry sources said Nansei Sekiyu, part of the General Sekiyu KK group, had suspended discussion on CPC's processing requirement for July to December, while Okinawa Sekiyu had no plans to meet Taiwanese negotiators after talks fell through in July.  </p>
<p>The main point of contention in the talks is the added cost for improving the quality of fuel oil.</p>
<p>CPC wants to cut the sulphur content of the fuel oil to 0.5 percent from its previous 1.0 percent to meet stricter environmental regulations.</p>
<p>&quot;Simply put, an agreement could not be reached over the cost for the additional task of lowering the sulphur content,&quot; a second Japanese industry source said.</p>
<p>The previous processing fee per barrel between Nansei Sekiyu and CPC was between $2 and $2.50, the sources said. The level is believed to be roughly the same for Okinawa Sekiyu -- a subsidiary of Idemitsu Kosan Co Ltd -- and CPC, one Japanese source said.</p>
<p>The Japanese sources said Nansei Sekiyu was asking for an additional 30 to 40 cents as their bottom line.</p>
<p>They said there was a one dollar difference between CPC and Okinawa Sekiyu.</p>
<p>Nansei Sekiyu's facility does not include a desulphurisation unit. This means it will be forced to switch to a sweeter crude grade to obtain lower sulphur content. Previously Nansei used a mix of crudes, such as Champion and Oman.  </p>
<p>Okinawa Sekiyu, on the other hand, has a processing agreement with South Korea in which the requirement is for 1.0 percent sulphur fuel oil.</p>
<p>&quot;Okinawa Sekiyu has to ask for a premium for lowering the sulphur content, it can't keep the refining fee the same for Taiwan and South Korea,&quot; the first source said.</p>
<p>The Japanese sources said CPC was unlikely to compromise as it was in a position to cover its requirements by making the necessary oil product purchases through tenders.</p>
<p>Nansei Sekiyu might join talks for the January to October term, but nothing had been decided yet, the sources said.</p>
<p>It wants to continue to build on the five-year business ties that it has forged with CPC but not at the risk of ignoring the economics of the agreement, they said.</p>
<p>Refining companies in Okinawa, Japan's southernmost island, are often chosen by countries like Taiwan to refine crude because of their geographical proximity, which helps cut shipment costs.</p>
<p>The third refiner on Okinawa, Nippon Petroleum Refining Co Ltd, stopped operating its primary refining facility in 1987 and no longer processes crude for an outside party.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
