<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7333" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Toyo Pile says to merge with Tosen Asano.</title>
<headline>Toyo Pile says to merge with Tosen Asano.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Concrete pile maker Toyo Pile Hume Pipe Production Co Ltd said on Wednesday that it would merge with unlisted pile maker Tosen Asano Pole Co Ltd on March 31, 1997.</p>
<p>The merger ratio will be one Toyo Pile share for every half share in Tosen, Toyo Pile said in a statement. Tosen Asano will be dissolved after the merger, Toyo Pile said.</p>
<p>They decided to rationalise their businesses in order to survive severe competition, Toyo Pile said. The two companies started cooperating in production, sales and research last December, it said.  </p>
<p>Trade in shares of Toyo Pile was suspended in the afternoon.</p>
<p>Toyo Pile forecasts parent current profit at the merged firm will hit 470 million yen and net profit will reach 220 million yen in the year to end-February 1998. Sales are expected to hit 19.83 billion yen, it said.</p>
<p>In 1998/99, the merged firm is expected to post a parent current profit of 463 million yen and net profit of 218 million yen, Toyo Pile said. Sales are expected to reach 20.33 billion yen, it said.</p>
<p>In the 1995/96 business year, Toyo Pile posted a parent current profit of 336 million yen and net profit of 135 million yen on sales of 9.74 billion yen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
