<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7358" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Key JGB futures end higher, cash bonds firmer.</title>
<headline>Key JGB futures end higher, cash bonds firmer.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Key September Japanese government bond futures closed higher on Wednesday, although they shed some gains after reaching 121.04, their highest level since December 22.</p>
<p>Dealers said long-yield cash JGBs, which pierced one key technical chart point, were particularly strong and lead the bullish mood in the market.</p>
<p>The 10-year JGB auction, the main event of the day, confirmed underlying firm support for the JGBs, they said.</p>
<p>The September contract closed at 120.88, up 0.08 from Tuesday. Volume was 40,284 contracts.  </p>
<p>The September opened firm this morning, taking its cue from the Federal Open Market Committee's decision to leave rates unchanged, dealers said.</p>
<p>Although the Fed's decision to leave rates unchanged was largely expected, it prompted last-minute short-covering by those who were hedging their bets on a rate hike by the Fed, said a dealer at a securities firm.</p>
<p>Also in the morning, the Bank of Japan's (BOJ) surprise outright bond buying boosted the market.  </p>
<p>After having being blocked a couple of times at strong resistance at 121, the September contract finally managed to climb above 121 in the mid-afternoon, hitting its highest point in almost eight months.</p>
<p>But it failed to hang on to that level for long. &quot;It'd take another fresh factor to bid up the September above 121,&quot; said another dealer at a Japanese city bank.</p>
<p>The announcement of 10-year JGB auction results was in line with market expectations. Dealers said there was reasonable demand for the offered bonds. A couple of securities firms are said to have bought large amounts.  </p>
<p>A securities firm's dealer said investors' appetites for the auctioned JGBs were strong.</p>
<p>The yield of the cash benchmark 182nd 10-year JGBs dropped below 3.100 percent for the first time since April. As of 0658 GMT, the yield was 3.100 percent, down 0.025 from Tuesday.</p>
<p>Long-end bonds, which had been lagging futures contracts in the recent uptrend, were the main driving force of the bull run today, said a dealer at a city bank's securities unit.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody may now looking for these bonds to rise further, after the yield broke through 3.1 percent,&quot; said a dealer at another city bank's securities affiliate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
