<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7386" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Takefuji shares average price at 9,691 yen - sources.</title>
<headline>Takefuji shares average price at 9,691 yen - sources.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The weighted average auction price of Takefuji Corp shares, which will go public on the over-the-counter market on August 30, is estimated at 9,691 yen, market sources said on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>The official share price of Japan's largest consumer financing firm, which is offering five million shares to the public, will be announced at 0630 GMT after the stock market closes.</p>
<p>Market sources said the bids for the 2.5 million shares offered via auction totalled 8.24 million.</p>
<p>They said the lowest accepted bid was 9,100 yen and the highest 15,700 yen. The lowest bid for the share was 5,660 yen.</p>
<p>Keiji Arai, a strategist at Sanyo Securities, said the market was looking forward to the listing of consumer financing firms.</p>
<p>&quot;Takefuji posts solid profits and has a healthy capital/asset ratio,&quot; Arai said.  </p>
<p>In the business year that ended March 31, 1996, Takefuji posted a parent current profit of 110.77 billion yen on revenues of 246.22 billion yen, the Japan Securities Dealers' Association (JSDA) said earlier.</p>
<p>It also posted 48.0 billion yen in net profit and issued an annual dividend of 10 yen per share in 1995/96, JSDA said.</p>
<p>Arai added that other consumer finance firms such as Sanyo Shinpan Finance Co Ltd and Promise Co Ltd, which were recently upgraded to the second section of the Tokyo Stock Exchange from the over-the counter market, were popular with investors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
