<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7389" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan market rates flat until tankan - traders.</title>
<headline>Japan market rates flat until tankan - traders.</headline>
<byline>Chikafumi Hodo</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Further falls in Japanese market interest rates should be limited unless investors are given reasons to buy Japanese government bonds when a key corporate survey is released next week, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The U.S. Federal Open Market Committee's decision to leave interest rates unchanged at its meeting on Tuesday produced no major fireworks in Japanese markets on Wednesday as the result was widely expected, they said.</p>
<p>Traders said the key 182nd 10-year bond yield was not likely to fall sharply below 3.1 percent until the Bank of Japan's quarterly &quot;tankan&quot; survey of corporate sentiment next Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's too early to say the BOJ will also refrain from changing its credit policy after the Fed's decision yesterday. The Fed's move was widely expected,&quot; said Shuji Igarashi, assistant general manager on Daiwa Securities' bond section.</p>
<p>Traders said the market consensus that the United States and Japan would raise interest rates together by late August or early September had already fallen apart a long time ago.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market needs more reasons to buy (the key 10-year bond) actively below 3.1 (percent),&quot; he said. &quot;Investors could flood into the market to buy long bonds if the tankan gives clear buying signals.&quot;</p>
<p>Cash-rich Japanese investors, who missed chances to buy in the recent rapid rallies, are expected to scale up their buying if the tankan shows no strong improvement in corporate sentiment.</p>
<p>Japanese government bond (JGB) yields have fallen in the past several weeks, along with short-term money rates, after a series of economic indicators and comments by monetary officials decreased the likelihood of an interest rate hike in Japan soon, traders said.</p>
<p>That mood increased particularly since BOJ Governor Yasuo Matsushita reiterated on August 7 that it was appropriate for the BOJ to maintain its easy credit stance.</p>
<p>Fuji Securities' chief market economist Yasunari Ueno said technical buying in the JGB futures market initiated the recent buying trend, and economic fundamentals eventually supported further purchases.  </p>
<p>&quot;There is a possibility that the market could test the (key 182nd 10-year bond) yield at about the 3.0-percent barrier,&quot; Ueno said.</p>
<p>The yield of the key 10-year bond fell to just below 3.1 percent on Wednesday afternoon from around 3.3 in early August.</p>
<p>The key three-month certificates of deposit (CD) rate fell as low as 0.59 percent on Wednesday morning from about 0.70 in early August.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking at the spread of about 250 basis points (between the key bond yield and the three-month CD rate), it seems the key bond yield is unlikely to tumble more,&quot; said Hidenobu Furuhashi, bond section manager at Toyo Trust Securities.</p>
<p>Furuhashi, however, added the market was also becoming more convinced that a snap rate hike was not possible soon as the BOJ was unlikely to change its stance as long as the Fed stood still.</p>
<p>BOJ officials said on Wednesday that the Fed's decision to leave interest rates unchanged would not influence the BOJ's monetary policy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
