<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7394" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Jilin Pharmaceutical H1 net down 44 pct.</title>
<headline>Jilin Pharmaceutical H1 net down 44 pct.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shenzhen-listed drug firm Jilin Pharmaceutical Co Ltd said its after-tax earnings fell 44 percent year-on-year to 5.47 million yuan in the first half of 1996 under Chinese accounting standards.</p>
<p>That compared with 9.72 million yuan racked up in the year-ago period, it said in an interim report published in the Shenzhen-based Securities Times.</p>
<p>Its main operating income reached only 104.55 million yuan, versus 105.13 million yuan in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>The company said the decline in profits was due in part to rate rises on electricity and to higher transport fees.</p>
<p>Beijing's reduction of export tax rebate levels also cut into the company's first-half profits, the report said.</p>
<p>Jilin Pharmaceutical said in its annual report for last year that a 26 percent decline in net earnings for 1995 was primarily triggered by price rises for raw materials and a steep drop in returns on investments.</p>
<p>The firm said that it had net earnings of 17.39 million yuan last year, down from 23.50 million yuan in 1994.</p>
<p>Higher prices for precursor chemicals and the firm's limited ability to pass the costs on to consumers cut into profit margins last year, it said.</p>
<p>An official at the firm said earlier that its business outlook for 1996 remained gloomy in light of the central government's ongoing moves to slash export tax rebates.</p>
<p>Sales of the its leading product, aspirin, accounted for about one-third of the company's main operating income annually, the official said.</p>
<p>The firm exported about 95 percent of the drug, he added.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
