<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7402" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian parties pledge to support Suharto.</title>
<headline>Indonesian parties pledge to support Suharto.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's three sanctioned political parties pledged to support President Suharto and avoid criticism of each other in the run-up to next year's general elections, the official Antara news agency said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The ruling Golkar party, the Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI) and the Moslem-based United Development Party (PPP) will contest 425 of the 500 seats in parliament. The remaining 75 will be allocated to non-voting representatives of the armed forces.</p>
<p>Antara said Golkar chairman Harmoko, PDI chairman Surjadi and PPP chairman Ismail Hasan Metareum signed a statement at a ceremony held at the National Election Institute on Tuesday, in which they expressed support for Suharto and said they would avoid manouevres against each other.</p>
<p>They later shook hands and embraced. Antara gave no other details.</p>
<p>A notable absentee was ousted PDI leader Megawati Sukarnoputri, who had become a figurehead for dissent in Indonesia until a government crackdown following riots in Jakarta on July 27.</p>
<p>Megawati, the daughter of late founding president Sukarno, was ousted by Surjadi's government-backed faction in June. The riots, the worst violence in Jakarta for over two decades, broke out after police raided the PDI headquarters in the capital and evicted Megawati's supporters entrenched within.</p>
<p>Political analysts have said the government backed the move to depose Megawati because it feared she could cut into Golkar's votes in the elections and perhaps stand against Suharto in the 1998 presidential elections.</p>
<p>Only the three recognised political parties are eligible to contest the elections and lists of candidates, which are finalised by party chiefs, have to be approved by the military.</p>
<p>The 500 representatives of parliament will join 500 nominated members to form the People's Consultative Assembly, which forms the electoral body for the presidential elections.</p>
<p>Suharto, one of the longest-ruling leaders in the world, has won six five-year terms as president unopposed. He has not said if he will stand in 1998, but analysts say it is likely.</p>
<p>The Jakarta Post newspaper quoted Harmoko as denying the statement was prepared because the contestants feared the conflict within the PDI might render the election legally defective.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a long-dormant group of former government and military officials critical of Suharto issued a statement blaming the PDI imbroglio on the nation's rigid political system.</p>
<p>&quot;The first and primary step to be taken should be to change and revise the laws on the national political system,&quot; said the statement by the Petisi 50 group issued on Tuesday. &quot;In this context, there needs to be a law on the presidency, which includes a limit on the presidential term.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
