<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7407" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: SE Asian Grain - Corn prices drift generally lower.</title>
<headline>SE Asian Grain - Corn prices drift generally lower.</headline>
<byline>Vithoon Amorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southeast Asian corn prices were steady to easier this week on a combination of harvest pressure, high stocks and weak regional demand, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Thai domestic maize/corn prices paid by feed producers eased to an average 4.28 baht/kg this week from 4.42 a week ago due to sustained increased supply from the new Thai harvest reaching the market.  </p>
<p>A major feed producer said the Thai harvest, mostly from eastern Prachinburi and Chantaburi provinces, has raised domestic supply, while parts of the new crops from northeast and north central Thailand have also started to arrive.</p>
<p>&quot;The fresh harvest is adequate to allow most feed plants to open for operation since early August,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>A projected four million tonnes of corn is expected from the domestic 1996/97 (July/June) crop with harvesting continuing until December.  </p>
<p>Bangkok soymeal prices firmed slightly to 9.70 baht/kg from 9.60 a week ago as no additional Brazilian imports have been made this month, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to receive about 5,000-6,000 tonnes from Brazil in mid-September. I estimate total imports next month at over 10,000 tonnes,&quot; an official at Bangkok Produce said.</p>
<p>Feed producers said soymeal fetched a higher price this week as it was mostly made from fresh domestic high-protein soybean which is more expensive than imported product.  </p>
<p>Soymeal prices are expected to ease in late September or early October when the domestic soybean harvest starts reaching the market.</p>
<p>In Indonesia, corn prices were a little lower as demand dropped off in the middle of August following regular orders earlier in the month, traders said.</p>
<p>They said that in the main growing area in Lampung in southern Sumatra corn was around 500 rupiah/kg. In Jakarta, they said the price ranged from 510-520 rupiah/kg, compared with between 530-540 rupiah/kg last week.  </p>
<p>&quot;Those buying corn usually buy at the beginning of the month so the price usually falls around this time,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Another trader said around 90,000 tonnes of corn was thought to have been imported this month but it had not yet hit the market as the importers were waiting for the price to rise.</p>
<p>In Malaysia, product prices were generally maintained at around last week's level.</p>
<p>Traders and buyers said the local market was adequately stocked in the near-term and that fresh orders would depend on lower prices.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market is very quiet, there's been no big business,&quot; said a trader in Singapore. &quot;As for corn and meal, the country (Malaysia) seems adequately stocked until November.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Wheat is also slow, everybody's waiting for the new Australian Wheat Board (production) figures,&quot; added the trader.</p>
<p>Bulk corn in the local market was steady at between 530 and 540 ringgit ($213-$217) at ex-factory/godown rates in the central region.</p>
<p>Singapore traders said on Wednesday that they expected Malaysia to buy small parcels of corn totalling over 100,000 tonnes over the next month.  </p>
<p>&quot;We feel Malaysia will buy small parcels of slightly more than 100,000 tonnes of corn because they need it. Everything else is quiet because people are waiting for Chicago (corn futures) to settle down,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Another trader said the Malaysians would want to lock in their late 1996, early 1997 supply of corn, but find the current price too high. &quot;They're interested, but not at these price.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The international market doesn't look very good now,&quot; said Johnny Ong, managing director of Ho Seng Chan, a regular Malaysian corn buyer. &quot;I'm just waiting to see as prices are going up and down.&quot;  </p>
<p>Imported soymeal in bags was unchanged at around 760 ringgit a tonne at ex-factory/godown rates in the central region. The local material in bags was fetching around 777 ringgit.</p>
<p>&quot;A&quot; grade wheat in bags was also steady at 880 a tonne ex-factory/godown central region while low-grade wheat was in the range of 580-600 ringgit a tonne.</p>
<p>    SOUTHEAST ASIAN GRAIN/MEAL PRICES:     AUG 21   AUG 14</p>
<p>Thailand - Corn/Maize (baht/60 kg)	   257	266</p>
<p>Thailand - Soymeal (baht/kg)		   9.70     9.60</p>
<p>Malaysia - Corn (ringgit/tonne)		530-540  530-540</p>
<p>Malaysia - Grade A wheat (ringgit/tonne)   880	880</p>
<p>Malaysia - Local soymeal (ringgit/tonne)   777	777</p>
<p>Malaysia - Imported soymeal		    760	760</p>
<p>Indonesia - Corn (rupiah/kg)		   510-520  530-540</p>
<p>Indonesia - Soymeal (rupiah/kg)		780	780</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
