<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7427" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PLDT plans to restructure call rates.</title>
<headline>PLDT plans to restructure call rates.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Telecommunications giant Philippine Long Distance Telephone Co. (PLDT) is firming up plans to restructure rates to eliminate the cross-subsidy between international and domestic long distance rates, Edgardo del Fonso, PLDT's chief finance officer, said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan to restructure rates so each segment of the business is viable on its own, Del Fonso told Reuters.</p>
<p>PLDT intends to submit its proposal to the government's National Telecommunciations Commission before the end of the year, he said, adding that the implementation of the restructured rates could coincide with the planned metering of local calls in the first or second quarter of next year.  </p>
<p>&quot;We think that this is the best scenario for the industry. New entrants are not very keen to lay out lines&quot; because of the low rates for national long distance calls versus overseas calls, Del Fonso said.</p>
<p>PLDT's average revenue is 2.10 pesos (8 cents) per minute on national long distance calls but $1.70 per minute on calls to the U.S., which comprise 35 percent of its overseas revenues.</p>
<p>In the first half of 1996, international long distance calls accounted for 58.8 percent of PLDT's revenues, while national long distance calls made up 14.5 percent.</p>
<p>Because of this, the competition is keen on getting a slice of the market for international calls, Del Fonso said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're vulnerable to international calls. It is the source of subsidy for our local exchange, which is being eroded by the competition and the reduction in accounting rates,&quot; the PLDT official said.</p>
<p>The accounting rates refer to the share in revenues of PLDT with other foreign telecommunications companies for overseas calls.</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom (632) 841-8937</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
