<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7429" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan's interest rate policy seen on hold for now.</title>
<headline>Japan's interest rate policy seen on hold for now.</headline>
<byline>Linda Sieg</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan is likely to mirror U.S. inaction on interest rates and maintain its super-easy money policy for now, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The U.S. Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) left its interest rates unchanged at a meeting on Tuesday, a decision financial markets had widely anticipated.</p>
<p>The Federal Reserve has held its target for the key federal funds rate -- which banks charge each other for overnight loans -- at 5.25 percent since January 31, 1996. Despite signs of strong economic growth since then, inflation remains quite low.  </p>
<p>&quot;The view had already spread in the forex market that the Fed would postpone a rise in interest rates, and the fact that the FOMC actually did that was probably due to the Fed's view that there are no strong inflation worries,&quot; a Japanese government source told Reuters.</p>
<p>A Bank of Japan (BOJ) official told Reuters separately that the FOMC decision would not affect Japan's monetary policy.</p>
<p>&quot;It's really a matter of another country's monetary policy, and thus the BOJ's policy will not be affected,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Economists said the Bank of Japan was likely to keep rates at their current rock-bottom levels -- perhaps for the rest of this year -- despite forecasts that a key survey by the central bank, due out next week, would show corporations have become less gloomy about business prospects.</p>
<p>The Bank of Japan has kept its official discount rate, at which it lends to commercial banks, at a record low 0.5 percent since last September. It cut the rate to that level then to ensure Japan's economy did not slip back into recession.  </p>
<p>Speculation swirled last month that the central bank was poised to raise rates, but many economists say those expectations were overdone.</p>
<p>Despite signs the economy is recovering, the pace of improvement is slow and fears remain that the recovery could falter later this year when public spending runs out. A planned increase in Japan's three-percent consumption tax to five percent from April 1, 1997 is another worry.  </p>
<p>Economists expect the Bank of Japan's quarterly corporate survey, known as the &quot;tankan&quot;, to show a modest improvement in business sentiment when data compiled this month is unveiled next Wednesday.</p>
<p>The tankan is closely watched as a clue to monetary policy.</p>
<p>Some expect the tankan's diffusion index for big manufacturers, an important gauge of corporate sentiment, to rise into positive territory for the first time since November 1991, although others say it could languish below zero again.  </p>
<p>The index, which represents the percentage of firms expecting business to improve minus those who expect it to worsen, rose to minus three in the last survey in May. The higher the number, the more optimistic the outlook.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if it (the manufacturers' diffusion index) goes wildly up beyond expectations...I doubt they will raise rates,&quot; said Ron Bevacqua, senior economist at Merrill Lynch in Tokyo.</p>
<p>&quot;I think if they do tighten, it will not be before the end of the calendar year,&quot; he said. Some other economists think the BOJ could nudge up short-term money rates sooner, perhaps this autumn, but not in direct response to the tankan data.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
