<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7438" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper Editorials - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper Editorials - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>With 314 days to go before the British colony reverts to China, the Hong Kong media focused on Taiwan and China relations in the wake of China's announcement on direct shipping ties.</p>
<p>The Beijing-funded TA KUNG PAO said China had long supported the establishment of direct shipping, postal, civil aviation and trading links, but Taiwan had never responded positively.</p>
<p>The paper said many people believed that if direct shipping links between Hong Kong, China and Taiwan were not realised after the Hong Kong handover, Taiwan's economy would suffer.</p>
<p>It said direct shipping ties were an inevitable trend and the Taiwan authorities had no choice but to follow the wishes of the people across the Strait.</p>
<p>The middle of the road MING PAO said Taiwan's policy towards the mainland had toughened recently.</p>
<p>Beijing believed that while Taiwan President Lee Teng-hui avoided talking about the &quot;one China&quot; principle, he was not sincere in giving up Taiwan's independence.</p>
<p>The Chinese language daily said the cold war had come to an end throughout most of the world and it would be sad for all Chinese if a new cold war started across the Strait.</p>
<p>The English language SOUTH CHINA MORNING POST said international trade was not a zero sum game in which one city's gain must always result in another's loss.</p>
<p>Cross-strait links would boost the economies of Taiwan and the neighbouring mainland province of Fujian. This would be beneficial to all of China and to Hong Kong.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843-6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
