<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7471" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: PLO rejects Israel's condition for Hebron pullout.</title>
<headline>PLO rejects Israel's condition for Hebron pullout.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The PLO rejects any linkage between an Israeli troop redeployment in the West Bank city of Hebron and stopping PLO activity in Arab East Jerusalem, a Palestinian official said in an interview published on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Israel said on Tuesday it would not redeploy the troops until the Palestinian Authority closed PLO offices in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>&quot;This logic is unacceptable to us. In fact we reject it completely because the obligations must be fulfilled in time,&quot; Mahmoud Abbas (Abu Mazen), secretary of the PLO's executive committee, told the London-based Arabic newspaper al-Hayat.</p>
<p>An Israeli official quoted Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Tuesday as telling a closed-door session of Israel's Foreign Affairs and Defence Committee that there would be no progress until the offices were closed.</p>
<p>Under a peace accord with the PLO, Israel was due to have redeployed its troops by the end of March in Hebron, the last major Arab West Bank city still under Israeli control.</p>
<p>Israel delayed the redeployment in Hebron after Moslem militants killed 59 people in Israel in a spate of suicide bombings in February and March.</p>
<p>Abu Mazen said the two sides had made preparations to revive the activities of a joint economic committee, including naming heads of the two delegations.</p>
<p>&quot;There is hope to complete other circles. I mean to revive the higher committee and hold summit meetings between (Palestinian President Yasser) Arafat and Netanyahu,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But he said the situation was still difficult and uncertain. &quot;What I am sure about is that we are not going to allow things to go backwards,&quot; Abu Mazen said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
