<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7476" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwait MPs toughen British, French missile probe.</title>
<headline>Kuwait MPs toughen British, French missile probe.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kuwait's parliament has given its public funds watchdog investigatory powers to probe a planned purchase of British naval missiles after officials rejected a cheaper French offer, an official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The public funds committee has been given the power of an investigation commitee to look into the missiles deal,&quot; an official at the national assembly said by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;MPs complained about lack of cooperation from defence ministry officials,&quot; said the official, who declined to be indentified.</p>
<p>Investigatory powers will enable its public funds protection committee, which normally has a monitoring function, to summon defence officials for questioning, political analysts say.</p>
<p>The opposition-dominated house in July gave the committee two weeks to report on the government's choice of British Aerospace Sea Skua missiles over French MM-15 missiles made by Aerospatiale.</p>
<p>Kuwaiti newspapers have said the British missiles would cost 27 million dinars ($90 million) and French missiles about 22 million dinars. MPs say that in view of the price discrepancy they want to ensure the planned deal involves no impropriety.</p>
<p>The committee says it has not completed its report because it has not been able to contact Colonel Marzouk al-Bader, a key figure in the affair who headed a defence ministry committee that selected the French missile. The panel's decision was later overruled and the government chose the British missile.</p>
<p>The defence ministry says Bader is away on an unspecified overseas assignment. The government says the British missile was selected simply because it was better than the French.</p>
<p>The missiles are due to be installed on eight fast patrol boats worth $500 million sold to Kuwait by France in 1995.</p>
<p>($1 = 0.299 dinars)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
