<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7478" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Jordanian press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>JORDAN TIMES</p>
<p>- King, visiting Ramtha, urges citizens to remain united and steadfast. &quot;We should push forward on path of dialogue, democracy and respect for human rights and reject chaos.&quot;</p>
<p>- Curfew on Karak town is relaxed.</p>
<p>- Democratic framework will govern re-evaluation process, government says. Politicians agree on need for opening objective and balanced dialogue.</p>
<p>- King meets senators and deputies from south on Wednesday. Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti exchanges views with southern parliamentarians on recent events, reaffirms no one will face injustice.</p>
<p>- Trade relations with Iraq are unlikely to suffer, officials say.</p>
<p>AL RAI</p>
<p>- King calls for more cohesion and development.</p>
<p>- Karabiti meets senators and deputies from south. Meeting condemns acts of sabotage against government and private-owned buildings.</p>
<p>AD DUSTOUR</p>
<p>- Ramtha experiences national day of happiness after meeting King Hussein.</p>
<p>- King vows to protect gains of every Jordanian. Ramtha citizens pledge loyalty to king and vow to protect homeland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
