<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7479" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: PRESS DIGEST - Turkey - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Turkey - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Turkish press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>SABAH</p>
<p>- Isin Celebi is to stand as a candidate against the Motherland party (ANAP) chairman Mesut Yilmaz at the ANAP annual conference this weekend.</p>
<p>- State Minister Soylemez says reports by the credit rating agency Moody's and the International Monetary Fund (IMF) prove that no economic crisis is likely in Turkey soon.</p>
<p>MILLIYET</p>
<p>- Islamist premier Erbakan is criticised by opposition parties for saying during his visit to Indonesia that there is no brain power in Turkey.</p>
<p>- Police arrest Faysal Akcan, who pulled down the Turkish flag at the pro-Kurdish HADEP party's congress.</p>
<p>HURRIYET</p>
<p>- The Directorate of Religious Affairs says that a women infected with AIDS through a blood transfusion will be a martyr if she dies.</p>
<p>CUMHURIYET</p>
<p>- Celebi, the rival candidate for the chairmanship of the Motherland party vows to revive the party in the spirit of the party's founder Turgut Ozal.</p>
<p>YENI YUZYIL</p>
<p>- The narcotics squad chief says Turkey has gone beyond being a transit country in the drugs trade to becoming a trading centre.</p>
<p>DUNYA</p>
<p>- Treasury bonds are the favourite investment of companies.</p>
<p>ZAMAN</p>
<p>- The outlawed Kurdistan Workers' Party (PKK) kills 13 civilians in Sivas, central Turkey, which is turning into a PKK base.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
