<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7481" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Egyptian press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-AHRAM</p>
<p>- Palestinian President Yasser Arafat asks Egypt's President Mubarak to help stop construction of Jewish settlements in the West Bank and Gaza Strip.</p>
<p>- Japanese Foreign Minister Ikeda in Cairo to discuss economic cooperation and latest developments in the Middle East. He will also meet Mubarak during his three-day visit.</p>
<p>- French daily &quot;Liberation&quot; lauds Mubarak's economic policy and dealings with the International Monetary Fund, says Egypt has gained from the experiences of other countries and not raised prices of basic goods.</p>
<p>- Egypt's Interior Ministry, to support Egypt's economic progress, will help set up a specialised company to ferry banks deposits and will deploy expert security personnel to protect financial institutions.</p>
<p>AL-AKHBAR</p>
<p>- Labour Minister Ahmed el-Amawi says United Nations fund approved $492 million to compensate Egyptian workers affected by the Gulf War. Amawi also told reporters there are too many civil servants, too little job opportunities and that the private sector is now the place to find jobs.</p>
<p>- Egypt to spend up to four billion pounds this year to subsidise bread and other foodstuffs.</p>
<p>AL-GOMHURIA</p>
<p>- Education minister says private universities will not lessen education opportunities for the income-impaired.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
