<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7486" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in Israeli newspapers on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>HAARETZ</p>
<p>- &quot;We are not threatening Syria,&quot; Israeli Prime Minister Netanyahu says.</p>
<p>- Arrow 2 makes first successful intercept of missile.</p>
<p>- Givati brigade soldier killed by comrades' fire in Lebanon.</p>
<p>- U.N. coordinator Larsen warns of financial collapse of Palestinian Authority within weeks.</p>
<p>YEDIOTH AHRONOTH</p>
<p>- Israeli soldier killed in Lebanon by comrades' fire.</p>
<p>- Israel calms Syria: We want peace -- not war.</p>
<p>MAARIV</p>
<p>- Tragedy in Lebanon: Israeli soldier shot to death by comrades.</p>
<p>- Arrow 2 -- successful test.</p>
<p>- Israel has no intention of attacking Syria.</p>
<p>- Netanyahu's office trying to arrange a meeting with Moroccan king.</p>
<p>GLOBES</p>
<p>- Africa-Israel board expected to fire managing director.</p>
<p>- Revised estimate: Q2 GDP up 0.6 percent.</p>
<p>- State-owned companies' profits, excluding retirement payments, increased to 594 million shekels in 1995.</p>
<p>- First International Bank of Israel profits drop 8.5 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>JERUSALEM POST</p>
<p>- Soldier killed in friendly fire mishap in Lebanon.</p>
<p>- Arrow intercepts target.</p>
<p>- Netanyahu: Syrian missile test poses no new threat.</p>
<p>- U.N. coordinator: Palestinian Authority near financial collapse.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
