<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7488" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Moroccan King calls for &quot;yes&quot; vote in referendum.</title>
<headline>Moroccan King calls for &quot;yes&quot; vote in referendum.</headline>
<byline>Ali Bouzerda</byline>
<dateline>RABAT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>King Hassan of Morocco on Tuesday called on the country to vote &quot;yes&quot; in a referendum on constitutional reform to split the existing 333-seat parliament into two chambers.</p>
<p>The referendum would be held on September 13, he said.</p>
<p>In a 45-minute live televised speech, the Moroccan monarch said the reforms aimed for decentralisation, regionalisation and local democracy as well as the split-up of the assembly.</p>
<p>&quot;I call on you dear people to vote &quot;yes' in favour of this new step in Morocco's democratic experience,&quot; the king said.</p>
<p>The speech came on a national holiday to commemorate his father King Mohamed V's temporary removal from the throne by French colonial authorities in 1953.</p>
<p>Hassan, 67, said the constitutional amendment would split the Majlis Anuwab (Chamber of Representatives) into two chambers to strengthen regional representation in a new, lower house.</p>
<p>The new chamber would be named the Majlis al-Mustacharin (Consultative Chamber) but would have &quot;a decision-making power&quot;, he said. &quot;It will have the power to pass a vote of no confidence against the government.&quot;</p>
<p>The king said local councils, chambers of commerce, industry and agriculture would be represented in the lower house. It would be elected through indirect suffrage, while the Chamber of Representatives will be elected by direct vote.</p>
<p>He said the lower house would &quot;play a key role in responding to youth demands for jobs&quot;.</p>
<p>An estimated 300,000 young Moroccans enter the job market each year but jobs are scarce and wages are low. Unemployment is officially said to be 16 percent but opposition trade unions estimate it at 23 percent of Morocco's 10-million workforce.</p>
<p>The king gave no details of the number of deputies or structure of the future bicameral parliament.</p>
<p>He said he expected the existing parliament to be dissolved a few months after the referendum and general elections to take place before April 1997.</p>
<p>The referendum and elections would be held in the disputed Western Sahara, under Moroccan administration since 1976.</p>
<p>The desert territory, whose independence is sought by the Polisario Front, has a dozen deputies in the present parliament, which was elected in 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RABAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
