<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7493" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Krupp down after warning for H2 business.</title>
<headline>Krupp down after warning for H2 business.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in German steel and machinery group Fried. Krupp AG Hoesch-Krupp dropped on Wednesday after the company warned that the second half of 1996 would be more difficult than expected.</p>
<p>Dealers said the forecast, made in Krupp's interim report, was interpreted by the market as a profit warning.</p>
<p>The stock had dropped 2.7 percent to 214 marks by 0921 GMT, making it among the three biggest decliners, while the blue-chip DAX index was down 0.6 percent at 2,545.11 points.</p>
<p>However one dealer predicted that the effect would be short-lived as the difficulties the company faces, especially in the steel sector, were already well known.</p>
<p>Dealers also attributed a small sell-off in steelmaker Thyssen AG during the pre-bourse session to Krupp's warning.</p>
<p>Thyssen shares were down one mark at 262.50 in bourse trade, more or less in line with the overall market, after falling to a low of 260 in the early electronic trading session.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
