<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7502" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Legal system under attack in Belgian sex scandal.</title>
<headline>Legal system under attack in Belgian sex scandal.</headline>
<byline>Nieck Ammerlaan</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian media on Wednesday accused judicial authorities of incompetence in handling the country's child sex scandal as the search widened for two young girls abducted by a convicted child rapist.</p>
<p>The whereabouts of An Marchal and Eefje Lambrecks were still a mystery after they were kidnapped in the port of Ostend last August by Marc Dutroux, a child sex abuser who served time in prison between 1989 and 1992.</p>
<p>Belgian newspapers lambasted the lack of cooperation between public prosecutor's offices and investigating judges, adding that investigators had ignored warnings about Dutroux's practices.</p>
<p>Several papers cited reports by an unnamed informer who said he told the public prosecutor's office in the southeastern town of Liege repeatedly between mid-1993 and August 1995 that Dutroux kidnapped children for money -- 100,000 to 150,000 francs ($30,000 to $45,000) -- and sexual abuse.</p>
<p>Two other girls -- eight-year-olds Julie Lejeune and Melissa Russo -- were snatched in June 1995 and handed to him. They died of starvation early this year while Dutroux was in prison on charges of theft and violence.</p>
<p>The papers said the informer also told the authorities Dutroux was building underground cells in his houses - reportedly some 10 - to hold child kidnap victims prior to their transfer abroad.</p>
<p>A police report of the informer's allegations was sent to police in Lejeune and Russo's home town of Grace-Hollogne, but they did not appear to have taken it into account during searches in the case or others involving Dutroux, the newspaper reports said.</p>
<p>Investigators searched two locations while probing a case of theft but found nothing suspicious. When asked about the underground construction in the houses, Dutroux reportedly said he was redesigning the cellars.</p>
<p>Two other girls -- a 14-year-old and a 12-year-old -- were rescued last Friday from a makeshift concrete dungeon in a house owned by Dutroux in Charleroi.</p>
<p>Judicial authorities in Neufchateau -- responsible for orchestrating the rescue -- won praise for their swift and coordinated actions. But authorities from the districts where Lejeune and Russo, and Marchal and Lambrecks lived came under fire.</p>
<p>Dutch-language newspaper De Standaard said the legal system had been slow, lethargic and insensitive.</p>
<p>It had not taken the investigation seriously; it had told Lejeune and Russo's parents to accept the death of their missing children while they were still alive; it had failed to monitor a convicted child rapist after his release, the paper charged.</p>
<p>Dutroux was released 10 years early in 1992 from a 13-year sentence for multiple rape and child abuse despite stern warnings from the prosecutor involved and his own mother.</p>
<p>In a bid to find Marchal and Lambrecks, an extra 30 investigators are being added to the team which widened its searches to a number of other countries, including the Netherlands and Britain.</p>
<p>Neufchateau public prosecutor Michel Bourlet told a news conference on Tuesday that there were elements in the dossier allowing him to believe the girls were still alive.</p>
<p>At least 15 children have disappeared in Belgium in the past six years. Seven have now been found dead, six are still missing and only two have been rescued.</p>
<p>Lejeune and Russo's horrible deaths from hunger have shocked Belgians who have been signing condolence registers, offering floral tributes and filing past the girls' coffins.</p>
<p>Between 50,000 and 100,000 are expected to attend Thursday's memorial service for the two friends in Liege, which will be broadcast live on Belgian television.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
