<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7514" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: PRESS DIGEST - Italy - Wednesday Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Italy - Wednesday Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the top headlines in leading Italian newspapers.</p>
<p>---------------</p>
<p>TOP POLITICAL STORIES</p>
<p>*Three magistrates from Mantova, Bergamo and Tolmezzo have asked for authorisation to prosecute Northern League party leader Umberto Bossi on charges ranging from slander to reconstitution of the Fascist party, instigation to criminal behavior and outrage against the head of State. Bossi attacked Luciano Violante, speaker of the House of Representatives, saying &quot;he is a fascist&quot;.(all).</p>
<p>*Minister for Public Works Antonio Di Pietro blames Ciriaco De Mita, former Christian Democrat secretary general, for not assuming his responsabilities in Tangentopoli (Bribesville): &quot;Even last time I saw him he asked me a favour&quot;. De Mita said Di Pietro is &quot;a liar&quot; (all).</p>
<p>* &quot;The government is optimistic over Stet privatisation. Dialogue with communist leader Fausto Bertinotti is open&quot; says undersecretary to the Prime Minister Enrico Micheli (La Stampa, L'Unita').</p>
<p>TOP BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>*Inflation heads towards another slowdown, after Istat released lower June PPI, down 0,2 per cent, and wholesale prices, down 0,4 per cent. Innocenzo Cipolletta, general director of Confindustria, says: &quot;Now, the last problem is the renewal of contracts&quot; (Corriere).</p>
<p>* Trade union CGIL says Public Employment Minister Franco Bassanini should go ahead with his proposal to check whether any public sector employees are holding down two jobs (all).</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>Reuter has not verified these stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>--- Milan bureau +392 66129450</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
