<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7533" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Finland - August 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Finland - August 21.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The folowing are some of the leading stories in Finnish papers this morning.</p>
<p>HELSINGIN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Waiting lines to state-subsidised student apartments have doubled in two years. Demand oupaces available flats also on the open market.</p>
<p>- One of twenty mentally ill out-patients with record of violent begaviour but not sentenced due to illness commits a new violent crime, most aim to kill their victim, Finnish doctor says.</p>
<p>- Too many passenger ferries compete in the English channel, says Silja CEO Jukka Suominen, who also criticises Eurotunnel. Silja's Sally UK unit, operating in the channel, runs at a loss.</p>
<p>- Opposition Centre Party leader Esko Aho expects regional differences to grow. Party opposes government plan to reduce number of provinces.</p>
<p>- Ministries fight over how to use about 2.5  billion markka income from state's sale of Valmet shares, no decision yet.</p>
<p>- Greenpeace activists, chaining themselves to harvesters and trees, halted logging by Enso in Russian Carelia. Enso said logging did not take place in environmentally protected area.</p>
<p>KAUPPALEHTI</p>
<p>- Finnish cooperative banking group management and regional medium-sized banks in dispute as many smaller banks unwilling to join new association and be forced to help pay losses of co-op banks in capital area.</p>
<p>- Decision on who wins concession to operate fourth national TV-channel expected in the near future.</p>
<p>- We do not want to mislead investors, Neste vice-president, soon-to-be CEO Jukka Viinanen said in response to share analysts expressing surprise that Neste so openly told of crude oil trading losses.</p>
<p>DEMARI</p>
<p>- King of Sweden Carl Gustaf, Queen Silvia and Crown Princess Victoria to visit Finland next week.</p>
<p>AAMULEHTI</p>
<p>- Last year's syphilis epidemic showed that young docotors did not recognise the symptoms of syphilis, which already had almost disappeared from Finland.</p>
<p>-- Paivi Mattila, Helsinki Newsroom +358 - 0 - 680 50 292</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
