<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7534" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Wednesday morning's Austrian newspapers.</p>
<p>DIE PRESSE</p>
<p>- Johannes Ditz, finance chief of the national postal system, said he doubted the 1999 deadline for privatisation could be met. He said it was only possible &quot;under optimal conditions&quot;.</p>
<p>- Austria has the fourth highest wage costs world-wide.</p>
<p>- Austria's industry is not expected to pick up until 1997, chamber of economy expert Joachim Lamel said.</p>
<p>- OMV is investing seven billion schillings in a new expansion drive this year, almost twice as much as last year. The company plans to build 100 petrol stations abroad by 1998 and cut the number of stations in Austria.</p>
<p>DER STANDARD</p>
<p>- Tyre-maker Semperit AG will be split into two limited liability companies directly subordinate to the German group Continental. The two units will handle sales and production seperately.</p>
<p>KURIER</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Viktor Klima said the state would have to consider a tax reform in 1999 or 2000 &quot;at the latest&quot;. He said loopholes would be eliminated and tax rates cut.</p>
<p>- Raiffeisen Zentralbank said it was expanding its eastern European activities, moving into investment banking in Croatia and Russia. The company expects both sectors to break even within two years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
