<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7535" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - August 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - August 21.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of stories in the Irish press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>IRISH INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>- Police in Queensland are searching for four Irish people missing in Australia.</p>
<p>- Ireland's olympic triple gold medallist Michelle Smith has rejected the advances of Hollywood and turned down an initial approach from film moguls worth millions.</p>
<p>- Ireland's Kerry Group on Tuesday announced a better-than-expected jump in half-year profits to just under 20 million Irish pounds, a rise of over 21 per cent.  </p>
<p>- Unilever Ireland is to send a circular to minority shareholders in Lyons Irish Holdings later on Wednesday, following the notification to the Stock Exchange this morning of how many of those shareholders accepted the company's 323p per share offer for their shock.</p>
<p>IRISH TIMES</p>
<p>- It is easier to get into a college in Ireland in 1996, but more difficult than ever to secure a place on high-points courses such as medicine, physiotherapy and computing according to the first round of offers from the Central Applications Office.</p>
<p>- The annual cost to Irish-owned manufacturers of financing over-due credit payments is 79 million Irish pounds, according to a study commissioned by the Irish Small and Medium Enterprises Association (ISME).</p>
<p>--Dublin Newsroom +353 1 6603377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
