<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7536" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Aug 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Aug 21.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in the Swedish papers this morning. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAGENS NYHETER</p>
<p>- A parliamentary working hours committee proposes liberalisation of legislation governing holidays. At present, the fifth statutory holiday week may only be saved for five years after which the employer buys out the holiday time from the employee.</p>
<p>- Two rail workers were killed on Stockholm's underground system on Tuesday when they were hit by a southbound train. It is as yet unclear why all of the safety systems failed.</p>
<p>- More than half of naval shipyard Kockums' 900 employees in the southern city of Malmo are to lose their jobs in a thorough restructuring of the Celsius-owned unit.</p>
<p>SVENSKA DAGBLADET</p>
<p>- A decision on the fate of Sweden's state pension system will be delayed for at least a year. The government will not have time to deal with the issue during the autumn, and the social affairs ministry is not prepared to promise a new system before next year.</p>
<p>DAGENS INDUSTRI</p>
<p>- Saab Aircraft must improve 48 points of its quality assurance system if it is to qualify as a sub-contractor to U.S. aircraft manufacturer Boeing, even though Saab is certified under the ISO 9000 quality standard.</p>
<p>- Nine small power producers have accused market leaders such as Vattenfall of manipulating electricity prices. The nine say the giants on the market keep prices high by refusing to deliver power to the new Nordic electricity bourse.</p>
<p>- Anders Scharp, chairman of Wallenberg-sphere companies such as SKF, Electrolux, Incentive and Scania, says he expects to recruit more bosses from abroad. However, foreign managers would not be expected to move to Sweden's disadvantageous tax and meterological climates.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
