<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7541" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: PRESS DIGEST - Netherlands - August 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Netherlands - August 21.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main stories in Dutch newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>HET FINANCIEELE DAGBLAD</p>
<p>- Manufacturing output was 4.7 percent higher in June than in the year-earlier period. (p1)</p>
<p>- Shipping and storage concern Pakhoed forecasts clear profit increase in second half. (p1)</p>
<p>- Dutch railways NS books higher profit with lower government subsidy. (p1)</p>
<p>- Lower tax revenue as company profits rise stronger than wages - finance ministry research. (p1)</p>
<p>- Unlisted securities market is to be converted into a low threshold stock exchange for new companies. (p1)</p>
<p>- Transport and tank storage company Van Ommeren's H1 net up 15 pct due to tank storage. (p3)</p>
<p>- Food and detergent group Unilever's bid for Lyons Irish Holdings forces the Irish tea company's board to resign. (p3)</p>
<p>- Office quipment supplier Ahrend targets fast growth of its German activities. (p3)</p>
<p>DE VOLKSKRANT</p>
<p>- Labour shortage will force up wages in 1997, according to Central Planning Bureau. (p1)</p>
<p>- Green investors start shareholders lobby group VBDO. (p2)</p>
<p>DE TELEGRAAF</p>
<p>- Korea's industrial giant Samsung in ultimate attempt to takeover bankrupt aircraft maker Fokker. (p1)</p>
<p>- Amsterdam to build houses in port area despite U.S. company Cargill's fierce opposition. (p9)</p>
<p>- Steel concern Hoogovens is to start a European works council. (p21)</p>
<p>- Realty investment company Pay-Bas Property Fund first half results up to Dfl 8.2 million from Dfl 3.9 million. (p21)</p>
<p>TROUW</p>
<p>- Work-to-rule strike threatens at Royal Dutch Airlines/ KLM. (p7)</p>
<p>ALGEMEEN DAGBLAD</p>
<p>- Internet providers and companies giving staff access to the internet are punishable in case of misuse, says justice minister. (p1)</p>
<p>- Agriculture minister persists in his refusal to allow waste disposal ovens AVR to destroy British BSE cows. (p13)</p>
<p>-- Amsterdam Newsdesk +31-20-504-5000 (FAX 31-20-504-5040)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
