<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7550" id="root" date="1996-08-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Russia thanks U.N. for role in airmen's release.</title>
<headline>Russia thanks U.N. for role in airmen's release.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's ambassador Sergei Lavrov on Tuesday thanked the United Nations for its efforts to secure the release of seven Russian airmen, who escaped last week after a year's captivity in Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Lavrov, according to a U.N. statement, thanked U.N. Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali &quot;for the steps taken in the interest in freeing the Russian airmen detained by the Afghan Taleban movement.&quot;</p>
<p>U.N. officials said their staff in Afghanistan held negotiations with the Islamic militia, which captured the airmen a year ago. But the United Nations did not take credit for the airmen's escape in their own plane last Friday from the southern Afghan town of Kandahar.</p>
<p>The new U.N. special representative in Afghanistan, Norbert Holl of Germany, who took up his post last month, had visited the airmen in captivity, German sources said.</p>
<p>The Taleban, which controls about half of Afghanistan, says it forced down the Russians' plane last August because it was carrying ammunition, claiming this was proof that Moscow backed the Kabul government.</p>
<p>Soviet troops supported a communist government in Afghanistan from 1979 until their withdrawal in 1989. Islamic and other factions overthrew the communist government three years later but have battled each other since then.</p>
<p>The airmen, who flew on Friday to the United Arab Emirates in their own Ilyushin-76 cargo plane, returned home on Monday.</p>
<p>In Moscow, Russia's deputy prime minister, Vitaly Igatenko, said several countries had helped to free the airmen, including the United States, Pakistan, India and Morocco.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
