<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7552" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London underground rail strikes called off.</title>
<headline>London underground rail strikes called off.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Planned strikes on London's underground railway were called off on Thursday after a union representing train drivers agreed to a pay and hours deal.</p>
<p>Although London commuters will now be spared 24-hour strikes that had been scheduled for Friday and next Tuesday, the Rail, Maritime and Transport union (RMT) was still planning to stage a 24-hour walkout on Friday against seven train companies up and down Britain.</p>
<p>The stoppage was expected to cripple train services at the start of a busy three-day holiday weekend.</p>
<p>The main union representing London's underground drivers, Aslef, had already accepted the pay and hours package.</p>
<p>Separately on Thursday, Britain's postal delivery workers staged the sixth in a series of one-day strikes in protest at new working arrangements drawn up by the Royal Mail.</p>
<p>However, hopes of a settlement rose after the Communication Workers Union (CWU) sent a letter to managers asking for more talks. The Royal Mail has declined previous offers of talks after the CWU executive threw out a deal accepted by its own negotiators, but a spokeswoman said it was considering the latest request.</p>
<p>Industrial unrest has been on the rise in Britain in recent months after several years of relative calm.</p>
<p>The number of working days lost to strikes in June was 228,000, the highest figure in six years but still a far cry from the 2.4 million days lost in the summer of 1989 in a series of rail and docks strikes.</p>
<p>During the 1984 miners' strike, three million working days were lost in one month.</p>
<p>Alan Johnson, general secretary of the CWU, blamed the new rash of strikes on growing job insecurity in both the public and private sectors.</p>
<p>&quot;People feel insecure. Many of them are on short-term contracts and performance-based pay -- all ideas that were introduced during the 1980s and they have led to a situation where people do not feel tranquil in their employment. And that leads to all kinds of tensions,&quot; he told Channel Four news.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
