<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7558" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Morton Downey to file tobacco suit.</title>
<headline>Morton Downey to file tobacco suit.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Gail Appleson, Law Correspondent</p>
<p>Former talk show host Morton Downey, Jr. who has contracted lung cancer, is planning to sue the tobacco industry and the Kansas City, Mo., law firm of Shook, Hardy &amp; Bacon, his lawyer said Thursday.</p>
<p>Steven Kramer, Downey's New York City lawyer, told Reuters that the suit will be filed next month in New Jersey where Downey had lived and his show was produced.</p>
<p>Downey now lives in Sherman Oaks, Calif.</p>
<p>&quot;He wants to speak out to stop young people from smoking,&quot; Kramer said. &quot;He's very angry at the tobacco companies for not telling the truth about nicotine.&quot;</p>
<p>The television personality's planned suit is the latest in a host of legal attacks on the tobacco industry. On Thursday alone, a key smoker's case is expected to go to an Indianapolis jury and Oklahoma became the 14th state to sue the industry to recoup health care costs.</p>
<p>On Friday, the White House plans to announce its endorsement of Food and Drug Administration regulations aimed at keeping cigarettes away from children.</p>
<p>Downey underwent surgery in July at the Cedars-Sinai Medical Centre in Los Angeles, where doctors removed an inch-and-a-half diameter tumour from the upper lobe of Downey's right lung.</p>
<p>Downey, 63, who used to be a strong advocate of smokers' rights, announced last month that his lung cancer was the result of 50 years of smoking.</p>
<p>He recently made an anti-smoking public service announcement on behalf of the American Lung Association.</p>
<p>Downey was dubbed &quot;The Mouth&quot; for his sometimes confrontational style, in which he often jabbed a cigarette in the faces of audience and guests on his popular syndicated TV show in the late 1980s.</p>
<p>A former board member of the National Smokers Alliance, Downey resigned in January.</p>
<p>&quot;I realised that the major tobacco companies were lying when they said they weren't adding dangerous levels of nicotine to cigarette tobacco. They're nothing but tobacco terrorists,&quot; he had said.</p>
<p>Kramer said the Downey suit will be filed in Newark, N.J. federal court and will be brought under the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organisations Act.</p>
<p>Last week Kramer filed two other RICO actions against the tobacco industry in New York and New Jersey and will be filing a third Friday in Newark, N.J., federal court. He said he believes that the cases were the first to name Shook Hardy as a defendant.</p>
<p>One suit was brought Aug. 12 in Newark federal court by Judy Mantel, a 61-year-old New Jersey resident who had smoked for 45 years and has been diagnosed with lung cancer.</p>
<p>The other suit was filed Aug. 13 in the New York Supreme Court in Queens County by four plaintiffs one of whom wrote advertising copy about Kent cigarettes.</p>
<p>The complaints alleged that the tobacco industry has lied about its knowledge of the addictive nature of nicotine.</p>
<p>The suits also alleged that the defendants have controlled the amount of nicotine &quot;with the effect of creating and sustaining the addiction of plaintiffs.&quot;</p>
<p>To support the racketeering claims, the plaintiffs cite internal industry documents and testimony by tobacco companies' chief executives in 1994 congressional hearings at which they denied that nicotine is addictive.</p>
<p>The lawsuits also alleged that the Shook Hardy firm designated certain documents as confidential by wrongfully claiming that they were protected by attorney client privilege.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
