<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7561" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks rally led by technology shares, German rate cut.</title>
<headline>Stocks rally led by technology shares, German rate cut.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks rallied Thursday, boosted by renewed strength in battered technology shares and a surprisingly sharp cut in the German central bank's key money market interest rate.</p>
<p>At 1 p.m. EDT, the Dow Jones industrial average jumped 38.47 points to 5,728.29. In the broader market, advancing issues beat declines 2-1 on moderately active trading of 216 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index, which is laced with high technology stocks, gained 12.94 points at 1,139.78. The American Stock Exchange index was up 2.05 at 559.73.</p>
<p>The move by Germany's Bundesbank to lower its repurchase rate by 0.30 percentage point to 3 percent surprised currency markets, which had anticipated a smaller reduction.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank's cut, which may make U.S. assets more attractive to international investors, was quickly followed by European and Canada's central banks and helped sparked a dollar rally in Europe that carried over to U.S. stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;We're seeing a nice little rally here,&quot; said Scott Bleier, chief investment strategist at Prime Charter Ltd. &quot;Markets were encouraged by the European rate cuts.&quot;</p>
<p>Broad buying emerged in technology stocks, but analysts cautioned that most tech stocks have a long way to go before any talk of a new rally is in order.</p>
<p>&quot;To us, this still looks like a rally from an oversold condition,&quot; said Chris Dickerson, analyst at Global Market Strategists Inc.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, tobacco stocks remained under pressure, with Philip Morris sliding another 1-5/8 to 86 after losing nearly 4 on Wednesday under the weight of mounting lawsuits and rising prospects of added regulation.</p>
<p>President Clinton was expected to say on Friday that he accepts a Food and Drug Administration recommendation that tobacco be regulated as a drug.</p>
<p>SDL Inc. fell 10 to 18 after Cowen &amp; Co. cut its earnings estimates on the company and Donaldson, Lufkin &amp; Jenrette expressed concern about the company's third quarter outlook.</p>
<p>Zenith Electronics jumped 4-1/2 to 15-7/8 after winning a $1 billion contract to produce set-top boxes for programming consortium Americast.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
