<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7564" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London precious metals drift in pre-holiday lull.</title>
<headline>London precious metals drift in pre-holiday lull.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold drifted in sleepy trading on Thursday and was likely to remain listless ahead of a holiday weekend in Britain and Hong Kong, dealers said.</p>
<p>Precious metals, led by silver, made a half-hearted attempt to push higher late in the afternoon but quickly reverted to previous price levels.</p>
<p>Gold bullion closed at $386.95 an ounce in London, compared with $387.25 on Wednesday. Little change was expected until after the holidays on Monday, dealers said.</p>
<p>The market shrugged off news that the German Bundesbank had cut its key money market interest rate much more than expected.</p>
<p>But analysts said that a more accommodating monetary policy stance might lower real interest rates and boost demand for precious metals from both investors and fabricators.</p>
<p>Gold prices turned higher last month after sinking steadily since hitting a six-year peak of $418 an ounce in February.</p>
<p>But they have stagnated under the key $390-an-ounce level, as a summer lull in leading consumer India and jewellery producer Italy dulled demand.</p>
<p>Silver, which had managed to rally briskly in New York on Monday, failed in its latest attempt to break through a tough resistance level around $5.25 an ounce.</p>
<p>It closed at $5.23, up three cents from Wednesday.</p>
<p>Dealers were mixed on whether it could break out of its post-rally range before the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to be $5.15-$5.25. That's it,&quot; one said. But others said it still had momentum from Monday's overnight rally to break higher and test resistance around $5.30.</p>
<p>Platinum barely budged, ending at $399.25 an ounce, up $0.25. But palladium, which had recovered slightly after tumbling to 2-1/2 year lows earlier this week, slid lower in late trading. If finished $1.75 lower at $123.75 an ounce.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
