<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7565" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Japan links new loans to Egypt with IMF reforms.</title>
<headline>Japan links new loans to Egypt with IMF reforms.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan has told Egypt it may consider resuming soft loans to Cairo if the Egyptian government sticks to an IMF economic reform programme due to be agreed later this year, a Japanese official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be watching the implementation of the (International Monetary Fund) agreement with great interest and resumption of yen loans would be considered in this context,&quot; the foreign ministry official, who asked not to be named, told reporters.</p>
<p>He said Japan's foreign minister Yukihiko Ikeda made the offer at a meeting with Egyptian Prime Minister Kamal Ganzouri in Cairo on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Japan's concessionary loans to Egypt stopped in 1991 when Tokyo agreed to write off Egyptian debts of 209 billion yen ($1.93 billion) as part of a deal by Western creditor nations to cut Cairo's crippling debt burden by half.</p>
<p>The official said Ganzouri had told Ikeda that a deal with the IMF on a wide-ranging package of economic refoms was now &quot;in sight&quot; and resumption of the loans would provide incentive for Japanese firms to invest in Egypt.</p>
<p>Egyptian and IMF officials said earlier this month they had reached agreement on a draft for the economic reforms, aimed at transforming Egypt's lumbering command economy into a dynamic market-driven system. The draft deal has yet to be formally approved by the IMF in Washington.</p>
<p>Ikeda is on the third day of his visit to Egypt, the first stop on a Middle East tour. He will also visit Syria, Israel, the Palestinian self-rule areas and Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>He met Egypt's President Hosni Mubarak in the Mediterranean city of Alexandria on Thursday and discussed plans for a $140 million road bridge over the Suez Canal, which would be the only fixed overland link between continents of Africa and Asia.</p>
<p>Egypt says Japan has promised to pay 60 percent of the costs but the Japanese official said no commitment was made.</p>
<p>&quot;Costing is still being discussed,&quot; the official said. &quot;Ikeda said it is Japan's intention to continue to move this project forward because it will be a symbol of peace.&quot;</p>
<p>$1 = 108.33 yen</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
