<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7567" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: China, Taiwan call for talks amid Ukraine uproar.</title>
<headline>China, Taiwan call for talks amid Ukraine uproar.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Parker</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>China and Taiwan restated their desire on Thursday to resume talks stalled a year ago over the estranged island's drive to wriggle free of political isolation enforced by its huge communist rival.</p>
<p>But China's fury over a secretive mission by Taiwan's vice-president ito Ukraine chilled hopes for a breakthrough.</p>
<p>&quot;Now is the time for the sides (China and Taiwan) to engage in political talks... to end the state of hostility,&quot; China's top negotiator, Tang Shubei, was quoted by state media as saying.</p>
<p>Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Shen Guofang, in a subsequent interview in Beijing, sounded less enthusiastic, repeating Beijing's line that Taipei was holding up talks.</p>
<p>&quot;The necessary atmosphere for the opening of the talks has been disrupted by the Taiwan authorities,&quot; Shen told Reuters.</p>
<p>Taiwan issued a positive, though noncommittal, response.</p>
<p>&quot;We have never ruled out talks on political issues with the mainland,&quot; said Kao Koong-lian of Taiwan's Mainland Affairs Council. &quot;The most urgent thing now is to resume negotiations.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts were quick to note that previous calls for talks had come to naught, though they pointed out that China's earlier expressions had called for a &quot;timetable for talks&quot; while Tang's latest comment said the time for talks had come.</p>
<p>The mutual calls coincided with Beijing's furious censure of the former Soviet republic Ukraine, which offended China by allowing a private visit by Taiwan Vice-President Lien Chan.</p>
<p>Taiwan media said Lien won agreement to swap unofficial representative offices with Ukraine during a meeting with President Leonid Kuchma.</p>
<p>Kuchma aides denied that any meeting took place, though Ukraine Foreign Minister Hennady Udovenko later took a shot at Beijing, calling its official protest &quot;out of proportion&quot;.</p>
<p>Lien, on his return to Taipei, coyly declined to confirm or deny meeting Kuchma but said: &quot;I met the people I wanted to meet and discussed the things I wanted to discuss&quot;.</p>
<p>Lien said Kiev understood the importance of representative offices and that &quot;subsequent development&quot; could be expected, adding that he had agreed not to reveal details of his visit.</p>
<p>Beijing has viewed Taiwan as a rebel province since a civil war split them in 1949, pushing it into isolation and reserving the right to use force to bring it under China's red flag.</p>
<p>China on Monday won the latest round in its diplomatic tug-of-war with Taiwan, restoring ties with Niger four years after it switched recognition to Taipei. Only 30 states now recognise Taiwan's exiled Republic of China.</p>
<p>The next day, Beijing launched a separate effort to woo Taiwan back to the fold, publishing rules governing direct shipping across the Taiwan Strait, despite Taiwan's 47-year-old ban on direct investment, transport and communications.</p>
<p>The rules buoyed Taiwan investors, who have poured some $20 billion into China and clamour for cheaper direct links.</p>
<p>It remained to be seen whether either side would allow vessels flying third-country flags to pioneer direct routes.</p>
<p>After decades of cross-straits enmity, an economic thaw in the late 1980s heralded historic quasi-official talks in 1993, which evolved into increasingly productive contacts.</p>
<p>But relations crashed in mid-1995 after Washington allowed Taiwan President Lee Teng-hui to make a private U.S. visit.</p>
<p>Beijing assailed Lee's journey as a breach of Washington's &quot;one-China&quot; policy, the cornerstone of U.S.-China ties.</p>
<p>It also punished Taiwan by freezing the talks and mounting a campaign of intimidating war games and missile tests in waters near the island that peaked just before Taiwan's first-ever direct presidential election on March 23 this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
