<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7614" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IFC emerging market index up 0.6 pct at 290.88.</title>
<headline>IFC emerging market index up 0.6 pct at 290.88.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Finance Corporation composite investable index, denominated in dollars, rose 0.6 percent to 290.88 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Latin America was down 0.4 percent day-on-day at 534.39, Asia was up 1.5 at 250.13, and Europe, Middle East and Africa were up 0.4 percent at 130.28.</p>
<p>The IFC composite index touched a 1996 high of 308.77 on July 4, up from the year's 275.79 low, recorded on January 1.</p>
<p>ING Barings' Global Emerging Market Index  BFFO, also denominated in dollars, was up 0.53 percent day-on-day at 157.41 at 1138 GMT.</p>
<p>The year's high was 165.948, reached on July 3. It touched the year's 148.85 low on January 2.</p>
<p>Morgan Stanley's dollar-denominated Emerging Markets Free index, was up 0.55 percent at 472.731, calculated after the close of play on Wednesday.</p>
<p>It touched a 1996 high at 505.452 on July 4; the year's 458.369 low was recorded on January 1.</p>
<p>All indices are capitalisation-weighted and are calculated daily. The IFC index measures returns on equities, liquid and accessible to foreign investors, from 26 emerging market countries. It is updated at 2300 GMT.</p>
<p>The BEMI index measures equity returns from some 20 emerging market countries, with the latest changes reported by 0900 GMT.</p>
<p>The MSCI Free measures equity returns from 22 emerging market nations. Changes are reported with one day's lag at 1300 GMT.</p>
<p>--Julia Meehan, London Newsroom +44 171 542 2734</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
