<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7615" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Gold prices locked in range by summer doldrums.</title>
<headline>Gold prices locked in range by summer doldrums.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Precious metals prices were virtually stationary on Thursday, paralysed by summer doldrums and an upcoming long holiday weekend in Britain and Hong Kong, dealers said.</p>
<p>Bullion markets in London and Hong Kong will be closed on Monday for holidays, meaning dealers will be anxious to avoid of any sharp price movements ahead of next week.</p>
<p>&quot;That's not going to help. But there hasn't been any interest for the past two days anyway,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Bullion fixed at $386.90 an ounce, just $0.10 higher than Wednesday's afternoon fixing.</p>
<p>Gold prices turned higher last month after sinking steadily since hitting a six-year peak of $418 an ounce in February.</p>
<p>But they have stagnated under the key $390-an-ounce level, as a summer lull in leading consumer India and jewellery producer Italy dulled demand.</p>
<p>The market also ignored a decision on Thursday by Germany's Bundesbank to cut a key money market rate.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see it making any difference. If the FOMC (U.S. Federal Open Market Committee meeting) this week didn't impact gold, I don't see why the Bundesbank should,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Silver, whose rally early in the week had given a mild boost to the other precious metals, was also static at $5.20 an ounce.</p>
<p>The white metal's failure to attract follow-through buying since the rally could mean it will drift to the low end of its current $5.15-$5.25 range, dealers said.</p>
<p>Platinum prices were unmoved at $399.00 an ounce, while palladium was $0.25 lower at $125.25 an ounce.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
