<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7626" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Rentokil profits soar, changes company name.</title>
<headline>Rentokil profits soar, changes company name.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Rentokil Plc notched up a 35.6 percent rise in half-year profits on Thursday, easily beating its own ambitious growth target of 20 percent and anounced plans to change its name to Rentokil Initial Plc.</p>
<p>The name change follows the pest-to-security group's victorious 2.1 billion pounds ($3.25 billion) takeover of BET in April which brought a batch of new businesses under Rentokil's control, including BET's Initial cleaning and washroom services brand.</p>
<p>&quot;It is proposed to change the name of the company...to reflect the plans to develop two international brands, Rentokil and Initial,&quot; the firm said in its first-half results statement.</p>
<p>Rentokil made a pre-tax profit of 134.5 million pounds in the six months to June 30, just at the bottom end of analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>Turnover more than doubled to 842 million pounds from 400.9 million and shareholders will receive an increased dividend of 1.48 pence up from 1.23 pence.</p>
<p>The results include two months of trading from BET's businesses which contributed 344.3 million pounds to turnover and 15.1 million pounds to profits.</p>
<p>Rentokil said the integration of BET was progressing swiftly as planned and the board expected continued good growth for the full year.</p>
<p>Rentokil's chief executive Sir Clive Thompson was dubbed &quot;Mr 20 percent&quot; by admiring investors for his track record of continually delivering annual profits and sales growth of 20 percent.</p>
<p>He was under pressure to make good on his boast that this would continue even though Rentokil now had BET's businesses to tackle too.</p>
<p>But his reputation was intact on Thursday as Rentokil said in a statement that even excluding the BET buy, the firm's first-half turnover rose 24.1 percent to 497.7 million pounds and profit increased by 20.4 percent to 119.4 million pounds. ($1=.6460 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
