<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7636" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenyan mills expand to meet rising sugar demand.</title>
<headline>Kenyan mills expand to meet rising sugar demand.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenya's main sugar millers have started major revamping programmes to meet high demand at a time when imports are expected to slow, commodity analysts and sugar executives said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Senior commodity analysts said constant breakdowns and lower recovery rates at the factories made it impossible to meet crushing targets or to attain their full crushing capacities.</p>
<p>But the major constraint remained funding and management problems, they said.</p>
<p>Kenya's six mills, all located in western Kenya, have a production capacity of 530,000 tonnes. The seventh miller, West Kenya, is privately-owned and produces only 500 tonnes a year.</p>
<p>Total Kenyan sugar production is forecast at 420,000 tonnes this year against consumption of 560,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Government figures show that sugar imports reached 244,400 tonnes in 1995 but commodity experts say taxes will cut that to around 80,000 tonnes this year.</p>
<p>Mumias Sugar Company, which accounts for 55 percent of the national output, is replacing its mills with diffusers at a cost of 4.5 billion shillings ($78.95 million) to raise cane crushing capacity to 8,000 tonne per day from the current 7,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;Diffusers are modern and cut costs on repairs. They will be operational at end-December,&quot;  said David Carter, general manager of the Mumias Sugar Company.</p>
<p>Augustine Sakwa, of the farmers' body Mumias Out-Growers Company, said maintenance had cut crushing capacity at the Mumias mill to 4,000 tonnes per day from 7,000 tonnes per day.</p>
<p>Sakwa added that nearly two million tonnes of cane was rotting in the Mumias fields because of transportation problems.</p>
<p>Financing for the diffusers was sought from internal sources and foreign investors, Carter told Reuters.</p>
<p>Sugar officials said South Nyanza Sugar Company was still negotiating for loans to expand its crushing capacity to meet an oversupply of cane in that area.</p>
<p>&quot;To adequately address the supply situation, the factory plans to raise its crushing capacity to 3,000 tonnes of cane per day, up from the installed capacity of 2,500 tonnes per day,&quot; said an official at the state-run Kenya Sugar Authority.</p>
<p>Muhoroni Sugar Company's immediate programme was to install a turbine generator powered by steam from the boilers to generate an adequate supply of electricity.</p>
<p>Crushing there has been undermined by frequent power shortages. The  Kenya Power &amp; Lighting Company, a marketing monopoly, refuses to give guarantees on supply.</p>
<p>Miwani Sugar Company, which continues to perform poorly three years after privatisation, was closed between May and July for a major rehabilitation. It is the only Kenyan factory with the ability to process white mill sugar for industrial use.</p>
<p>Although it has a capacity to produce 40 tonnes of refined white sugar per day, many industry observers believe that the factory is not capable of producing even half of that capacity.</p>
<p>The government still holds a 49 percent stake in Miwani.</p>
<p>The cash-strapped  Nzoia Sugar Company has requested credit from the Kenya Sugar Authority to pay growers who have refused to supply cane owing to outstanding payment problems.</p>
<p>There were no indication of plans at Chemelil Sugar.</p>
<p>-- Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100128">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100136">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
