<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7643" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria cuts stakes slated for mass privatisation.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria cuts stakes slated for mass privatisation.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's cabinet decided on Thursday to reduce the stakes earmarked for sale against mass privatisation vouchers in 60 state enterprises.</p>
<p>&quot;The stakes allocated for mass privatisation in 60 companies were reduced because the privatisation procedures for most of them are expected to be completed in a month,&quot; privatisation agency director Veselin Blagoev told reporters.</p>
<p>The list of firms includes Sheraton Sofia Balkan Hotel of which 10 percent will be offered for mass sell-offs, from previously planned 25 percent, Troiafarm pharmaceuticles producer where the stake is cut to 25 percent from 67 percent and Shumensko Pivo brewerer with 10 percent instead of 70 percent.</p>
<p>Under Bulgaria's mass privatisation programme launched earlier this year, some 1,050 enterprises with capital of around 95 billion levs were slated for mass privatisation.</p>
<p>The first mass privatisation tender is expected to end in October. -- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
