<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7667" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Profit-taking sees Australia stocks end lower.</title>
<headline>Profit-taking sees Australia stocks end lower.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A late bout of profit-taking triggered by fears of weaker session for Wall Street saw the Australian share market close down near its lows on Thursday.</p>
<p>The key share market barometer, the All Ordinaries index finished 11.4 points lower at 2,274.6, just off its intra-day bottom of 2,272.0.</p>
<p>The September share index futures contract closed down 22 points at 2,279, a slim 5.4 point premium to the index.</p>
<p>Brokers said the market was concerned that another tobacco stock meltdown on Wall Street could inflict a more painful sell-off than the one seen on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The S&amp;P 500 futures tipped lower this afternoon and I think this worried some of the funds who did not want to get caught long ahead of a weak night on Wall Street,&quot; a Brisbane-based dealer said.</p>
<p>The dealer said the market was looking for an excuse to take some profits following the pre and post-budget-inspired rally of the past few sessions.</p>
<p>&quot;Banks ran out of steam today and I think this was due to natural market forces following their run higher,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Going against the negative trend was the insurance sector which was still seen benefiting from budget changes.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar was holding firm at US$0.79 and was seen well supported at this level given expectations of U.S. fund buying on the back of Samurai bond transactions.</p>
<p>Analysts said the local bond market also suffered the effects of profit-taking with no news to support the market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
