<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7671" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia's Qantas profit up, tips more lift off.</title>
<headline>Australia's Qantas profit up, tips more lift off.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Morrison</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's flag carrier Qantas Airways Ltd on Thursday reported a 37 percent surge in net profit for 1995/96 and tipped healthier profits ahead as a public company as it focuses on trimming costs.</p>
<p>&quot;The Flying Kangaroo,&quot; in its first year as a publicly-owned company, posted a net profit of A$246 million (US$195 million) in the year to June 30, 1996, exceeding its prospectus forecast of A$237 million.</p>
<p>&quot;I think in financial terms this is a very strong result,&quot; Qantas chairman Gary Pemberton told reporters.</p>
<p>But Qantas, 25 percent owned by British Airways Plc, recorded a loss in overall international market share with revenue falling on British, European and Japanese routes.</p>
<p>But revenue increases in Qantas' domestic market, the fast-growing Southeast Asian/Northeast Asian markets and in the North American and Pacific routes helped group revenue rise 6.1 percent to A$7.60 billion with 17.5 million passengers carried.</p>
<p>&quot;It was quite a remarkable result,&quot; said Paul Xavier, aviation analyst at broker BNP Equities. &quot;But with the outlook, I think there will be revenue pressure coming from both the domestic market and on international routes.&quot;</p>
<p>Pemberton said Qantas would not continue to chase market share at the expense of profitability and would focus on trimming costs.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's not confuse market share with getting smaller, we are continuing to grow, we are continuing to expand, but not as fast as the market,&quot; said Pemberton, adding he expected Southeast Asian routes to expand at around nine to 10 percent.</p>
<p>The number of passengers flying with Qantas has increased about 20 percent over the past two years, Pemberton said. To maintain that growth, the airline would have to spend about A$400 million on new aircraft, which is not planned, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not going to get the traditional airline disease, that when you see some passengers you go and buy some aircraft irrespective of the rate of return,&quot; Pemberton said.</p>
<p>A better return is what Pemberton expects for 1996/97.</p>
<p>Operating profit, which rose 25.3 percent to A$401.4 million in 1995/96, could climb further to A$450 million in 1996/97, Pemberton said.</p>
<p>He also expected revenue to grow by around six percent in the current year, similar to the growth in 1995/96.</p>
<p>But there was no mistaking where Qantas expected the profit growth to come from -- a fall in operating costs.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook for the 1996/97 year presents the same issues encountered in the year just completed,&quot; Qantas said in a statement with its annual results.</p>
<p>&quot;To deliver profit growth in line with market expectations, cost reduction targets for new initiatives in the coming year have been increased from A$230 million to A$330 million.&quot;</p>
<p>Growth in parts of Asia was strong, but at prices which failed to provide strong profit margins, Qantas said.</p>
<p>&quot;Additional cost reduction initiatives are therefore an essential requirement for any further significant expansion of the business,&quot; the airline said.</p>
<p>Although the results were at the upper end of expectations, investors marked down Qantas shares three cents to A$2.14 in a generally weaker Australian sharemarket.</p>
<p>(A$1 = US$0.79)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
