<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7672" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Burmese activist pushes for sanctions.</title>
<headline>Burmese activist pushes for sanctions.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leading Burmese dissident on Thursday criticised Southeast Asian nations over their dealings with Rangoon, pleading with foreign governments to impose sanctions on the military regime to force democratic reforms.</p>
<p>Sein Win, prime minister of Burma's government-in-exile, said neighbouring countries should pressure the Burmese regime to negotiate with democracy movement leader Aung San Suu Kyi.</p>
<p>Win said the constructive engagement policy of the seven-member Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN), which promotes links with Burma's State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC), did nothing to encourage reform.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't agree that this constructive engagement policy will bring a change in this regime,&quot; Win said. &quot;Our experience ... is that it is not becoming better, but is getting worse.&quot;</p>
<p>Australia on Thursday criticised SLORC over the latest round of jailings of pro-democracy activists, including Suu Kyi's private secretary, Win Htein.</p>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Tim Fischer said the jailings were &quot;yet another example of the disregard of SLORC for normal political freedoms&quot;.</p>
<p>Fischer urged SLORC to immediately free all political prisoners. Last week, Win Htein was among several activists jailed for seven years.</p>
<p>Sein Win said only international pressure could prevent the re-arrest of his cousin Suu Kyi, a Nobel Peace Prize winner, as she continues to hold popular pro-democracy rallies amid growing calls for action against her.</p>
<p>Official newspapers in Rangoon on Sunday urged legal action against Suu Kyi, leader of the National League for Democracy.</p>
<p>But Win said SLORC, fearful of international reaction, was unlikely to re-arrest Suu Kyi until after it had been admitted to ASEAN.</p>
<p>ASEAN, which includes Brunei, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam, admitted Burma as an observer last month.</p>
<p>Suu Kyi's party won a 1990 election in a landslide, but the victory was never honoured by the military leadership. Suu Kyi was released from six years' house arrest in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Today the situation in Burma is very tense and I believe that action in Australia and the rest of the international community could help swing the balance away from repression towards dialogue,&quot; Win said.</p>
<p>Win said Burma's ruling generals shored up their power through foreign investment and trade and only sanctions would force them to the bargaining table.</p>
<p>Win sought Australian support for sanctions. But Australia's policy remains opposed to sanctions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
