<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7680" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ share investors fling aside election worries.</title>
<headline>NZ share investors fling aside election worries.</headline>
<byline>James Gray</byline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investors abruptly cast aside election worries on Thursday to sharply re-rate the New Zealand share market in a flurry of activity that took several key stocks substantially higher.</p>
<p>By mid-afternoon the benchmark NZSE-40 Capital Index was up 27 points, 1.27 percent, at 2,203.5, just off its peak of 2,207.47 -- its highest point since October 20, 1995.</p>
<p>Brokers and analysts said the catalyst for the new-found enthusiasm was the successful sale on Tuesday of Forestry Corp, New Zealand's second biggest privatisation.</p>
<p>The main beneficiaries were Forestry Corp's new owners -- Fletcher Forest, up nine cents to NZ$1.95 US$, and Brierley Investments, up two to NZ$1.43.</p>
<p>BIL was also enjoying a re-rating as the partial sell-down of its biggest asset, British hotel chain Thistle, drew near.</p>
<p>Not so easy to explain was the gain in International Paper-controlled Carter Holt Harvey, which firmed five cents to NZ$3.22 despite disappointment the forest products company missed out in the bidding for Forestry Corp.</p>
<p>But brokers said CHH was recovering from an oversold position after a disappointing first quarter result.</p>
<p>There was also the ever-present speculation that IP, which normally takes full control of its units, may launch a bid for the remaining 49 percent of CHH.</p>
<p>Yield-sensitive Telecom, which makes up about a quarter of the NZSE-40, was sharply re-rated, despite weakness in bonds.</p>
<p>However, brokers pointed out the bond market had come a long way. Government 10-year bonds had rallied about 20 points in just a week and by 100 basis points since early June.</p>
<p>&quot;The catalyst for the rally was certainly Fletcher Forest,&quot; Don Turkington at Cavill White Securities said.</p>
<p>&quot;After the (FCL) briefing yesterday a lot of invstors were very excited about the acquisition and that led the charge.&quot;</p>
<p>There was also relief that FCL would not be raising money from the market to fund the acquisition, brokers said.</p>
<p>New Zealand faces its first election under the Mixed Member Proportional electoral system on October 12, which analysts expect will deliver a coalition government of some kind.</p>
<p>Investors have become nervous as the political landscape grows more mercurial by the day, with parties jostling for position in the leadup to the poll.</p>
<p>But some have taken heart from a surge in the opinion polls of the Christian Coalition and ACT New Zealand, both potentially benign partners for the existing conservative National Government which has the most support at 37-39 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The election fears seem to have been put to one side,&quot; Turkington said.</p>
<p>Tim Koller at Hendry Hay McIntosh said the Forestry Corp sale was exactly what the market wanted to see.</p>
<p>&quot;The government put it through before the election to show that they still are on their economic path and are not being pushed around by the other parties, which is a good sign,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;With the market rising up like this it's feeding off itself. There has been very good underlying demand over the last few weeks and it's just come to a climax today,&quot; Koller said.</p>
<p>US$1=NZ$1.447</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
