<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7681" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian court acquits former high-flier Elliott.</title>
<headline>Australian court acquits former high-flier Elliott.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Australian corporate high-flier John Elliott was acquitted on Thursday of defrauding his old business empire of A$66.5 million (US$53 million), emerging as one of the few survivors of the 1980s debt binge.</p>
<p>Victoria Supreme Court Judge Frank Vincent ordered the acquittal after the prosecution withdrew its case, noting an earlier court ruling that much of the evidence was inadmissable.</p>
<p>&quot;In consequence a verdict of not guilty should be entered into the record,&quot; Vincent said in handing down his ruling.</p>
<p>Elliott, the former head of the brewing, finance and pastoral group Elders IXL, now known as Foster's Brewing Group, said after leaving the courtroom that he felt relieved and totally vindicated.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously we are very relieved and happy. I've had this matter running for six years...I have today been totally vindicated,&quot; said a smiling Elliott, surrounded by close friends and suppporters, who hugged him and yelled &quot;Sham&quot;.</p>
<p>In stark contrast to Elliott's acquittal, this week an Australian court jailed another 1980s corporate giant, Alan Bond, for three years for fraud involving the French impressionist painting La Promenade.</p>
<p>Allegations of conspiracy to defraud Elders of A$66.5 million, using sham foreign exchange transactions, were brought against Elliott and three other former Elders colleagues on Christmas Eve 1993.</p>
<p>Judge Vincent on Wednesday said that the National Crime Authority (NCA), which launched the case, had acted unlawfully in its investigation of the case.</p>
<p>&quot;The NCA accepts Justice Vincent's ruling, but does not agree that it acted unlawfully in conducting an investigation into these matters,&quot; the NCA said in a statement on Thursday.</p>
<p>The prosecution said immediately after the acquittals that it would appeal the decision.</p>
<p>&quot;We welcome the announcement by the office of public prosecutions that it will challenge the judge's ruling in the court of appeal,&quot; the NCA said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
