<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7686" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FORECAST - News seen rebounding in 96/7.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FORECAST - News seen rebounding in 96/7.</headline>
<byline>Bernard Hickey</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>News Corp Ltd's profits are expected to rebound to about A$1.6 billion in 1996/97 (June 30) as lower paper costs and the hit movie Independence Day overpower a disappointing 1995/96 result, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The year just gone was disappointing, but the outlook for the current year looks good,&quot; First Pacific analyst Lachlan Drummond said after the results were announced on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a touch below my expectations, but we're now looking at 25 to 30 percent better for 1996/97, which gives you about A$1.6 billion,&quot; said another Sydney analyst.  </p>
<p>Earlier on Thursday News announced a pre-abnormals net profit fall of six percent to A$1.263 billion for the year to June 30, 1996, down from A$1.342 billion in 1994/95. Annual earnings per share also dropped to 40 cents from 46 cents.</p>
<p>Analysts had on average forecast a A$1.343 billion net profit before abnormals.</p>
<p>But News said in its commentary after its results that a budgeted profit rise of at least 20 percent for the full 1996/97 year was very attainable. It said the current year had begun with great promise due to Independence Day, moderating paper prices and solid U.S. television advertising orders.  </p>
<p>Analysts said sharply lower earnings from News' book publishing division and its U.S. magazines and inserts had been the main surprise elements in the results for 1995/96.</p>
<p>Book publishing earnings fell to A$90 million in 1995/96 from A$182 million in 1994/95, while magazines and inserts earnings fell to A$324 million from A$356 million.</p>
<p>News said revenue gains at the magazines and inserts division were offset by higher paper prices and lower sales at TV Guide.  </p>
<p>News said dramatically lower earnings from the British arm of its Harper-Collins publishing division more than offset healthy results from its U.S. operation.</p>
<p>It said the demise of the Net Book Agreement had hurt the British operations and weak performances from the San Francisco unit of Harper Collins had not helped.</p>
<p>Analysts said News' forecast of at least 20 percent profit growth in 1996/97 may understate the bullishness of the outlook.</p>
<p>&quot;If they're saying at least 20 percent then their internal forecasts are probably saying 25 or 30 percent,&quot; said one analyst.  </p>
<p>Nomura analyst Eric Betts also said the 1995/96 result was lower than expected. &quot;But looking forward there's some positive factors,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some analysts again pointed to News' cashflow as a possible area of concern, saying however that News continued to have a reasonably strong balance sheet that was well supported by MCI Communications Corp's option to invest up to A$2 billion in a stake in News.</p>
<p>Cash provided by operating activity in 1995/96 slumped to A$872 million from A$1.123 billion in 1994/95, while investments surged to A$2.998 billion from A$1.182 billion.  </p>
<p>News has invested huge sums in the creation of satellite television networks in America, Asia and Japan over the last year.</p>
<p>&quot;It's pretty much short term pain for long term gain,&quot; said Nomura's Betts.</p>
<p>News shares were down four cents at A$6.43 at 12.30 p.m. (0230 GMT).</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
