<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7715" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Filipino Fund plans NASDAQ listing.</title>
<headline>Filipino Fund plans NASDAQ listing.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Filipino Fund Inc, a closed-end mutual fund, said on Thursday it intends to improve liquidity and enhance its share price through a listing on NASDAQ.</p>
<p>Anton Heras, assistant manager of BPI Investment Management which handles Filipino Fund, said the option of a NASDAQ listing was taken because the fund was trading at a 35 percent discount to its net asset value at the local exchange. The average discount for such an issue in the United States is about 12 percent.</p>
<p>Last week, Filipino Fund's board of directors approved the plan to offer the stock in New York through NASDAQ.</p>
<p>Though no timetable has been set yet for the NASDAQ listing, Heras said BPI Management has started talking to prospective foreign underwriters.</p>
<p>Filipino Fund's board also approved increasing the number of board seats to seven from five. This will enable investors who want to hold a larger portion of Filipino Fund to get board seats, he said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Filipino Fund's net asset value per share was 1.2069 pesos, while its closing price on the Manila Stock Exchange was 80 centavos - Manila newsroom (632) 841-8937</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
