<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7719" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Bauble bubble bursts in Japan.</title>
<headline>Bauble bubble bursts in Japan.</headline>
<byline>Keiko Takagi</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>They bought baubles by the bushel in the &quot;bubble&quot; economy, but nowadays Japanese consumers are getting finicky -- with the result that jewellery makers face hard times.</p>
<p>&quot;Japan's jewellery sales have been bleak, especially since April this year,&quot; Yukuji Sonoda, president of Sumisho Gold Co Ltd, said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the smaller-sized jewellery makers will be forced to merge or more jewellery firms will go bankrupt,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The number of bankruptcies among Japanese jewellery firms edged down but the amount of debt soared in the April-to-July period, according to research firm Teikoku Databank Ltd.</p>
<p>It said 45 firms went bankrupt with overall debts of 14.2 billion yen ($131 million) compared with 46 cases and 5.82 billion yen ($53.8 million) worth of debt in the same period a year earlier.</p>
<p>A major trading house said that overall jewellery sales in Japan, the world's largest consumer of platinum, had fallen by an average of five percent annually since hitting a peak of 2.88 trillion yen ($26.6 billion) in 1992. This was expected to fall to about 1.8 trillion yen ($16.6 billion) by 2000, it said.</p>
<p>Industry sources attributed the weak sales to changing consumer tastes and an economy that has been recovering very slowly since the bursting of the &quot;bubble&quot; economy of inflated asset prices in the early 1990s.</p>
<p>&quot;Japan's jewellery market shifted to a buyer's market from a seller's market after the bursting of the 'bubble' era,&quot; an official of the trading house said.</p>
<p>&quot;As consumers become more selective, only good items and strong retailers will enjoy growth in sales. We think that trend will accelerate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Due to slack sales, jewellery makers have had to offer big price discounts that have cut into their profit margins, industry officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;Not only pricey items, but lower-priced items ranging from 30,000 yen ($277) to 50,000 yen ($462) are not selling well,&quot; an analyst at Teikoku Databank Ltd said.</p>
<p>Industry officials also noted that many jewellery firms have tried to lower their stocks, as excess inventories have depressed fresh demand.</p>
<p>A leading specialty jewellery maker, Miki Corporation, has stopped placing fresh orders over the past few months due to poor sales, industry officials said.</p>
<p>Miki, ranked among Japan's top specialty jewellery firms, had an estimated sales volume of 111.2 billion yen ($1.02 billion) in the year ending March 1995.</p>
<p>Of the jewellery firms, traditional retailers have been struggling the most, pressured by the success of mail-order firms and discounters in penetrating the market, a senior official of a major bullion house said. ($1=108 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
