<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7730" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: U.S. to help Taiwan build more missile bases - TV.</title>
<headline>U.S. to help Taiwan build more missile bases - TV.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan plans to build seven more missile bases on the island with the help of the United States, which recognises Beijing instead of Taipei, Taiwanese television reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the assistance of the United States, the military plans to increase its anti-air missile bases to 20 from 13,&quot; state-funded Chinese Television System said.</p>
<p>&quot;The range of anti-air defence will cover from (northeastern) Ilan to (southern) Pingtong,&quot; it said without giving the source of the information.</p>
<p>China, which has regarded Taiwan as a renegade province since the civil war split them in 1949, strongly objects to Taiwan having military links with foreign countries.</p>
<p>However, Washington announced in 1993 that Taiwan planned a private purchase from U.S. defence giant Raytheon Co of a Patriot-based &quot;Modified Air Defence System&quot; for an estimated $175 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The Patriot missiles will be assembled in Taiwan starting in February 1997 and should enter service in the second half of 1998,&quot; the television said.</p>
<p>&quot;To prepare for communist China's missile threats from time to time, our national troops have increased anti-air defence ability overall,&quot; the television said.</p>
<p>Beijing held several missile tests in waters near Taiwan after President Lee Teng-hui visited the United States in June 1995. It also warned Taiwan not to drop its pledge for reunification.</p>
<p>In addition to 500 domestically made surface-to-air Sky Bow missles in six batteries, Taiwan planned to buy 75 batteries of French Mistral missiles and 74 batteries of U.S. anti-aircraft Avenger missiles, the broadscast said.</p>
<p>Washington said recently it was processing a request for Taiwan to purchasee the Avenger.</p>
<p>Taiwan developed the Sky Bows in the late 1980s after having trouble buying advanced weapons from the West under pressure from China.</p>
<p>China threatens to recover Taiwan by force if it seeks independence. Taiwan says it wants reunification, but only after China becomes democratic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
