<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7736" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Malaysia backs southern Philippine peace deal.</title>
<headline>Malaysia backs southern Philippine peace deal.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian Deputy Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim on Thursday welcomed the Philippines' peace deal with Moslem rebels, saying this could spur foreign investment in the south of the country.</p>
<p>Anwar, on a visit to the Philippines, said he had conveyed to President Fidel Ramos Kuala Lumpur's support for the peace accord aimed at ending a 24-year Moslem rebellion in the Mindanao region.</p>
<p>&quot;We consider this to be a major move...in the settlement of hostility in the Philippines,&quot; Anwar told reporters.</p>
<p>He said this would benefit Southeast Asia as a whole and he expected countries in the area to help in the reconstruction of the Philippine provinces affected by the conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;I would certainly appeal to the Malaysian investors also to come ... and I think we would certainly see a more aggressive flow of investments and tourism into the region,&quot; Anwar added.</p>
<p>Ramos said Anwar told him the Malaysian cabinet at its meeting on Wednesday &quot;lauded the peace efforts of the (Philippine) government and that Malaysia is pooling support (for) our initiatives&quot;.</p>
<p>He said Anwar expected more Malaysian investments would go into Mindanao where Malaysian businessmen are already involved in tourism, energy and steel projects.</p>
<p>An interim peace accord between Manila and the Moro National Liberation Front calls for the setting up of a rebel-led administrative council which will supervise development projects in 14 southern provinces.</p>
<p>Officials say they expect a final peace agreement to be signed in Jakarta by the end of this month with a ceremonial signing to be held in Manila in the first week of September. Indonesia heads an Islamic panel that is mediating the talks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
