<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7746" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan newspapers say Ukraine prize is office swap.</title>
<headline>Taiwan newspapers say Ukraine prize is office swap.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan media on Thursday revealed the prize that Vice-President Lien Chan snared during a mystery Ukraine mission that has incensed China -- an exchange of representative offices.</p>
<p>The Central Daily News, the ruling Nationalist Party's mouthpiece, said on its front page that Lien and Ukraine President Leonid Kuchma reached the agreement in a meeting on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Ukraine, already bearing the brunt of China's scorn over the Lien's visit, has flatly denied that the two leaders met.</p>
<p>The Central Daily News and other papers said the two leaders also agreed to bolster cultural and technology exchanges between Taiwan and Ukraine, which do not have diplomatic ties.</p>
<p>Taiwan and Ukraine were expected to set up economic and cultural representative offices in each other's territory within six months, the independent Liberty Times reported.</p>
<p>None of the reports identified the sources of their information.</p>
<p>Ukraine recognises Beijing, which regards Taiwan as a renegade province since a civil war split them in 1949. Beijing says Taiwan is a Chinese province not entitled to foreign ties and has scorned even allies who it sees as giving political or diplomatic quarter to the island's leaders.</p>
<p>Furious over the welcome Kiev accorded Lien, Beijing angrily scrapped a high-level visit to the former Soviet republic that was to have begun on Wednesday.</p>
<p>On Wednesday China's Foreign Ministry summoned Ukraine's ambassador to express Beijing's displeasure at Ukraine's decision to allow Lien's visit.</p>
<p>The Taiwan government said Lien would hold a news conference on his return to Taipei on Thursday evening.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
