<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7753" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore shares open flat, bargain hunting seen.</title>
<headline>Singapore shares open flat, bargain hunting seen.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Singapore share index opened flat on Thursday as bargain hunting in blue chips emerged after a week of price rallies in second-liners, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sentiment is up but on selective buying in large cap and small retail stocks,&quot; said a dealer with a local brokerage.</p>
<p>Brokers cautioned another round of price gains would be limited after the Monetary Authority of Singapore predicted non-oil domestic exports would grow at a much slower rate of 7.0 to 8.0 percent this year late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The key Straits Times Industrials Index was up 0.39 at 2,155.99 at 0215 GMT.</p>
<p>Market volume was 25.21 million shares. However the market was mixed with decliners leading the advances by 95 to 56.</p>
<p>Keppel Corp was among the day's top gainers, rising Singapore $0.20 (US$0.14) to S$10.80 on a volume of 662,000 shares. It saw an early crossed deal of 517,000 shares done on an average price of S$10.57.</p>
<p>Property firm Guthrie GTS topped volume with 2.81 million shares. The share rose S$0.015 to S$0.715.</p>
<p>Transmarco and City Development were among the losers, shedding S$0.45 and S$0.20 respectively. (US$1.00=Singapore $1.41)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
