<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7762" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Moroccan stock market returns to upper trend.</title>
<headline>Moroccan stock market returns to upper trend.</headline>
<dateline>CASABLANCA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Casablanca stock market on Thursday returned to its upper trend pushed up by a seven-point gain made by Morocco's largest private ONA Group, analysts said.</p>
<p>The bourse all-share index surged by 0.30 percent to close at 398.84 compared with the previous session.</p>
<p>&quot;The market reacted positively to Wednesday's official announcement of the purchase of four mining firms by ONA Group,&quot; a stockbroker at Upline Securities said.</p>
<p>With its 6.9 billion dirhams ($802 million), ONA Group, is the second largest capitalised company and accounts for more than 10 percent of the total bourse capitalisation, he said.</p>
<p>The conglomerate closed at 400 dirhams, up seven dirhams on the previous session.</p>
<p>The Moroccan government agreed to sell four mines, including a silver and copper mine to ONA Group at a minimum price of 648.8 million dirhams, the Minister of Privatisation Abderrahman Saaidi said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>It launched an international tender in March to sell four mines -- silver, copper, fluorite, cobalt -- in one lot. The biggest mine is Societe Metallurgique d'Imiter (SMI), in which the state offered its majority 69 percent holding or 668,380 shares. It valued the stake at a minimum 448.9 million dirhams.</p>
<p>Samir oil refinery, which the government will privatise more than 30 percent of its stock in September, remained unchanged at 246 dirhams.</p>
<p>But a block of 100,000 shares of the refinery exchanged hands on the over the counter, a trader said.</p>
<p>The bourse total turnover was 12.6 million dirhams, down from 20.8 million dirhams on Wednesday. ($1= 8.6 dirhams) -- Rabat newsroom (212-7) 726518</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CASABLANCA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
