<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7773" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: mechanical difficulties.</title>
<headline>mechanical difficulties.</headline>
<byline>Michael Conlon</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>For the 140 or so passengers who watched mechanical difficulties turn a recent 4 p.m. flight from Los Angeles to Chicago into a 5 p.m. flight that finally left well after 7, the question made the rounds in the cabin.</p>
<p>&quot;Why can't they just bring in another plane?&quot;</p>
<p>It's a situation frequent travelers dread. In the case described above passengers were taken off the 4 p.m. flight after a hydraulic leak couldn't be fixed fast enough.</p>
<p>They dashed to a 5 p.m. flight which was delayed by another mechanical problem and were facing the next option -- a late night &quot;red eye&quot; -- if the problem had not been resolved.</p>
<p>The simplest answer to the lack of back-up equipment is that where the airlines are concerned, if an aircraft isn't in the air it's not making money. Almost none are parked around airports just-in-case.</p>
<p>&quot;There are other aircraft but they all have a mission,&quot; says Joe Hopkins of United Airlines. &quot;We do substitute at times, depending on availability, if a flight is cancelled. But on some routes there's only one flight a day. At hubs where there are a lot of flights we do substitute&quot; if a lengthy delay is involved and if a plane is available.</p>
<p>The Los Angeles problem involved United but it could have been any carrier.</p>
<p>With flights crowded and with most passengers travelling on cheaper, restricted tickets, simply getting off the plane and trying to find another airline -- if your flight guide indicates there's an alternative at another gate -- may not always work.</p>
<p>In addition, for current security reasons, anyone who had checked baggage on the flights mentioned above would not have been allowed to change planes since unaccompanied baggage is a no-no.</p>
<p>On another matter, a reader who describes herself as a working mother of three says one of her complaints  &quot;is the irritating and often non-stop noise level of crying children ... have any of the companies ever considered flights for '18 and older only?' I would gladly pay a premium for this.</p>
<p>&quot;Or if this sounds drastic, how about a 'family section' on each flight, separated by noise-absorbing barriers.&quot;</p>
<p>The answer appears to be no, and the best advice might be to plug in the headset and listen to music, or buy one of those noise-blocking earphone sets that cut down on ambient sounds.</p>
<p>United's Hopkins says a children's section wouldn't be practical and might not work anyway since you could probably still hear the noise four or five rows away. And, fortunately, not all children cry.</p>
<p>Business travelers: Question, complaint or pet peeve? Send them to Away on Business, c/o Reuters, Room 1170, 311 S. Wacker Dr., Chicago 60606. Or via Internet E-mail Mike.Conlon(at)Reuters.com using the &quot;at&quot; sign on computer keyboards. We cannot promise personal replies but will try to address letters as space permits.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
