<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7801" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mississippi gives tobacco attorneys list of experts.</title>
<headline>Mississippi gives tobacco attorneys list of experts.</headline>
<dateline>JACKSON, Miss 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former U.S. Surgeon Gen. Jesse Steinfeld heads a list of health and smoking experts who may be called to testify in the state of Mississippi's landmark lawsuit against the U.S. tobacco industry, legal documents show.</p>
<p>A 40-member list of potential state witnesses obtained by Reuters on Wednesday also included market researchers, cancer specialists, public health experts and analysts capable of estimating the cost of treating smoking-related illnesses.</p>
<p>State Attorney General Mike Moore called the list a &quot;who's who&quot; of scientists and doctors from across the country. &quot;They have volunteered to help us on this case,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The list was turned over to tobacco attorneys last week as part of pre-trial discovery proceedings before Jackson County Chancery Judge William Myers in Pascagoula, Mississippi.</p>
<p>Moore said those listed also would likely testify in suits filed against tobacco companies by 12 other states.</p>
<p>Mississippi is seeking $940 million in damages from the tobacco industry as compensation for state Medicaid funds spent treating poor people for smoking-related illnesses since the 1960s.</p>
<p>The lawsuit contends that tobacco executives knew of smoking's health hazards and the addictiveness of nicotine as early as 1954 but concealed their research.</p>
<p>A trial is set for March 1997.</p>
<p>R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co. attorney Daniel Donahue said the witnesses listed have a long history of involvement in tobacco issues but no connnection with any cigarette companies.</p>
<p>A corporate spokeswoman for the RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp. tobacco unit described the witnesses as anti-tobacco activists, saying, &quot;This is not an objective group where tobacco issues are concerned.&quot;</p>
<p>Steinfeld, who was surgeon general in 1970, marked his term of office with a call for a non-smoker's bill of rights.</p>
<p>Also on the list are:</p>
<p>-- Richard Peto, a medical statistics and epidemiology professor at Britain's Oxford University, who has done extensive studies on the link between smoking and death rates worldwide.</p>
<p>-- Dr. Neal Benowitz, a professor of medicine, psychiatry and pharmacy at the University of California at San Francisco and a recognized expert on nicotine addiction. He has proposed Food and Drug Administration rules by which tobacco companies would have to lower nicotine levels in cigarettes over several decades.</p>
<p>-- Dr. Lester Breslow, former dean of the University of California-Los Angeles School of Public Health and past president of the American Public Health Association.</p>
<p>-- Dr. David Burns, a University of San Diego medical professor who has testified in previous lawsuits against the tobacco industry.</p>
<p>-- Dr. Donald Davis, director of the Center for Health Promotion and Disease Prevention at the Henry Ford Health System in Detroit.</p>
<p>-- Dr. Joseph Roland DiFranza of the University of Massachusetts Medical Center, who has published studies linking smoking to miscarriages and linking the much-assailed R.J. Reyonlds cartoon character Joe Camel to smoking among youngsters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JACKSON, Miss"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
