<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7807" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: CZECH TABAK SHARES SEEN UNAFFECTED BY SUITS.</title>
<headline>CZECH TABAK SHARES SEEN UNAFFECTED BY SUITS.</headline>
<byline>Alan Crosby</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Czech cigarette maker Tabak a.s., majority-owned by Philip Morris Inc Cos, should not be affected by a spate of events that have hit hard tobacco issues in other markets, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton is expected to announce on Friday a series of restrictions to try to curb the growing use of tobacco by young people ranging from banning cigarette vending machines to limiting cigarette sponsorship of sporting and entertainment events.</p>
<p>The timing of the White House announcement could hardly be worse for the industry, which is still reeling from a surprise $750,000 damage award earlier this month to a Florida man who smoked for 44 years before he was stricken with lung cancer.</p>
<p>Since the decision, a growing list of states seeking to recover hundreds of millions of dollars for the costs of treating smoking-related illnesses have filed law suits against tobacco companies.</p>
<p>Shares of Philip Morris, which holds 77.4 percent of Tabak, and other firms such as RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp , owner of R.J. Reynolds Tobacco, have fallen steadily since the case, but analysts said they do not expect the same to happen here.</p>
<p>&quot;It is unlikely that there will be a negative reaction by domestic investors (over the court case) with regard to Tabak,&quot; said Leos Jirman of BH Securities in Prague.</p>
<p>Tabak shares traded unchanged on the Prague Stock Exchange on Thursday at 6,700 crowns, where they have hovered for most of the past month.</p>
<p>Analysts said the firm's dominant position on the expanding domestic market should help ensure it maintains its position as one of the Czech Republic's most-profitable companies.</p>
<p>Tabak is estimated to hold a 75 percent market share in the country.</p>
<p>&quot;With its position on the domestic market, export potential technology and extra capacity, we still recommend buying Tabak shares,&quot; Alexander Marcek told Reuters on Thursday.</p>
<p>Tabak posted a net profit of 1.805 billion crowns last year, up 93.7 percent from 1994 while the company's gross profit rose 70.7 percent in 1995 to 3.077 billion crowns.</p>
<p>The firm also set a record with its 1995 gross dividend payment of 656 crowns, the largest ever in the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
