<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7826" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German July car registrations up 14.2 pct yr/yr.</title>
<headline>German July car registrations up 14.2 pct yr/yr.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German first-time registrations of motor vehicles jumped 14.2 percent in July this year from the year-earlier period, the Federal office for motor vehicles said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The office said 356,725 new cars were registered in July 1996 -- 304,850 passenger cars and 15,613 trucks. The figures represent a 13.6 percent increase for passenger cars and a 2.2 percent decline for trucks from July 1995.</p>
<p>Motor-bike registration rose 32.7 percent in the period.</p>
<p>The growth was partly due to an increased number of Germans buying German cars abroad, while manufacturers said that domestic demand was weak, the federal office said.</p>
<p>Almost all German car manufacturers posted gains in registration numbers in the period.</p>
<p>Volkswagen AG won 77,719 registrations, slightly more than a quarter of the total.</p>
<p>Opel AG together with General Motors came in second place with 49,269 registrations, 16.4 percent of the overall figure. Third was Ford with 35,563 registrations, or 11.7 percent.</p>
<p>Only Seat and Porsche had fewer registrations in July 1996 compared to last year's July. Seat posted 3,420 registrations compared with 5522 registrations in July a year earlier. Porsche's registrations fell to 554 from 643.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
