<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7827" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish shares rise, buoyed by German rate cut.</title>
<headline>Swedish shares rise, buoyed by German rate cut.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's bourse closed higher on Thursday after a swatch of half year results, reversing earlier losses after Germany's Bundesbank announced a 30 basis point cut to its key repo rate.</p>
<p>The general index rose 1.09 percent to 1973.18 after turnover of 3.2 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Brokers said telecoms group Ericsson made good gains in reasonable trade, closing 4.5 crowns higher at 152.5 crowns.</p>
<p>The drugs sector index rose 0.92 percent as blue chip Astra rose 4.0 to 281 crowns and Pharmacia &amp; Upjohn climbed 4.5 to 286 crowns in line with gains in the U.S.</p>
<p>Locally a list of half year reports kept turnover steady.</p>
<p>Swedbank reported a healthy 46 percent leap in operating profit to 2.47 billion crowns, reconfirming the recovery in the banking sector. It rose one crown to 85 crowns.</p>
<p>Construction and real estate group Skanska rose 4.5 crowns to 252 crowns after posting a substantially improved first half profit after financial items and forecasting a good profit for the full year.</p>
<p>Steels major SSAB closed one crown lower at 84 crowns after saying it expected to see 1996 profits sharply down with steel prices falling.</p>
<p>Industrial gas company AGA said 1996 profits were likely to be 10 percent lower than in 1995. AGA shares fell three crowns to 106 crowns.</p>
<p>Steels group Avesta Sheffield posted a sharp drop in profits in the first quarter of 1996/97 and its shares closed 0.5 crowns higher at 66 crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;But considering that they still made a profit in such a lousy market climate, I think this disperses some of the uncertainty surrounding profitability,&quot; a broker said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
