<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7835" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Avesta warns of Q2 profit drop.</title>
<headline>Avesta warns of Q2 profit drop.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>British-Swedish steel producer Avesta Sheffield posted on Thursday a sharp drop in profits for the first quarter of the 1996/97 financial year, and warned that a further fall in could be expected in the second quarter. &quot;A further deterioration in profits is expected for the second quarter. There are, however, signs that sales prices will recover during the autumn,&quot; Avesta said in a statement.</p>
<p>Avesta, which is 51 percent owned by British Steel, reported a pre-tax profit of 228 million crowns ($34.5 million) for the first quarter, almost a billion crowns lower than the same period last year when the company posted a 1.23 billion crown profit.</p>
<p>Sales fell to 4.58 billion crowns, a 25 percent fall on the 6.13 billion crowns reported in the first quarter of last year.</p>
<p>Demand for stainless products had been satisfactory during the period, but prices for cold-rolled products had fallen sharply, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite an improvement in demand, the price scenario worsened dramatically in May and June as competitors attempted to increase market share,&quot; Avesta said, adding that prices were almost 45 percent below mid-1995 levels.</p>
<p>Prices of cold-rolled plate had also fallen in Asia during the period, Avesta said, but the American market had been stable despite low-cost imports.</p>
<p>The company said tube and wire product areas had shown similarly weak development to cold-rolled products but the market for precision strip remained relatively stable.</p>
<p>Production volumes at the steel mill in Avesta had increased as commissioning problems wer overcome and production from the British mill had been the highest ever.</p>
<p>&quot;A production record was achieved at the Sheffield steel mill, which, together with slab sales from the Degerfors mill, met the group's billet requirement for flat products during the start-up in Avesta,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>Although there was little in the first quarter report to cheer Avesta shareholders, group CEO Per Molin said the worst was behind the company.</p>
<p>&quot;During the second quarter of the year, sales prices of cold-rolled materials will have touched bottom after the dramatic fall in prices in the first quarter of the financial year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the positive signs now discernible of price increases during the autumn remain, we expect a slight improvement in results compared with the very low level we expect for the current quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>Avesta shares were 0.5 crowns weaker at 65 crowns at 1310 GMT. -- Trevor Datson, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1006 ($ = 6.613 Swedish Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
