<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7847" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Rate cuts help Finnish shares to higher close.</title>
<headline>Rate cuts help Finnish shares to higher close.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A wave of rate cuts in Europe after the German Bundesbank's repo rate cut boosted activity and helped shares to a higher close for the third straight day on Thursday, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said shares could extend gains on Friday since the rate cuts increased hopes for lower interest rates also in Finland.</p>
<p>The HEX index rose 0.34 percent to 2,116.41 in fair volume of 350 million markka, with most action in Nokia, retailer Kesko and food group Raision Tehtaat.</p>
<p>Telecoms group Nokia advanced 1.00 markka to 181.50, partly helped by a weakening markka against the dollar, but ignoring news Nokia had lowered its stake in tyres manufacturer Nokian Renkaat below one third.</p>
<p>Food and chemicals group Raisio continued a rally sparked by its announcement on Wednesday about a new cost-saving dairy cattle feed formula. It closed 6.00 markka up at 321.00.</p>
<p>Retailer Kesko closed 1.30 markka up at 74.90 after hitting a year-high 75.10 markka in lively trade, boosted by some positive analysts' comments, brokers said.</p>
<p>But sporting goods group Amer, gaining strongly in recent weeks, ran out of steam as investors took profits after another sharp rise on Wednesday. Amer lost 2.00 markka to 114.00.</p>
<p>Insurer Pohjola advanced 1.50 markka to 80.50 in fair volume helped by improved first-half profits reported on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
