<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7850" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Raisio to meet home Benecol demand in Dec.</title>
<headline>Raisio to meet home Benecol demand in Dec.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish food and chemicals group Raision Tehtaat Oy said on Thursday it could fulfil domestic demand for its cholesterol-reducing Benecol margarine in December when a new plant sterol processing unit is opened.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect we will be able to fullfil the domestic demand in December,&quot; Raision Tehtaat information manager Jarkko Heino told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>Heino was asked to comment on local media reports that Raisio could increase output of its cholesterol-reducing Benecol margarine five-fold after the new unit to process its key ingredient, plant sterol, comes on stream.</p>
<p>&quot;There is some misunderstanding. It is not true,&quot; Heino said. &quot;But production will certainly increase.&quot; He declined to specify any amount.</p>
<p>Heino also declined to estimate when Raisio's production capacity would allow exports of Benecol.</p>
<p>&quot;It will not happen this year, and nothing can be said about next year,&quot; Heino said.</p>
<p>Not processing capacity, but the lack of plant sterol has been the bottleneck for Benecol production, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect we can solve it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He repeated Raisio's forecast that net sales of Benecol would be some 60 million markka this year, but declined to give any estimate for 1997.</p>
<p>-- Ilkka Virtanen, Helsinki newsroom +358-0-6805 0248</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
