<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7851" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Seita slips on U.S. anti-smoking moves.</title>
<headline>Seita slips on U.S. anti-smoking moves.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Seita slipped on Thursday, suffering like the rest of the tobacco industry from the anti-smoking measures U.S. President Bill Clinton is expected to announce on Friday.</p>
<p>At 1440 GMT, Seita was 2.34 percent lower at 209 francs in a volume of 123,667 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;In France we will never go as far as in the U.S. as far as anti-smoking measures are concerned. But this decision by Clinton reminds investors that we are entering a period which will be favourable for anti-smoking campaign groups,&quot; said a financial analyst.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton is expected to announce on Friday a long awaited series of restrictions to try to curb the growing use of tobacco by young people, White House officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The curbs would range from banning cigarette vending machines to limiting cigarette sponsorship of sporting and entertainment events popular with young people.</p>
<p>Clinton last year endorsed a Food and Drug Administration finding recommendation that nicotine was a drug, paving the way for FDA regulation of tobacco.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
