<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7863" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Generale des Eaux could join SFP bid.</title>
<headline>Generale des Eaux could join SFP bid.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cie Generale des Eaux said in a statement that it did not exclude joining in a privatisation bid for film and television production company SFP.</p>
<p>Generale des Eaux said it would only join an offer if this would help &quot;the continuity and the development of SFP, after a restructuring plan which is indispensable for a fresh start in the best possible conditions.&quot;</p>
<p>Businessman Walter Butler has put a 50 million franc bid on the table for loss-making SFP via his Global Studios vehicle, but that is conditional on a 1.2 billion franc state capital injection.</p>
<p>Generale des Eaux said in its statement that it was not a founding shareholder of Global Studios, as some newspapers had suggested, and had at the moment not taken any decision -- neither positive nor negative -- as far as its participation in any SFP bid was concerned.</p>
<p>Butler's bid has run into resistance by staff of the Societe Francaise de Production (SFP) who fear that 667 out of 1,056 jobs have to go.</p>
<p>Generale des Eaux is an important player in the French media industry through its Generale des Images unit which has stakes in Canal Plus and Havas.</p>
<p>It is also France's second-biggest television cable operator, has production units and owns Germany's Babelsberg studios.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
