<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7895" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: BASF sees 96 profits at least matching 95.</title>
<headline>BASF sees 96 profits at least matching 95.</headline>
<dateline>LUDWIGSHAFEN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German chemicals group BASF AG on Thursday predicted its 1996 profits would at least match 1995 levels after reporting a 14.5 percent rise in group pre-tax profit to 2.32 billion marks in the first six months.</p>
<p>The company said it expected full-year group sales to be up slightly after growth of 0.9 percent to 24.27 billion marks excluding taxes in the first half.</p>
<p>The company, which will hold a news conference on its first-half results in London at 0900 GMT, saw its earnings growth slow during the second quarter, when group pre-tax profit rose five percent to 1.2 billion marks.  </p>
<p>&quot;For 1996, we continue to expect the BASF Group to increase its sales slightly and to record a profit at least at the 1995 level,&quot; BASF said in its interim report. In 1995, BASF made a group pre-tax profit of 4.13 billion marks.</p>
<p>But it added that it would probably not be able to maintain the first-half earnings growth during the second six months because of relatively high earnings during the second half of 1995.</p>
<p>The first-half pre-tax profit was broadly in line with forecasts, which had ranged from 2.27 billion to 2.38 billion marks, although analysts had on average predicted a higher growth rate of 17 percent.</p>
<p>BASF shares were barely changed in early pre-bourse dealings, trading down 0.04 marks or 0.1 percent at 42.20 marks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUDWIGSHAFEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
