<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7927" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREECE - AUG 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREECE - AUG 22.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek financial press:</p>
<p>FINANCIAL KATHEMERINI</p>
<p>-- Reduction of seven percent in Public Power Corporation's (DEH) electricity bills. The first pre-election bonus to one million small-and-medium sized companies from the government</p>
<p>-- Euphoria continues at the Athens bourse</p>
<p>KERDOS</p>
<p>-- The hard drachma is the winner of early elections. Agreement among political parties on foreign exchange policy</p>
<p>-- State telecommunications organisation (OTE): On the eve of a decision about the supply of digital switches from Siemens and Intracom</p>
<p>IMERISIA</p>
<p>-- The economy is at the centre of the pre-election campaign</p>
<p>-- Calmness in the interbank market. The central bank monitors developments</p>
<p>EXPRESS</p>
<p>-- After delays of two years. 101 billion drachmas from Community Support Framework funds for small-and-medium sized firms are being unblocked</p>
<p>-- The euphoria caused by elections continues at the Athens stock exchange</p>
<p>NAFTEMBORIKI</p>
<p>-- Positive first-half corporate results from listed firms</p>
<p>-- Flexibility in foreign exchange policy, capital inflows and continuous fall in interest rates. Rational reaction by the money markets --Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
