<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7931" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: PM SAYS FINNISH ERM DECISION IN NEAR FUTURE - MEDIA.</title>
<headline>PM SAYS FINNISH ERM DECISION IN NEAR FUTURE - MEDIA.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finland would decide in the near future whether to link the markka to the European Union's Exchange Rate Mechanism (ERM), Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen was quoted as saying on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He also said a further strengthening of the markka was not desirable.</p>
<p>The ERM decision would be made &quot;in a fairly near future,&quot; Lipponen said according to Thursday's edition of daily Helsingin Sanomat. &quot;I can not say anything more specific about the timing. The government analyses an ERM link together with the Bank of Finland,&quot; Lipponen said.</p>
<p>Lipponen, speaking at the Social Democratic Party's executive committee meeting in Kuopio in central Finland, did not say whether a decision would be made before or after Finland's October 20 local and European parliament elections.</p>
<p>&quot;The markka has strengthened and I doubt it would be desirable that it would strengthen terribly much more. It is not realistic considering our economy compared to other countries,&quot; Lipponen said according to the Finnish news agency (STT).</p>
<p>The government has said earlier that a decision for or against joining ERM would have to be made this autumn, last repeated by Finance Minister Sauli Niinisto two weeks ago.</p>
<p>Since early May, the markka has strenghened almost five percent against the German mark, over five percent compared the the ECU basket and eight percent against the dollar.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +358-0-6805 0245</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
