<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7970" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: ID card proposals highlight British disunity.</title>
<headline>ID card proposals highlight British disunity.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The British government unveiled a new national identity card on Thursday and ran straight into a major row over whether it should carry Britain's red, white and blue flag.</p>
<p>The voluntary cards, which can also serve as driving licences, were attacked by Welsh, Scottish and Irish nationalists as well as by Britons opposed to closer links with the European Union.</p>
<p>The cards were announced by Home Secretary Michael Howard, Britain's interior minister, and will incorporate the coat of arms of Britain's royal family, the British flag and the European Union flag.</p>
<p>Nationalists in Scotland and Wales immediately demanded that the Cross of St Andrew and the Red Dragon, symbols of their respective countries, should replace the British flag on cards issued in their areas.</p>
<p>In Northern Ireland nationalist politicians who want the province to become part of the Irish Republic also attacked the use of the British flag.</p>
<p>Howard made a concession by allowing Northern Ireland to keep existing driver's licences, which feature no national symbols, until 2001.</p>
<p>Anti-Europeans were annoyed that the twelve stars of the EU flag, a symbol of the power of Brussels, should appear on documents issued by Britain.</p>
<p>Britons, unlike the citizens of many other countries, do not have to carry an identity document. The voluntary new cards are intended to act as a convenient means of identification and the government has denied they will eventually become compulsory.</p>
<p>Howard told a news conference that objectors to the use of the British flag were a very small minority.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not need to explain or justify the use of a national flag on a document of this kind,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Mike Russell, chief executive of the Scottish National Party, which advocates independence for Scotland, disagreed.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there will be a huge reaction against an identity card which imposes the (British) flag on people,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>In Northern Ireland, Eddie McGrady of the moderate nationalist Social Democratic and Labour Party welcomed the driver's licence concession, but added: &quot;An identity card for Northern Ireland should not have a symbol on it at all.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
