<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7973" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Rentokil says 20 pct growth still the aim.</title>
<headline>Rentokil says 20 pct growth still the aim.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rentokil Group Plc said on Thursday that it is sticking with its 20 percent growth target which the pest control-to-security firm has met for the past 14 years.</p>
<p>&quot;The objective remains,&quot; chief executive Sir Clive Thompson told a news conference.</p>
<p>Earlier the firm posted first half results that beat its goal as it saw pre-tax profit rise 35.6 percent to 134.5 million stg. Excluding the contribution from its massive buy of BET, Rentokil said the firm's profit increased by 20.4 percent to 119.4 million stg.  </p>
<p>The firm's shares rose on the figures and by 1141 GMT were up 8-1/2 pence to 417-1/2p.</p>
<p>Thompson said the integration of BET was going well and the firm was trying to bring in its management culture to the acquired group. He said BET had been marked by greater independence for its units, while Rentokil concentrated more on high performance and centralisation.</p>
<p>The firm also earlier announced it plans to change its name to Rentokil Initial Plc in an effort to focus its diverse operations around the two brand names of Initial and Rentokil.  </p>
<p>Corporate affairs director Charles Grimaldi said the process of rebranding all of the firm's operations would be a lengthy and gradual one, but that doing it slowly would incur less costs.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of extra cost it will be very limited...it will not be overnight,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Paul Harris, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8823</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I92300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
