<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7983" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dollar jumps 80 ticks after Buba lops repo by 30bp.</title>
<headline>Dollar jumps 80 ticks after Buba lops repo by 30bp.</headline>
<byline>Phil Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar jumped around 80 ticks in immediate reaction to news that the Bundesbank had decided to chop 30 basis points off the repo rate to 3.00 percent. &quot;The move was surprisingly aggressive and must in part reflect the slowdown in M3,&quot; said Jeremy Hawkins, senior economic adviser at BankAmerica.</p>
<p>&quot;It almost certainly also reflects the rise in the mark following the failure to cut at the last meeting in May.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar jumped to 1.4920 marks from 1.4840 within a few minutes of the news but then started to drift lower.  </p>
<p>The mark also slumped on the crosses with the Bundesbank's move helping to take some of the recent pressure off the French franc and lira. Deakers said it was fair to say the move was totally unexpected and the most bullish forecasts in the market were for a 20 basis point reduction.</p>
<p>&quot;What was new this time was that the dollar was weaker and the French franc was weaker,&quot; said Avinash Persaud, head of currency research at JP Morgan. &quot;The markets, rightly or wrongly, are going to conclude that this was a signal that the Bundesbank was concerned about the weakness of the franc.  </p>
<p>Persaud said the Bundesbank was also expressing concern about dollar/mark and this will help give a floor to the dollar and support for the French franc. &quot;This must undermine the deutschemark over the next few weeks,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The mark moved to 3.4084/89 French francs and 1017.50/8.00 Italian lire after trading at around 3.42 francs and 1022.00 lire just before the repo move.</p>
<p>As the dust settled traders were beginning to question whether still more German rates can be expected.</p>
<p>Or is this the Bundesbank's last-hurrah?  </p>
<p>If the market does decide this represents the last move by the Bundesbank, the mark could firm up again further out.</p>
<p>&quot;If the market decides this is the last in the cycle the Bundesbank has no more carrots to offer to the market,&quot; said David Coleman, chief economist at CIBC Wood Gundy.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the sell-off we have seen in the mark is going to be transitory, it's enough to keep the Bundesbank happy, but there are still big fundamental problems in Europe,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;All the budget, political and monetary union problems are still in place,&quot; Coleman said.  </p>
<p>Dollar/mark's move up helped dollar/yen reach a high of around 108.50-60 from 108.20 before the rate move.</p>
<p>Technically, dollar/mark has some problems with resistance pegged around the 1.4950-60 level and it must shrug this off in order to move higher, with 1.50 marks the target after that.</p>
<p>In later trading the dollar bounced off 1.4960 marks twice and was showing a marked reluctance to go higher.</p>
<p>&quot;People will be very nervous about being long (of dollars) even after this cut,&quot; said one trader. &quot;I don't think people are going to get their wallets out in a big way after this.&quot;  </p>
<p>Any dollar setback would raise grave doubts in investors' minds and if the rally cannot be sustained it could be in trouble, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the dollar can't be supported by this news, what will support it?&quot; Persaud said. --London Forex desk +44-171-542-6284.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
