<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7985" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: German rate cut has limited effect on UK - analysts.</title>
<headline>German rate cut has limited effect on UK - analysts.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A larger than expected cut in Germany's money market repo rate will give Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke some extra room for manoeuvre should he wish to cut base rates again, analysts said.</p>
<p>But the 30 basis point reduction in the repo rate is far from a decisive factor for UK monetary policy, they added, and will have only a limited effect on UK markets.</p>
<p>&quot;It opens the door a little bit, but certainly not wide, for a (UK) rate cut,&quot; said Jeremy Hawkins, senior economic advisor at BankAmerica.  </p>
<p>Short sterling futures leapt after the Bundesbank announced it had fixed its key money market rate 30 basis points lower at 3.00 percent.</p>
<p>The repo had been stuck at 3.30 percent since February.</p>
<p>December short sterling was seven basis points up on the day at 94.27 by 1100 GMT. But at that level, it is still essentially pricing in no change to UK base rates, from their current 5.75 percent, by the year-end.</p>
<p>The March contract leapt eight basis points to 94.05, discounting a likely tightening in the first quarter of next year.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the move has big implications for the UK,&quot; Hawkins said. &quot;We set our rates according to domestic economic conditions.&quot;</p>
<p>Unless sterling rose sharply against the mark, it would be unlikely to impinge on monetary policy, he said. &quot;But it's certainly good news for those looking for a rate cut.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Mike Peacock, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
