<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="7999" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK GDP data confirm twin-track economy.</title>
<headline>UK GDP data confirm twin-track economy.</headline>
<byline>Michael Peacock</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>UK second quarter GDP data have confirmed Britain has a twin-track economy, with consumers spending freely but manufacturers struggling, analysts said.</p>
<p>The figures, which added some detail to preliminary GDP estimates released last month, showed consumer spending at market prices grew by 2.3 percent year-on-year in the second quarter while manufacturing output was flat.</p>
<p>But there was a glimmer of hope for Britain's beleaguered manufacturers as stockbuilding slowed in the second quarter -- a sign that firms are tackling large inventory overhangs.  </p>
<p>&quot;The composition on the whole bodes well for GDP down the road,&quot; said Jeremy Hawkins, senior economic advisor at BankAmerica.  &quot;A necessary unwinding of stocks...should help relieve such pressures on output over coming quarters.&quot;</p>
<p>Stockbuilding fell to just 440 million stg in the second quarter, from about 1.5 billion in the first. But that process may have some way still to run and while it does, the British economy remains one of two very different halves.</p>
<p>&quot;The breakdown of growth highlights the continuing gulf between industry and consumers,&quot; said Jonathan Loynes, UK economist at HSBC Markets.  </p>
<p>But he too said the erosion of stocks was good news for the economy. &quot;Survey evidence suggests that the overhang could depress output for a little while longer, but once it is unwound, the stage is set for a decent acceleration in growth in the second half of this year and into 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>The revised GDP figures, released by the Office for National Statistics, left overall GDP growth unrevised at 0.4 percent up on the quarter and 1.8 percent higher year-on-year.</p>
<p>With consumers spending fast, the service sectors of the economy prospered in the second quarter. Total service industry growth was 2.7 percent year-on-year.  </p>
<p>At the other end of the spectrum, construction output was 0.6 percent below its year ago level while agriculture, blighted by the BSE crisis, was down 9.2 percent year-on-year.</p>
<p>The ONS said if the effects of the mad cow crisis were stripped out of the equation, and cattle had been sold to the market as normal, overall GDP growth would have been about 0.1 percentage point higher.</p>
<p>John Shepperd, chief economist at Yamaichi International, noted another positive for the UK economy, namely a pick-up in investment. Gross domestic fixed capital formation grew 2.1 percent in the second quarter, from just 0.7 in the first.  </p>
<p>&quot;But if anything leaps out, it's the negative contribution from stocks,&quot; Shepperd said. The ONS said the move by companies to shift unsold stocks rather than produce more, took about 0.7 percentage points of GDP growth in the second quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the stock adjustment now appears to have taken place,&quot; Shepperd said. &quot;The strength of domestic demand should soon be reflected in fresh production rather than a stock rundown. There's potential for a fairly sigificant acceleration of growth in the second half of the year.&quot;</p>
<p>The UK Treasury echoed his sentiments, forecasting stronger growth in the second half of 1996.  </p>
<p>And Loynes at HSBC Markets concurred. He said Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke's forecast of 3.25 percent GDP growth next year &quot;is beginning to look easily achievable.&quot;</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
