<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8052" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel plays down tension with Syria.</title>
<headline>Israel plays down tension with Syria.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Heller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's outgoing peace negotiator with Syria said on Thursday current tensions between the two countries appeared to be a storm in a teacup.</p>
<p>Itamar Rabinovich, who as Israel's ambassador to Washington conducted unfruitful negotiations with Syria, told Israel Radio it looked like Damascus wanted to talk rather than fight.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears to me the Syrian priority is still to negotiate. The Syrians are confused, they are definitely tense, but the general assessment here in Washington is that this is essentially a storm in a teacup,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rabinovich is winding up his term as ambassador. He will be replaced by Eliahu Ben-Elissar, a former Israeli envoy to Egypt and right-wing Likud party politician.</p>
<p>Israel on Wednesday sent Syria a message, via Washington, saying it was committed to peace and wanted to open negotiations without preconditions. But it slammed Damascus for creating what it called a dangerous atmosphere.</p>
<p>&quot;The message that we sent to (Syrian President Hafez al-) Assad is that Israel is ready at any time without preconditions to enter peace negotiations,&quot; Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy told Israel Radio in an interview.</p>
<p>Syria accused Israel on Thursday of putting unacceptable preconditions on resuming the negotiations by backing away from a previously agreed basis of exchanging land for peace.</p>
<p>Israeli-Syrian peace talks have been deadlocked since 1991 over the future of the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights despite the previous government's willingness to make Golan concessions. Peace talks between the two sides were last held in February.</p>
<p>Tension has mounted since Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu took office in June vowing to retain the strategic plateau, captured from Syria in the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
<p>Syria accused Israel on Wednesday of launching a hysterical campaign against it after Israeli television reported that Damascus had recently test fired a missile. It said its arms purchases were for defensive purposes.</p>
<p>Israel's Yedioth Ahronoth newspaper reported the tensions arose largely from recent &quot;irregular&quot; movement of several Syrian army units from their usual positioins in Lebanon's Bekaa Valley to Syria itself.</p>
<p>Israel interpreted the move as Syria's response to a public warning by Netanyahu of a strong Israeli military response to attacks by Lebanese Hizbollah guerrillas against Israeli occupation forces in south Lebanon, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>Sudden troop movements sound alarm bells in Israel, which was caught off-guard by surprise Syrian and Egyptian attacks that started the 1973 Middle East war.</p>
<p>A security source said &quot;nothing out of the ordinary&quot; had happened in the north since the Syrian troop movements at the beginning of the week.</p>
<p>Israel's Channel Two television said Damascus had sent a &quot;calming signal&quot; to Israel. It gave no source for the report. Netanyahu and Levy's spokesmen said they could not confirm it.</p>
<p>The television also said that Netanyahu had sent messages to reassure Syria via Cairo, the United States and Moscow.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SYRIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
