<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8055" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: UAE stocks unmoved, but selling pressure seen.</title>
<headline>UAE stocks unmoved, but selling pressure seen.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Arab Emirates shares resisted a wave of selling pressure in the week to Thursday to end without any significant price changes, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said buying interest remained low for the second week running as most investors focused their demand on a 209 million dirham public offering by a new UAE insurance firm.</p>
<p>&quot;Subscription in Al-Khazna Insurance Company which started on Tuesday was the centre of attention,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>He said small investors resorted to selling some recently- acquired shares as the 12-day subscription period was too short for them to arrange alternative funding to buy into the new flotation. But shares managed to hold recent levels.</p>
<p>Dubai Investment Co (DIC) was the exception, with its share price ending half a dirham lower at 12.5 dirhams.</p>
<p>Other share prices were unchanged.</p>
<p>The unofficial National Bank of Abu Dhabi 27-share index ended the week fractionally lower at 2,333.02 points from 2,335.06 the previous week.</p>
<p>-- Dubai Newsroom  9714-626990</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
