<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8057" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turk PM Erbakan gives Islamist spin to diplomacy.</title>
<headline>Turk PM Erbakan gives Islamist spin to diplomacy.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Lyons</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan has used his first overseas trip, to Iran and mainly Moslem Asian states, to give the pursuit of basic Turkish interests a gloss of Islamist solidarity.</p>
<p>The result is a new-look Turkish foreign policy but no real threat -- as feared in Western capitals -- to Ankara's close security and economic ties to its NATO allies. The trip also marked Ankara's first real foray into the Pacific Rim.</p>
<p>Analysts say headlines about a clash with Washington over a $23 billion gas deal with Iran and dreams of an &quot;Islamic Airbus&quot; consortium have distracted attention from the traditional economic and political goals of Erbakan's 10-day tour.</p>
<p>At the same time, they say, the visit to four Moslem states -- plus Singapore -- has given Turkey's first Islamist prime minister a boost with his Welfare Party faithful, unnerved by recent concessions to Western demands.</p>
<p>&quot;The natural gas deal is important for Turkey,&quot; said Dogu Ergil, a leading expert on relations with the Middle East.</p>
<p>&quot;There is nothing ideological about it. Turkey is facing an energy crisis,&quot; Ergil told Reuters, noting that big financial and technical obstacles remained before the project could be realised.</p>
<p>&quot;This deal was in the works for a long time,&quot; said Ilnur Cevik, editor of the Turkish Daily News and a confidant of the prime minister.</p>
<p>&quot;It was not Erbakan but the former (secularist) energy minister who warned of an energy crisis. It has nothing to do with Islam,&quot; said Cevik, who accompanied the prime minister.</p>
<p>Western analysts largely agree.</p>
<p>&quot;There are good, sound economic reasons why the Iran gas deal should be signed, but going there first and making it a theme of the whole trip shows a change of emphasis,&quot; said one NATO diplomat.</p>
<p>Washington, a close ally, rebuked Turkey for the gas supply deal signed one week after enactment of a U.S. law to penalise companies investing in energy projects in Libya or Iran. The White House cites both countries as sponsors of terrorism.</p>
<p>However, U.S. condemnation has been tempered by sympathy for Turkey's growing energy shortfalls.</p>
<p>Turkey consumes nearly nine billion cubic metres (318 billion cubic feet) of gas a year, almost all imported from Russia. The Iranian deal would supply an initial three billion cubic metres (106 billion cubic feet) from 1999.</p>
<p>Energy ministry projections show Turkey will produce about 93 billion kilowatt hours (KWH) of power this year, with consumption set at 97.5 billion KWH. The shortage will be bridged for now by electric power imports from neighbouring Iran and elsewhere.</p>
<p>&quot;What could be more natural than us getting such cheap, abundant natural gas from right next door?&quot; Erbakan told reporters on his return.</p>
<p>Likewise, Erbakan played the Islamist card in a bid to increase trade and improve security in what Turkish officials like to refer to as &quot;a rough neighbourhood&quot;.</p>
<p>Aides say he made the gas deal contingent on Iran's curtailing support for the separatist Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK), which is waging a bloody insurgency against Turkish forces. &quot;He was very blunt, very tough,&quot; said one participant.</p>
<p>Asian tigers Malaysia and Indonesia were given pride of place on the itinerary to underscore their success in blending Western-style development with traditional Islamic values.</p>
<p>Officials say Erbakan signed export trade deals worth up to $4.5 billion, providing a stimulus to the troubled economy.</p>
<p>Among the deals were accords with Pakistan to begin joint projects in defence and production of transport aircraft. Turkey will also export heavy farm equipment.</p>
<p>Turkey and Malaysia agreed to cooperate in aviation and the manufacture of armoured combat vehicles, frigates and submarines, while Turkey and Indonesia agreed aviation deals of their own. Few details have so far emerged.</p>
<p>Whatever the economic benefits, Erbakan won renewed goodwill from his Islamist constituents, some of whom feared he had made too many concessions to the West since taking office in June.</p>
<p>These included dropping his opposition to the U.S.-led air force patrolling northern Iraq from a Turkish base and abandoning efforts to scrap a military training deal with Israel that angered Moslems at home and abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;Welcome Back Great Leader,&quot; said Milli Gazete, the Welfare Party daily. &quot;You have fulfilled the responsibility of fraternity on us all by visiting approximately 500 million Moslems.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
