<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8063" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BAHRAIN: Bahrain's index ends slow week 2.06 points up.</title>
<headline>Bahrain's index ends slow week 2.06 points up.</headline>
<dateline>MANAMA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bahrain's share index ended the week 2.06 points higher in lacklustre trade dominated by bank shares, official figures showed on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Bahrain Stock Exchange said the index rose to 1,333.29 points in the week ending on Thursday from 1,331.23 points a week earlier.</p>
<p>It said trading volume fell sharply to 2.5 million shares worth 360,092 dinars ($955,152) from 4.8 million shares worth 728,327 dinars the previous week.</p>
<p>The bourse said shares of Bahrain Middle East Bank dominated trade, with 1.57 million shares worth 106,023 dinars changing hands. The bank closed half a fil higher at 67.5 fils.</p>
<p>The exchange said 128,059 Investcorp shares worth 66,140 dinars were traded. Its share price was flat at $1.37.</p>
<p>Shares of 16 firms out of the 39 registered at the bourse were traded in 58 transactions, it added.</p>
<p>Bahrain's bourse is open to nationals in Gulf Arab states -- Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Qatar, Oman, Bahrain and the United Arab Emirates. Some firms are also open to foreign investors.</p>
<p>($1=0.377 dinar)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BAHRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BAHRAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
