<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8065" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Opposition to appeal Lebanon election results.</title>
<headline>Opposition to appeal Lebanon election results.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Tarnowski</byline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Christian opposition candidates, citing heavy intimidation and fraud by the pro-Syrian government, announced on Thursday they will appeal to the courts against their defeat in Lebanon's parliamentary election.</p>
<p>Albert Moukheiber, an anti-Syrian nationalist defeated in Sunday's first round, said he would appeal to the Constitutional Council, a new 10-member court which can cancel the results and order a new poll if it finds the vote was seriously flawed.</p>
<p>Defeated candidates have 30 days to appeal. The court's creation last year has for the first time given losing candidates the chance to appeal to an independent body. Appeals in the past were made to the incoming parliament which routinely ignored them.</p>
<p>The Constitutional Council showed its independence last month by striking down part of the election law after opposition deputies appealed against it on grounds of unconstitutionality.</p>
<p>Moukheiber's aides said two colleagues on his seven-member list would appeal with him against the results in the North Metn district where only one on the list was elected.</p>
<p>Other appeals are expected in two more of the six Mount Lebanon districts -- from Ali Ammar, a Shi'ite Moslem of the pro-Iranian Hizbollah (Party of God) in Baabda district and Joseph Abou Sharaf, a Maronite Christian in Keserwan district.</p>
<p>The government crushed opposition hopes by winning 32 of the 35 seats in Mount Lebanon, the Christian heartland, and the press, an independent monitoring group and the opposition have raised an uproar with charges that it used fraud, threats and vote-rigging.</p>
<p>Newspapers have expressed concern that the government, intent on allowing only a few opposition deputies in parliament, will intensify alleged abuses in the next four rounds of voting in different regions on the next four Sundays.</p>
<p>The government and its supporters have so far ignored all charges of electoral abuse. Interior Minister Michel al-Murr, who organised the vote and easily won a North Metn seat, refused to answer questions when announcing the first round results.</p>
<p>Moukheiber accused the government of failing to guarantee a free and fair vote and of exploiting its authority to the maximum in favour of its supporters. But he said the opposition must fight on and denounced calls by hardline Christians for an electoral boycott as cowardice.</p>
<p>He drew cheers from his supporters when he said the government, which is backed by 35,000 Syrian troops, was making Lebanese elections like those in Syria.</p>
<p>&quot;The state coordinates with sister Syria on all levels and the turnout in Damascus elections is 99.99 percent. So this Syrian system has been adopted in Lebanese elections,&quot; Moukheiber said.</p>
<p>&quot;The president (Maronite Christian Elias Hrawi) has to resign. He has taken an oath to preserve the constitution and the independence of Lebanon,&quot; Moukheiber added. Opposition candidates have called repeatedly for Murr's resignation.</p>
<p>Moukheiber said the government &quot;made all the civil and military bodies work for its electoral interests, sometimes through terrorism and sometimes through enticements ... Honourable campaigners were detained illegally on phoney charges the night before the elections.&quot;</p>
<p>Other breaches he listed were failure to give the opposition voter lists, lack of curtained booths and secrecy at polling stations, pressures on newly naturalised citizens and removal of their identity documents to allow forgery.</p>
<p>Opposition candidates have also said many polling stations were moved before or during the voting, and some closed without reason and police were present inside polling stations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
