<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8067" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iranian president Rafsanjani to visit Kenya.</title>
<headline>Iranian president Rafsanjani to visit Kenya.</headline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iranian President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani will visit Kenya soon to boost relations with the African nation, Iranian media reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>Iran's official news agency IRNA said a delegation headed by Deputy Foreign Minister Hossein Sheikholeslam was in Kenya to prepare for Rafsanjani's trip which would also take him to other African countries.</p>
<p>It did not name the other African countries the Iranian president would visit.</p>
<p>The daily Jomhuri Eslami quoted Sheikholeslam as saying in Nairobi that Rafsanjani would visit Kenya soon. He did not give a date.</p>
<p>During the delegation's visit, Iran and Kenya agreed to set up joint trade, banking, telecommunications, transport, industrial, cultural and tourism commissions, IRNA added.</p>
<p>Iran has been actively seeking to strengthen its international ties to counter efforts by the United States to isolate it.</p>
<p>Washington earlier this month tightened its sanctions against Tehran when President Bill Clinton signed an Iran-Libya Sanctions Act which would penalise companies that invest $40 million or more a year in oil and gas projects in those states.</p>
<p>Washington accuses Tehran of sponsoring terrorism and seeking to develop nuclear arms. Iran denies both charges.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
