<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8074" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan's Aqaba discharges 51,058 T sugar for Iraq.</title>
<headline>Jordan's Aqaba discharges 51,058 T sugar for Iraq.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four vessels with 51,058 tonnes of Brazilian sugar for both the Iraqi government and re-sale to private Iraqi traders, were unloading at Jordan's Red Sea port of Aqaba, shippers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Two sugar cargoes are direct state purchases, the St. Vincent-flag Dalia with 9,000 tonnes and the Ukraine-flag Kapitan Kaminskiy with a consignment of 14,058 tonnes.</p>
<p>Traders say the 14,058 tonnes consignment was arranged on deferred payment terms for Iraq by a London-based trader.</p>
<p>The other two consignments, 14,000 tonnes each, are for re-export in small lots via free zones to private Iraqi traders, shippers said.</p>
<p>The first is on the Cypriot-flagged Panadros which arrived on Wednesday and the second on the Cypriot-flagged Nearchos arrived on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Traders say the prices of Brazilian sugar purchased averaged $410 per tonne, c and f.</p>
<p>Grain traders say another two vessels with 28,000 tonnes of Brazilian sugar imported by Jordanian traders are expected to unload at the free zone in September.</p>
<p>Traders say the shipments are the first sugar cargoes bought by both Iraq and Jordanian traders for re-export to Iraqi private traders in recent months.</p>
<p>They say loading problems in Brazil have delayed most of the cargoes, which should have arrived at least a month ago.</p>
<p>Aqaba's free zone sugar stockile was virtually empty, although it can hold at least 30,000 tonnes. Jordanian traders stockpile sugar that Iraqi traders buy in small to medium-sized lots for cash.</p>
<p>Jordanian traders said Iraq has bought small shipments of Dubai sugar re-exports because of the shortage in the Aqaba free zone.</p>
<p>Jordanian agents for international sugar suppliers have sounded out Iraqi state buyers but few deals have been clinched since Baghdad signed a deal last May that allows Iraqi oil exports worth $2 billion over six months.</p>
<p>Traders say Iraq was ready to start ordering food but was delayed because the U.N. accord's implementation mechanism was not complete.</p>
<p>Jordanian traders said Iraq's oil-for-food pact will change the suppy pattern, which depended mainly on private Iraqi purchases. The pact lets the Baghdad government purchase from suppliers the bulk of its food needs.</p>
<p>-- Amman Bureau Suleiman al-Khalidi 9626+623776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100136">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
