<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8076" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>QATAR: Qatar shares keep climbing in the week.</title>
<headline>Qatar shares keep climbing in the week.</headline>
<dateline>DOHA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares at Qatar's unofficial stock market continued their gradual rise in the week to Thursday, boosted by renewed expectations that government will soon announce the setting up of a formal exchange, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;An announcement regarding the setting up of an official market can be expected any time during the next two months,&quot; said a banker.</p>
<p>In July 1995 the Emir Sheikh Hamad bin Khalifa al-Thani decreed the setting up of the Doha Securities Market. The authorities are currently drafting regulations for the exchange.</p>
<p>In the week to Thursday, the 18-share Commercial Bank of Qatar (CBQ) index, which has been rising steadily for the past three months, closed at 115.22 points from 114.66 last week.</p>
<p>Ten shares rose, seven were steady and one fell in trade focused on financial stocks.</p>
<p>Market leader Qatar National Bank rose five riyals to 545 and Qatar Insurance climbed by the same amount to 630.</p>
<p>The CBQ and Qatar General Insurance added two riyals each to a respective 316 and 507. Doha Bank and Al Ahli Bank of Qatar were each one riyal higher at 263 and 202 respectively.</p>
<p>Al Khaleej Insurance moved up a riyal to 281 and Qatar Navigation and Qatar Flour Mills each gained two riyals to 680 and 282. Qatar Cement also advanced a riyal to 280.</p>
<p>The only loser in the week, Qatar Tourism and Leisure Co, was two riyals lower at 43.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DOHA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="QATAR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
