<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8082" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey plans commission to value Turk Telekom.</title>
<headline>Turkey plans commission to value Turk Telekom.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey is to form a commission to assess the value of state telecommunications company Turk Telekom, the centrepiece of the government's sell-off programme, the Privatisation Administration (OIB) said on Thursday.</p>
<p>OIB deputy chairman Ismail Karakaya spoke to the state-run Anatolian news agency about progress in the privatisation process.</p>
<p>Karakaya said he was optimistic the newly-revised law on Turk Telekom's privatisation would not face opposition from the constitutional court, which annulled a previous bill.</p>
<p>As part of the liberalisation of the telecommunications sector, Turkey is continuing &quot;intense efforts&quot; towards awarding more licences for mobile phone services, Karakaya said. Two licences have been awarded so far.</p>
<p>Work on the privatisation of Etibank has entered the final stage, he said. Proposals being considered include the division of the bank into two or three entities, which would require cabinet approval.</p>
<p>The administration has reached an advanced stage in plans to issue a golden share in the privatisation of iron and steel manufacturer Erdemir, which was delayed earlier this year because of insufficient investor demand.</p>
<p>The pace of the privatisations remains linked to the appointment of new officials to Turkey's other sell-off body, the High Board of Privatisation, Karakaya said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
