<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8089" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Mideast Gulf oil outlook - India shapes price fate.</title>
<headline>Mideast Gulf oil outlook - India shapes price fate.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mideast Gulf middle distillate product market has gained some steam with higher Asian demand but significant movement in the next few weeks hinges on strong Indian buying, Gulf-based traders said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has seen an upward trend. Far East buyers are undertaking winter buying in advance because last year prices went through the roof. These safeguarding measures have boosted the market,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>&quot;But the most important factor is India, how much India is going to buy,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Jet kerosene was assessed at $27.22 a barrel fob Gulf on Thursday, up from $26.35 last week.</p>
<p>&quot;Good quality kerosene will stay firm but normal grade is under pressure and we expect it to stay soft for two or three more weeks,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Traders said the market would improve if Iran emerged as an active player. &quot;The Iranians are shrewd buyers and they are watching the market carefully, waiting for the right price,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Traders pinned hopes on demand from the state-owned Indian Oil Corp (IOC).  </p>
<p>IOC cancelled its two tenders for superior kerosene for August and September deliveries. But one trader said &quot;we expect IOC buying to strengthen the market&quot;.</p>
<p>Gas oil was put at $24.10-$24.24 a barrel fob Gulf compared to last week's $23.60 and traders expected the market to strengthen.</p>
<p>&quot;The gas oil market started to become quite tight. There are shortages at the moment,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Gas oil premiums for 0.5 percent sulphur material were assessed at 80-85 cents and potential Indian October demand raised hopes of a stronger market, traders said.  </p>
<p>&quot;IOC is expected to buy a lot in October. Both middle distillates will become firm with the end of the monsoon season and the harvest,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>-- Michael Georgy, Dubai Newsroom +971 4 626990</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DUBAI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
