<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8090" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Arafat cancels Israeli-PLO meeting.</title>
<headline>Arafat cancels Israeli-PLO meeting.</headline>
<dateline>RAMALLAH, West Bank 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat cancelled an Israeli-PLO meeting on civilian affairs on Thursday to protest against Israel's decision to prevent him from flying to the West Bank, an official said.</p>
<p>&quot;President Arafat has ordered the cancellation of a meeting between (Palestinian negotiator) Jamil al-Tarifi and (his Israeli counterpart) Oren Shahor,&quot; Palestinian legislator Hassan Asfour told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Tarifi and Shahor had been scheduled to meet at the Allenby bridge which links the West Bank with Jordan to discuss easing travel arrangements for Palestinians abroad. Tarifi confirmed that the meeting was cancelled.</p>
<p>Palestinian officials told Reuters Arafat had been angered by what they said was an Israeli decision to prevent him from flying by helicopter from the Gaza Strip to the West Bank to meet former Israeli prime minister Shimon Peres.</p>
<p>There was no immediate word from Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's office on Arafat's cancelled West Bank visit.</p>
<p>Asfour also said the Palestinian Legislative Council decided to adjourn its meeting in the West Bank town of Ramallah and move to Gaza where it would resume its session in Arafat's presence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RAMALLAH, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
