<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8097" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Sheikh supports Egyptian apostasy divorce ruling.</title>
<headline>Sheikh supports Egyptian apostasy divorce ruling.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Sheikh of al-Azhar, Egypt's leading authority on Islamic affairs, said in an interview published on Thursday that an Egyptian court was right to divorce a university professor on grounds of apostasy.</p>
<p>The only way back for academic Nasr Abu Zeid was to renounce his writings in public, Sheikh Mohamed Sayyed Tantawi told the London-based Arabic newspaper al-Hayat.</p>
<p>The Court of Cassation upheld earlier this month a ruling annulling Abu Zeid's marriage, against the wishes of Abu Zeid and his wife, because of his writings on interpretations of the Moslem holy book the Koran.</p>
<p>The case has become a cause celebre in the ideological battle between Islamic traditionalists and advocates of human rights and intellectual freedom.</p>
<p>&quot;The judiciary in this case followed the rules of Islamic law,&quot; the sheikh said.</p>
<p>&quot;The verdict is now binding and the case is closed. The judiciary has annulled the marriage and the couple must separate. By this ruling, he has been separated from her and she from him and if one dies, the other cannot inherit,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Asked if Abu Nasr could repent, the sheikh said: &quot;This depends on whether he comes again and declares that he dissociates himself from everything he has written.&quot;</p>
<p>It would not be enough for Abu Zeid merely to repeat the Moslem profession of faith if he also made blasphemous remarks on the Koran, the sheikh added.</p>
<p>Abu Zeid and his wife, fellow academic Ibtihal Younis, have taken refuge in the Netherlands and human rights group say their lives could be in danger if they came home to Egypt.</p>
<p>Younis has said that she and her husband will continue to fight against the court's verdict.</p>
<p>The professor, like other liberal Moslems, has upset the traditionalists by analysing the political factors behind the development of orthodox Islam. He says references in the Koran to some supernatural phenomena should be read as metaphors.</p>
<p>Asked if the ruling would not close the door to new interpretations in Islam, the sheikh said he welcomed innovation where innovation was permissible.</p>
<p>&quot;But if someone came and said that the sun rises in the west rather than the east, we wouldn't call this new interpretation. There can be innovation only in peripheral matters, not in aspects of religion which are necessarily permanent,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
