<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8099" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Palestinian says Iran plotting to overthrow Arafat.</title>
<headline>Palestinian says Iran plotting to overthrow Arafat.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian leader Mahmoud Abbas said in remarks published on Thursday Iran was helping radical Palestinian groups in plans to overthrow the Palestinian Authority by military operations and assassinations.</p>
<p>Iranian officials and Palestinian and Islamist militant groups discussed the plans at recent meetings in Tehran, Abbas told the London-based Arabic newspaper Asharq al-Awsat.</p>
<p>&quot;The Palestinian Authority has recently received information and reports that Iran is planning with extremist Palestinian organisations to carry out military operations and assassination attempts on the Palestinian Authority and its leaders with the aim of deposing it,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The newspaper said Abbas, who is also known as Abu Mazen, declined to say where the information came from.</p>
<p>Abbas, one of the architects of the self-rule agreements between Israel and the Palestinians, said last week that Palestinian President Yasser Arafat had already faced several assassination attempts in recent weeks.</p>
<p>Arafat is the head of the Palestinian Authority, the self-rule body which runs Gaza and the West Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;There were several attempts. Arafat's life is always in danger, from individuals, from organisations against peace, and from countries opposed to the agreement,&quot; he told the israeli daily Yedioth Ahronoth. He did not elaborate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
