<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8102" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: European banks remove liens on Bezeq.</title>
<headline>European banks remove liens on Bezeq.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>European banks have agreed to remove $345 million worth of liens attached to Bezeq Israel Telecom income after negotiations with the company, Bezeq said in a statement.</p>
<p>The liens were a guarantee for loans the company obtained from these banks last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The negotiations were fully successful due to the great confidence the banking community has in Bezeq,&quot; said Isaac Kaul, president of the company.</p>
<p>Until late 1995 Bezeq obtained loans from European banks by attaching, as guarantees for these loans, part of the income expected from international communication services.</p>
<p>Union Bank of Switzerland attached liens on Bezeq income of $300 million from U.S. communication companies for a loan to Bezeq. Other liens were attached by German banks from whom Bezeq received loans, the company said.</p>
<p>Bezeq vice president for finance, Avi Hochman, said that since late last year Bezeq secures loans on international capital markets without the need for liens.</p>
<p>He said that once these improved loans conditions were attained, without the liens, a certain lack of symmetry was created regarding the conditions under which the above loans were obtained and the company initiated negotiations for removing the liens on previous loans.</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
