<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8104" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Jordanian press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>JORDAN TIMES</p>
<p>- King urges dialogue, efforts to protect democracy, meets parliamentarians from south, reviews situation after bread price riots.</p>
<p>- Life largely normal in Karak, residents seek end to curfew.</p>
<p>- Government minister Shneikat won't quit cabinet despite disagreement over way government raised bread prices.</p>
<p>- Authorities start releasing detainees arrested in bread riots after questioning.</p>
<p>- King says Jordan depends on its workers to build itself and achieve self-reliance.</p>
<p>AL RAI</p>
<p>- Deputies and senators of southern governates confirm loyalty of residents to Hashemite leadership.</p>
<p>- 208,000 bounced cheques worth 216.7 million dinars.</p>
<p>AD DUSTOUR</p>
<p>- Amman governor denies granting permission to stage &quot;march of one million hungry&quot; called by Islamic Action Front on Friday.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Kabariti meets trade union council on Thursday.</p>
<p>- Amman prosecutor detains chief editor of Al-Bilad weekly and reporter at magazine.</p>
<p>AL ASWAQ</p>
<p>- Investors expect upward trend in Amman Financial Market to continue.</p>
<p>- Opposition deputies call on government to engage in real dialogue.</p>
<p>- Start of project to set up peace park in Aqaba.</p>
<p>($=0.7080 dinar)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
