<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8106" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Cyprus press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>ALITHIA</p>
<p>- Cyprus Airways says liberalisation of charter flights from Gatwick will be catastrophic for airline.</p>
<p>- Cyprus Chamber of Commerce and Industry votes in favour of liberalisation of interest rates.</p>
<p>CHARAVGHI</p>
<p>- Agriculture minister meeting representative of fishermen's committee on Thursday; urgent need to face up to serious problems of coastal fishing.</p>
<p>- Turkish Ministry of Foreign Affairs requests direct talks with Greece on Cyprus problem.</p>
<p>CYPRUS MAIL</p>
<p>- Amnesty International calling on U.N. to establish effective commission of inquiry on missing persons.</p>
<p>- Greek foreign minister calls on Iran to mediate in Cyprus problem.</p>
<p>PHILELEFTHEROS</p>
<p>- United Nations, Washington and London insist on meeting between Cyprus President Clerides and Turkish Cypriot leader Denktash.</p>
<p>- Central bank will prepare parliamentary bill on changes in supervision of commercial banking affairs to comply with European Union.</p>
<p>SIMERINI</p>
<p>- United States and Turkey show concern over new miliary equipment ordered for Cyprus.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
