<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8113" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Egyptian press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-AHRAM</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Kamal Ganzouri announced that the next cabinet meeting, on the first Wednesday of September, would discuss the new single investment law after it has been studied at all levels. The aim of the law is to bring together all the laws governing investment activity in one law.</p>
<p>- It has been decided to sell 75 percent of the shares in eight new industrial companies working in the milling, textiles, housing and mining sectors, starting from next month, Public Enterprise Minister Atef Obeid said.</p>
<p>- President Hosni Mubarak meets Japanese Foreign Minister Yukihiko Ikeda today and the minister brief him on the plans Egypt and Japan have agreed for a bridge across the Suez Canal, which Japan will finance.</p>
<p>- Presidential adviser Osama el-Baz said the economic conference opening in Cairo on November 12 should convince the Israelis that it is in their interests to meet the Arabs halfway on a basis of justice and equality.. He said he hoped that Israeli policy would gradually change.</p>
<p>- 120 passengers survive EgyptAir accident in Istanbul.</p>
<p>AL-AKHBAR</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Amr Moussa will visit Tunis next week with a letter for Tunisian President Zine al-Abidine Ben Ali.</p>
<p>- Transport Minister Suleiman Metwalli said 37 companies had bought the documents on the BOT airport project for Mersa Alam on the Red Sea coast. The deadline for bids for the project is the end of September.</p>
<p>- It has been decided to carry out an urgent plan to develop the mental hospitals at Abbasiya, Khanka and Helwan.</p>
<p>- An Iraqi trade delegation will visit Egypt in early September to discuss Iraqi requirements for Egyptian medicines.</p>
<p>AL-GOMHURIA</p>
<p>- The ministerial privatisation committee will soon discuss offering eight state companies for sale next month. The shares on offer would have a value of about 900 million pounds ($290 million), Atef Obeid said.</p>
<p>$1 = 3.40 pounds</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
