<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8127" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. uses lawmaker to put out feelers to Nigeria.</title>
<headline>U.S. uses lawmaker to put out feelers to Nigeria.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Worsnip</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Clinton administration has put out feelers to Nigeria in an attempt to engage the country's military rulers in a discussion of human rights and democracy, U.S. officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>They said Rep. Bill Richardson, who has undertaken similar missions to other countries, visited the West African state on Aug. 18-20 as a White House envoy. During his stay, the New Mexico Democrat spent two hours on Monday night with army ruler Gen. Sani Abacha, Richardson's press secretary, Stu Nagurka, said.</p>
<p>Nagurka told Reuters early indications were that progress was slow but said later the congressman had &quot;made headway on human rights issues&quot; and had engaged the Nigerians in &quot;a positive dialogue.&quot;</p>
<p>The decision to send Richardson appeared to reflect U.S. hopes of building on faint signs of progress toward democracy in Africa's most populous state.</p>
<p>Richardson's officially sanctioned trip also contrasted with a heavily criticized private visit by Illinois Democratic Sen. Carol Moseley-Braun, who denied at a news conference on Tuesday that her chief of staff had quit over the affair.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Glyn Davies said the administration had not been advised of her trip to Nigeria or asked to brief or assist her. &quot;We wish we'd had an opportunity to talk to her before she went, but we didn't,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Had she made some time and come and talked to us before she went, we could have explained to her what our policy is toward the Abacha regime and toward Nigeria,&quot; Davies told a news briefing. &quot;It's always better if senior people from the government, regardless of branch, speak with one voice.&quot;</p>
<p>Richardson, by contrast, &quot;was delivering the message that we've delivered to Abacha and his cronies since they came to power ... that they must cease what they're doing on the human rights front, which is a complete lack of respect for human rights,&quot; Davies said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Nigerian government has shown some slight signs of an interest in a dialogue with the United States, and so we thought it was important to have somebody go out,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Another official said Richardson's mission was &quot;to explore the possibilities for starting a meaningful dialogue with Nigeria.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The Nigerians claim to be serious about human rights,&quot; the official, who asked not to be identified, said. &quot;We're trying to see how serious they are.&quot;</p>
<p>The official said Nigeria had released some detainees and was moving toward a transition to democracy. &quot;They've taken some good first steps, but there's a lot still to be done,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Officials said Richardson, whose office said he was visiting Peru on Wednesday, had not yet formally briefed the administration on his Nigeria trip.</p>
<p>Abacha, who seized power after a presidential election was annulled in 1993, has set out a timetable to restore democracy by late 1998. But Nigeria became a pariah after nine activists of the Ogoni people, led by poet Ken Saro-Wiwa, were executed for murder last November, provoking international protests and the country's suspension from the Commonwealth.</p>
<p>The Abacha government has been condemned by black American organizations, including the influential Transafrica lobbying group. The Clinton administration has imposed some sanctions on Nigeria but has held back from a ban on oil imports.</p>
<p>Richardson acted on several previous occasions as an envoy to countries with which Washington has strained or nonexistent relations, including North Korea and Iraq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
