<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8144" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Official says TWA jet sustained center tank blast.</title>
<headline>Official says TWA jet sustained center tank blast.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>TWA Flight 800 sustained an explosion in the centre fuel tank area, but it was unclear if that was the primary explosion that brought the plane down or a secondary blast, the lead investigator said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Robert Francis, vice chairman of the National Transportation Safety Board, said in an interview on CNN that evidence such as the condition of the seats over the centre tank showed an explosion occurred in that area.</p>
<p>&quot;We've decided we can say that, and how it came about ... whether it was primary or secondary or whatever is part of the remaining puzzle that we haven't put together yet,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Paris-bound Boeing 747 exploded and crashed into the Atlantic Ocean off Long Island, New York, on July 17, killing all 230 people on board.</p>
<p>Investigators have said there was no definitive evidence to indicate whether a bomb, missile or mechanical failure caused the fiery crash.</p>
<p>Francis said another body had been found, bringing the total of those recovered to 209. He said he hoped more bodies would be retrieved as the recovery vessel Grasp was still working over an area that contained a lot of wreckage.</p>
<p>&quot;One hates to be too optimistic and one doesn't want to get peoples' hopes up too much, but I think as long as we're dealing with a major area of wreckage which is still under Grasp, that there's hope we'll find some more,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said he was uncertain how long it would take the Grasp to bring up the wreckage.</p>
<p>Francis said in a CNN interview on Wednesday that the noise heard on the cockpit voice recorder was unlike the noise detected when Pan Am 103 blew up over Lockerbie, Scotland, in 1988 or in other aircraft disasters.</p>
<p>Francis said experts in Washington did not expect to learn anything more from the cockpit voice recorder or the flight data recorder.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
