<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8159" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pioneer sees FY96 EPS at high end of range.</title>
<headline>Pioneer sees FY96 EPS at high end of range.</headline>
<dateline>DES MOINES, Iowa 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pioneer Hi-Bred International Inc said Thursday its fiscal 1996 earnings likely will be on the high side of the $2.50-$2.60 a share it projected in May, and could exceed that range.</p>
<p>In fiscal 1995, ended August 31, Pioneer earned $2.16 a share. It earned $2.40 a share in fiscal 1994.</p>
<p>Higher revenues from sales of Pioneer corn hybrids, soybean varieties and other products in North America are major factors in the improved earnings expectations, Charles Johnson, president, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Strong performance in Europe, Latin America and Asia also added significantly to overall results, he added.</p>
<p>Pioneer said preliminary estimates show its share of the North American hybrid seed corn market in 1996 appears to be about 44 percent. In 1995 its market share was about 45 percent.</p>
<p>Pioneer said it expects to have a &quot;better idea&quot; of hybrid seed corn market share next month when more information is available.  </p>
<p>These genetically enhanced new products include insect-resistant Bt corn, soybeans that resist the use of Monsanto Co's Roundup herbicide, and corn that resist the use of  AgrEvo GmbH's Liberty herbicide.</p>
<p>Herbicide-resistant corn and soybeans allow farmers to spray fields with particular herbicides without damaging crops.</p>
<p>Pioneer said in May it expected its share of the hybrid seed corn market to be stable to slightly lower.</p>
<p>Johnson said Pioneer's North American seed field yields are expected to meet expectations, although crop maturity is running behind normal because of cooler than normal weather in the Midwest. Seed field yield could still be affected by an early frost, he said.</p>
<p>-- Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DES MOINES, Iowa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
