<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8165" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton to sign sweeping welfare reform bill.</title>
<headline>Clinton to sign sweeping welfare reform bill.</headline>
<byline>Gene Gibbons</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite his open disdain for some of its elements, President Bill Clinton Thursday signs a welfare reform measure into law that will fundamentally change how poor people are treated in the United States.</p>
<p>Several state governors, members of Congress and some &quot;welfare success stories&quot; -- people who have gotten off public assistance -- are to attend a White House Rose Garden ceremony where Clinton will sign the politically popular legislation.</p>
<p>Known as the Personal Responsibilty and Work Opportunity Act of 1996, the Republican-backed bill ends the 61-year-old federal guarantee of aid to the poor and gives states broad power to design their own welfare programmes.</p>
<p>Clinton, who promised in his 1992 bid for the presidency to &quot;end welfare as we know it,&quot; said in July he would sign the bill despite its &quot;serious flaws&quot; because it offered a chance to wean millions of Americans from a cycle of dependency.</p>
<p>Some of his Democratic supporters sharply criticised his decision, arguing that the bill would hurt children and throw hundreds of thousands into poverty.</p>
<p>Many analysts viewed his decision to sign it as the latest in a series of moves toward the political centre before the Nov. 5 presidential election.</p>
<p>In a new book entitled &quot;Between Hope and History: Meeting America's Challenges for the 21st Century,&quot; Clinton writes that parts of the bill &quot;are just plain wrong.&quot;</p>
<p>Particularly offensive to him are cuts in child nutrition assistance that will hit working families and the cutting off of assistance to legal immigrants.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be refining this reform for some time to come,&quot; Clinton says in the book, a 178-page campaign manifesto that reaches stores this week, just in time for the fall campaign.</p>
<p>Aides have said Clinton is likely to call for tax breaks for businesses that hire people off the welfare rolls in a speech to the Deocratic convention in Chicago next week.</p>
<p>Enactment of welfare reform caps a series of bill-signings this week that could help Clinton win re-election.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Clinton signed a 90-cent raise in the minumum wage, which will increase the pay of 10 million workers. That was followed Wednesday with his signing of a measure that will help millions of Americans with health insurance hold on to it when they become ill or change jobs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
