<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8166" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Miss Universe back in public, quiet on weight issue.</title>
<headline>Miss Universe back in public, quiet on weight issue.</headline>
<byline>Kieran Murray</byline>
<dateline>LAS CRUCES, N.M. 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Miss Universe Alicia Machado returned to the public spotlight on Wednesday night under intense scrutiny over alleged weight problems but kept silent on whether she was ordered to get back in shape or risk losing her crown.</p>
<p>Dressed in a black strapless evening gown, Machado attended the 1996 Miss Teen USA pageant in the southern New Mexico town of Las Cruces.</p>
<p>While clearly heavier than the other beauty queens on stage, the 19-year-old Venezuelan who won Miss Universe in May looked well and appeared relaxed.</p>
<p>Organisers kept Machado well away from reporters and the general public, but she scored rave reviews from most people attending the pageant and its dress rehearsals.</p>
<p>&quot;Well, she is bigger than the other girls out there but she still looks great,&quot; said local resident Ann Gardner. &quot;She's a really fabulous girl.&quot;</p>
<p>Machado came under pressure on Monday when officials of the Miss Venezuela Organisation said she was given an ultimatum by Miss Universe organisers to shed 27 pounds (12 kg) in two weeks or risk having her title taken away.</p>
<p>But Martin Brooks, president of Los Angeles-based Miss Universe Inc, said on Wednesday the claim was &quot;totally untrue&quot; and that he had no idea where it came from.</p>
<p>Brooks spoke with Machado to assure her that organisers were not putting pressure on her and said she was well used to close public scrutiny in Venezuela, which takes its reputation as the world's beauty queen capital very seriously.</p>
<p>&quot;She's fine with it. She wished, as we all did, that it hadn't happened but she's spiritually and mentally terrific. There's no problem whatsoever,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>At 5 feet 7 inches (1.73 meters) tall, Machado weighed 112 pounds (51 kg) in Las Vegas in May when she became the fourth Venezuelan to win the Miss Universe title.</p>
<p>People close to her said she gained some weight after the pageant by indulging a passion for pasta and cake, but it was still not clear on Wednesday how many pounds she has put on. Most people who saw her said she was still far from fat.</p>
<p>&quot;It's her body, her deal. She won the crown and they shouldn't take it away from her just for putting on a few pounds,&quot; said Autumn Smith, the reigning Miss Alabama USA and a contestant for Miss USA next year.</p>
<p>The 1996 Miss Teen USA Pageant was broadcast nationwide and was won by Christie Lee Woods, an 18-year-old Texan.</p>
<p>In an ironic twist, most of the advertisements shown during the pageant were for products helping women to lose weight.</p>
<p>Brooks said he had received calls from a couple of fans angered at what they believed were efforts to force Machado onto a radical diet. Organisers have always denied claims from some quarters that beauty pageants are glorified meat markets by stressing the importance of personality and &quot;inner beauty&quot;.</p>
<p>This week's controversy recalled that of Vanessa Williams, who became the first black winner of the Miss America pageant in 1984 but was stripped of the title after nude photos of her with another woman appeared in Penthouse magazine.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS CRUCES, N.M."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
