<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8167" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Washington Post carried the following front page stories on August 22:</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - President Bill Clinton is scheduled to sign an executive order on Friday putting into effect proposals to regulate tobacco products to curb underage smoking.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - With several key Democratic constituencies furious over his decision to sign the welfare reform bill, Clinton is considering how to soften the measure's impact and soothe party relations at next week's convention.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>MOSCOW - Russian national security chief Alexander Lebed promises Chechen leaders that he will stop Russian military commanders who have threatened an all-out attack on Grozny.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - High school enrollment will rise sharply over the next 10 years as the children of baby boomers reach adolesence and one of the effects could be increased competition to get into college.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - In the air wars of tomorrow, the Pentagon expects U.S. fighters to remain largely invisible to tracking radar and has embarked on an ambitious overhaul of the nation's air combat force.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>JOHANNESBURG - South Africa's last apartheid president Frederik de Klerk aplogised to the nation's truth commission for the &quot;pain and suffering&quot; caused by the system of racial separatism.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>AMERICUS, Georgia - Habitat for Humanity has quietly become a major charity and homebuilder, putting up 3,190 homes in the United States in 1995 and 10,155 worldwide.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
