<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8186" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada court rules for MacMillan Bloedel.</title>
<headline>Canada court rules for MacMillan Bloedel.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Canadian Supreme Court ruled on Thursday in favor of MacMillan Bloedel Ltd in dismissing an appeal from the environmental group Greenpeace, which had tried to stop logging on British Columbia's Clayoquot Sound.</p>
<p>Greenpeace challenged the use of sweeping injunctions banning unnamed persons from blocking roads that loggers were using, but the court ruled that the injunctions were acceptable.</p>
<p>The injunctions have expired, and Clayoquot Sound is now quiet, but experts said the case was relevant for possible future clashes between environmentalists and loggers.  </p>
<p>&quot;I conclude that the British Columbia Supreme Court has jurisdiction to make orders enjoining unknown persons from violating court orders,&quot; Justice Beverley McLachlin wrote in the 9-0 decision.</p>
<p>&quot;Such orders are enforceable on the long-standing principle that persons who are not parties to the action, but who violate an order of the court, may be found guilty of contempt for interfering with justice.&quot;</p>
<p>Between 1991 and 1993, more than 1,000 people were charged with criminal contempt of court and fined or sent to jail for trying to stop MacMillan Bloedel's clear-cutting on Clayoquot.  </p>
<p>Clayoquot Sound is the site of an old-growth rain forest on Vancouver Island, and MacMillan Bloedel had government authority to log there despite concerns by groups such as Greenpeace about environmental damage.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the Canadian public will be surprised to find that they don't have the right to protect the public's forest,&quot; Greenpeace forest campaigner Tamara Stark said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are disappointed the court has decided to protect private interests at the expense of the interests of the public.&quot;</p>
<p>She said Greenpeace would continue to campaign to end the logging of pristine rain forests, although she said there were no immediate plans to blockade roads.</p>
<p>-- Randall Palmer, Reuters Ottawa Bureau (613) 235-6745</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
