<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8194" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bank of Canada cuts bank rate 25 bps to 4.25 pct.</title>
<headline>Bank of Canada cuts bank rate 25 bps to 4.25 pct.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Canada cut its key Bank Rate by 25 basis points to 4.25 percent on Thursday by conducting special purchase and resale operations at 4.25 percent.</p>
<p>The move effectively lowered its target range for the overnight lending rate to 3.75-4.25 percent from 4.0-4.5 percent, money market traders said.</p>
<p>The Bank Rate is the top of the central bank's target range for the overnight rate, at which it lends to financial institutions in its role as lender of last resort.</p>
<p>A basis point is one-hundredth of a percentage point.  </p>
<p>The move by the Bank of Canada follows a decision by Germany's Bundesbank to cut short-term interest rates. The Bundesbank's move triggered rate cuts in other European countries.</p>
<p>The move also followed a report from Statistics Canada that Canadian retail sales rose 0.6 percent in June but that early indications for July retail sales pointed to a drop.</p>
<p>Many analysts had expected the Bank of Canada to lower interest rates in a bid to boost a sluggish economy. The Canadian money market rallied this week and this morning to fully price in the impact of a rate cut.  </p>
<p>It was the seventh easing by the Bank of Canada this year and the sixth done independent of the U.S. Federal Reserve. The Bank has eased 16 times since May 8, 1995 by a total of 400 basis points.</p>
<p>Major chartered banks quickly followed the central bank easing by lowering their prime rates to 5.75 percent from 6.0 percent.</p>
<p>The bank rate is now at its lowest level since March 22, 1994. The bank rate fell as low as 3.87 percent in February, 1994. Prime rates are now at their lowest level since March 27, 1994 when they were 5.5 percent.</p>
<p>-- Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
