<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8218" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dura sees $100 mln sales from Lilly pact.</title>
<headline>Dura sees $100 mln sales from Lilly pact.</headline>
<dateline>SAN DIEGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dura Pharmaceuticals Inc Thursday said the two products covered in its agreement with Eli Lilly and Co could generate annual sales totalling $100 million in the year 2000.</p>
<p>Dura said it agreed to acquire acquire exclusive U.S. marketing rights to Lilly's patented cephalosporin antibiotics Keftab and Ceclor for $100 million plus additional contingent amounts.</p>
<p>The transaction is expected to close next month and is subject to review under U.S. antitrust law, Dura said.  </p>
<p>Dura said the market for oral antibiotics in the U.S. was about $4.8 billion in 1995. Keftab has current annual sales of some $15 million.</p>
<p>Currently there are about four million prescriptions written annually in the United States for the solid form of Ceclor. Ceclor CD, for which Lilly received U.S. marketing approval in June and which Dura expects to launch this autumn, will offer the advantage of twice-a-day dosing.</p>
<p>The addition of Ceclor CD and Keftab complements Dura's existing line of prescription products and is expected to have strong strategic and positive financial impact, Dura said.  </p>
<p>The products are expected to produce incremental earnings and continued strong sales growth, and will enable Dura to grow its field sales force to effectively launch its first Spiros product, expected in late 1998, Dura said.</p>
<p>Dura said it will immediately undertake expansion of its field sales force from about 140 to over 200 by the end of 1996, and expects to continue sales force growth in 1997.</p>
<p>Dura will begin promoting Keftab to physicians immediately after the transaction closes and will launch and vigorously promote Ceclor CD in time for the upcoming respiratory-distress season.</p>
<p>&quot;Earnings from these products should build significantly starting in 1997,&quot; Dura said.</p>
<p>Dura is a San Diego-based developer and marketer of prescription pharmaceutical products for the treatment of allergies, asthma and related respiratory conditions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN DIEGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
