<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8227" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Maritrans sues U.S. govt for taking barges.</title>
<headline>Maritrans sues U.S. govt for taking barges.</headline>
<dateline>PHILADELPHIA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Maritrans Inc said Thursday it has filed suit against the United States government for taking 37 tank barges, citing the Fifth Amendment of the U.S. Constitution which specifically prohibits the taking of private property for public use without just compensation.</p>
<p>Maritrans said it is seeking over $200 million in compensation.</p>
<p>The company said the vessels were taken with the passage of Section 4115 of the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 (OPA 90).  </p>
<p>Section 4115 prohibits all existing single-hull tank barges from operating in U.S. waters unless the vessels are retrofitted with double hulls according to a retirement schedule which began January 1, 1995.</p>
<p>Martrans said that under this retirement schedule, its single-hulled tank barges will be forced from service starting January 1, 2003, with a significant portion of their economic lives remaining or required to be retrofitted.</p>
<p>A company spokesman told Reuters that no vessels have been physically taken. He said that the value of the vessels have been &quot;taken,&quot; in the sense that useful lives have been reduced to 10 years from 50 to 60 years.</p>
<p>In a press release, the company said that the Section 4115 mandate contrasts &quot;greatly&quot; with the useful lives it expected these vessels would have when the company made its investment in the fleet in 1987 and arranged for its financing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHILADELPHIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
