<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8228" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pioneer Hi-Bred up on EPS outlook - analyst.</title>
<headline>Pioneer Hi-Bred up on EPS outlook - analyst.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of Pioneer Hi-Bred International Inc rose 1-1/8 to 55-1/8 on Thursday after the company said fiscal 1996 earnings likely will be on the high side of its earlier range of projections of $2.50-$2.60 a share.</p>
<p>Pioneer added that results for the year could exceed that range.</p>
<p>Piper Jaffray analyst George Dahlman, who has projected fiscal 1996 earnings at $2.55 a share, said the company's latest announcement was &quot;a pleasant surprise.&quot;  </p>
<p>Dahlman said Pioneer's soybeans and operations in Europe and South America have been particularly strong in fiscal 1996, which ends in August.</p>
<p>Pioneer also said Thursday that preliminary indications are that its North American seed corn market share will be about 44 percent, down from about 45 percent a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;We went on record (in January 1996) as saying they would lose market share,&quot; Dahlman said.</p>
<p>Pioneer also said its North American seed field yields are expected to meet expectations, although crop maturity is running behind normal because of cooler than normal weather in the Midwest. Yields also could be affected by an early frost.</p>
<p>Dahlman added the chance of an early frost is a concern for the seed crop. &quot;We can't ignore that one,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
