<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8242" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US spot prods up with NYMEX,Bayway fire discounted.</title>
<headline>US spot prods up with NYMEX,Bayway fire discounted.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot products rose moderately Thursday morning, with traders predicting New York Harbor gasoline would derive minimal benefit from a fire early Wednesday at Tosco's Bayway, New Jersey refinery.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is treating the fire as a non-event,&quot; one New York trader said, predicting New York Harbor gasoline differentials will remain stable Thursday despite earlier concern about operations at the 230,000 barrel per day refinery.</p>
<p>Tosco said late Wednesday that a small fire in the refinery's crude unit had been quickly extinguished and did not affect operations.</p>
<p>News of the fire, however, gave a slight lift to energy futures in overnight ACCESS trade.</p>
<p>The plant, which added a solvent deasphalter unit 10 days ago, experienced a small amount of damage to some measuring instruments, according to Dwight Wiggins, president of Tosco Refining.</p>
<p>In other news, Tropical Storm Dolly was upgraded again overnight from a tropical depression and is gradually picking up steam in the Gulf of Mexico, the National Meteorological Service said Thursday.</p>
<p>-- New York Energy Desk 212 859-1632</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
