<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8248" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Voters oppose Miami stadium plan, poll says.</title>
<headline>Voters oppose Miami stadium plan, poll says.</headline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nearly two-thirds of the voters in Florida's Dade County oppose the use of tax money to build a $165 million basketball arena for the Miami Heat, according to a Miami Herald poll published Thursday.</p>
<p>The poll of 613 registered Dade County voters showed 62.1 percent opposed the arena plan, 24.6 percent supported it and 13.2 percent were undecided. The poll was conducted for the newspaper and NBC television Aug 15-18 and has an error margin of four percent.</p>
<p>The arena plan does not require voter approval, but Miami attorney Dan Paul is leading a petition drive to collect the 36,000 signatures needed to force a public referendum.</p>
<p>The facility would be financed with bonds issued by Miami Sports and Exhibition Authority. The Heat agreed to pay $50 million and another $20 million would come from a sales tax rebate. The remaining debt service would be paid from hotel bed tax revenues.</p>
<p>Knight-Ridder Chairman Tonny Ridder, who helped draft the arena plan, said the poll results were flawed because of the way the question was worded.</p>
<p>Respondents were told the arena plan would use public money from a tax on tourists and asked, &quot;Do you support using public money or oppose using public money?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If people think that money is money that could be going for police protection or schools or some other purpose, then they might think they would rather have the money go to schools or whatever,&quot; Ridder said.</p>
<p>--Jane Sutton, 305-374-5013</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97911">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
