<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8249" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Money managers' US debt allocations steady - survey.</title>
<headline>Money managers' US debt allocations steady - survey.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Money managers made few changes to their U.S. debt portfolios in the week ended August 20, said a survey by Stone &amp; McCarthy Research Associates Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;Money managers simply were not involved in the market to any significant degree,&quot; the report said. &quot;Those who were involved made only modest changes in portfolio structure.&quot;</p>
<p>The report said the survey's bear/bull index arithmetic reading climbed to 4.66 from 4.46 the week before, while the asset-weighted number came in at 4.65, up from the 4.52 of the previous period.  </p>
<p>A number above 5.00 is seen as indicating investors are mostly long on the market.</p>
<p>The cash/assets ratio held mostly steady at 6.21.</p>
<p>Duration bogey upticked slightly to 4.06 on an arithmetic basis from 4.05 the week before. On a weighted basis, duration bogey was unchanged at 4.69.</p>
<p>Duration bogey is the level of asset or liability duration sought in the management of a portfolio.</p>
<p>Duration refers to a portfolio's average maturity and is used by portfolio managers to calculate exposure to risk.  </p>
<p>Twelve percent of portfolio managers polled said they were planning to be active in the coming week, down from 16 percent the week before. The bear/bull index collected among those who intend to be active rose to 5.67 from 4.88.</p>
<p>The Stone &amp; McCarthy survey is conducted by the research firm weekly. It includes 25 market participants with total assets of about $100 billion, the firm said.  </p>
<p>Results of the survey follow:</p>
<p>    Survey Average*			    Aug 22, 1996</p>
<p>    Cash/Assets				    6.21 pct</p>
<p>Duration Bogey</p>
<p>     -- Arithmetic				 4.06</p>
<p>     -- Weighted				   4.69</p>
<p>Actual Duration</p>
<p>     -- Arithmetic				 4.01</p>
<p>     -- Weighted				   4.64</p>
<p>Actual/Target Duration</p>
<p>     -- Arithmetic				98.71 pct</p>
<p>     -- Weighted				  98.84 pct</p>
<p>Bear/Bull index</p>
<p>     -- Arithmetic				 4.66</p>
<p>     -- Asset Weighted			   4.65</p>
<p>Percentage planning to be</p>
<p>     active**				     12.00 pct</p>
<p>	-- Actual/Bogey			  105.33 pct</p>
<p>	-- Bear/Bull index			 5.67</p>
<p>* Table provided by Stone and McCarthy Research Associates.</p>
<p>** Respondents intending to adjust portfolio in coming week.</p>
<p>-- Scott Gerlach, (212) 859-1868</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
