<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8290" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. stocks seen up unless jobless claims surprise.</title>
<headline>U.S. stocks seen up unless jobless claims surprise.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street stocks are expected to rebound slightly from Wednesday's sell-off but the day's outlook rests on this morning's weekly jobless claims report.</p>
<p>Analysts said stocks should get a boost from a surprising 30 basis point cut the Bundesbank's repurchase rate. The cut exceeded market forecasts and buoyed the dollar in Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;The street expects a rise in jobless claims and if that number comes in as expected, I think the German rate cut is going to be an important influence,&quot; said Larry Wachtel, market analyst at Prudential Securities.  </p>
<p>At 0830 EDT/1230 GMT the Labor Department will report new jobless claims for the week ended August 17. Economists polled by Reuters expect 331,000 new claims, up from 321,000 in the prior week.</p>
<p>Only two days after the Federal Reserve opted not to increase interest rates, markets are already eyeing data for confirmation the economy is slowing down from its scorching 4.2 percent growth rate in the second quarter.</p>
<p>Of particular interest will be the August employment report, due September 6. The jobless claims data are considered a key indicator for the monthly employment report.  </p>
<p>&quot;If those claims show a healthy drop, the notion that the economy is slowing will be put on the back burner again,&quot; said Peter Cardillo, director of research at Westfalia Investments.</p>
<p>In Tokyo, stocks closed marginally higher on cautious buying. The Nikkei-225 gained 88 points to 21,363.</p>
<p>In London, U.S. stocks were steady but investors remained nervous after Wednesday's sell-off in the tobacco sector. The FTSE-100 climbed 15 points to 3887.1.</p>
<p>The dollar eased against the yen in late Tokyo but rallied against the mark in Europe after news of the Bundesbank's rate cut.  </p>
<p>U.S. Treasuries were firmer. The benchmark 30-year bond rose 6/32 to yield 6.82 percent. The S&amp;P 500 index future gained 1.1 point to 667.1.</p>
<p>The New York Times Marketplace column reports that corporate bond demand has picked up and junk bond mutual funds are taking in money at record levels this year.</p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal's Heard on the Street column notes recent victories by Coca-Cola Co in its battle for international market share against PepsiCo Inc. Even so, many analysts remain bullish on Pepsi, the column states.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
