<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8306" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Merrill wants higher &quot;supermarket&quot; fees - WSJ.</title>
<headline>Merrill wants higher &quot;supermarket&quot; fees - WSJ.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Merrill Lynch and Co is making little headway in trying to charge fund companies above the going rate for a variety of &quot;no-loan&quot; mutual funds, The Wall Street Journal reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>Merrill, the biggest brokerage house on Wall Street, is expected make its long-awaited entry into the no-load &quot;supermarket&quot; arena perhaps as early as next month, perhaps as soon as after the Labor Day holiday at the start of September.</p>
<p>The idea is to let Merrill customers trade no-load mutual funds from at least 10 unrelated fund companies without going outside the big brokerage house.</p>
<p>However, Merrill has not yet managed to persuade any participating fund families to pay a higher rate to Merrill than they already fork over to be in rival supermarket programs such as Charles Schwab Corp's.</p>
<p>Merrill wants to collect as much as a 0.4 percentage point of all new dollars flowing into fund companies through its new program, industry sources told the newspaper.</p>
<p>That amounts to $4 for every $1,000 invested. But the fund companies so far are balking, and holding out for as little as 0.25 percentage point.</p>
<p>&quot;Merrill Lynch is big enough to think they can demand more,&quot; said an unidentified executive at a no-load fund company.</p>
<p>No-load funds are mutual funds offered by an open-end investment company that imposes no sales charge, or &quot;load,&quot; on its shareholders.</p>
<p>The outcome is important to fund shareholders. If fund companies start paying a premium to be in a supermarket, the costs will eventually filter down to investors.</p>
<p>-- New York newsroom, (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
