<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8315" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: EMERGENCY WEATHER CONDITIONS -  WSC - 22-AUG.</title>
<headline>EMERGENCY WEATHER CONDITIONS -  WSC - 22-AUG.</headline>
<text>
<p>The center of Typhoon Niki has moved westward across southern Hainan, China, and is now in the Gulf of Tonkin. Niki produced very heavy rain and damaging winds on Hainan, and is expected to bring similar conditions to northern Vietnam. Landfall on the upper coast of Vietnam is expected in 12-18 hours. Top winds, now near 95 mph, should be near 105 mph at the time of landfall. Niki will also be a major threat to shipping from Hainan through the Gulf of Tonkin to Vietnam during this period. Once Niki moves inland, it will rapidly weaken but heavy rainfall will likely produce flooding  </p>
<p>Tropical Storm Dolly is centered about 80 miles west of Campeche, over water in the southwestern Gulf of Mexico. Top winds have increased to 40 mph and further strengthening will continue during today as Dolly continues to track west northwestward about 8 to 10 mph. Dolly will be a threat to shipping, then the threat to land will increase as the storm heads for the upper coast of eastern Mexico. Landfall is expected late Friday on the coast north of Tampico, Mexico. Winds should be between 80 and 90 mph at the time of landfall.  </p>
<p>Tropical Depression 19W, in the western Pacific northwest of the Mariana Islands, is drifting to the north and is expected to continue this motion during the next 36 hours. Top winds, now 35 mph, may reach 45 mph as the system becomes a tropical storm during this period. The threat to shipping is moderate.</p>
<p>Tropical Depression 5, 440 miles west southwest of the Cape Verde Islands, will likely intensify to a tropical storm during the next 12-18 hours as it tracks west northwestward. This system remains a threat only to shipping at this time.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
