<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8327" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>Belgium: Thousands at service for Belgian child sex victims.</title>
<headline>Thousands at service for Belgian child sex victims.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>LIEGE, Belgium 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tens of thousands of Belgians attended an emotional memorial service on Thursday for two eight-year-old girls starved to death by a paedophile gang in a case that has shaken the country.</p>
<p>The bodies of Melissa Russo and Julie Lejeune, accompanied by parents, were borne to Saint Martin basilica in the town of Liege in white coffins. The cortege was led by fire engines decked with flowers.</p>
<p>As the coffins passed, onlookers crossed themselves and many wept. There was respectful clapping for the mothers who wore white as a sign of hope and purity.</p>
<p>Postcards were handed to the crowd, saying, &quot;We were eight-year-olds and full of dreams. We thought life would be beautiful... you grown-ups - make us a better world.&quot;</p>
<p>Belgians across the country observed one minute of silence.</p>
<p>Police were led to the bodies of the girls, buried in a garden, by Marc Dutroux, 39, unemployed, and a father of three. Two other girls held by him in a sealed cellar had been rescued earlier.</p>
<p>Ther girls had been buried along with an accomplice of Dutroux who had allowed the girls to die while in his charge. Dutroux killed him in retaliation, police said.</p>
<p>Dutroux, in jail at the time for violent theft, is seen as the mastermind behind a kidnapping and child trafficking gang.</p>
<p>The national grief since the bodies were found last weekend surpassed the mourning after the death of the much-loved King Baudouin three years ago.</p>
<p>One of the mourners, Anne-Marie Lamory of Bastogne in southern Belgium, told Reuters, &quot;I am here for the poor parents of those martyred children. The people who did this must be made to suffer...they too should die suffering...they are monsters.&quot;</p>
<p>After the service, broadcast live on radio and television across the nation, the girls will be buried privately.</p>
<p>Giant bouquets in pastel shades stood at the entrance of Saint Martin's. There were wreaths from the Belgian government and King Albert and Queen Paola.</p>
<p>Shops in Liege closed for three hours and work in its large industrial zone came to a standstill. Flags flew at half-mast.</p>
<p>An estimated 100,000 people attended the mass.</p>
<p>Support for the parents of Lejeune and Russo echoes a widespread campaign mounted to find them after their abduction in June 1995.</p>
<p>The mood was somber, but the anger about the cruel deaths of the girls, starving in a blocked-off cellar, has not abated.</p>
<p>An outraged 14-year-old Liegeoise Marie-Charles Orjet said: &quot;I have not got the words to describe these people.&quot;</p>
<p>Eleven-year-old Sophie said: &quot;I know this could happen to me even though I take care.&quot;</p>
<p>Two other young girls, An Marchal and Eefje Lambrecks, whom Dutroux has admitted kidnapping, are still missing. The search for them has crossed borders.</p>
<p>Their parents and Michel Bourlet, public prosecutor in charge of the case, are hopeful they can be found alive.</p>
<p>An's parents and the mother of Eefje Lambrecks attended the service and were cheered and applauded by the crowd.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope An and Eefje met Julie and Melissa somewhere and told them their parents were looking for them,&quot; Betty Marchal to television.</p>
<p>Sophisticated heat-seeking and radar equipment was being used to ensure no further bodies were hidden at Dutroux's various properties.</p>
<p>The machinery was used in the investigation into the &quot;House of Horrors&quot; murders in Gloucester, western England, in which more than a dozen women and girls were killed.</p>
<p>At least 15 children have vanished in Belgium in the past six years. Seven have now been found dead. Six are missing. Only two have been rescued. Police said more bodies could be found.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIEGE, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
