<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8330" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O. LICHT - Daily coffee report.</title>
<headline>F.O. LICHT - Daily coffee report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>COFFEE: World market for August 21, 1996</p>
<p>Robusta futures in London ended firmer following fund and speculator buying in New York. September added $23 to close at $1,703 while November closed $25 higher at $1,679. In New York concerns about a scarcity of available coffee for delivery against the September contract pushed prices higher. Traders said that producers were strong sellers into the rise but that open interest has been falling, which suggests funds have yet to participate on the long side. Should this occur and producers have already sold heavily, the market might be able to rally further, it was added. September is likely to end firm, thereafter, however, the market may be vulnerable to a setback, as more supplies become available.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>UNITED STATES - According to the CSCE daily warehouse figures some of the coffee that was pending classification is no longer there. 3,750 bags were taken from New Orleans and 1,500 from San Francisco. It could be that this coffee failed and hence supplies should remain tight for now.</p>
<p>COLOMBIA - The Colombian government raised its internal coffee price to 235,500 pesos per 125-kg load in a bid to prevent protests against the low domestic prices. The internal price, set by the National Coffee Growers Committee, had held at 201,500 pesos per 125-kg since February 16. But the Growers Committee set it at 221,500 pesos after a long round of negotiations, with a premium of 14,000 pesos paid because of poor prospects for this year's harvest, set to begin in September. Producers said that the price hike was welcome but barely enough to cover soaring production costs. They demanded that there should be complementary measures to deal with high interest rates, the high cost of equipment and the fight against the berry borer.</p>
<p>TURKEY - Turkey imported 184,200 bags of coffee in calendar year 1995, 38 percent more than was imported the previous year. The main supplier of green coffee in 1995 was Brazil with 143,800 bags vs 92,300 bags the previous year and 175,400 bags in 1993.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Hong Kong imported 88,600 bags of coffee in January/June 1996, 3 percent more than was imported the same period in 1995. Hong Kong gets most of its coffee in the form of solubles from China. In January/June China shipped 27,200 bags of solubles to Hong Kong against 41,600 bags the same period in 1995. Hong Kong exported 31,400 bags of coffee in January/June 1996, 38 percent less than in the same period in 1995. Total exports in calendar year 1995 dropped to 121,000 bags from 227,100 bags in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
