<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8332" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Paris to review expulsions, but no end to fast.</title>
<headline>Paris to review expulsions, but no end to fast.</headline>
<byline>John Follain</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>France promised on Thursday to re-examine expulsion orders for African protesters entrenched in a Paris church but 10 immigrants kept up their hunger strike for a 49th day bent on winning more concessions.</p>
<p>The centre-right government's conciliatory stance after weeks of firmness, including a police raid to briefly take the fasters to hospital, has failed to sway them or the other 300 or so protesters at the Saint-Bernard church.</p>
<p>Signalling their determination to force the government into a humiliating climbdown, the protesters called a new rally for next Wednesday after a march through Paris drew 5,000 demonstrators on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be no residence permits en masse, there will be no automatic right to stay but the government will study things on a case-by-case basis,&quot; Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre told RTL radio.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who have had their demands for (political) asylum rejected will not be granted permits. That is the law,&quot; he added, declining to put a number on how many of the protesters would be allowed to stay. An estimated 117 of them have been refused asylum, according to their spokesmen.</p>
<p>The hunger strikers, most of them Malians, have said they would break their fast only when all 300 have won residence permits. They have been drinking sweet tea and taking vitamin pills, but two are said to be in serious condition.</p>
<p>An official at France's highest administrative court, the Council of State, said it would probably release later on Thursday its review of controversial immigration laws -- only a day after the government requested it in an attempt to solve the crisis.</p>
<p>He said the court would issue recommendations on whether to grant residence permits for all possible individual cases.</p>
<p>&quot;We respect the law but in its enforcement we try to have a humane attitude so that we can stretch out a hand to the worst cases,&quot; Debre said.</p>
<p>&quot;I have sympathy for those who are struggling and for those who are trying to have humanitarian aspects taken into consideration, but I also have sympathy for those who say the law must be respected,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The first opinion poll on the dispute, in the daily Le Parisien, said most voters sympathised with the protesters but most opposed giving them all an automatic right to stay.</p>
<p>The conservative Le Figaro, shooting a rare barb at the government, took it to task for letting the protest rot and refusing to tackle the enforcement of the immigration laws.</p>
<p>&quot;Politics, like war, is about carrying things out. People have to remember that, otherwise they have their backs to the wall,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>But it said the immigration laws pushed through by hardline then-interior minister Charles Pasqua in 1993 needed clarifying.</p>
<p>The protesters say they are all entitled to stay. They say many of them enjoyed residence rights until they were plunged into illegality by the laws which tightened residence and citizenship regulations to drastically curb immigration.</p>
<p>The church, in the heavily immigrant Goutte d'Or district, is surrounded by hundreds of sympathisers, including celebrities like film star Emmanuelle Beart, determined to prevent any police raid.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
