<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8334" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German court jails U.S. neo-Nazi for four years.</title>
<headline>German court jails U.S. neo-Nazi for four years.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Gray</byline>
<dateline>HAMBURG, Germany 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A German court jailed U.S. neo-Nazi leader Gary Lauck for four years on Thursday, finding him guilty of inciting racial hatred by smuggling extreme right-wing propaganda into Germany.</p>
<p>But time spent in custody in Germany and Denmark would be taken into consideration, which is usual in Germany, and it was unlikely he would spend the full term in a German prison.</p>
<p>Prosecutors had demanded a five-year prison term for Lauck, dubbed the &quot;farm-belt Fuehrer&quot; by U.S. Nazi watchers, who say he has been the main source of neo-Nazi propaganda in Germany for two decades. His defence team had requested an acquittal.</p>
<p>Eager to get the 43-year old Hitler fanatic from Lincoln, Nebraska, behind bars, prosecutors had limited their charges to offences over the past few years to avoid a long and complex trial.</p>
<p>Lauck, who is so obsessed with Nazism that he speaks English with a German accent, heads the National Socialist German Workers' Party Foreign Organisation (NSDAP-AO) -- a group which derives its name from the full German title of Hitler's party.</p>
<p>Publishing and distributing neo-Nazi material is illegal in Germany but Lauck's lawyer insisted his client had broken no laws in the United States and prosecutors had not proved he was deliberately smuggling material into Germany.</p>
<p>Lauck's worldwide propaganda empire produces anti-Semitic and rightist publications such as the &quot;NS Kampfruf&quot; magazine (&quot;National Socialist Battle Cry&quot;) and other propaganda including posters, badges and stickers.</p>
<p>The conviction was a major coup for Nazi-busting prosecutors, who had been trying to get Lauck extradited to Germany for trial for years. U.S. authorities had said they could not touch him as he had broken no laws in his homeland.</p>
<p>Germany finally got its chance to nab Lauck, a U.S. citizen, when he visited Denmark in March last year.</p>
<p>Police detained him on an international arrest warrant and the courts decided he could be extradited as, although neo-Nazi propaganda is not illegal there, his material was so extreme it violated Denmark's racial hatred laws.</p>
<p>Lauck was also accused of portraying violence and disseminating insignia and propaganda of anti-constitutional organisations in his publications produced in all major European languages.</p>
<p>Lauck maintained a defiant silence during his three-month trial to underline his belief that the court had no right to try him for actions he carried out in the United States and that his extraditon from Denmark contravened international law.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
