<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8340" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austria Natbank cuts repo, gomex effective Sept 2.</title>
<headline>Austria Natbank cuts repo, gomex effective Sept 2.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Austrian National Bank said on Thursday it was leaving its discount and Lombard rates steady, but was cutting its repurchase rate to a fixed 3.00 percent from 3.20 percent and the Gomex to 3.4 percent from 3.5 effective September 2.</p>
<p>The repo tender from August 26 to September 2 remains unchanged at 3.20 percent.</p>
<p>The discount rate remains at 2.50 percent and the Lombard emergency financing rate at 4.75 percent.  </p>
<p>The securities repurchase rate or repo has been steady at 3.20 percent since April 19, while the Gomex was last changed on February 2. Bids for the 3.20 percent repo have to be in by 1200 GMT on Friday, and bids for the 3.00 percent repo have to be in by 1200 GMT on August 30.</p>
<p>Today's action by the Austrian central bank came hot on the heels of the German Bundesbank, which cut its repo by 30 basis points to three percent.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank held its discount and Lombard rates steady at 2.50 percent and 4.50 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>The German central bank's repo rate had been steady at 3.30 percent since February. -- Vienna newsroom, +431 531 12 274</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
