<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8345" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Iran wraps red tape around nuke test ban.</title>
<headline>Iran wraps red tape around nuke test ban.</headline>
<byline>Stephanie Nebehay</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran delayed the Conference on Disarmament from taking a decision on Thursday to wrap up its work on a nuclear test ban treaty, drawing the wrath of Western envoys.</p>
<p>Iran's envoy Sirous Nasseri set off more than two hours of heated procedural debate on whether to accept a proposal by Pakistan merely to send the negotiating committee's final report to the General Assembly.</p>
<p>The conference had been expected to wrap up its work on a Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty (CTBT) on Thursday by adopting the committee's report. It summarises more than two years of negotiations and states that no consensus was reached.</p>
<p>Although India vetoed formal adoption of the draft pact in the Geneva forum this week, treaty backers nevertheless hope to send the text to the full world body for signature next month.</p>
<p>Poland's envoy Ludwig Dembinski, who currently chairs the 61-member conference, announced consultations were needed and the formal session would resume at five p.m. (1500 GMT).</p>
<p>But Nasseri doubted whether he would be able to get instructions by day-end from Tehran as it was a holiday there.</p>
<p>A campaign by big powers to salvage the treaty won procedural support on Thursday from influential non-aligned states including Pakistan, Mexico, Brazil, Egypt, Peru and Chile.</p>
<p>Pakistan's envoy Munir Akram read out his country's simple proposal: &quot;The Conference on Disarmament decides to transmit immediately the report of its ad hoc commitee on the nuclear test ban treaty to the U.N. General Assembly.&quot;</p>
<p>But Iran's Nasseri repeatedly objected that Pakistan's proposal was not appropriately formatted and did not respect rules of procedure allowing delegations two weeks to decide.</p>
<p>U.S. ambassador Stephen Ledogar took the floor to warn: &quot;If this report is killed today by unprecedented procedural manoeuvring, it will be dead and with it the national statements it contains.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a matter of good faith,&quot; he said in impromptu remarks. &quot;Time is of the essence because we have accepted the deadline which the international community has set.&quot;</p>
<p>Later, in a brief speech, Ledogar said: &quot;I wish to make clear that the United States supports this treaty text as it is.</p>
<p>&quot;We call on those delegations which have not yet done so to join with us in support of this text.&quot;</p>
<p>Nearly identical statements were read out by officials from the other four declared nuclear powers: Grigory Berdennikov, Russia's envoy, and China's ambassador Sha Zukang, France's Joelle Bourgois and Britain's Sir Michael Weston.</p>
<p>China's envoy Sha Zukang left the debate, telling reporters: &quot;It is a waste of time. I am fed up.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier, Sha said in a speech: &quot;China hopes the CTBT will be ready to sign before the end of the year and is convinced efforts will not have been in vain.&quot;</p>
<p>Australia's envoy Richard Starr called for salvaging the text, the fruit of years of work and decades of expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;The text is as reasonable a compromise as is possible to achieve. To hold further negotiations would be to threaten its very existence,&quot; Starr said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a workable treaty and a commitment by the five declared nuclear weapon states to endorse and sign it. We cannot give up. The opportunity is there and we must grasp it.&quot;</p>
<p>Given this &quot;paralysis&quot;, Australia would be looking at ways to work with treaty supporters to bring the shelved text before the General Assembly, according to Starr.</p>
<p>Australia, seen as the country best able to bridge the gap between major powers and the rest of the world, might be asked to take a draft nuclear test ban to the U.N. General Assembly, according to diplomats.</p>
<p>Iran's envoy Sirous Nasseri raised questions about procedure being invoked to push through Pakistan's proposal, which he complained was not in appropriate format.</p>
<p>&quot;While we are not able to agree the text it should not rule out at least having an understanding of what further action is expected at the level of the General Assembly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Argentina's delegate said at one point: &quot;we are getting the impression we cannot indefinitely turn around in circles without taking a decision on the subject.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
