<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8350" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Vienna stocks end steady, but AMS loses over 5 pct.</title>
<headline>Vienna stocks end steady, but AMS loses over 5 pct.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Vienna ATX index of 21 blue chips ended flat on Thursday after being caught in a tug-of-war between selling in AMS and OMV and demand for Creditanstalt and Flughafen Wien stock.</p>
<p>The ATX ended down just 0.02 percent, or 0.19 points, at 1,025.82 after earlier slipping down to 1,019.98. Of its constituents, 10 gained, nine fell and two were unchanged.</p>
<p>Traders said they did not expect today's cut in the repo and gomex rates by the Austrian National Bank to have much impact on the stock market and expect the ATX to tread water.</p>
<p>Chip producer AMS was again the leading decliner, shedding another 5.4 percent to record a new low for the year at 648 schillings. Since releasing disappointing first half earnings on Tuesday, AMS has shed a total 18 percent.</p>
<p>Oil and chemicals group OMV also remained under selling pressure since releasing first half figures on Tuesday, which came in below some analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>Austria's largest industrial concern lost 15.5 schillings to 998.5. One trader said the selling was predominantly from abroad, adding the current level offered &quot;a good buying opportunity&quot; although a fall to 970/80 could not be ruled out.</p>
<p>&quot;Austrian banks obviously have a different perspective of this stock than the English,&quot; said another trader in reference to the selling coming out of Britain.</p>
<p>The day's best performer was Creditanstalt's preferred shares, up 4.49 percent at 500 schillings.</p>
<p>Traders said Vienna airport company Flughafen Wien saw spirited demand, also from the customer side. Flughafen added on 3.3 percent to 668 schillings.</p>
<p>The broad-based Vienna bourse index lost 0.05 percent to 399.97.</p>
<p>The September ATX future gained 2.7 points to 1,028.7 on turnover of 555 contracts. -- Vienna newsroom, +431 531 12 274</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
