<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8352" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Finland Bank seen quite likely to follow Buba cut.</title>
<headline>Finland Bank seen quite likely to follow Buba cut.</headline>
<byline>Sara Henley</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Finland is quite likely to follow Thursday's 30 basis point German repo rate cut by trimming its key tender rate by up to 25 basis points, possibly as soon as Friday, economists said on Thursday.</p>
<p>A straw poll of six houses by Reuters turned up five which expected a further easing from the Bank of Finland.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank move gave &quot;everybody plenty of room&quot;, said OKOBANK Treasury economist Teijo Rantatupa. &quot;There is no reason for us to not go along. If we want to be a European country we should jump on to the bandwagon.&quot;</p>
<p>Countries including France, Belgium and Austria followed the Bundesbank's move on Thursday. But Rantatupa said a Finnish cut only looked very likely if the markka continued to strengthen.</p>
<p>&quot;If the markka strengthens, say below 3.00 per mark, if 2.97 comes within sight, then a cut will become very likely,&quot; he said, adding it could be between 25 and 50 basis points with 25 basis points far more likely.</p>
<p>&quot;If the markka remains in a 3.03-3.05 range I think a cut is more unlikely,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The tender rate, currently at 3.50 percent, was last lowered by 10 basis points on July 5.</p>
<p>Petteri Hirvonen at Stockbrokers Davy Protos said there was about 70 percent probability of a Finnish cut, and he had changed his mind after the Bundesbank's larger-than-expected easing.</p>
<p>&quot;I have to admit that the size of this Buba cut changed the situation a little bit,&quot; he said. &quot;If they cut, I would think 25 (basis points) -- it would be logical to follow the same magnitude as other central banks.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said a cut seemed more likely next week than on Friday.</p>
<p>At Aktia Bank, dealers said a cut was highly likely &quot;within a few days rather than a week&quot;, but they opted for a more cautious 10-15 basis points.</p>
<p>And a debt analyst at another house, requesting anonymity, said a cut could be up to 30 basis points, soon, and Friday was not ruled out.</p>
<p>Merita Bank economist Reijo Heiskanen, while expecting a further cut from the Bank of Finland, said he believed the Finnish central bank would not be led by Buba although Buba's move might increase the scope of an easing.</p>
<p>&quot;This (Buba cut) will hardly push them into making a move. They want to make their decision based on their own reasons,&quot; he said. &quot;I think they want to keep a certain distance and retain their autonomy.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We said already before the Bundesbank cut that we believed there was room for a cut in Finnish interest rates. Now that the Bundesbank has cut it increases the possibility, there certainly is room,&quot; he said, adding he saw no reason for Finland to retain a 50 basis point differential over Germany.</p>
<p>Heiskanen said the chances were that the size of a Finnish tender rate cut would be bigger than the most recent 10-15 basis point easings.</p>
<p>On the other side of the fence was Pertti Thornberg, market advisor at Enskilda, who put the probability of a cut at just 30 percent: &quot;I don't think (a cut) is very probable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a good level for Finnish interest rates,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +35 80 6805 0247</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
