<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8353" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Algeria drafts law to ban Islamic parties.</title>
<headline>Algeria drafts law to ban Islamic parties.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Algerian political parties have drafted a new law that would ban Islamist parties in an effort to stabilise Algeria, where more than 50,000 people have died in four years of fighting set off when the government cancelled general elections the Islamists were poised to win.</p>
<p>Political sources told Reuters on Thursday that a joint committee set up this month between political parties and government representatives sent the draft law to President Liamine Zeroual after a week of talks.</p>
<p>&quot;The law will de facto ban Islamist parties,&quot; said one party representatiuve involved in the talks.</p>
<p>But current legal parties would have a year in which to change their focus or founding principles in order not to run foul of the law, sources said.</p>
<p>In 1992 Algerian authorities cancelled a general election that the radical Islamic Salvation Front (FIS) was poised to win and the party was banned.</p>
<p>The move set off a Moslem guerrilla war in the north African country.</p>
<p>Although FIS was banned, Algeria has two legal Islamist parties, La Nahda and Hamas.</p>
<p>The draft law also tightened rules for party founders and party sources said this could close down 18 small political parties.</p>
<p>Political sources say the new legislation hopes to stabilise the country's political field by cutting back on minor parties.</p>
<p>Zeroual, who is trying to get agreement on political reform through a series of meetings he is holding with political leaders, plans a referundum on an amended constitution this year followed by general elections early in 1997.</p>
<p>A joint committee on changing the consitution this week reached agreement that Islam is the state religion of Algeria.</p>
<p>A national conference, probably in early September, will be the last stage to seal a consensus on Zeroual's reforms before voting the referendum and an elected parliament.</p>
<p>The Main secular opposition party, Socialist Forces Front, walked out this month of Zeroual's talks, from which radical Islamists were excluded.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
