<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8354" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish retail rate rise still possible - analysts.</title>
<headline>Irish retail rate rise still possible - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Jane O'Sullivan</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A rise in Irish retail interest rates remains on the cards despite the Bundesbank's decision to cut the repo rate by 30 basis points to 3.0 percent, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>They said the larger-than-expected cut should help the short end of the Irish bond market and allow Irish interbank rates to ease slightly.</p>
<p>But money market rates may not fall far enough to avert the threat of a rise in Irish retail interest rates unless the Irish pound performs very strongly against the mark, they said.  </p>
<p>The key one-month interbank rate has been trading close to 5.75 percent in recent weeks.</p>
<p>This is well above the 5.5 percent trigger level for retail rate rises but Irish lending institutions held off announcing any increases in their commercial lending rates until the outcome of today's Bundesbank meeting was clear.</p>
<p>The one-month interbank rate was little changed following the Bundesbank announcement, settling at 5.56/5.69 against 5.63/5.69 before the cut.</p>
<p>The punt gained close to a pfennig and a half to 2.4030 marks by 1403 GMT before slipping back to 2.4005 by 1412 GMT.  </p>
<p>Many analysts believe the central bank has allowed interest rates to edge up in recent weeks, not just because of concern about strong Irish credit growth, but to bolster the Irish pound and keep it closely pegged to the mark.</p>
<p>Unless the punt makes significant gains against the German unit, they believe the bank would be reluctant to see money market rates fall too back far.  </p>
<p>&quot;I would expect tension on interbank rates to ease back a little bit but as regards averting a retail rate hike, we would need quite a substantial fall in the deutschmark,&quot; said Padhraic Garvey, economist at Riada Stockbrokers.</p>
<p>&quot;The one-month rate should fall at the margin but I would be very surprised if it fell to 5.5 percent. I suspect it will remain above 5.5 percent,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Dermot O'Brien, economist at NCB Stockbrokers, also believes interbank rates are unlikely to fall dramatically, avoiding the need for retail rate rises.  </p>
<p>&quot;If the pound were to strengthen sharply versus the mark there might be some possibility but there is not much immediate possibility.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is still open. It's really up to the banks and building societies,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>But AIB's Pat O'Sullivan believes interbank rates are likely to drop by around an eighth, alleviating immediate pressure for a retail rate rise although he warned that pressure could emerge again within weeks.  </p>
<p>&quot;All this could change come next month when we get credit numbers again and if they show continued signs of robust growth it could reverse much of the gains seen here at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts agree that the German repo cut should provide a fillip for Irish bonds, particularly at the short end.</p>
<p>&quot;Short yields are down 15-20 basis points in continental Europe so you could expect short yields here to fall by 10 or 15 basis points,&quot; Riada's Garvey said.</p>
<p>O'Brien noted that the Bundesbank move was likely to bolster plans for Economic and Monetary Union (EMU), encouraging convergence trades likely to benefit the Irish market.  </p>
<p>&quot;We should see a positive reaction as convergence opinion resurfaces after the shock of last month,&quot; he said, referring to the Bundesbank's surprise decision to leave the repo unchanged at its last meeting.</p>
<p>-- Dublin Newsroom +353 1 676 9779</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
