<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8367" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German court jails unrepentent U.S. neo-Nazi.</title>
<headline>German court jails unrepentent U.S. neo-Nazi.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Gray</byline>
<dateline>HAMBURG, Germany 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Hamburg court jailed U.S. neo-Nazi leader Gary Lauck for four years on Thursday for pumping banned propaganda material into Germany from his U.S.-based publishing house.</p>
<p>A defiant Lauck, from Lincoln, Nebraska, yelled a tirade of abuse at the court after his conviction for inciting racial hatred.</p>
<p>&quot;The struggle will go on,&quot; the 43-year-old shouted in German before being escorted out by security guards.</p>
<p>Lauck's lawyer vowed he would appeal against the court's decision, arguing that his client should have been set free because he had not committed any offence under German law.</p>
<p>The conviction was a major coup for prosecutors, who had been trying for years to scupper Lauck's worldwide network -- the main source of anti-Semitic propaganda material flowing into Germany since the 1970s.</p>
<p>&quot;Lauck possessed a well-oiled propaganda machine, honed during more than 20 years,&quot; presiding judge Guenter Bertram told the court.</p>
<p>&quot;He set up a propaganda canon and fired it at Germany.&quot;</p>
<p>Eager to put Lauck behind bars quickly and avoid a long and complex trial, prosecutor Bernd Mauruschat limited his charges to offences since 1994. He had demanded a five-year jail term but said he was satisfied with the court's sentence.</p>
<p>Publishing and distributing neo-Nazi material is illegal in Germany but Lauck's defence team had argued that U.S freedom of speech laws meant he was free to produce his swastika-covered books, magazines, videos and flags in the United States.</p>
<p>Lauck, dressed in a sober blue suit and sporting his trademark Hitleresque black moustache, showed no sign of emotion as Bertram spent more than an hour reading out the verdict and explaining the court's decision.</p>
<p>But as he was about to be led away, Lauck turned to reporters and blurted out a virtually incomprehensible quick-fire diatribe against the court.</p>
<p>&quot;Neither the National Socialists (Nazis) nor the communists dared to kidnap an American citizen,&quot; he shouted, in an oblique reference to his extradition to Germany. &quot;That's the truth.&quot;</p>
<p>His attorney, Hans-Otto Sieg, told reporters outside the courtroom that the judges had failed to address whether a German court could convict someone for producing propaganda on foreign soil and sending it to Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;You can't just say he set up a propaganda canon and fired it at Germany,&quot; Sieg said. &quot;Journalists may be able to write that but it's not a legal point. I still don't see which German law he is supposed to have broken.&quot;</p>
<p>Bertram said Lauck was obsessed by Nazism and devoted his life to his National Socialist German Workers' Party Foreign Organisation (NSDAP-AO), which derives its name from the full German title of Hitler's Nazi party.</p>
<p>The court also rejected Sieg's argument that Lauck's extradition from Denmark, where he was arrested in March last year at the request of German authorities, was illegal.</p>
<p>Lauck will probably be free in around two and a half years as the court ruled that the 15 months he has spent in custody since his arrest should be subtracted from his prison term.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
