<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8369" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: African fasters hijack French political agenda.</title>
<headline>African fasters hijack French political agenda.</headline>
<byline>Francois Raitberger</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ten Africans who are on hunger strike to fight deportation from France have forced the government to take a deep second look at controversial hardline immigration laws.</p>
<p>Holed up in a church after months of playing cat-and-mouse with police through Paris, the fasters and 300 poor, uneducated fellow immigrant protesters managed what left-wing politicians, lawyers and human rights activists had failed to achieve.</p>
<p>The conservative government has asked the country's highest administrative court for guidelines on the enforcement of the 1993 &quot;Pasqua laws&quot; and Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre said he would re-examine expulsion orders on a case-by-case basis.</p>
<p>Spurred by the rise of the far-right National Front and anti-immigrant feeling fuelled by acute unemployment and mounting insecurity in heavily immigrant suburbs, hardline then-interior minister Charles Pasqua announced in 1993 plans to move towards &quot;zero immigration.&quot;</p>
<p>The laws drastically tightening residence and citizenship regulations were hastily steamrollered through parliament, meeting little opposition in the wake of the Left's election rout.</p>
<p>But lawyers soon pointed out loopholes and legal kinks meaning some foreigners could neither be expelled nor win residence permits. Legal conflicts broke out, with courts often quashing orders to expel illegal residents.</p>
<p>A case in point was a breach of the tradition of granting citizenship to any child born in France. The 1993 laws say children of foreigners will only become French if they live in France until the age of 16 and then request nationality.</p>
<p>Thus parents of children born before the Pasqua laws may not be expelled. Parents of children born later may, although their children, as potential French citizens, may not.</p>
<p>&quot;Must they go and leave their children behind? This is absurd,&quot; said human rights lawyer Dominique Noguere.</p>
<p>A crackdown on marriages of convenience has broken up families, with foreign spouses of French citizens or legal residents no longer being automatically entitled to stay.</p>
<p>&quot;The legislators did not foresee all the effects of the laws. All these cases have to be re-examined,&quot; Noguere said.</p>
<p>The African protesters say many of them did enjoy residence rights but were plunged into illegallity by the &quot;Pasqua laws&quot; which Socialist Party spokesman Francois Hollande described as &quot;a factory of illegal immigrants.&quot;</p>
<p>There are no official figures for the number of illegal immigrants and estimates vary from 200,000 to one million.</p>
<p>A report to the United Nations Human Rights Commission last April sharply attacked the laws as inspired by &quot;a wave of xenophobia and racism&quot; running counter to France's tradition of integrating foreigners and image as the cradle of human rights.</p>
<p>It recommended making the laws more humane.</p>
<p>Yet a parliamentary committee last June proposed harsher measures, including extending detention of foreigners facing deportation, limiting access to education and health care for illegal aliens.</p>
<p>The report was shelved after an outcry but it shows that anti-immigrant feeling leaves Debre little room for manoeuvre to meet the protesters' blanket demand for 300 residence permits.</p>
<p>He said he would take family situations into account. But there was no legal way all of them could be allowed to stay, particularly those whose political asylum requests had been rejected, and the law would not be re-drafted.</p>
<p>An opinion poll published by the daily Le Parisien backed his stand. An overwhelming 85 percent majority of voters called for a case-by-case review of the protesters' legal situation, but only 12 percent favoured a blanket permission to stay.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
