<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8372" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Finnish interest rates near right level - premier.</title>
<headline>Finnish interest rates near right level - premier.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish interest rates were near a level &quot;where they should be&quot; considering Finland's unemployment problem, Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has staked out its medium-term goals very clearly. The basic target is to achieve a medium-term period of growth, which will lower unemployment significantly from the current level,&quot; Lipponen said in a seminar, according to a copy of his prepared speech.</p>
<p>Many positive things had happened over the past year, he said. &quot;Interest rates have approached the level where they should be, considering the difficult unemployment situation,&quot; he said but did not elaborate.</p>
<p>The prepared speech made no reference to the exchange rate of the markka or the timetable of a coming decision whether to peg it to Europe's exchange rate mechanism.</p>
<p>Instead, Lipponen spoke in broad terms about his five-party coalition's economic policy programme. Halting state indebtedness, keeping inflation in check and interest rates low were key government objectives, he said.</p>
<p>Finland had a good chance to reach its target of slightly more than three percent annual growth on average in 1997-2000, Lipponen said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am emphasising that the question is explicitly about average growth, not that the increase in production would be completely even from quarter to quarter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said he was convinced that the economic policy pursued by the government would bear fruit. Signs of strengthening domestic growth were visible, he said.</p>
<p>Recovering domestic demand would be crucial to combat the current mass unemployment, he said.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +35 80 6805 0247</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
