<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8374" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Iran's Khameini ordered Kurd killings.</title>
<headline>Iran's Khameini ordered Kurd killings.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Iranian president Abolhassan Banisadr told a heavily-guarded Berlin court on Thursday that Iran's religious leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei ordered the assassination of opposition Kurd leaders in 1992.</p>
<p>Banisadr told the court that a &quot;council for special operations&quot; supervised by Khameini had ordered and carried out the gangland-style slaying of three Iranian Kurdish leaders and their translator at a Berlin restaurant.</p>
<p>&quot;According to the current (power) structures (in Iran) there can only be one person who ordered this and that is the ruler himself -- Iran's religious leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei,&quot; Banisadr said in his testimony.</p>
<p>Speaking in his native tongue, Farsi, he told the court through translators that he based his assertions on information he had gathered about the power structures in Iran during his 15 years in exile from sources &quot;within the regime and outside&quot;.</p>
<p>Banisadr alleged that the &quot;council for special operations&quot; in Tehran was outside the official political structures and was responsible for determining who would be assassinated and how.</p>
<p>He said that, apart from Khameini, four other men sat on the council including Intelligence Minister Ali Fallahiyan. German authorities issued an arrest warrant for Fallahiyan in March in connection with the 1992 Kurd dissident killings.</p>
<p>&quot;After this council works out an (assassination) plan and it is approved by Khameini it is handed over to (Iranian President Akbar Hashemi) Rafsanjani,&quot; Banisadr said.</p>
<p>Once it is blessed by the Iranian president it goes back to Fallahiyan to be carried out, he told the court.</p>
<p>&quot;There are sources (that back this up) within the regime and outside the regime. There is a large network of Iranians across the world with different political views who want to see a return to democracy in Iran,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Banisadr, 63, told German authorities he had heard Tehran was sending two squads of hired assassins to intimidate him while he gives evidence in Berlin on Thursday and Friday.</p>
<p>The court in the city's Moabit district was surrounded by a top-security cordon of about 100 police officers, some wearing bullet-proof vests and armed with machineguns. Police marksmen were posted on surrounding rooftops and traffic was diverted away from the main road where the court is located</p>
<p>In the courtroom itself, ten police officers sat amidst spectators crowding the public gallery.</p>
<p>Banisadr is the star prosecution witness against an Iranian, Kazem Darabi, and four Lebanese who have been on trial for nearly three years on charges of murdering the dissidents.</p>
<p>Two masked men armed with machineguns burst into the Mykonos restaurant in Berlin on September 17, 1992, and fired at dozens of Iranian dissidents seated at a table.</p>
<p>Three leaders of the Iranian Democratic Party of Kurdistan (DPK-I) and their translator were killed in the hail of bullets.</p>
<p>The case has strained relations between Bonn and Tehran, particularly after prosecutors issued the warrant for Fallahiyan's arrest, accusing him of masterminding the attack.</p>
<p>Iran has denied Fallahiyan was involved in the killing.</p>
<p>Tehran has also rejected Banisadr's allegations, saying that he is a fierce opponent of its Islamic fundamentalist government and that 14 years have passed since his administration was toppled and his ties with Iran were severed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
