<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8378" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Danish bonds fall tad on Buba, local cut possible.</title>
<headline>Danish bonds fall tad on Buba, local cut possible.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish bond prices were largely unaffected by the German Bundesbank's repo cut on Thursday, falling only slightly with speculation on a possible Danish trimming rampant.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not know quite which way the market is going, short term yields are going down all over Europe after the German repo cut,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The benchmark 8 percent state bond due 2006 rose 0.23 point to 194.86 on the Buba cut, yielding 7.25 percent against 7.28 percent before in over one billion crown turnover with its Sept future 0.24 point down at 104.50 in 100 contract trade.  </p>
<p>Speculation on a possible new Danish repo rate cut of 0.10 basis points was rife in the market, with doubt about the timing of such a move. The six percent mortgage bond due 2026 lost 0.10 point to 81.85.</p>
<p>The crown traded at 3.8637 per mark at 1135 gmt, up from around 3.8655 at the opening.</p>
<p>The 10-year yield gap with Germany narrowed one basis point to 95 since the morning start.</p>
<p>--Chris Follett, Copenhagen newsroom, 45-33-969652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
