<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8381" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: INSTANT VIEW - Bank of France cuts key rate.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - Bank of France cuts key rate.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are analysts' comments on the Bank of France's reduction on Monday in its key intervention rate to 3.35 percent from 3.55 percent.</p>
<p>Economists had generally believed a cut was highly unlikely, with a majority saying French franc weakness counted against such a move even if the Bundesbank cut German rates.</p>
<p>Philippe Brossard, economist, ABM-AMRO:</p>
<p>&quot;This should be the end to the mini-crisis for the franc. The cut is bigger than expected in Germany and in France. I'm not sure you can conclude that this was the last cut from the Buba.&quot;  </p>
<p>Patrick Mange, economist, Deutsche Bank:</p>
<p>&quot;The German cut was a surprise in terms of timing and size, but everybody had expected a cut if not now, by October. For France, it (the French cut) was a necessity, it would have been psychologically negative for the markets if it did not cut.</p>
<p>&quot;I could imagine rates staying roughly steady at this level to the end of the year but would not rule out a cut.&quot;</p>
<p>Jean-Louis Mourier, economist at Louis Dreyfus Finance:</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank gave the Bank of France a margin of manoeuvre. There could be more tension on the franc around budget time (in September). The franc weakness was not an interest rate story. It was about worries over the budget. That's why I think the Bank of France did not use all its room for manoeuvre at once.&quot;</p>
<p>Sean Shepley, economist of CS First Boston</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank has made a decisive move on rates and that should be enough for now to ease tension on currency markets. It would not be surprising if there were to be a degree of intervention in the currency markets just to ensure the situation remains relatively stable. The German move on rates means the political decisions in September regarding budgets and reforms that must take place in France and Germany can occur in an atmosphere of less market tension than would have been case.&quot;  </p>
<p>Herve Goulletquer, economist, Banques Populaires</p>
<p>&quot;Germany moved decisively. Certainly to support the dollar. France has killed two birds with the one stone in cutting by 20 basis points, saluting the Bundesbank move and at the same time keeping room to support the franc against the mark.&quot;</p>
<p>Philippe Ithurbide, chief economist, Societe Generale</p>
<p>&quot;Even if the franc benefits from the cut in German rates there is still another big deadline looming, the budget. When we try to reconstruct the budget with the information we have, it's hard to make it all out. The job will be difficult. The rate cut is necessary but not enough.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
