<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8383" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French wheat firms on EU bids but currency weighs.</title>
<headline>French wheat firms on EU bids but currency weighs.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>French wheat prices firmed a touch after the grain trade doubled the quantity of wheat it was ready to export at tender to approaching 300,000 tonnes, traders said.</p>
<p>Wheat was up to 10 francs firmer at 890 francs per tonne, excluding carrying charges, for delivery into the northern port of Rouen from September onwards.</p>
<p>But a sharp uptick in the dollar after the German Bundesbank slashed a key interest rate, also boosting the franc against the mark, was seen making markets cautious. French wheat has been sensitive to volatile French currency levels this month.  </p>
<p>Traders bid through France for 278,750 tonnes of European Union soft wheat at Thursday's main auction compared with 123,550 tonnes at the last tender two weeks ago.</p>
<p>Based on currencies at the time of the bids, traders were offering a premium over U.S. grades of nine or 10 dollars per tonne with bids worth up to $186.70 per tonne, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;We think Brussels will be generous this evening,&quot; said one trader, referring to EU cereals management committee talks.</p>
<p>After the Bundesbank move, the same highest bids were worth around a dollar less but traders said the EU's export position still looked more attractive than in recent months.  </p>
<p>Traders said the highest bid of any significant tonnage was based on an export tax of 2.27 Ecus per tonne instead of the top tax offer of 3.08 Ecus per tonne.</p>
<p>That appeared to rate first-half September French soft wheat around $184.25 per tonne compared with U.S. soft red winter at $177 per tonne.</p>
<p>EU officials have recently expressed optimism that with a bigger than expected harvest this year, they will be able to keep up a reasonable flow of exports at taxes which keep prices at a premium to the U.S., thus avoiding a return to subsidies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
