<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8387" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Late German grain harvest to delay winter sowings.</title>
<headline>Late German grain harvest to delay winter sowings.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Delays to the German grain and oilseeds harvests would have a knock-on effect on winter plantings, which usually start being planned at the end of August, traders and farm official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If the seeds aren't ready, farmers will have to wait and this will make their life more difficult in the autumn,&quot; a farm ministry official in Bonn said.</p>
<p>&quot;The delays are not critical but they will shorten the winter vegetation period and divert attention from marketing discussions to more hectic field work.&quot;</p>
<p>Showers continue to disrupt the grain harvest, which is now in its final stages across the country.</p>
<p>National met office DWD forecast mixed weather, but less rain, than over the last week in the period to August 29.</p>
<p>Volumes and qualities have not suffered much from the latest disruptions but farmers had to pay drying costs which will add to the final grain price, traders said.</p>
<p>Farm co-op organisation DRV in a publication today forecast a 40-41 million tonne crop which would exceed last year's 39.9.</p>
<p>DRV said the area was five percent higher but yields would not reach last year's average 6.1 tonnes per hectare due to the severe winter and drought in the spring.</p>
<p>Traders said Hagberg falling numbers and protein contents in wheat, which accounts for 45 percent of the harvest area, differed widely.</p>
<p>These measure different sets of baking qualities, which should be still better than in other EU countries, but are expected to lag last year's results.</p>
<p>South and southwestern German wheat quality was most hit by rains in August and French material from an earlier and exceptionally good harvest was pressurising markets.</p>
<p>But farmgate price reductions in Germany were expected to make domestic grain competitive versus France later on, especially when the precise baking quality is established.</p>
<p>But France would compete with Germany in typical export markets such as Italy and the Benelux, where cheap British supplies were also making inroads, the traders said.</p>
<p>-- Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
