<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8391" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: INSTANT VIEW - Bundesbank cuts repo to 3.00 pct.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - Bundesbank cuts repo to 3.00 pct.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are comments from economists and traders on the decision of the Bundesbank to cut the main securities repurchase rate, or repo, to 3.00 percent from the 3.30 percent level seen since February.</p>
<p>A Reuter survey showed seven of 10 economists polled believed the Ifo institute business climate index, which on Wednesday jumped to an eight-month high of 94.1 in July, had decreased the chance of a repo rate cut at the meeting.</p>
<p>A poll of the economists before the Ifo data showed 8 of 10 economists expected a rate cut of five to 20 basis points.  </p>
<p>Uwe Angenendt, BHF Bank, Frankfurt:</p>
<p>&quot;We had not expected such a large step. The Bundesbank appears to have made this decision a while ago and it was down to the timing. It now looks as though M3 money supply will go back into the four to seven percent target growth corridor. This is positive news for the dollar. I see a strengthening of the dollar against the mark on this news.</p>
<p>&quot;It is difficult to say whether this will be the end of rate cuts in this cycle. We see a strengthening of the economy, and against that background it could be an end to this cycle. But we have to wait for more data.&quot;  </p>
<p>Stefan Schneider, Senior Economist, Paribas Capital Markets, Frankfurt:</p>
<p>&quot;After yesterday's strong improvement in the July Ifo index, the consensus switched in favour of no change. It was quite a big surprise. I believe more and more signs of the German economy recovering has limited the scope of the Bundesbank to keep the interest rate fantasy alive.</p>
<p>&quot;I interpret this cut as the final move in interest rates for this cycle.</p>
<p>Patrick Mange, Deutsche Bank France, Paris:</p>
<p>&quot;After this cut, there could be other key rate cuts but it will depend on the economic pace. We do not expect as strong an economy in the second half. We will probably make at least another move on the repo rate.</p>
<p>&quot;The discount rate is more difficult to say. We can expect the repo rate to go back to a level of about 2.75 percent. But after that level a cut would be needed in the discount rate.&quot;</p>
<p>Michael Hochguertel, Head of Money Market, BHF Bank, Frankfurt:</p>
<p>&quot;I must say that I am a little surprised by the move. I expected a maxmium cut of 10 basis points. I was under the influence of that Ifo report. I am a bit confused by this 30 basis point cut. I would also say that a further cut at the moment is not on the cards.</p>
<p>It obviously means that M3 is going in the right direction. It is also reflecting that inflation is not a problem and the economy is not as strong as we think it is. It is reflecting concerns about unemployment and the current economic prospects.&quot;</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
