<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8392" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austria's far-right chief to face legal action.</title>
<headline>Austria's far-right chief to face legal action.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Drees</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian state prosecutors said on Thursday they were launching legal action against far-right Freedom Party leader Joerg Haider, accusing him of defaming a senior government minister.</p>
<p>The Klagenfurt prosecutor's office said it would start the proceedings, over comments Haider made last year about Interior Minister Caspar Einem, before the end of the week.</p>
<p>It will be the first time a state prosecutor has initiated legal action against the controversial nationalist politician.</p>
<p>&quot;We will definitely initiate the defamation of character legal proceedings against Joerg Haider,&quot; Klagenfurt chief prosecutor Erwin Grimschitz told Reuters.</p>
<p>Klagenfurt, 350 km (215 miles) southwest of Vienna, is in Haider's regional stronghold of Carinthia.</p>
<p>&quot;Haider's comments at a Freedom Party convention pertained to Einem's alleged abuse of office,&quot; Grimschitz said. He did not say what the remarks were.</p>
<p>Interior Ministry spokesman Rudolf Gollia said the case also concerned allegations by Haider that Einem had spent time in jail because of a drugs offence.</p>
<p>Haider, his spokesman and his lawyer were not immediately available to comment.</p>
<p>&quot;We are responsible for this case because the comments were made at the party convention in the town of Voelkermarkt in Carinthia, which falls into our jurisdiction,&quot; Grimschitz said.</p>
<p>Once the prosecutor has started proceedings, a court in Voelkermarkt will set the date for a trial.</p>
<p>&quot;In our experience that takes three to four weeks,&quot; Grimschitz said. &quot;The court will then rule whether Haider is guilty or not of the charge.&quot;</p>
<p>If found guilty, the far-right member of parliament could face up to a year in prison.</p>
<p>&quot;Now Herr Haider will have to justify his actions to the court at Voelkermarkt,&quot; Grimschitz said.</p>
<p>Members of parliament are normally guaranteed immunity from prosecution. But in March a special parliamentary committee revoked Haider's immunity in an unprecedented step, the prosecutor said.</p>
<p>The proceedings are the latest in a series of political controversies to plague Haider since he took over as head of the Freedom Party in 1986.</p>
<p>In 1991, he was forced to resign as governor of Carinthia after praising Adolf Hitler's labour policies. In February 1995 he had to backtrack after referring to Nazi extermination camps as &quot;punishment camps&quot;.</p>
<p>In June this year, the Jewish humanitarian organisation B'nai B'rith launched legal proceedings against Haider, accusing him of reviving Nazism. That action is continuing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
