<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8395" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Lipponen signals markka-ERM link near - analysts.</title>
<headline>Lipponen signals markka-ERM link near - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Peter Starck</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen has kicked life into forex market speculation about the timing and level of a link for the markka to Europe's exchange rate mechanism, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>They saw his reported remarks that a further firming of the markka was unjustifed, and an ERM decision would come in the fairly near future,as a clear sign Finland will link the markka.</p>
<p>&quot;What he said increased the likelihood that a link will be made speedily,&quot; said Jukka Lepomaki, head of market advisory at Merita Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;It points in the direction that we are going in,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>It was no surprise that Finland would, by joining the ERM, try to make sure it will formally meet the exchange rate stability criterion for Economic and Monetary Union (EMU), said Ari Aaltonen, chief economist at Postipankki.</p>
<p>&quot;But it was a significant statement for the development of the exchange rate,&quot; said Aaltonen, referring to Lipponen's remarks. &quot;The sentiment changed, the ERM autumn has started,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The markka started to weaken late on Wednesday on reports that Lipponen believed a further strengthening was not justified.</p>
<p>The markka, which has firmed gradually during the summer on strong macro-economic fundamentals, fell sharply to 3.05 to the German mark from Wednesday's 3.018 close. It eased to 0.684 against the Swedish crown from 0.677.</p>
<p>The central bank on Thursday declined to comment on whether it had intervened to reduce volatility in the markka.</p>
<p>Handelsbanken Markets Finland chief economist Carlo Erakallio said Lipponen's comments &quot;indicate that a change in exchange rate policy is on its way. We are now in a transition phase, on our way towards a fixed exchange rate regime.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The ERM fix is drawing near,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Analysts expect the decision to join the ERM to come between late September and November. &quot;Talking the exchange rate weaker like that just before a decision to go in would be seen as too outrageous manipulation,&quot; Lepomaki said.</p>
<p>Aaltonen at Postipanki said Lipponen made sense when he said fundamentals did not support a stronger exchange rate. He expected the markka to trade in a 3.03-3.05 range per mark in the near term and then move towards a 3.05-3.10 band.</p>
<p>Aaltonen said a fix was &quot;more than 50 percent&quot; likely and its central parity exchange rate would be between 3.05 and 3.10 markka per German mark.</p>
<p>Erakallio said Handelsbanken stood by its earlier forecast that the markka would join the ERM in late October or early November at around 3.04 per mark.</p>
<p>Merita's Lepomaki said the political establishment had been expected to echo recent concerns voiced by industry about the strength of the markka.</p>
<p>Finnish industry fears a stronger markka would undermine its competitiveness, in particular against neighbouring Sweden, which is not expected to link the crown to the ERM.</p>
<p>Lepomaki said Finland might go for a central parity exchange rate as weak as 3.07 -- the average markka/mark level over the past two years -- but was more likely to have to settle for a stronger rate between 3.03 and 3.05.</p>
<p>The markka weakening caused by Lipponen's comments was temporary, he said. Strong fundamentals and exporting firms' pent-up need to convert foreign currency earnings would strengthen the markka again, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;By linking it (to the ERM), they seek a way to prevent the markka from strengthening too much,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Helsinki Newsroom  +358-0-680 50 245</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
