<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8400" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Dublin airport sees record passenger level in July.</title>
<headline>Dublin airport sees record passenger level in July.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A record one million passengers passed through Dublin airport in July, the Irish airports authority Aer Rianta said on Thursday.</p>
<p>A total of 1,019,673 passengers used the airport, an eight percent increase on the same month last year.</p>
<p>Over 541,000 UK passengers passed through Dublin airport, representing about half of the July's traffic total, Aer Rianta said in a statement.</p>
<p>Transatlantic traffic received a boost from the introduction of new services to the U.S. and rose 17 percent in July.  </p>
<p>European passenger numbers were little changed at 358,006 in July but Aer Rianta said the figures were distorted by the fact that there were only four weekends in July this year compared with five last summer. Continental holiday-makers generally tend to travel at weekends.</p>
<p>Aer Rianta said that more than five million passengers have used Dublin airport to date this year and a further four million are expected to pass through by the end of 1996.</p>
<p>-- Dublin Newsroom +353 1 676 9779</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
