<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8414" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EMU hopefuls enter 1997 budget slashing season.</title>
<headline>EMU hopefuls enter 1997 budget slashing season.</headline>
<byline>Henry Engler</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A large number of European Union governments will come under close scrutiny in September as they unveil their 1997 budgets, a key step in their attempt to meet the preconditions of a single currency.</p>
<p>Most analysts say the challenge is not so much whether they can bring public deficits exactly in line with the Maastricht treaty's criteria -- a long shot for most.</p>
<p>The more important issue is whether they can get close enough to qualify for EMU and inspire confidence among investors that it will be launched on time.  </p>
<p>Between now and mid-October, France, Spain, Italy, the Netherlands, Belgium, Sweden, Denmark, Finland, Portugal and Greece are all expected either to announce their 1997 draft budgets or have updates on the state of budget negotiations.</p>
<p>Under the treaty, governments must bring their 1997 budget deficits close to three percent of total output and put their outstanding debt levels on a sustainable path towards 60 percent of GDP. Nearly all observers agree that discretion will be employed when interpreting the strictness of such targets.  </p>
<p>Within the group, analysts say the most closely watched will be France which is expected to announce details of its 1997 budget on either September 18 or 25. The stakes for Paris are enormous given renewed uncertainty over France's economic outlook and the implications for revenue growth.</p>
<p>While the broad outlines of its plan have already been announced -- France is looking for spending cuts of 60 billion francs ($11.82 billion) and tax cuts of roughly 20 billion -- important details such as growth and revenue estimates remain to be finalised.  </p>
<p>&quot;We think the biggest uncertainty is on the receipts side,&quot; says Svenja Nehls, economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in Paris. &quot;It would be very important that (economic) growth expectations are not too high for next year.&quot;</p>
<p>Too optimistic a forecast could prompt investors to question the government's ability to bring next year's deficit under 4.0 percent of GDP. Many reckon an outcome in the range of 3.5 to 4.0 percent might suffice for EMU entry.  </p>
<p>Following France, analysts say market attention will turn towards Italy and Spain -- two countries that are unlikely to take part in the single currency in 1999, but want desperately to enter relatively soon thereafter.</p>
<p>For Italy, the more important hurdles appear to be in the political realm with the government seen facing strong opposition from its Communist coalition partners to planned spending cuts.</p>
<p>Details of Rome's 1997 budget are expected in September, with anticipated savings of 32.4 trillion lire ($21.33 billion).  </p>
<p>The package is expected to put the deficit at around 4.5 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's unlikely Italy will be in the first round,&quot; says John Llewellyn, chief economist at Lehman Brothers in London. &quot;Nonetheless they wish to join EMU and to do so you have to stay with a good budgetary situation.&quot;</p>
<p>Under Italy's budget process, parliament must approve next year's plan by year-end.  </p>
<p>In Spain, meanwhile, the recent and unfortunate discovery of a budget gap of almost 530 billion pesetas ($4.22 billion) will have no effect on the 1997 budget. The government has already announced a zero wage rise for public-sector employees, as well as reductions in subsidies to public firms.</p>
<p>Despite these efforts many think it will be quite difficult to see a deficit near 3.0 percent GDP, with most estimates hovering at or around 4.0 percent. The draft budget must be submitted to parliament by the end of the September.  </p>
<p>Regarding other budgets, analysts say investor interest is more muted either because the candidates are more than likely to qualify for EMU in the first round -- Austria, Belgium, Luxembourg, the Netherlands and possibly Finland -- or are undecided if they want to join -- Britain, Denmark and Sweden.</p>
<p>Ireland already has an exemplary budget performance, Portugal is seen struggling and Greece is considered to have virtually no chance of qualifying for EMU in 1999. Which leaves Germany, perhaps the linchpin of the entire project.  </p>
<p>No important budgetary developments are expected out of Bonn during September. The major concern at the moment is whether Germany's federal states can assist the government's efforts to bring the overall deficit near 3.0 percent of output.</p>
<p>Since roughly 40 percent of their expenses are tied to wages and salaries, there is little room for maneouvre. Analysts say developments in this area are likely to unfold before year-end.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
