<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8417" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's separatist leader heckled at opera.</title>
<headline>Italy's separatist leader heckled at opera.</headline>
<byline>Vera Haller</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Umberto Bossi, Italy's separatist leader who plans to declare an independent northern state next month, was heckled at a performance of a Giuseppe Verdi opera in the northern town of Verona on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>Shouts of &quot;Bossi Go Away&quot; and &quot;Long Live a United Italy&quot; greeted Bossi as he escorted his wife Emmanuele to their 13th row seats in Verona's ancient ampitheatre before the start of Verdi's &quot;Nabucco&quot;.</p>
<p>Bossi ignored the hecklers and similar insults flung in his direction as he left the arena when the opera was suspended because of rain in the middle of the third act. He and his wife went to a nearby restaurant and did not return to hear the end.</p>
<p>&quot;I am an Italian who doesn't want our country to be divided,&quot; one of the hecklers, retired Fiat auto worker Luciano Mordenti, told television cameras.</p>
<p>Bossi, for his part, told reporters as he left the arena that he believed the protests had been orchestrated by workers at the arena.</p>
<p>Wednesday night's performance was part of Verona's popular open-air opera season and was attended by many foreign tourists.</p>
<p>Verona is located in the centre of Bossi's so-called &quot;Padania republic&quot;. Bossi has said he will lead a big demonstration on September 15 at which the League has said it will declare an &quot;independent northern state&quot;.</p>
<p>Bossi's Northern League is the biggest political party in Verona with 27 percent of the electorate supporting it at the last general election in April.</p>
<p>The League took root in the 1980s as a protest movement against the excesses of Rome central government and was instrumental in helping bring about the collapse of the old, corrupt political guard at the start of the 1990s.</p>
<p>Its support has grown steadily and at the April election it polled 10 percent of the vote nationwide.</p>
<p>Bossi told reporters his decision to attend the Verona opera had special political significance because Verdi came from the town of Busseto which lies within Padania.</p>
<p>&quot;Verdi came from Padania,&quot; he said. &quot;The performance of 'Nabucco' at the Arena of Verona at this moment in Italian history has a particular interest to me, above all else the chorus of Lombardy.&quot;</p>
<p>But newspapers said Bossi had got his operas muddled up, pointing out that &quot;the chorus of Lombardy&quot;, actually comes from another Verdi work, &quot;Lombardi alla prima Crociata&quot;.</p>
<p>They said historians had interpreted the famous chorus in &quot;Nabucco&quot;, sung by characters depicting Jews, to mean that Verdi identified with citizens of the northern regions of Lombardy and Veneto who were at the time governed by Austria and wanted a unified Italy.</p>
<p>&quot;What a blunder,&quot; read the headline above an editorial in the respected Corriere della Sera daily. &quot;Verdi's music is a slogan for unity.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Nabucco&quot; premiered in 1842, 19 years before Italian unification in 1861.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
