<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8423" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Scandinavian govts could cut stake in SAS - ministry.</title>
<headline>Scandinavian govts could cut stake in SAS - ministry.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The governments of Sweden, Denmark and Norway, part owners of Scandinavian Airlines System (SAS) would consider reducing their holdings in the carrier to increase private ownership, a senior Danish transport ministry official told Reuters on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a very long term concept tied to the purchase of new aircraft and the three governments would insist on holding on to at least 35 percent of shares in each SAS unit in the three countries,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>&quot;This would ensure that the governments could block any major changes in SAS. The governments are prepared to surrender their majority shareholdings if it is necessary to attract new capital for buying new planes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Given European Union monopoly policies and (national) budgetary considerations, the Scandinavian governments are hardly interested in increasing their shareholding in SAS. They would prefer to allow the airline to seek funding through a possible share issue on the private market,&quot; he concluded.</p>
<p>Media reports say that SAS will in the coming years have to consider investing in some 50 new aircraft for European routes and an unspecified number for intercontinental services.</p>
<p>SAS is jointly owned by the governments of Sweden, Denmark and Norway and private investors with the three Scandinavian states currently holding 50 percent of shares in each of the three local SAS units.</p>
<p>Sweden has a three-sevenths stake in SAS, with Denmark and Norway each holding two-sevenths.</p>
<p>--Chris Follett, Copenhagen newsroom +45-33969652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
