<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8433" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Danish economic outlook improves - ministry.</title>
<headline>Danish economic outlook improves - ministry.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Danish government on Thursday revised downward its forecasts for 1996 inflation and unemployment while projecting a higher current account surplus.</p>
<p>The government left unchanged its gross domestic product (GDP) forecast at 1.8 percent.</p>
<p>In its periodic forecast revision, the economy ministry predicted a 2.0 percent rise in consumer prices -- 0.1 point lower than in the previous forecast in May.</p>
<p>The unemployment rate was seen at 9.0 percent instead of 9.2 percent and the current account surplus at 10 billion crown instead of 8.3 billion.</p>
<p>However, the public sector deficit projection was increased to 15.3 billion crowns from 12 billion but the ministry sharply revised downwards its 1997 deficit projection, to 5.8 billion from 9.1 billion.</p>
<p>The 1997 deficit forecast was carried out according to the current economic environment and Economics Minister Marianne Jelved repeated the government's goal of eliminating the deficit next year.</p>
<p>&quot;The government intends to see public expenditure balance in 1997. It is a necessary requirement to allow Denmark to begin paying off its large public debt,&quot; Jelved said in her ministry's outlook.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a good foundation for Denmark to continue the recent years' positive economic development,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The forecast for 1997 showed an improved outlook for most indicators, even though GDP growth forecast was flat at 3.0 percent.</p>
<p>Inflation was projected at 2.3 percent against May's forecast of 2.4 percent while the unemployment rate at 8.6 percent instead of 8.7 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
