<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8450" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Algerian FIS leader's sons go on trial in Germany.</title>
<headline>Algerian FIS leader's sons go on trial in Germany.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Liffey</byline>
<dateline>DUESSELDORF, Germany 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two sons of Algerian fundamentalist opposition leader Abassi Madani went on trial in a high-security court on Thursday accused of smuggling arms and explosives from Germany to anti-government forces in Algeria.</p>
<p>Salim and Ikbal Abassi, aged 29 and 25, and two other Algerians, Nasr-Eddine Layachi Hemaz, 30, and Mahmoud Logbi, 25, face up to five years in prison if convicted on formal charges of belonging to a criminal organisation.</p>
<p>The accused, who all deny involvement, have been in custody for more than a year since authorities cracked down on Algerian fundamentalists using southern and western Germany as a base to support an armed conflict against Algeria's military rulers.</p>
<p>Because of the security risk, the men went on trial in a high-security area of the high court in Duesseldorf where four right-wing youths were convicted last year of a 1993 racist arson murder in Solingen.</p>
<p>The trial was due to open on Wednesday but was postponed because interpreters did not arrive in time.</p>
<p>The 160-page charge sheet in what is likely to be a tortuous case says the men belonged to a gun-running group that worked independently but kept conspiratorial links with other Islamic fundamentalist groups in France, Italy, Belgium and Algeria.</p>
<p>The group is alleged to have shipped around 100 assault rifles, over 30 machine pistols, 20 repeating rifles, 15 hand guns, eight pump guns and assorted ammunition and explosives to Morocco and Algeria between March 1993 and April 1994.</p>
<p>The weapons were allegedly sent to the Armed Islamic Group (GIA) and the Islamic Salvation Army (AIS), the military wing of the fundamentalist Islamic Salvation Front (FIS).</p>
<p>The Abassis' father, Abassi Madani, is co-founder of the FIS, which took up arms against Algeria's military rulers after they intervened in 1992 to scrap a general election the FIS was set to win.</p>
<p>Abassi Madani still lives in Algeria but his wife Saida and sons Ikbal, Salim and Oussama fled to Germany in 1992 and were been allowed to stay as political refugees.</p>
<p>Ikbal and Salim were sentenced to death in absentia in May 1993 by an Algerian court for alleged involvement in a bombing of Algiers airport which killed nine people and wounded 124.</p>
<p>Investigators who raided the brothers' apartment near Aachen in March 1995 found a detonator, passport photographs, material for forging documents, some 20 sets of fake identity papers and about $70,000 in cash.</p>
<p>In addition to the main charge of belonging to a criminal organisation, the brothers are also accused of forgery together with Logbi, and of explosives offences together with Hemaz.</p>
<p>Both Logbi and Hemaz have had asylum requests rejected.</p>
<p>An estimated 50,000 people have been killed in Algeria since Moslem militants took up arms against the government.</p>
<p>Authorities say there are 30 to 50 FIS members and 200 or so sympathisers among the 23,000 Algerians living in Germany.</p>
<p>France, which was the target of a wave of bombings by Algerian militants last year, has put pressure on Bonn to crack down on Algerians in Germany amid fears authorities here were not keeping a close enough watch on them.</p>
<p>The trial is expected to last at least four months.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUESSELDORF, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
