<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8455" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Crowds gather for Belgian sex victims funeral.</title>
<headline>Crowds gather for Belgian sex victims funeral.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>LIEGE, Belgium 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Silent crowds began gathering in this eastern Belgian town on Thursday ahead of the funeral of two eight-year-old girls who died while in the hands of a convicted child sex offender.</p>
<p>Melissa Russo and Julie Lejeune will be buried after what will be an emotional memorial service in the Saint Martin basilica in their home town of Liege beginning at 11 a.m. (0900 GMT) and to be televised live across a shocked nation.</p>
<p>Up to 100,000 people are expected to attend the service which will be held after a private commemorative ceremony for the close relatives of the two friends. The burial of the two white coffins with the girls' remains will be private too.</p>
<p>Those who will not be able to enter the church can follow the service on a large video screen outside.</p>
<p>Hundreds of people lined the streets to the basilica down which the cortege will pass, having arrived with floral tributes from all over the country and leaving condolence cards in a gradually filling box.</p>
<p>Giant bouquets in pastel shades stood at the entrance of Saint Martin's as the sun was trying to break through the early morning mist. Police handed out water to the crowds in the warm, humid weather.</p>
<p>There were wreaths from the Belgian government and King Albert and Queen Paolo, the gendarmerie, bus companies, postal workers, the Brussels Metro, private citizens and villages and television companies.</p>
<p>The government will be represented at the service by Justice Minister Stefaan De Clerck and Public Service Minister Andre Flahaut.</p>
<p>The mood was sombre, but the anger about the cruel deaths of the girls -- who died of starvation -- has not abated.</p>
<p>One of the mourners, Anne-Marie Lamory of Bastogne on southern Belgium, told Reuters: &quot;I am here for the poor parents of those martyred children. The people who did this must be made to suffer...they too should die suffering...they are monsters.&quot;</p>
<p>The bodies of the girls were found last weekend, pointed out by Marc Dutroux, 39, and a father of three, in the garden of a house he owned.</p>
<p>Two other girls held by him had been rescued earlier.</p>
<p>Russo and Lejeune had been buried along with an accomplice of Dutroux who had allowed the girls to die while in his charge. Dutroux killed him in retaliation.</p>
<p>Dutroux, in jail at the time for violent theft, is seen as the mastermind behind a kidnapping and possibly child trafficking gang which also included his second wife.</p>
<p>Two other girls, whom he has admitted kidnapping, are still missing. The search for them has been extended to other European countries outside Belgium.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIEGE, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
