<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8461" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in the Swedish papers this morning. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAGENS NYHETER</p>
<p>- Swedish truck producer Scania said it is to introduce flexible working hours for 10,000 workers from September 1. Hours will be cut but Scania will have a better chance prevent redundancies.</p>
<p>- Swedish retail sales rose by six percent in July, compared to the same month last year, according to the Swedish Retail and Wholesale Research Institute (HUI). Radio and television retailers were the big winners.</p>
<p>- Investor AB is searching for a new owner to its Saab Aircraft unit.</p>
<p>SVENSKA DAGBLADET</p>
<p>- Coca-Cola is likely to back down on its decision not to employ workers from Swedish Pripps Ringnes when they move Coca-Cola's soft-drink production from Pripps to a new plant.</p>
<p>- SSAB Tunnplat has brought a lawsuit against insurance company Trygg-Hansa because it says it was not adequately compensated for an accident at its plant in 1993.</p>
<p>- Plans by the Swedish government to extend sick-leave pay from 14 days to 28 days is likely to create chaos in the work market.</p>
<p>DAGENS INDUSTRI</p>
<p>- Stagecoach, the Scottish bus company, views its acquisition of Swedish Swedbus as a platform for its continuing expansion in nothern Europe, according to Stagecoach founder and chairman Brian Souter.</p>
<p>- Swedish defence and technology group Celsius, which is cutting the workforce at its Kockums unit by 600, says these are the last cuts.</p>
<p>-- Paul de Bendern, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
