<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8463" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: UN members get new plan to end Burundi fighting.</title>
<headline>UN members get new plan to end Burundi fighting.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>In an attempt to force Burundi's leaders to the negotiating table, several Security Council members want to threaten sanctions and promise aid if Burundians resolve their conflict peacefully, diplomats said.</p>
<p>A proposed resolution, initiated by Chile and Botswana, is to be circulated on Thursday in an effort to stop violence between the country's minority Tutsis and majority Hutus and deal with last month's coup by the Tutsi-led army.</p>
<p>So far the council has criticised but not taken any action in response to the July 25 coup that overthrew the government of elected Hutu President Sylvestre Ntibantunganya and installed Major Pierre Buyoya .</p>
<p>The proposals follow closed discussions on Wednesday between council members and parliamentarians from Burundi's main political parties in Burundi, the first time a delegation of legislators expressed its views at a semi-formal meeting of the 15-member body.</p>
<p>In a carrot and stick approach, the draft resolution demands an immediate end to fighting and says all parties and factions &quot;without exception&quot; should initiate negotiations with a view to agreeing on &quot;basic components&quot; for a political settlement within 60 days after the resolution is adopted.</p>
<p>It also imposes an immediate arms embargo, although diplomats recognise enforcement would be difficult.</p>
<p>Should the parties fail to make progress within 60 days, the draft threatens &quot;targeted measures&quot; aimed at the government and political leaders who encouraged violence.</p>
<p>Chile's ambassador, Juan Somavia, in an earlier paper, recommended automatic trade sanctions if the negotiations failed but apparently was unable to get enough support.</p>
<p>Instead the draft now calls for measures &quot;in the political, military and diplomatic fields.&quot;</p>
<p>Should the talks make progress, the document says the United Nations would hold a conference to raise funds for reconstruction of the country, where more than 150,000 people have died in fighting over the past three years.</p>
<p>Diplomats said some variation of the resolution is expected to be adopted. But some Western envoys questioned the 60-day target date, saying more preparations would be needed after decades of sporadic fighting and massacres.</p>
<p>Boutros-Ghali, in a report to the Security Council earlier this week, again recommended that countries assemble a force of 50,000, outside of a U.N. command, in case the conflict escalated to widescale genocide. But he said that of more than 50 countries approached, only four offered troops.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the Burundian legislators, brought to New York by the Parliamentarians for Global Action, an independent group, gave conflicting views on what the council should do, depending on whether they belonged to the Hutu-dominated FRODEBU party or the Tutsi-run UPRONA party.</p>
<p>Jean-Marie Ngendahavo, a former foreign minister now in exile and a spokesman for the overthrown president, and Jean Minani, the FRODEBU chairman, said they asked the council to support sanctions imposed on Burundi by its neighbours in reaction to the coup.</p>
<p>Ngendahavo told reporters on Wednesday the president wanted any help available. But he said the army had to be part of any negotiations and be restructured &quot;to serve the people.</p>
<p>But UPRONA spokesmen differed, saying sanctions would be harmful. Adrien Sibomana, the prime minister in 1987 when Buyoya was last put in office by the military, said that sanctions would not be helpful.</p>
<p>He said that Buyoya was a factor one had to deal with, along with his government, even if the coup was illegal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
