<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8464" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: PRESS DIGEST - Italy - Thursday, Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Italy - Thursday, Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the top headlines in leading Italian newspapers.</p>
<p>-------</p>
<p>TOP POLITICAL STORIES</p>
<p>*Northern League party leader Umberto Bossi was booed by theatre audience at A performance of Giuseppe Verdi's Nabucco in Verona. Bossi says he is ready to renounce his parliamentary immunity and face magistrates who want to prosecute him: &quot;To put me on trial is to put Northern Italy on trial&quot; (all).</p>
<p>*Minister for Public Works Antonio Di Pietro says he can prove his accusations against former Christian Democrat secretary general Ciriaco De Mita. Di Pietro blamed De Mita saying &quot;he keeps asking favours&quot; (all).  Di Pietro is also quoted by friends as saying that after the Prodi government he wants to lead a center political movement (all).</p>
<p>*Communist leader Fausto Bertinotti says &quot;I appreciate the government good will over some of next autumn's big issues such as employment, education...and STET&quot;. (La Stampa). But Interior Minister Giorgio Napolitano says that Bertinotti's recent threats to sink the government over STET privatisation are unacceptable. (Corriere della Sera).</p>
<p>------------------------</p>
<p>TOP BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>*Inflation data from six sample cities show a sharp slowdown. A 3.3 pct rate is expected on a year on year basis, the lowest since July 1969.</p>
<p>*Sources from Treasury Ministry said &quot;the inflation slowdown is not due to recession&quot; and that banks are &quot;too slow in reducing interest rates&quot;. Banking association Abi replies &quot;It's up to the Bank of Italy&quot; (Corriere, Stampa, Il Sole 24 Ore).</p>
<p>---------</p>
<p>Reuter has not verified these stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau  +392 66129450</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
