<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8467" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German court convicts U.S. neo-Nazi for racism.</title>
<headline>German court convicts U.S. neo-Nazi for racism.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG, Germany 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A German court on Thursday convicted U.S. neo-Nazi leader Gary Lauck on racial hatred charges for exploiting freedom of speech laws in his homeland to pump extreme right-wing propaganda into Germany.</p>
<p>The Hamburg court sentenced Lauck to four years in jail. Prosecutors had demanded a five-year prison term for Lauck, dubbed the &quot;farm-belt Fuehrer&quot; by U.S. Nazi watchers. His defence team had requested an acquittal.  </p>
<p>The 43-year old from Lincoln, Nebraska, has run the National Socialist German Workers' Party Foreign Organisation (NSDAP-AO) -- a name derived from the full German title of Hitler's Nazi party -- for the past two decades.</p>
<p>Prosecutors said the NSDAP-AO had been the main source of neo-Nazi, including anti-semitic, material in Germany during that time but restricted their charges to offences over the past few years in a bid to secure a quick conviction.</p>
<p>Publishing and distributing neo-Nazi material is illegal in Germany but Lauck's lawyer insisted his client had broken no laws in the United States and prosecutors had not proved he was deliberately smuggling material into Germany.</p>
<p>Lauck was arrested during a visit to Denmark in March last year and extradited to Germany in September. His attorney argued the extradition was illegal as the charges he faced in court did not correspond exactly to those on his extradition warrant.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
