<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8472" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Blasts rock Corsica targets as truce buried.</title>
<headline>Blasts rock Corsica targets as truce buried.</headline>
<byline>Sylvie Florence</byline>
<dateline>AJACCIO, Corsica 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two blasts rocked public buildings in Corsica overnight as separatists announced they were burying a shaky seven-month truce, accusing the Paris government of reneging on secret commitments.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre quickly pledged that police would catch the authors of a series of attacks on state targets on the French Mediterranean island, and accused the perpetrators of sabotaging efforts to pull it out of an impasse.</p>
<p>The two latest bombs on the island in just over a week caused minor damage to tax collection offices in Calvi and welfare offices in Ile Rousse, both in the northeast of the island, police said. No one was injured.</p>
<p>No one claimed responsibility for the attacks but investigators said they were most probably part of an apparent resumption of two-decade-old separatist violence.</p>
<p>&quot;Police are reacting and will react with the utmost efficiency to arrest the authors of these attacks. They go against government efforts to find a solution to the real economic problems of Corsica,&quot; Debre told RTL radio.</p>
<p>&quot;The French people will not forgive the perpetrators for their attitude and their violence, because this is an unacceptable blow to efforts to pull Corsica out of an impasse,&quot; Debre added.</p>
<p>Judges on the island have accused the government of a lax stance on guerrilla violence as Paris, according to unconfirmed media reports, conducted secret talks with separatists over recent months.</p>
<p>Separatists said in a weekly published on Thursday that they were ending a truce already broken by a series of bombings.</p>
<p>&quot;The end of a peace process&quot;, was the headline of an article in Ribombou, the newspaper of the nationalist movement Cuncolta Naziunalista seen as the political arm of outlawed Corsican National Liberation Front (FLNC) separatist guerrillas.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has betrayed all its commitments, made in negotiations with the FLNC,&quot; Cuncolta leader Francois Santoni wrote.</p>
<p>It was unclear what commitments were in question. Santoni accused Prime Minister Alain Juppe of despising Corsicans and dismissed promised economic aid as charity.</p>
<p>&quot;Threats against outlawed groups have no effect on the determination to continue a fight which began more than 20 years ago,&quot; he said. A crackdown on the guerrillas would fail and &quot;could even hasten (Juppe's) political demise,&quot; Santoni said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AJACCIO, Corsica"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
