<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8476" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: PRESS DIGEST - Germany - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Germany - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Thursday morning's German newspapers:</p>
<p>FRANKFURTER ALLGEMEINE ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- German parliamentary controll commission discusses export of dual-use goods to Libya in the light of scandal over German firm that exported equipment to Libya that could be used to manufacture poison gas. Head of the committee denied any wrongdoing on part of German government.</p>
<p>- No definitive ruling from Federal Administrative Court over nuclear power station Kruemmel.</p>
<p>- Deutsche Telekom wants to lure investors by giving away free shares. Rebate for private investors. Listings planned in Frankfurt, New York, Tokyo and regional German stock exchanges.</p>
<p>- Construction industry hopes for more orders.</p>
<p>- German DIW economic research institute says that trade with eastern and central Europe helps to create more employment in those countries.</p>
<p>- Signs of hope for the consumer goods industry only on the export side.</p>
<p>HANDELSBLATT</p>
<p>- Deutsche Telekom says it will offer small investors a rebate. A discount of upto five percent should keep investors who buy Telekom shares in November. Those who keep the stock until september 1999 receive &quot;loyalty&quot; shares.</p>
<p>- Boom in the worldwide car industry is expected, according to the Essen-based Analysis Institute Marketing Systems.</p>
<p>- Parliamentary control commission discusses Germany's poison gas affair.</p>
<p>- Kloeckner-Humboldt-Deutz (KHD) rejects accusations.</p>
<p>- Trial opens for possibly one of Germany's biggest cases of investor fraud.</p>
<p>- Steel creates worries for Krupp-Hoesch.</p>
<p>- Ifo economic institute says the economic climate in July was better</p>
<p>SUEDDEUTSCHE ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- Court must examine leukaemia cases in area around Kruemmel nuclear power station. Federal Administrative court orders new safety examination for the reactor near Hamburg after questions over the links between children there with leukaemia and the atomic power station.</p>
<p>- Bonn demands an explanation from Tripoli.</p>
<p>- Deutsche Telekom lures investors with discounts in share prices.</p>
<p>- Gregor Gysi, the chairman of the Party of Democratic Socialism (PDS) -- east Germany's reform communists -- supports his party's involvement in the Bonn government.</p>
<p>DIE WELT</p>
<p>- Row over aid for Volkswagen intensifies.</p>
<p>- Gregor Gysi, the chairman of the Party of Democratic Socialism (PDS) -- east Germany's reform communists -- gets tougher with his critics within the party.</p>
<p>- New ruling called for over Kruemmel nuclear power station and whether there is link between new nuclear rods and high rate of leukaemia in region among children.</p>
<p>KHD manager insists on innocence. Executive board said it knew nothing about billion marks losses.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom +49 228 2609760</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
