<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8477" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights of stories in the Danish press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>BERLINGSKE TIDENDE</p>
<p>--- Danish mobile phone company Sonofon has agreed with the electricity company NESA on using NESA's cable net for telecommunication to compete against the telecommunications group Tele Danmark.</p>
<p>POLITIKEN</p>
<p>--- The Danish Red Cross has established a new department for business sponsors and is already negotiating with a number of large Danish companies on sponsorship deals.</p>
<p>--- Small Danish companies fail to obtain orders because they do not use the Internet says the Director of the Danish IT sector asssociation.</p>
<p>JYLLANDS-POSTEN</p>
<p>--- The Danish public sector deficit is decreasing sooner than expected, but the government still cannot expect to reach its goal of balance on the budget in 1997.</p>
<p>--- Danish poultry firm Danpo in western Denmark has won its fight to produce the first Danish samonella-free chicken. The new Danpo chicken will be launced in October.</p>
<p>BORSEN</p>
<p>--- Wage increase in companies which are members of The Danish Federation of Industry will  be lower than last year, the Federation foresees.</p>
<p>DET FRI AKTUELT</p>
<p>--- Conservativ leader Hans Engell, says his party will not demand a change in the present early retirement rules in the state Budget negotiations later this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
