<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8484" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: PRESS DIGEST - France - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - France - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are leading stories in this morning's Paris newspapers.</p>
<p>LES ECHOS</p>
<p>-- Prime Minister Alain Juppe back from holidays to deal with immigration affair and tax reform.</p>
<p>-- Generale des Eaux interested in backing Walter Butler's bid for SFP television production company.</p>
<p>-- Markets fret over Bank of France Monetary Policy Council meeting today as government hopes for new interest rate cut to stimulate growth and businesses foresee flat second half .</p>
<p>-- Credit Lyonnais denies management failed to provide timely swap cover for bailout financing package.</p>
<p>-- Paris Bourse down on the eve of Thursday Bundesbank meeting.</p>
<p>LA TRIBUNE DESFOSSES</p>
<p>-- German business climate picks up in July.</p>
<p>-- Bank of France would have great difficulty cutting interest rates alone today.</p>
<p>-- World Bank offers to back system of public naming of high-pollution companies.</p>
<p>LE FIGARO</p>
<p>-- Conseil d'Etat, France's highest administrative court, may rule on African hunger strikers today after Prime Minister Alain Juppe promises firm but humane enforcement of immigration laws.</p>
<p>LE FIGARO-ECONOMIE</p>
<p>-- Any German or French interest rate cuts today would be modest at best.</p>
<p>-- Concerted action is not the Bundesbank's strongest point.</p>
<p>LIBERATION</p>
<p>-- Juppe softens stand against Africans on hunger strike to renew or obtain work and residence rights.</p>
<p>THE INTERNATIONAL HERALD TRIBUNE</p>
<p>-- Africans will continue hunger strike despite Juppe's softened stance.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5381</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
