<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8491" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Paris ready to review expulsions, protest goes on. [corrected 08:43 gmt]</title>
<headline>Paris ready to review expulsions, protest goes on. [corrected 08:43 gmt]</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre said on Thursday he was ready to re-examine expulsion orders for African protesters but ten immigrants went into the 49th (Corrects from 48th) day of a protest fast bent on winning more concessions.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be no residence permits en masse, there will be no automatic right to stay but the government will study things on a case-by-case basis,&quot; Debre told RTL radio.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who have had their demands for (political) asylum rejected will not be granted permits. That is the law,&quot; he added, declining to put a number on how many of the 300 protesters occupying a Paris church would be allowed to stay.</p>
<p>An estimated 117 of the protesters are estimated to have been refused asylum, according to their spokesmen.</p>
<p>The hunger strikers, most of them of Malian nationality, have pledged to continue their fast, buoyed by government concessions and bent on winning residence permits for all of the 300. They have been drinking sweet tea and eating vitamin pills.</p>
<p>The government said on Wednesday it would seek the opinion of the highest administrative court after Prime Minister Alain Juppe cut short his holiday to chair a ministerial meeting and Debre met a spokesman for the protesters for the first time.</p>
<p>&quot;We respect the law but in its enforcement we try to have a humane attitude so that we can stretch out a hand to the worst cases,&quot; Debre said.</p>
<p>&quot;I have sympathy for those who are struggling and for those who are trying to have humanitarian aspects taken into consideration, but I also have sympathy for those who say the law must be respected,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The protesters say they are all entitled to stay. They say many of them enjoyed residence rights until they were plunged into ilegallity by 1993 laws tightening residence and citizenship regulations to drastically curb immigration.</p>
<p>The church, in the heavily immigrant Goutte d'Or district, Juppe's former constituency, is surrounded by hundreds of sympathisers, including media celebrities, determined to prevent any police bid to seize the protesters.</p>
<p>The first opinion poll on the dispute, published in the daily Le Parisien, said most French voters sympathised with the protesters but most opposed giving them all an automatic right to stay.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
