<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8492" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Finland - August 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Finland - August 22.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the leading stories in Finnish papers this morning.</p>
<p>HELSINGIN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Government to make decision whether to linking markka to ERM in near future, any further strengthening of markka not desirable, Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen said at social democratic party meeting in Kuopio.</p>
<p>- Government has completely failed in its main goal to halve unemployment, major opposition Centre Party said.</p>
<p>- Nordic ministers for foreign affairs condemn use of violence in Chechnya.  </p>
<p>- The army has started to talk about positive military discipline, but changing habits is slow, army researcher says.</p>
<p>- Estonian airport worker died as a Finnair engine propeller hit him in the head on Tallinn airport.</p>
<p>KAUPPALEHTI</p>
<p>- Profit on core operations in the banking sector to weaken this year, despite increasing demand for loans, Postipankki says.</p>
<p>- Import restrictions on alcohol, set in May, did not reduce travel to Tallinn from Finland, statistics show.  </p>
<p>- Sales at Siwa, Valintatalo and Euromarket supermarkets increased strongly in the first half of the year.</p>
<p>- Huhtamaki CEO Timo Peltola surprised by Chicago Tribune's continuous writing about Huhtamaki selling Leaf to Swiss company. Says the spreading of such rumours is annoying.</p>
<p>DEMARI</p>
<p>- Lake waters clearly warmer than usual this time of the year -- three to five degrees higher in almost whole country.</p>
<p>- Finns smoke about seven percent less than a year ago, survey shows. But youths smoke as much as earlier.  </p>
<p>HUFVUDSTADSBLADET</p>
<p>- UN Human Rights Controller in Bosnia, first runner-up in Finland's last presidential election, Euro MP Elisabeth Rehn says ready to reconsider candidacy for the European parliament elections if Swedish People's Party asks her to run.</p>
<p>-- Paivi Mattila, Helsinki Newsroom +358 - 0 - 680 50 292</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
