<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8494" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norske Skog sees weaker full year result.</title>
<headline>Norske Skog sees weaker full year result.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norway's biggest forestry company, Norske Skogindustrier ASA, on Thursday booked a first-half pre-tax profit of 1.04 billion crowns but expected second half results to be weaker because of changing market conditions.</p>
<p>The pre-tax profit rose from 857 million crowns in the same year-ago period. Operating revenue increased to 6.72 billion crowns from 5.86 billion and the operating result rose to 1.20 billion from 886 million crowns.</p>
<p>The company said the weakening of the markets for SC magazine paper and newsprint during the first half triggered price reductions in some countries for the second half year. Weaker markets for both products were expected in the second half, but the situation for LWC magazine paper had stabilised.</p>
<p>Building activity in western Europe was expected to continue to be low during the second half.</p>
<p>&quot;On the whole, we believe that the changed market conditions will contribute to a weaker result in the second half year,&quot; the company said in a statement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
