<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8495" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - August 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - August 22.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of stories in the Irish press on Thursday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>IRISH TIMES</p>
<p>- A large Japanese tuna-fishing vessel was standing off Irish fishery limits on Wednesday night following the Irish Naval Service's detention of one of its vessels about 180 miles off Galway Bay.  </p>
<p>- The Department of Enterprise and Employment's investigation into fund managers Taylor Asset Managers is expected to focus on the accounts handled by the company's founder and mananging director Tony Taylor.</p>
<p>- Irish building materials firm CRH refused to comment on newspaper reports that it was close to an agreement to acquire U.S. concrete and stone business Tilcon Inc.</p>
<p>- Anglo-Dutch consumer products group Unilever has extended its offer to shareholders in Lyons Irish Holdings but has not increased it beyond the original offer of 323p.  </p>
<p>- Persistent rumours that IRA money was behind the internet service provider Indigo forced the family which owned the company to sell it, a member of the family said.</p>
<p>IRISH INDEPENDENT -</p>
<p>- Talks are underway within the Irish third-level education system to create more college places for students next year.  </p>
<p>- The Irish Fraud Squad is unable to investigate the activities of Dublin-based company European Business Support Ltd which has been criticised by Irish small firms for the misleading nature of the service it offers in relation to obtaining European grant aid.</p>
<p>- Irish exploration company Invernia should hear on Thursday evening whether it has received planning permission for its proposed lead zinc mine at Lisheen, County Tipperary.</p>
<p>- Irish industrial development advisory board Forfas said 300,000 jobs could be created in the next 15 years with the correct policy framework.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
