<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8499" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: PRESS DIGEST - Netherlands - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Netherlands - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main stories in Dutch newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>HET FINANCIEELE DAGBLAD</p>
<p>- Shipbuilders Van der Giessen-De Noord and Wilton Fijenoord study feasibility of alliance and maybe merger. (p1)</p>
<p>- Transport group Nedlloyd books strong recovery in second quarter, mainly due to its ocean shipping division. (p1)</p>
<p>- Publisher VNU takes Internet firm to court over the use of its registered trade names. (p1)</p>
<p>- Re-sale of Fokker Aviation to receivers not yet on the cards, says industrial engineering concern Stork. (p1)</p>
<p>- Papermaker Gelderse Papier reports Dfl 3.9 milion net losses due to write down on stocks. (p3)</p>
<p>- Industrial plastics supplier Schuttersveld posts 12 percent higher first half net at Dfl 14.9 million. (p3)</p>
<p>- Bank Nederlanse Gemeenten BNG sees first six months results rise to 20 million guilders. (p3)</p>
<p>DE VOLKSKRANT</p>
<p>- Cabinet does not expect pensioners to contribute financing to sharply rising costs of OAP benefits. (p1)</p>
<p>- Harbour concern HES Beheer to start new restructuring at unit European Bulk Services EBS after loss in first half. (p2)</p>
<p>- Dutch central bank DNB in danger of losing some Dfl 100 million a year as a result of new electronic payments. (p2)</p>
<p>- Bus company Hermes wants to take over Dutch Railways NS' unprofitable lines in the south east of the Netherlands. (p3)</p>
<p>DE TELEGRAAF</p>
<p>- Antillean island Aruba accuses Dutch Navy and security forces of possible involvement in smuggling drugs. (p1)</p>
<p>- Cabinet opts to phase in excise rise on cigarettes. (p7)</p>
<p>- Brewer Bavaria books lower first half net. (p19)</p>
<p>TROUW</p>
<p>- Korea's Samsung, still interested buying Fokker, prefers cooperation between the aircraft maker and Sweden's Saab. (p7)</p>
<p>ALGEMEEN DAGBLAD</p>
<p>- Traffic minister to invest hundreds of millions of guilders extra in roads and public transport. (p1)</p>
<p>- Educational facilities in the Netherlands, important to compete internationally, are of a mediocre level - economic affairs ministry research. (p8)</p>
<p>-- Amsterdam Newsdesk +31-20-504-5000 (FAX 31-20-504-5040)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
