<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8505" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FEATURE - Nazi slaves set for compensation 50 years on.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Nazi slaves set for compensation 50 years on.</headline>
<byline>Fiona Fleck</byline>
<dateline>BREMEN, Germany 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sara E. and 24 other former Nazi slaves are on the verge of winning compensation awards from Germany that could pave the way for thousands more claims from Holocaust survivors around the world.</p>
<p>Sara, a Polish Jew, survived massacres at the Warsaw ghetto where she lost her entire family. She was taken to Auschwitz concentration camp in 1943 and survived the notorious &quot;selections&quot; when deportees were singled out to join an army of slaves.</p>
<p>The rest were sent to their deaths in the gas chambers. Sara was sold by the SS, who ran Adolf Hitler's concentration camps, to a German firm to work in its arms factory.</p>
<p>After half a century of uncertainty, Sara, now 73, living in Israel on a meagre pension and still scarred by her ordeal, looks closer than ever to remuneration after Germany's highest court ruled last month there was no legal barrier to her claim.</p>
<p>A court spokesman said the court would set a date for the next hearing when it convened for the autumn session in September.</p>
<p>&quot;I worked 12 hours a day at the conveyor belt assembling grenades -- even with typhus and a raging fever. We were woken at 3 a.m. every day and had to march two hours to the factory,&quot; Sara said in a statement to the Bonn court examining her claim.</p>
<p>&quot;At midday we had a bowl of watery soup for three women. In the evening each had a piece of bread and ersatz tea,&quot; said Sara, who escaped her Nazi tormentors on the notorious &quot;death marches&quot; as SS camp guards fled the advancing Red Army.</p>
<p>Hitler's armaments minister Albert Speer cited 11 million slaves in 1944 -- seven million in Germany -- toiling in his vast empire of camps and arms factories stretching across the Nazi-occupied lands from Norway to Algeria.</p>
<p>A year later at the Nuremberg war crimes trials Speer was prosecuted and sentenced to 20 years in jail for his use of slave labour.</p>
<p>&quot;Work conditions were appalling. They were starved and beaten by SS guards and few survived,&quot; said Baron Klaus von Muenchhausen, who has campaigned for the women for 10 years.</p>
<p>Muenchhausen, who lectures at Bremen University's Raphael Lemkin Institute for the study of xenophobia and genocide, said the Nazis used and sold more slaves during their 14-year rule than traders who enslaved 15 million Africans over 300 years.</p>
<p>&quot;The Nazis debated whether labour should be a tool of extermination -- whether their victims should be worked to death -- or whether they should be treated better so that they would not have to keep re-training new workers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;These women are old and frail and do not have the means to press for compensation. I met them in 1985 and they asked me to help them,&quot; said Muenchhausen, who found an anonymous German sponsor to pay the women's legal fees.</p>
<p>Muenchhausen campaigned successfully on behalf of about 100 twins used as human guinea pigs for gruesome medical experiments by the &quot;Angel of Death&quot; Nazi doctor Josef Mengele. The German government awarded them prompt compensation in 1987.</p>
<p>But compensation for ex-slaves seemed unattainable because of a legal anomaly.</p>
<p>&quot;The Nazis' forced labour workers have long been entitled to compensation but have been prevented from making successful claims because of the London Debt Agreement of 1953,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>One article of the agreement, under which then-West Germany took over Nazi Germany's debts, states that forced labour workers could not be paid compensation until Germany signed a formal peace treaty with its former foes.</p>
<p>But divided Germany never did during the Cold War, Muenchhausen said.</p>
<p>&quot;Individual claims failed in the past because of this, so we are suing the government for obstructing these rightful claims by not keeping its laws in order,&quot; he said, on behalf of the women now living in Israel, the United States and Canada.</p>
<p>Muenchhausen argued that Germany had effectively declared peace with the countries it occupied and with former enemies in two historic agreements signed in 1990: the German-Polish border accord and the so-called &quot;Two-Plus-Four&quot; treaty.</p>
<p>The treaty signed by the four wartime Allies and two Germanys paved the way for German unification. This, he said, meant that compensation claims could no longer be barred.</p>
<p>In 1993 a Bonn regional court accepted his arguments but sought advice from the Federal Constitutional Court, Germany's highest court, on whether state-to-individual as opposed to state-to-state compensation payments were lawful.</p>
<p>In June this year the Constitutional Court said there was no legal barrier to stop the Bonn court processing the claims.</p>
<p>&quot;The next stage is for the parties and the court to negotiate, then the court officials will discuss what to do next,&quot; the court spokesman said.</p>
<p>Many German firms used slave labour during the Third Reich. This ruling could pave the way for a flood of compensation claims.</p>
<p>IG Farben, which produced the Zyklon B gas for the death camps, paid 30 million marks ($20 million) in compensation to the Jewish Claims Conference in 1957.</p>
<p>The firm was broken up after the war and its plants transferred to Hoechst, Bayer and BASF, now Germany's three largest chemical firms. But neither those firms nor IG Farben accept responsibility for the suffering of about 350,000 slave workers or have ever paid individual compensation.</p>
<p>Campaigners in Germany have infiltrated shareholders' meetings by buying stock in the listed companies to pressure the management into paying up, so far without success.</p>
<p>The firms argue they had no choice but to use slave labour at the time because the civilian workforce was depleted by the war. They say that if anyone should pay, it is the German government as the legal successor to Hitler's Third Reich.</p>
<p>Muenchhausen said the German state paid Union, the firm that owned the arms factory where Sara worked, 2.5 million marks ($1.68 million) in damages for loss of property at the end of the war.</p>
<p>&quot;You have a totally unjust situation where the perpetrators were reimbursed for their losses, while the victims were left in the lurch,&quot; he said. &quot;I think this will count in our favour.&quot; ($1=1.4895 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BREMEN, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
