<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8506" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N. official to discuss arms inspections in Baghdad.</title>
<headline>U.N. official to discuss arms inspections in Baghdad.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.N. official in charge of dismantling Iraq's weapons of mass destruction leaves for Baghdad on Friday to discuss the disputed issue of unrestricted arms inspections.</p>
<p>Rolf Ekeus, head of the U.N. Special Commission, responsible for ridding Iraq of dangerous weapons, is expected to arrive in Baghdad on Sunday and to stay for about three days of talks with Tareq Aziz, the deputy prime minister, and other Iraqi officials.</p>
<p>Iraq for the past few months has balked at surprise inspections by arms experts searching for documents or other weapons-related materials, saying the U.N. teams were delving into sensitive national security sites the Special Commission had promised not to touch.</p>
<p>The Ekeus-Aziz meetings will be based on a June 22 agreement that called for periodic sessions on the weapons controversy.</p>
<p>Iraq said in the agreement it would allow unconditional and unrestricted entry to its sites. In return, the United Nations promised to operate &quot;with full respect for the legitimate security concerns of Iraq.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Since then we have tried to test the arrangements, and it has not been a happy experience,&quot; Ekeus said on Thursday.</p>
<p>U.N. officials said a minor inspection trip was banned by Iraqi authorities as late as last week.</p>
<p>Ridding Iraq of its nuclear, chemical, biological and ballistic missile arms potential is a key requirement for lifting stringent trade sanctions imposed after Baghdad's troops invaded Kuwait in August 1990. The Security Council also has given inspectors the right to conduct surprise searches.</p>
<p>The destruction of dangerous weapons was central to an April 1991 ceasefire resolution that ended the Gulf War.</p>
<p>Council members, in comments to the press late in July, deplored what they called unacceptable delays in inspections but postponed convening a formal meeting or issuing threats until Ekeus was ready for his next visit.</p>
<p>The 15-member body is expected to adopt a statement on the issue by Friday, although some envoys said it might not be as strong as the United States and Britain wished.</p>
<p>The blanket sanctions are separate from a deal that is expected to go into force next month, allowing Baghdad to sell $2 billion worth of petroleum over six months to buy badly needed food and medicine.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
