<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8512" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French interest rates cut with German help.</title>
<headline>French interest rates cut with German help.</headline>
<byline>Brian Love</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The French central bank seized on a surprise German interest rate reduction on Thursday to deliver aB cut in a key French interest rate longed for by the centre-right government as it tries to get the economy firing on all cylinders.</p>
<p>However, the road ahead still looks rocky for Prime Minister Alain Juppe as he puts the final touches to a 1997 budget which is crucial to qualify for European monetary union, while trying to rekindle public and business confidence at the same time.</p>
<p>Just as financial markets were getting increasingly jittery about the French currency and economy, the German central bank waded in with an unexpectedly large cut in the core repurchase rate, cutting it to 3.00 percent from 3.30 percent.</p>
<p>The first repo cut since February inspired financial markets and was followed within 30 minutes by the Bank of France with a cut in the intervention rate to 3.35 percent from 3.55 percent, powering the franc higher against the German currency.</p>
<p>Economists had all but ruled out a French rate cut after foreign exchange markets started leaning on the franc amid renewed worries over the economy in the run-up to the budget in mid-September and on speculation of a &quot;rift&quot; between the government and central bank governor Jean-Claude Trichet.</p>
<p>Debt and currency markets saluted the cuts in both countries and economists said the move let off the pressure on the franc.</p>
<p>But views of the impact for the French economy varied even if many believed interest rates would now at worst stay stable until the year-end.</p>
<p>&quot;This should be the end to the mini-crisis for the franc,&quot; said Philippe Brossard, economist at ABN-AMRO bank.</p>
<p>It was unlikely to be the last cut by German's central bank and although the scale of the French cut did not guarantee a boost in French growth in itself, it could boost confidence and thereby fuel consumption and business activity, he said.</p>
<p>Jean-Louis Maurier, economist at Louis Dreyfus Finance, said the Bundesbank had provided the Bank of France with &quot;a margin of manoeuvre&quot; but warned that other possible pitfalls lay ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;There could be more tension on the franc around budget time The franc weakness was not an interest rate story. It was about worries over the budget. That's why I think the Bank of France did not use all its room for manoeuvre at once,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The franc fell to 3.4280 against the mark on August 13, its lowest since the end of March.</p>
<p>Credit Lyonnais economist Valerie Asselot said the German cut, a big helping hand to the Bank of France, seemed primarily motivated by worries about mark strength against the dollar, and the effect this would have on German exports and growth.</p>
<p>Another economist at a big French bank said France looked like it now had a formidable ally in Germany if the franc came under attack again or their were doubts about monetary union.</p>
<p>&quot;Whoever wants to destroy monetary union will have to fight the Bundesbank first and that is a very powerful partner to have,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Thursday's move by France's independent central bank, the biggest since January, will be welcome news to President Jacques Chirac and Juppe, who have both called for further cuts to boost an economy which has yet to show signs of picking up steam.</p>
<p>Speculation of a rift between Chirac and Trichet had been partly blamed for dragging the currency down against the mark and made the liklihood of rate cuts more remote.</p>
<p>Juppe meets Chirac in the south of France this weekend to discuss the budget and spending curbs which he hopes will allow France meet the deficit criteria in the Maastricht treaty to qualify for monetary union while including tax cuts promised by the President.</p>
<p>But he also has to tread very carefully as unions, unhappy at the prospect of further austerity and the loss of 7,000 civil service jobs at a time of worsening unemployment, beat the drum and talk of protest around budget time.</p>
<p>Analysts are nevertheless cautious about whether the unions would be able to mobilise on the scale they did late last year when the country was crippled by transport and other strikes in the wake of the 1996 austerity plans being unveiled.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
