<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8518" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Maurice Saatchi in million stg campaign deal - paper.</title>
<headline>Maurice Saatchi in million stg campaign deal - paper.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Maurice Saatchi, the advertising executive who started a new agency last year after being ousted from the Saatchi &amp; Saatchi agency he founded and headed, will be paid more than one million stg for an advertising campaign for Britain's Conservative party in the upcoming general elections, the Daily Telegraph reported.</p>
<p>Saatchi has negotiated a percentage deal that links his fee to the amount spent on the election advertising campaign, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>The Daily Telegraph said details of the deal were mentioned in a footnote to a leaked memorandum of the Tory election campaign, which was passed to Labour's chief election planner, Peter Mandelson, last month.</p>
<p>The newspaper reported one source said the deal was for between 12 and 15 percent of the campaign cost. If the Tories achieve their planned 10 million stg fund for the election, Saatchi can exepct to receive at least 1.2 million pounds, the paper said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
