<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8520" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Lloyd's of London chief confident on recovery plan.</title>
<headline>Lloyd's of London chief confident on recovery plan.</headline>
<byline>Christopher Adams</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lloyd's of London chairman David Rowland said on Thursday he did not believe a crunch court case brought against the insurance market in the United States would block completion of the 300-year old institution's recovery plan.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters, he said many U.S. investors have already accepted the terms of the recovery proposals and added any injuction served against the insurance market by the judge in the critical Virginia case would be quickly appealed.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's extremely unlikely that the judge would wish to overrule the free choice that they have already made,&quot; said Rowland in a reference to the U.S. investors and of the basis on which Lloyd's made its contingency plans for such a legal challenge. Investors in Lloyds are known as &quot;Names'.</p>
<p>U.S. district judge Robert Payne earlier delayed until Friday his ruling on demands by 93 U.S. Names for an injunction halting the recovery plan, under which Lloyd's aims to reinsure billions of pounds of liabilities into a new company Equitas.</p>
<p>Thousands of Names worldwide are waiting anxiously for this decision, with less than a week until the August 28 deadline by which Lloyd's wants Names to accept or reject the recovery plan.</p>
<p>Lloyd's asked Names to help pay for Equitas, but offered them 3.2 billion sterling ($5 billion) to offset the cost and end litigation.</p>
<p>Rowland declined to reveal how many of the 2,700 Names in the U.S. and 33,500 worldwide have accepted. He said such figures meant little as success depended on &quot;yes&quot; votes from two key blocks: the litigating Names and those with outstanding debts needed by Lloyd's to fund Equitas.</p>
<p>But the level of acceptance among Names was well ahead of where Lloyd's expected it to be at this stage. &quot;We've got a lot of votes in and we are beginning to see a substantial majority of the members who wish to accept,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rowland said believed it was extremely likely Lloyd's would have the substantial majority needed to go ahead with the recovery proposals. He added it was possible after declaring the offer unconditional that Names who had not yet agreed would be given extra time in which to do so.</p>
<p>In the U.S., Payne has indicated that it is not his intention to stop Lloyd's recovery plan worldwide and he may be considering a compromise ruling.</p>
<p>Industry sources have suggested he could, for example, issue an order that funds be held in escrow and that the Names be allowed more time to accept or reject the plan.</p>
<p>Rowland was hopeful any injunction against Lloyd's could be appealed by Monday or Tuesday next week.</p>
<p>The Names in this case claim their contracts with Lloyd's violate U.S. disclosure laws, while Lloyd's contends that they are under their contract with the market bound to conduct legal action against it in Britain.</p>
<p>($1=.6458 Sterling)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
