<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8521" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian pyramid scheme bilks thousands of investors.</title>
<headline>Canadian pyramid scheme bilks thousands of investors.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A 35-year-old man has been charged with running a large-scale pyramid scheme that apparently took in as many as 10,000 investors in Ontario, British Columbia and Europe, police said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Iranian-born Mehrdad Alibabaie, 35, of Toronto was arrested Wednesday for allegedly running a scheme that police estimate bilked investors of more than C$50 million ($36 million), said Toronto Police detective sergeant Chris Hobson.</p>
<p>Alibabaie also faces charges of fraud, extortion and possession of a prohibited weapon.</p>
<p>Police said investors contributed anywhere from C$20 ($15) Canadian to C$2 million ($1.46 million) each to the scheme, which was dubbed &quot;System B&quot;, between May 1995 and August 1996.</p>
<p>The scheme promised investors high returns on their money, which organisers told recruits was placed in the international currency and commodity markets, provided they spent an amount equal to 2 percent of their investment at a grocery store chain owned by an associate of Alibabaie.</p>
<p>The system began to collapse this month. This prompted investors to contact police.</p>
<p>Police believe that the scheme was kept running by the continuing influx of new contributors, and that no money was actually invested in financial markets.</p>
<p>Investigations are ongoing and more arrests may follow.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
