<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8525" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Number of displaced workers fell in 1993-95 period.</title>
<headline>Number of displaced workers fell in 1993-95 period.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>American workers were less likely to be displaced between 1993 and 1995 than they were two years before and those who were were more likely to find new jobs quickly, the Labour Department said Thursday.</p>
<p>The number of workers who were at least 20 years old and lost jobs because of plant or company closings, insufficient work or elimination of their position or shift fell about 7 percent to 8.4 million in the latest period from 9 million in the 1991-93 period, the department said.</p>
<p>The decline in the displacement of long-term workers, defined as those who held their jobs at least three years, was an even sharper 16 percent to 3.8 million from 4.5 million, while the number of displaced short-term workers rose slightly to 4.6 million, it said.</p>
<p>But the biennial report, which has tracked the trend of permanent, involuntary worker displacement since 1984, also found that workers displaced during the latest three-year period had more luck in finding a job by time the survey was taken this February than those surveyed in February 1994.</p>
<p>The report said 71 percent of displaced workers were re-employed by Febraury, 16 percent were unemployed and the rest left the labour force. Two years earlier, only 67 percent were re-employed and 21 percent were unemployed.</p>
<p>&quot;While the decline in job dislocation is a positive trend, the report also confirms that some American workers who lose their jobs remain unemployed and, for those who do find jobs, many experience a drop in earnings,&quot; said White House economic adviser Joseph Stiglitz.</p>
<p>Of the long-term workers who had been displaced from full-time jobs and were re-employed again by February, fewer than half were earning as much as, or more than they did in their previous jobs and one-third earned at least 20 percent less, the report said.</p>
<p>Nearly 20 percent of re-employed workers became part-time, self-employed, or unpaid family workers, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;This report underscores the importance of increasing access to education and worker training and protecting dislocated workers' health and pension benefits to help ease job transitiions and reduce the costs of job loss to American workers,&quot; Stiglitz said.</p>
<p>Manufacturing workers made up the largest share of displaced workers with 29 percent and were among the least likely to be re-employed, the report said. The biggest declines in displacement included managerial, professional and skilled craft employees, it said.</p>
<p>Those most likely to be re-employed quickly were younger and working as technicians and in related support jobs, while older workers who had been machine operators, assemblers and inspectors were least likely to be re-employed, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
