<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8527" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mattel names Jill Barad as CEO.</title>
<headline>Mattel names Jill Barad as CEO.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mattel Inc. Thursday promoted President Jill Barad to the post of chief executive officer, effective Jan. 1.</p>
<p>In a statement, the world's largest toy maker said Barad as CEO will succeed John Amerman, who will remain chairman.</p>
<p>The move had been widely expected as Barad has assumed more responsibility for running the $2.6 billion company.</p>
<p>&quot;Jill Barad has contributed so much to our success during her 15 years with Mattel, and particularly during the four years she has served as my partner in running this company,&quot; Amerman said in a statement.</p>
<p>Barad was named president and chief operating officer in 1992. She joined Mattel in 1981 as a product manager and was named marketing director for the Barbie Doll brand in 1982.</p>
<p>&quot;She has proven herself to be an excellent leader, marketer and manager. I have total confidence in Jill and know she will be an outstanding CEO,&quot; Amerman said.</p>
<p>Barad's appointment comes as Mattel is shuffling its executive ranks. Earlier this month Mattel named Sony Corp. executive Bruce Stein as president of Mattel Worldwide as part of a realignment of top managers reporting to Barad.</p>
<p>Separately, Mattel named Ned Mansour, president-corporate operations, and Stein to its board, which now has 13 members.</p>
<p>Other members of the top management team reporting to Barad are Byron Davis, president of Fisher-Price, Joseph Gandolfo, president-worldwide manufacturing operations, and Francesca Luzuriaga, chief financial officer.</p>
<p>For the 1996 second quarter Mattel reported net income of $66.3 million on revenues of $777.4 million, versus earnings of $67.5 million on revenues of $763.5 million a year earlier.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
