<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8529" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar surges to 5-week high after German rate cut.</title>
<headline>Dollar surges to 5-week high after German rate cut.</headline>
<byline>Donna Sells</byline>
<text>
<p>NEW YORK, Aug 22 - The dollar surged to a five-week high against the mark Thursday after Germany's central bank stunned currency traders by aggressively cutting a key interest rate, triggering a round of rate cuts in Europe.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank's policy-setting council cut its securities repurchase rate, or repo rate, to 3 percent from 3.30 percent. The central bank left its discount and Lombard rates -- the floor and ceiling for German money market rates -- at 2.50 percent and 4.50 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer said a slowdown in German money supply growth and low inflation had allowed the central bank to cut its main money market rate.</p>
<p>Lower rates typically hurt the mark by making deposits denominated in the currency less attractive.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, a repo cut was expected, but the size was completely unexpected,&quot; said Ben Strauss, assistant vice president at Bank Julius Baer &amp; Co.</p>
<p>&quot;To get 30 basis points on the repo was I guess a pleasant surprise for people that were (positioned) the right way,&quot; said Dennis Pettit, foreign exchange manager at Long Term Credit Bank of Japan in New York. There are 100 basis points in a percentage point.</p>
<p>After the Bundesbank move, the dollar jumped and continued climbing to 1.4964 marks, its highest level since July 16. But the rally ran out of steam as some investors took advantage of the move by selling dollars to book profits.</p>
<p>&quot;It moved a good strong pfennig,&quot; said Diego Giurleo, vice president of the Treasury Department at Royal Bank of Canada in New York. &quot;They bought the dollar (but the rally) lost momentum above 1.4950.&quot; There are 100 pfennigs to the mark.</p>
<p>Late in New York, the dollar settled at 1.4920 marks, up from 1.4825 marks late on Wednesday. The dollar fell to 108.20 Japanese yen from 108.45 yen.</p>
<p>The mark's losses were broad-based as the currency also lost ground to the French franc, Italian lira, British pound, Spanish peseta and the yen.</p>
<p>While currency traders applauded the Bundesbank's cut, concern about where German interest rates were headed from here may have helped limit the dollar's gains against the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm just surprised that it didn't move over 1.50 (marks) because that's a very strong move by the Bundesbank,&quot; said Tom Benfer, director of foreign exchange at Bank of Montreal in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market is now trying to grapple with the notion -- is this the last move of the Bundesbank or could there be further cuts in the future?&quot;</p>
<p>Other European central banks cut rates after the Bundesbank, including banks in France, Austria, Belgium and the Netherlands.</p>
<p>While the Swiss National Bank left its discount rate unchanged, it pumped liquidity into the Swiss money market in an effort to relieve upward pressure on money market rates.</p>
<p>The dollar rose to 1.2074 Swiss francs from 1.2005 francs. The British pound ended unchanged at $1.5506. The dollar fell to Canadian $1.3697 from C$1.3740.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
