<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8533" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-THREE SHARE FIRST-ROUND LEAD AT WORLD SERIES OF GOLF.</title>
<headline>GOLF-THREE SHARE FIRST-ROUND LEAD AT WORLD SERIES OF GOLF.</headline>
<dateline>AKRON, Ohio 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>On a day when only six golfers broke par, Billy Mayfair, Paul Goydos and Japan's Hidemichi Tanaki shared the first-round lead at the World Series of Golf after shooting four-under-par 66 Thursday.</p>
<p>Two strokes back at Firestone C.C. was Steve Stricker, a two-time winner this year. Another stroke back after shooting one-under 69 were PGA Champion Mark Brooks and Justin Leonard.</p>
<p>The World Series is a limited-field event, with 43 golfers earning invitations by winning tournaments in America and on the world's other major tours over the past 12 months.</p>
<p>Mayfair, who lost this tournament in a playoff with Greg Norman last year and who qualified this time by winning the Tour Championship 10 months age, had a bogey-free round.</p>
<p>He picked up his four birdies on the back nine, three in the last four holes.</p>
<p>&quot;I seem to come here and just start playing well, maybe because I like being here,&quot; said Mayfair. &quot;It's an honour to be here.&quot;</p>
<p>Goydos had six birdies and two bogeys, and was the last player to finish before a one-hour lightning delay.</p>
<p>For most players the rough that surrounds Firestone's narrow fairways produces bogeys or hard-won pars, but Goydos made two birdies out of the rough.</p>
<p>&quot;The key was that when I was in the rough, I drew pretty good lies,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Goydos earned a place here by winning the Bay Hill Invitational in March when he was part of a springtime streak of first-time winners.</p>
<p>Because Goydos had been fairly obscure before that win and has played unimpressively since then, he says that people have forgotten that he is a winner.</p>
<p>&quot;In the last couple of weeks 10 or 15 of the guys have asked me if I'm playing in Vancouver,&quot; said Goydos, referring to the Greater Vancouver Open, the PGA Tour event which is also being staged this week.</p>
<p>Tanaka, 25, the rookie of the year in Japan last year, is playing in just his third American event though he played well at the recent British Open, shootng a first-round 67 at Royal Lytham which put him in second place.</p>
<p>Tanaka held the lead on his own at five under par after birdieing the first three holes and then the 11th and 12th holes. His only bogey came on the 18th when he three-putted from 30 feet, missing a three-foot putt which would have left him sole leader.</p>
<p>A slight figure at just 5 feet 6 inches (1.68 metres) and 128 pounds (58 kg), Tanaka can hit drives that are John Daly-esqe. On the 464-yard final hole, Tanaka drove his tee shot some 350 yards, leaving himself just a 110-yard wedge shot to the green.</p>
<p>Tanaka said through a translator that his goal was to play in America, but added that he felt he needed to learn to speak English before he came over here full time. Asked what English words he knew, Tanaka replied: &quot;McDonald's.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AKRON, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
