<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8535" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: GOLF-BROADHURST LEADS GERMAN OPEN AFTER COURSE RECORD 62.</title>
<headline>GOLF-BROADHURST LEADS GERMAN OPEN AFTER COURSE RECORD 62.</headline>
<dateline>STUTTGART, Germany 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paul Broadhurst shot a 62 as several players tore the Nippenburg course apart in the first round of the German Open on Thursday.</p>
<p>His nine-under-par course record left him just one shot clear of fellow Briton Raymond Russell and two ahead of a group of seven players headed by course designer Bernhard Langer.</p>
<p>Broadhurst said of the course: &quot;The fairways are generous, there is little rough and the greens are soft and holding. It won't surprise me if someone breaks 60 this week.&quot;</p>
<p>Of the 156-strong field, 94 broke 70, 112 beat the par of 71 and 128 played to par or better.</p>
<p>Broadhurst, starting at the 10th, broke Gary Orr's year-old record of 63 with a near-faultless round of 31 out and 31 in, with nine birdies and no bogeys.</p>
<p>But he admitted he was very fortunate at the 15th hole, his sixth, where he drove into a bunker, played &quot;a terrible shot&quot; out of the sand and then holed out from 70 yards with his sand-iron for a birdie three.</p>
<p>Had he not three-putted the 13th from 60 feet, he would have had the best round on the European Tour this year.</p>
<p>However, he was well pleased with his lowest round in a Tour event.</p>
<p>Russell's 63 was his lowest round as a professional. He shot seven birdies and an eagle three at the 560-yard fourth hole. His only bogey came at the 10th where he three-putted from 35 feet.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STUTTGART, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
