<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8537" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: ATHLETICS-KOMEN TAKES ON MORCELI OVER 3,000 METRES.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-KOMEN TAKES ON MORCELI OVER 3,000 METRES.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Daniel Komen, the second fastest man over 3,000 metres, takes on Algerian Noureddine Morceli at the Brussels grand prix on Friday in a race which may well produce a world best.</p>
<p>The 20-year-old Kenyan failed to qualify for the Atlanta Olympics but has been in devastating form since on the grand prix circuit.</p>
<p>After running the second fastest 3,000 metres in history in Monaco on August 10, Komen clocked the second fastest 5,000 metres at last week's Zurich grand prix.</p>
<p>He now meets Olympic and world 1,500 metres champion Morceli who set the current 3,000 mark of seven minutes 25.11 seconds in Monaco two years ago.</p>
<p>Michael Johnson makes his first appearance at a major European meeting since he achieved an historic 200-400 metres double at the Atlanta Games.</p>
<p>A one-lap race has been added to the programme for the Texan who commands one of the biggest appearance fees in the sport.</p>
<p>But meeting sources denied reports that Johnson was now able to demand $100,000 after Atlanta. He will be paid around $75,000, the fee top athletes are guaranteed in Zurich.</p>
<p>Johnson injured a hamstring after smashing the world 200 metres record in Atlanta but said he was now back to peak form.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm in good shape now,&quot; he said on Thursday. &quot;I am looking forward to a good race.&quot;</p>
<p>He also dismissed suggestions that he might concentrate on the 100 metres in the run-up to next year's world championships.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not a depressed 100 runner who does the 200 and 400 because he isn't good enough,&quot; Johnson said. &quot;I run the 200 and 400 and I'm happy to carry on doing that.&quot;</p>
<p>Another record could go in the women's 1,000 metres where Russian Svetlana Masterkova, the Olympic 800 and 1,500 metres champion who broke the women's mile world record in Zurich, takes on Mozambique's former world champion Maria Mutola.</p>
<p>The men's 100 metres boasts each of the Olympic gold medallists from the last four Games -- Carl Lewis (1984 and 1988), Linford Christie (1992) and Canada's current champion Donovan Bailey.</p>
<p>Christie will be making his final appearance at a major grand prix outside Britain before retiring. Organisers confirmed on Thursday evening that he had recovered from a knee injury.</p>
<p>Atlanta bronze medallist Ato Boldon and American champion Dennis Mitchell are also in the field.</p>
<p>Namibia's silver medallist Frankie Fredericks will run the 200 metres where he is one of seven athletes still in contention for the Golden Four jackpot of 20 one-kilo gold bars, worth around $250,000.</p>
<p>Athletes winning specific events at all four meetings in the series in Oslo, Zurich, Brussels and Berlin can win the prize. The competition will be decided at next week's final meeting in the German capital.</p>
<p>The other athletes involved are Jamaican sprinter Merlene Ottey (100 metres), Denmark's Wilson Kipketer (800 metres), American Derrick Adkins (400 hurdles), Britain's Jonathan Edwards (triple jump), Germany's Lars Riedel (discus), and Bulgarian high jumper Stefka Kostadinova.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
