<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8538" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: HORSE RACING-PIVOTAL ENDS 25-YEAR WAIT FOR TRAINER PRESCOTT.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-PIVOTAL ENDS 25-YEAR WAIT FOR TRAINER PRESCOTT.</headline>
<dateline>YORK, England 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sir Mark Prescott landed his first group one victory in 25 years as a trainer when his top sprinter Pivotal, a 100-30 chance, won the Nunthorpe Stakes on Thursday.</p>
<p>The three-year-old, partnered by veteran George Duffield, snatched a short head verdict in the last stride to deny Eveningperformance (16-1), trained by Henry Candy and ridden by Chris Rutter.</p>
<p>Hever Golf Rose (11-4), last year's Prix de l' Abbaye winner at Longchamp, finished third, a further one and a quarter lengths away with the 7-4 favourite Mind Games in fourth.</p>
<p>Pivotal, a Royal Ascot winner in June, may now be aimed at this season's Abbaye, Europe's top sprint race.</p>
<p>Prescott, reluctant to go into the winner's enclosure until the result of the photo-finish was announced, said: &quot;Twenty-five years and I have never been there so I thought I had better wait a bit longer.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;It's very sad to beat Henry Candy because I am godfather to his daughter.&quot;</p>
<p>Like Prescott, Jack Berry, trainer of Mind Games, had gone into Thursday's race in search of a first group one success after many years around the top of his profession.</p>
<p>Berry said: &quot;I`m disappointed but I don't feel suicidal. He (Mind Games) was going as well as any of them one and a half furlongs (300 metres) out but he just didn't quicken.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="YORK, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
