<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8540" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: RALLYING-FINNISH PAIR SHOULD REVEL ON HOME TRACKS.</title>
<headline>RALLYING-FINNISH PAIR SHOULD REVEL ON HOME TRACKS.</headline>
<dateline>JYVASKYLA, Finland 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>World championship leader Tommi Makinen and fellow Finn Juha Kankkunen start the 1,000 Lakes Rally on Friday with a huge home advantage.</p>
<p>The route has been heavily revised since the big-name drivers last contested the world championship event in 1994 and new restrictions on practice have made local knowledge of the uniquely demanding terrain a key factor.</p>
<p>As rivals fretted, Makinen confidently declared: &quot;No problem.&quot;</p>
<p>Jumps taken at speeds of 120 kph and the constant twists and turns of the unsurfaced forest roads means that car control and precise lines are vital. A momentary lack of concentration can spell disaster.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very difficult to describe the roads with pace notes. You have to know it by heart,&quot; explained Ford number two Bruno Thiry of Belgium.</p>
<p>His Spanish team mate Carlos Sainz, second in the world championship, added: &quot;The main problem is knowledge. Some stages I know, some we just have to learn. The objective is to be in the top three.&quot;</p>
<p>Even Britain's world champion Colin McRae, who has tackled the 1,000 Lakes only once previously, does not rate his chances.</p>
<p>The loss of a day's preparation on Tuesday when he was fined $250,000 -- most of it suspended -- by an International Automobile Federation tribunal in Paris after colliding with spectators in last month's Argentine Rally, did not help.</p>
<p>&quot;I've practised everything one or two times less than everyone else -- and Finland is the most important rally in the championship to have practised,&quot; the Subaru driver said.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi driver Makinen's confidence is high as he aims to become only the fourth driver to complete the 1,000 Lakes hat-trick.</p>
<p>But Kankkunen, four times world champion, is expected to run him close in his Toyota.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JYVASKYLA, Finland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
