<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8541" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: MOTOR RACING - HILL UNDER PRESSURE AS VILLENEUVE THREATENS.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING - HILL UNDER PRESSURE AS VILLENEUVE THREATENS.</headline>
<byline>Tim Collings</byline>
<dateline>SPA-FRANCORCHAMPS, Belgium 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Damon Hill goes into Sunday's Belgian Grand Prix knowing a single mistake could bring Canadian Jacques Villeneuve right back into the drivers' title race.</p>
<p>The Briton has a 17-point lead over his Williams team mate -- the only man who can deprive him of his first world championship success -- and a win would take him to within touching distance of the title.</p>
<p>But if Hill fails to finish in the top six on the majestic Spa-Francorchamps circuit, and Villeneuve wins, the gap between the two will be just seven points with three races remaining.</p>
<p>The Canadian pipped Hill on the line in Hungary a fortnight ago, and the Williams team has said it will allow the two drivers to slug it out for the title without interference.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a pretty interesting situation, very competitive and tight, but I am still looking forward to the race,&quot; Hill said. &quot;I have a good idea of what I need to do to win the race and go on to take the title.&quot;</p>
<p>Hill won at the 6.97-km track -- the longest on the Grand Prix calendar -- in both 1993 and 1994, and relishes its combination of sweeping corners and straights through the undulating forest of the Ardennes.</p>
<p>&quot;It is wide, open and fast and now we have the Eau Rouge corner back it is great for all of us,&quot; he said. &quot;This is one of the most challenging corners in Formula One and it is a spectacular experience.</p>
<p>&quot;I thoroughly enjoy the circuit as you feel you can drive the car to its full potential.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition to his two victories in Belgium, Hill came second last year when double world champion Michael Schumacher of Germany drove an inspired race to win from 16th on the grid.</p>
<p>This year Schumacher has been hampered by his Ferrari team's chronic reliability problems, but the introduction of a seven-speed gearbox could boost his performance here.</p>
<p>Villeneuve has the disadvantage of never having driven the circuit, although this did not stop him winning the European and Hungarian Grands Prix.</p>
<p>&quot;From what I have seen and heard it is a bit like Suzuka, (in Japan) with a lot of high-speed ballsy corners,&quot; said the Canadian, dubbed `the Greta Garbo of the pit lane' because he shuns publicity.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know if I am going to be competitive. It's a tough track to learn but I know I am going to enjoy it and if, on top of that, I can learn it quickly it will be good.&quot;</p>
<p>The race takes place over 44 laps on Sunday afternoon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SPA-FRANCORCHAMPS, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
