<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8542" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-SANCHEZ VICARIO WINS DESPITE UPSET STOMACH.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-SANCHEZ VICARIO WINS DESPITE UPSET STOMACH.</headline>
<dateline>CARLSBAD, California 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spaniard Arantxa Sanchez Vicario overcame Naoko Kijimuta's upset bid and an upset stomach Wednesday to move into the quarter-finals of the $450,000 Toshiba Tennis Classic.</p>
<p>Sanchez Vicario, the top seed, beat the little-known Japanese 1-6 6-4 6-3 despite vomiting after being drubbed in the first set.</p>
<p>Fourth seed Kimiko Date beat Japanese Fed Cup teammate Yone Kamio 6-2 7-5, but compatriot and seventh seed Ai Sugiyama squandered a 4-1 lead before bowing to France's Sandrine Testud 6-3 4-6 6-4.</p>
<p>&quot;I was not feeling very well, I was having trouble with my stomach,&quot; said Sanchez Vicario. &quot;Maybe it was something I ate. I felt nauseous so I threw up. It was weird because it never happened to me before.&quot;</p>
<p>Kijimuta, ranked 53rd in the world, pushed the second-ranked Sanchez Vicario all over the court in dominating the opening set with pinpoint groundstrokes.</p>
<p>&quot;She played really well the first set,&quot; said Sanchez Vicario. &quot;I don't think she missed many shots. She was taking the ball really early and I was hitting the ball short. It took me a while to get used to the court.&quot;</p>
<p>Sanchez Vicario regrouped, however, and took the next set -- but not before Kijimuta erased a 3-0 lead to level it at 4-4. The Spaniard got the decisive break in the ninth game before holding serve.</p>
<p>&quot;After winning the second set, I got more confidence,&quot; said Sanchez Vicario, the French Open, Wimbledon and Olympic runner-up. &quot;I began to hit the ball deeper and not miss so many easy shots.&quot;</p>
<p>The feisty Spaniard traded breaks with Kijimuta in the first two games of the decisive set before running to a 5-1 lead. Kijimuta won the next two games before Sanchez Vicario sealed the win with her sixth break of the match.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a very good match for me,&quot; Sanchez Vicario said of the one hour, 50 minute tussle. &quot;It's good for me to have a tough match in the beginning.</p>
<p>Date sailed through her first set after racing out to a 5-0 lead on Kamio's many mistakes. But the tide briefly turned in the second set as the world's eighth-ranked player gave Kamio a 3-0 advantage.</p>
<p>Date levelled the score at 5-5 as each traded services breaks in the ninth and 10th games. Kamio drilled a forehand long on game point in the next game to give the decisive break to Date, who then served out the match.</p>
<p>Sugiyama, Date's other Fed Cup teammate, couldn't stand prosperity after amassing the big 4-1 lead, and Testud ran off the next five games en route to her three-set victory.</p>
<p>&quot;I had a chance to win but my mental state was too weak today,&quot; Sugiyama said. &quot;I didn't have the guts to play well.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARLSBAD, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
