<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8545" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-CHANG ADVANCES AT HAMLET CUP.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-CHANG ADVANCES AT HAMLET CUP.</headline>
<dateline>COMMACK, New York 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Overcoming some early erratic play, top-seeded Michael Chang defeated unseeded Sergi Bruguera of Spain 6-3 6-2 in the Waldbaum Hamlet Cup tennis tournament on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Chang, ranked third in the world, increased his summer hardcourt record to 16-1 with this win over Bruguera who is ranked 71st.</p>
<p>The duel between two former French Open champions found Chang fighting off four break points in a 14-point service game to start the match.</p>
<p>But after the two exchanged service breaks, Chang put things together and won the last two games of the first set with the loss of only one point, then won the last five games of the match.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a good match for me with the U.S. Open next week, though I didn't serve well and was inconsistent with my ground strokes,&quot; Chang said. &quot;But now I will refine these things.&quot;</p>
<p>Chang also said he was surprised to be seeded second for the U.S. Open and surprised that other players were not seeded according to their rankings.</p>
<p>&quot;Wimbledon has been the only tournament not to seed accoding to the computor rankings,&quot; he said. &quot;I'm a little surprised. I don't know why they did it.</p>
<p>&quot;It probably has upset some people.&quot;</p>
<p>Michael Joyce upset third-seeded Richey Reneberg 3-6 6-4 6-3 in an all-American second-rounder.</p>
<p>The victory, putting Joyce in the quarter-finals, was built around a steady service as Joyce, a former U.S. junior champion, rallied from 0-2 in the second set, hitting nine aces at crucial moments.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt sluggish at the start of the match and decided to rely more on my serve than try to move around the court,&quot; Joyce said. &quot;I made a conscious effort to get the first serve in, rather than go for speed.</p>
<p>&quot;It was good to win a match like this after having had trouble with elbow tendinitis this summer. I have a lot of my confidence back.&quot;</p>
<p>Czech Martin Damm also advanced to the quarter-finals, along with Karol Kucera of Slovakia.</p>
<p>Damm, unseeded, was leading sixth-seeded Younes El Aynaoui of Morocco, 5-7 6-3 3-0 when El Aynaoui retired with a recurence of a right foot injury. It was the fifth time he has retired in a match this year.</p>
<p>Kucera eliminated another Moroccan, Hicham Arazi, 7-6 (7-4) 7-5 in a match between unseeded players. Kucera won the last three points of the first-set tiebreaker with two of his eight aces and a volley placement. He then broke service on his third match point of the final game.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COMMACK, New York"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
