<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8547" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-COUNTY TITLE-CHASERS UPSET BY WEATHER AND GOOD BATTING.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-COUNTY TITLE-CHASERS UPSET BY WEATHER AND GOOD BATTING.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Good batting and bad weather frustrated Surrey and Kent on Thursday as they looked to keep up the pressure on English county championship leaders Derbyshire.</p>
<p>Third-placed Surrey -- desperate to take full advantage of their game in hand -- struggled to make an impact against Nottinghamshire at Trent Bridge.</p>
<p>Surrey found themselves on the receiving end of centuries from recalled batsmen Graeme Archer and Matthew Dowman, who led Nottinghamshire to 392 for six at the close.</p>
<p>Dowman was in sparkling form, striking 15 fours in his 141-minute innings of 107, while Archer remained unbeaten at the close on 143.</p>
<p>Second-placed Kent had their progress halted by heavy rain that restricted the first day of their match against Glamorgan in Cardiff to 42.5 overs.</p>
<p>They had reached 128 for one when the second interruption shortly after lunch sent the players off the field.</p>
<p>Matthew Walker (59) and David Fulton (53 not out) put together an opening partnership of 122 to build the foundation for a big first-innings total.</p>
<p>Fifth-placed Essex made the best start of all the title chasers thanks to a hat-trick from Ashley Cowan against Gloucestershire at Colchester.</p>
<p>The 21-year-old fast bowler removed Richard Davis with the last ball of his 14th over and then dismissed Martyn Ball and Andy Smith with the first two deliveries of his 15th over on his way to career-best figures of five for 68.</p>
<p>Cowan's inspired spell reduced Gloucestershire to 280 all out, with dropped England wicketkeeper Jack Russell top scoring with 63.</p>
<p>By the close Essex, seeking their fifth successive victory, were 72 without loss.</p>
<p>Yorkshire made solid progress on the opening day of the their clash with Lancashire at Headingley, reaching 305 for five by the close.</p>
<p>Michael Vaughan (57) and Martyn Moxon (66) put on 110 for the first wicket before former Yorkshire spinner Gary Keedy brought Lancashire back into the match by taking both their wickets.</p>
<p>Paceman Richard Green also bagged two quicket wickets to reduce Yorkshire to 187 for four, before Richard Kettleborough (34) and Craig White (66 not out) steadied the innings.</p>
<p>West Indies batsman Phil Simmons hit 108 and Paul Nixon an unbeaten 67 to steer Leicestershire to 343 for eight against Hampshire at Grace Road.</p>
<p>Neil Lenham celebrated his return from injury with a magnificent 145 for Sussex against second-from-bottom Northamptonshire at Northampton. Lenham hit 22 fours in his 226-ball knock in Sussex's 368 for seven.</p>
<p>An unbroken last-wicket stand of 86 between Ashley Giles and Tim Munton rescued Warwickshire's first innings against Worcestershire. Giles' unbeaten 57 took Warwickshire from 169 to 255 for nine.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
