<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8551" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-CRAWLEY CREEPS TOWARDS MAIDEN TEST CENTURY.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-CRAWLEY CREEPS TOWARDS MAIDEN TEST CENTURY.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kitson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>John Crawley's highest test score kept Pakistan at bay on Thursday as England reached 278 for six on the first day of the decisive third test at the Oval.</p>
<p>Crawley was unbeaten on 94 at the close after almost four hours of measured strokeplay, keeping alive the home side's chances of a big first innings total in a match they must win to square the best-of-three series.</p>
<p>The 24-year-old Lancashire batsman, whose previous best in 12 tests was 72 against Australia in Sydney in 1994, blossomed after a shaky start and enjoyed a splendid fourth-wicket stand of 89 with Graham Thorpe to lift England to 205 for three at one point in the afternoon.</p>
<p>It took a determined effort from the Pakistan attack to apply the brakes in fast-scoring conditions and the final session yielded a modest 70 runs as Crawley opted to dig in rather than accelerate towards a maiden test century.  </p>
<p>Crawley's first 10 balls scarcely hinted at a great innings to come. He might have been out lbw, caught at slip and bowled without playing a shot as Waqar Younis, who had already removed Michael Atherton and Nasser Hussain, strove for another victim.</p>
<p>But Crawley, who attended the same school as Atherton and has long been regarded as a test prospect of similar class, settled down impressively with Thorpe, playing leg-spinner Mushtaq Ahmed with an ease most of his team-mates struggled to match.</p>
<p>Three times in the same over the leg-spinner was struck clinically through the off-side and the Lancashire man's 50 required 19 fewer deliveries than Thorpe's 89-ball effort.</p>
<p>But to England's dismay, Thorpe, who has now passed 50 on 20 occasions for England yet scored only two centuries, was adjudged lbw for 54 to seamer Mohammad Akram, to become the third player guilty of wasting a good start.</p>
<p>Alec Stewart best summed up his side's slightly uneven day, hitting nine fours in a fluent 44 only to be bowled hitting across the line at a quicker ball from Mushtaq.</p>
<p>Hussain went for 12, steering Waqar to second slip, and England were in danger of squandering a good toss when the paceman bowled Atherton behind his legs for 31 with the score on 116.</p>
<p>It was a brave effort considering Atherton was struck a painful blow on the right shoulder in only the third over by Wasim Akram, who also had his rival captain dropped at leg slip when on 15.</p>
<p>The final session honours, though, were mostly Pakistan's after Nick Knight, who hoisted Mushtaq for a six over mid-wicket, was bowled by the same bowler off his pad and arm for 17.</p>
<p>The old ball belatedly began to swing for the faster bowlers and Wasim, who took nine for 103 in the match when Pakistan clinched a 2-1 series victory on their last visit to The Oval in 1992, surged back to remove Chris Lewis for five.</p>
<p>England, who unexpectedly omitted Andy Caddick to include two spinners, negotiated one over with the new ball before the close but will need the tail to give Crawley, who has faced 200 balls and hit 10 fours so far, solid support if they are to build a match-winning total.</p>
<p>Only one side -- England in 1994 against South Africa -- has come back from 1-0 to square a three-test series in Britain since 1965.</p>
<p>In England's favour, though, is an unsettled weather forecast and illness to Salim Malik who spent a long time off the field with a high temperature and a sore throat.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
