<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8553" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-CRAWLEY, THORPE LIFT ENGLAND WITH HALF-CENTURIES.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-CRAWLEY, THORPE LIFT ENGLAND WITH HALF-CENTURIES.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kitson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Middle-order batsmen John Crawley and Graham Thorpe carried the attack to Pakistan on Thursday to hoist England to 218 for four at tea on the first day of the final test at The Oval.</p>
<p>Both Crawley and Thorpe took advantage of fast-scoring conditions to register excellent half-centuries and prevent the home side from wasting a good start after winning the toss.</p>
<p>All the Pakistan bowlers extracted some bounce from a hard, dry pitch, but were forced on the defensive after Waqar Younis bowled captain Michael Atherton around his legs for 31 to leave England wobbling on 116 for three.</p>
<p>Thorpe was finally trapped lbw for 54 by Mohammad Akram with tea fast approaching, but Crawley was unbeaten on 58 at the interval, having reached his 50 in 70 balls with six fours.</p>
<p>The pattern for the first two sessions was set by Alec Stewart who raced fluently to 44 in just 51 balls only to be bowled playing an ill-advised shot to a quicker ball from leg- spinner Mushtaq Ahmed.</p>
<p>Nasser Hussain went for 12, steering Waqar to second slip, and England looked in danger of squandering the initiative when Atherton's gritty innings ended with only 16 runs added after lunch.</p>
<p>It was a brave effort considering he was struck a painful blow on the right shoulder in only the third over by Wasim Akram, although he did survive a hard chance to leg slip when he had made 15.</p>
<p>Crawley made a sketchy start and might have been out lbw, caught at slip and bowled offering no shot during his first 10 balls against the unlucky Waqar.</p>
<p>But he soon settled down to share an impressive fourth-wicket stand of 89 with Graham Thorpe, growing sufficiently in confidence to hit Mushtaq for three off-side boundaries in the same over.</p>
<p>But the leg-spinner gained enough turn to suggest Pakistan may yet regret omitting teenage off-spinner Saqlain Mushtaq in favour of an extra batsman if forecasted rain over the weekend does not arrive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
