<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8555" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-HODDLE NAMES BECKHAM, LE TISSIER IN FIRST SQUAD.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-HODDLE NAMES BECKHAM, LE TISSIER IN FIRST SQUAD.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Manchester United's David Beckham received his first England call-up and Southampton's wayward maestro Matthew Le Tissier was recalled as new manager Glenn Hoddle named his first squad on Thursday.</p>
<p>The two creative midfielders are included in the 22-strong party to face Moldova on September 1 in England's first qualifier for the 1998 World Cup.</p>
<p>With the experienced Arsenal players David Platt and Tony Adams both injured, Hoddle also recalled Newcastle's combative midfielder David Batty and Manchester United defender Gary Pallister.</p>
<p>Blackburn goalkeeper Tim Flowers loses his place to Liverpool's David James, while Manchester United youngster Phil Neville and Liverpool's Jamie Redknapp miss out through injury.  </p>
<p>The inclusion of Beckham and Le Tissier provides the clearest signal yet Hoddle wants his England side to play with invention as well as aggression.</p>
<p>Beckham has made an outstanding start to the league season and scored a spectacular goal from inside his own half for United against Wimbledon last Saturday.</p>
<p>He was also at the centre of the United team that demolished premier league rivals Newcastle in the Charity Shield at Wembley the previous weekend.</p>
<p>Le Tissier, who plays the same creative midfield role at Southampton as Hoddle used to play at Tottenham in the 1980s, returns after only six previous England appearances, four as substitute.</p>
<p>He never established a regular place in the side under Terry Venables, but has been widely tipped for a leading role under Hoddle, who took over after the European championship in June.</p>
<p>Brilliant on his day, Le Tissier has often been criticised for his work rate since making his England debut as a substitute against Denmark in 1994.</p>
<p>Squad:</p>
<p>Goalkeepers - David Seaman (Arsenal), Ian Walker (Tottenham), David James (Liverpool)</p>
<p>Defenders - Gary Neville (Manchester United), Stuart Pearce (Nottingham Forest), Gary Pallister (Manchester United), Steve Howey (Newcastle), Gareth Southgate (Aston Villa), Sol Campbell (Tottenham)</p>
<p>Midfielders - Paul Gascoigne (Glasgow Rangers), Paul Ince (Internazioale), Steve McManaman (Liverpool), David Batty (Newcastle), Matthew Le Tissier (Southampton), David Beckham (Manchester United), Steve Stone (Nottingham Forest), Nick Barmby (Middlesbrough), Darren Anderton (Tottenham)</p>
<p>Forwards - Teddy Sheringham (Tottenham), Alan Shearer (Newcastle), Les Ferdinand (Newcastle), Robbie Fowler (Liverpool)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
