<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8557" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-PAKISTAN MAKE PROGRESS DESPITE DOGGED ATHERTON.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-PAKISTAN MAKE PROGRESS DESPITE DOGGED ATHERTON.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>England captain Michael Atherton battled bravely through the opening session to prevent his side losing their way on the first morning of the third and final test against Pakistan on Thursday.</p>
<p>With the home team requiring a win to save the series, Atherton won what should have been a good toss on a rock-hard Oval pitch only to see Alec Stewart and Nasser Hussain surrender their wickets to unnecessary shots as England reached 100 for two at lunch.</p>
<p>Atherton's share was a modest 27 but he demonstrated some much-needed steel against a fired-up Pakistan attack who proved a handful on a surface offering more pace and bounce than any previously encountered in the series.</p>
<p>The England captain, who survived a sharp chance to leg-slip on 15 off Wasim Akram, did particularly well to cope with the initial threat of county team mate Akram and Waqar Younis who raced in with the new ball.</p>
<p>Akram looked extremely sharp and struck Atherton a painful blow on his right shoulder in the day's third over with a     </p>
<p>short-pitched ball which cannoned away to the boundary for four leg-byes.</p>
<p>The batsman needed treatment and scratched together only three runs in his first 45 minutes at the crease, in contrast to the in-form Stewart.</p>
<p>Playing on his home ground and with his wicketkeeping duties conveniently delayed, the Surrey batsman dealt confidently with the quicker bowlers and raced to 44 off just 51 balls with nine fours.</p>
<p>But the introduction of leg-spinner Mushtaq Ahmed altered the picture, a slightly quicker delivery deceiving Stewart on the back-foot as he played across the line. There was momentary confusion as Stewart appeared to seek confirmation the ball had hit the stumps, although no one else in the ground was in any doubt.</p>
<p>Hussain looked equally untroubled for half an hour before edging the second ball of a new spell from Waqar straight to Saeed Anwar at second slip after making 12.</p>
<p>It added up to an unexpected early boost for Pakistan, who had earlier included Mohammad Akram for his first test of the series ahead of Ata-ur-Rehman in a Pakistan line-up which also featured Aamir Sohail at the top of the order.</p>
<p>England sprung a surprise by dropping seamer Andy Caddick and awarding a first cap to Glamorgan's Robert Croft, giving them a second spin option alongside Ian Salisbury in their quest to bowl Pakistan out twice.</p>
<p>Since three-test tours were introduced in England in 1965, only once has a team come back from 1-0 down to level a series. England's victory over South Africa at the Oval two years ago proved the exception to the rule.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
