<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8559" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: MOTOR RACING-KEEP FRIDAY PRACTICE, WILLIAMS WARNS.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-KEEP FRIDAY PRACTICE, WILLIAMS WARNS.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The abolition of Friday practice in Formula One would be a dangerous error, according to leading team owner Frank Williams.</p>
<p>&quot;It is close to being infantile to believe that we could just arrive at a grand prix on a Saturday morning, go out and do some practice laps and qualifying and then go to the grid with the cars,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be dangerous and it would be wrong.&quot;</p>
<p>The International Automobile Federation (FIA), backed by most of the teams, plan to introduce the reduction in length of grand prix meetings in a package of changes from next season.</p>
<p>Williams, one of the most experienced men in the sport, originally stated his views in May. His comments were re-issued on Wednesday, the day after the FIA announcement.</p>
<p>&quot;We are talking about Formula One cars and they can be very dangerous machines,&quot; said Williams, whose team has entered 358 grands prix and won the world constructors' championship eight times over the past 20 years. &quot;They have to be clearly understood, properly set up and thoroughly checked over.</p>
<p>&quot;What if it rains on Saturday? Do you just go out and do the warm-up in the dry on Sunday morning and that's it? You would never ask a boxer to begin training for a world championship bout with Mike Tyson only a week before the fight.</p>
<p>&quot;Our sport is about striving to be the best in the world at everything and that means we need to keep Fridays.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
