<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8561" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-ENGLAND WIN TOSS AND ELECT TO BAT IN THIRD TEST.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-ENGLAND WIN TOSS AND ELECT TO BAT IN THIRD TEST.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>England captain Michael Atherton won the toss on Thursday and opted to bat in the third and final test against Pakistan at The Oval.</p>
<p>England, trailing 1-0, surprisingly omitted seamer Andy Caddick and gave a test debut to 26-year-old Glamorgan off-spinner Robert Croft.</p>
<p>There was no suggestion of Caddick suffering from an injury and his absence ensured a reprieve for Chris Lewis, a disappointment in the drawn second test at Headingley.</p>
<p>Pakistan made two changes, bringing back injured opener Aamir Sohail in place of Shadab Kabir and preferring seamer Mohammad Akram to Ata-ur-Rehman. Moin Khan retained the wicket keepers' gloves ahead of Rashid Latif.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>England - Michael Atherton (captain), Alec Stewart, Nasser Hussain, Graham Thorpe, John Crawley, Nick Knight, Chris Lewis, Robert Croft, Dominic Cork, Ian Salisbury, Alan Mullally. </p>
<p>Pakistan - Aamir Sohail, Saeed Anwar, Ijaz Ahmed, Inzamam- ul-Haq, Salim Malik, Asif Mujtaba, Wasim Akram (captain), Moin Khan, Mushtaq Ahmed, Waqar Younis, Mohammad Akram.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
