<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8562" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: TENNIS-MUSTER LASHES OUT AT U.S. OPEN OFFICALS OVER SEEDINGS.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-MUSTER LASHES OUT AT U.S. OPEN OFFICALS OVER SEEDINGS.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slighted world number two Thomas Muster accused U.S. Open officials of manipulating the draw and seedings for the Grand Slam event and went as far as suggesting that it all be done over.</p>
<p>In a departure from their usual by-the-rankings seeding format, Open officials Wednesday took great liberty in making their seeding decisions in the men's competition for the tournament which begins on Monday.</p>
<p>Muster strongly objected to the process in which the men's seedings were announced after the draw for the rest of the field had already taken place.</p>
<p>&quot;You can put the seeds in and then make the draw, but you can't make the draw and then put the seeds in then. It's like cheating. In my opinion they should re-do the draw,&quot; he said after his second-round defeat Wednesday at the Canadian Open.</p>
<p>Muster and French Open champion Yevgeny Kafelnikov were seeded below their rankings, while several players, including popular Americans Andre Agassi and Michael Chang, were bumped up, and one top-16 player was left out of the seeds.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to be that the ITF doesn't respect the ATP Tour rankings, that's one thing, and it's seems like they can do whatever they want anyway,&quot; said Muster, who was seeded third for the year's final major tournament.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm getting pretty used to it,&quot; complained the Austrian clay-court wizard who was seeded seventh at Wimbledon despite his number two ranking.</p>
<p>&quot;Wimbledon has been the only tournament not to seed according to the computor rankings,&quot; said Chang following his Hamlet Cup victory Wednesday night.</p>
<p>The third-ranked Chang received the second seeding that would normally have gone to Muster.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm a little surprised. I don't know why they did it. It probably has upset some people,&quot; Chang correctly predicted.</p>
<p>And while Tournament Chairman Les Snyder said player popularity and television were not factors taken into consideration in this year's seeding decisions, Muster had his own theory about the departure from longstanding U.S. Open tradition.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just to put Agassi not to face (Pete) Sampras in the quarters,&quot; Muster charged, suggesting that officials were hoping to arrange a rematch of last year's Sampras-Agassi final.</p>
<p>The eighth-ranked Agassi, who had miserable showings at Wimbledon and the French Open this year, could well have run into top-ranked Sampras in the quarter-finals had Open officials seeded him eighth. At sixth, Agassi cannot meet Sampras before the semifinals.</p>
<p>&quot;They have to take somebody out to put Agassi on six,&quot; Muster said, &quot;and then to put Chang on two so it doesn't really look like... they could not put Agassi on two, because it would have been too obvious.</p>
<p>&quot;And the next thing is to put Kafelnikov on seven which is nonsense,&quot; he said of the fourth-ranked Russian.</p>
<p>Wimbledon runner-up MaliVai Washington, while not as outraged as Muster, does not support the departure from the rankings in determining seedings.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it's a good idea,&quot; said the 12th-ranked Washington, seeded 11th for the Open.</p>
<p>Washington was especially sympathetic toward 16th-ranked Spaniard Felix Mantilla, who was not seeded, while number 17 Marc Rosset of Switzerland and 18th-ranked Frenchman Cedric Pioline were.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't mind shuffling within the top ten, but I don't think it's fair to move a guy out,&quot; Washington said.</p>
<p>&quot;Somebody who's worked his butt off during the course of the year to get into the top 16 should be seeded at a Grand Slam tournament.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
