<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8568" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: VOLLEYBALL-CUBA SACKS OLYMPIC GOLD MEDAL COACH.</title>
<headline>VOLLEYBALL-CUBA SACKS OLYMPIC GOLD MEDAL COACH.</headline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cuba's sports authorities on Thursday sacked the country's top women's volleyball coach just three weeks after the Cuban team won the gold medal at the Atlanta Olympics.</p>
<p>The National Sports Institute (INDER), the state body which runs sports in Cuba, said in a statement it was removing Eugenio George Laffita from his post as chief coach of the women's national volleyball team because of &quot;conduct incompatible with his educational role&quot;.</p>
<p>INDER said it was also replacing the National Volleyball Commissioner, Inocencio Cuesta Chapman, for &quot;errors of personal conduct&quot;.</p>
<p>The sports body did not elaborate on the reason for the sackings, which came as a complete surprise to Cuba's volleyball fans, delighted with the team's performance in Atlanta, where they retained the Olympic title won in Barcelona in 1992.</p>
<p>The INDER statement said only that the decision was aimed at strengthening the sport in Cuba and at ensuring that the athletes &quot;continued to deserve the respect, affection and admiration of the people.&quot;</p>
<p>In an interview with a Cuban state newspaper last Sunday, the coach had criticised what he said were inadequate training conditions in Cuba for his women's volleyball team. He mentioned shortages of balls, courts and equipment.</p>
<p>INDER, in its statement, said it had carried out a study before the Atlanta Olympics which had revealed problems in national and provincial competitions and in the general attention given to women's volleyball.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
