<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8570" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: SOCCER-BEBETO JEERED AS FLAMENGO LOSE AT HOME.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-BEBETO JEERED AS FLAMENGO LOSE AT HOME.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil international striker Bebeto was jeered by his team's own fans as Flamengo crashed to a 1-0 home defeat against little-known Juventude in the Brazilian championship.</p>
<p>Furious Flamengo fans chanted &quot;Romario, Romario,&quot; referring to the  Brazil World Cup hero who left Flamengo to join Spanish club Valencia shortly before Bebeto's arrival.</p>
<p>Bebeto, who returned to Brazil in July after four years in Spain with Deportivo Coruna, has yet to score in two competitive games for Flamengo, who won this year's Rio de Janeiro championship mainly because of Romario's prolific goalscoring.</p>
<p>He incurred the crowd's wrath after missing a gilt-edged chance in the second half, when he blasted the ball over the Juventude crossbar from six metres during Wednesday's match.</p>
<p>&quot;Sincerely, I didn't expect this,&quot; said a bemused Bebeto afterwards. &quot;But I'm not worried. This will pass and later on the same fans will be applauding me.&quot;</p>
<p>Bebeto, 32, has been included in Brazil's squad for a European tour at the end of the month while Romario has been left out.</p>
<p>Other midweek games saw last year's South American champions Gremio hammer Bragantino 6-1 and Palmeiras, who drew their first two games 0-0 before beating Coritiba 5-0 on Saturday, beat Vasco da Gama 3-1.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
