<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8571" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: SOCCER-REBEL CLUBS HANDED NEW DEADLINE IN ETHNIC ROW.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-REBEL CLUBS HANDED NEW DEADLINE IN ETHNIC ROW.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three of Australia's top soccer clubs escaped expulsion from the national league on Thursday but the game's ruling body set them a new deadline in a continuing row over the sport's ethnic image.</p>
<p>Champions Melbourne Knights, Marconi and Sydney United are defying Soccer Australia (SA) by refusing to scrap club logos which reflect their mainly European roots.</p>
<p>SA wants them to use new logos as part of a marketing plan aimed at broadening the league's appeal beyond its traditional migrant support base.</p>
<p>Chairman David Hill, who initially ordered the clubs to comply by Thursday, said they now have until September 4.</p>
<p>&quot;There is now the prospect that we can get the logos we want but ones that the clubs can live with to protect their heritage,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>The issue has bitterly divided the league, which struggles to compete with rugby league and Australian Rules football.</p>
<p>Officials from Marconi, whose logo features the red, green and white of the Italian flag, have described the SA policy as a kind of &quot;ethnic cleansing&quot;.</p>
<p>Marconi, the most successful club in Australian soccer with four titles, were founded by Italian migrants in Sydney, while the Melbourne Knights draw their support almost exclusively from the city's Croatian community.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
