<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8575" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-NEW DRAW TAKES AGASSI OUT OF SAMPRAS PATH TO FINAL.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-NEW DRAW TAKES AGASSI OUT OF SAMPRAS PATH TO FINAL.</headline>
<byline>Bill Berkrot</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite the unprecedented embarrassment of having to re-do the entire men's singles draw for the U.S. Open, tournament officials may have gotten what they wanted all along -- a possible Pete Sampras-Andre Agassi final.</p>
<p>Bowing to pressure and harsh criticism from irate players on the ATP Tour, and worried about the perception that the draw could have been manipulated to help popular American players, the U.S. Tennis Association on Thursday erased Wednesday's men's draw and did it all over again.</p>
<p>&quot;We responded mostly to the players. We listened to them and we have responded,&quot; said USTA President and tournament chairman Les Snyder.</p>
<p>The USTA was within the rules in departing from the ATP Tour rankings in choosing the 16 seeded men, and in the revised draw still did not bow to pressure to stick to the rankings.</p>
<p>But by placing the 112 non-seeded players in their slots before announcing the 16 seeds Wednesday, the tournament left itself open to charges of cheating, which came from outspoken world number two Thomas Muster and an outraged Andrei Medvedev.</p>
<p>&quot;They abused the rules. It would be like fixing a football, basketball or NHL game,&quot; said Medvedev, who had suggested the players not play unless the draw was re-done.</p>
<p>Muster, who along with French Open champion Yevgeny Kafelnikov was seeded below his ranking, also charged that the eighth-ranked Agassi was seeded sixth so he could not run into Sampras as early as the quarter-finals.</p>
<p>The original draw put Agassi on a semifinal collision course with the world number one, but the new draw should make CBS television and tournament officials even happier with the possibility of a rematch of the two American superstars in the final.</p>
<p>Sampras now begins defence of his title against Romanian Adrian Voinea, which is good news for Czech David Rikl, the top seed's original first-round victim.</p>
<p>Sampras still has fourth-ranked Kafelnikov in his quarter of the draw. But a likely third-round Grand Slam rubber match with recent nemesis Mark Philippoussis, who beat Sampras at the Australian Open and lost to him at Wimbledon, will have to wait until the fourth round.</p>
<p>Agassi, the 1994 champion who may now have second seed Michael Chang in his semifinal future, opens against Colombian Mauricio Hadad, while Chang gets a qualifier in round one.</p>
<p>Third seed Muster looks to be one of the winners of the revised draw. Instead of taking on accomplished hard court player Richey Reneberg in the first round, the Austrian clay court star faces another clay specialist in Argentine Javier Frana.</p>
<p>Muster is now drawn for a likely fourth-round meeting with 13th-seeded Swede Thomas Enqvist before a possible quarter-final against Agassi, who now has Wimbledon runner-up MaliVai Washington, seeded 11th, in his path.</p>
<p>But for retiring Swedish star Stefan Edberg, if he didn't have bad luck, he wouldn't have any luck at all.</p>
<p>The popular Swede, playing his Grand Slam finale, had the misfortune to draw eighth seed Jim Courier as his original first-round opponent.</p>
<p>Given a second chance at a new lease on life, Edberg, who could have ended up against any of the other 127 players in the field, landed fifth-seeded Wimbledon champion Richard Krajicek as his new opening-round opponent.</p>
<p>&quot;Sure none of us wish it had occurred,&quot; Snyder said of the decision to re-do the draw. &quot;But we are hopeful we are getting across a strong message -- the main thing is we must do what is best for the sport and for the U.S. Open.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
