<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8577" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-ORIOLES' MANAGER DAVEY JOHNSON HOSPITALIZED.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-ORIOLES' MANAGER DAVEY JOHNSON HOSPITALIZED.</headline>
<dateline>BALTIMORE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Baltimore Orioles manager Davey Johnson will miss Thursday night's game against the Seattle Mariners after being admitted to a hospital with an irregular heartbeat.</p>
<p>The 53-year-old Johnson was hospitalized after experiencing dizziness.</p>
<p>&quot;He is in no danger and will be treated and observed this evening,&quot; said Orioles team physician Dr. William Goldiner, adding that Johnson is expected to be released on Friday.</p>
<p>Orioles' bench coach Andy Etchebarren will manage the club in Johnson's absence.</p>
<p>Johnson is the second manager to be hospitalized this week after California Angels skipper John McNamara was admitted to New York's Columbia Presbyterian Hospital on Wednesday with a blood clot in his left calf.</p>
<p>Johnson, who played eight seasons in Baltimore, was named Orioles manager in the off-season replacing Phil Regan. He led the Cincinnati Reds to the National League Championship Series last year and guided the New York Mets to a World Series championship in 1986.</p>
<p>Baltimore has won 16 of its last 22 games to pull within five games of the slumping New York Yankees in the American League East Division.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BALTIMORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
