<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8579" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-USTA TO REMAKE U.S. OPEN MEN'S DRAW. [CORRECTED 22:04 GMT]</title>
<headline>TENNIS-USTA TO REMAKE U.S. OPEN MEN'S DRAW. [CORRECTED 22:04 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bowing to pressure and harsh criticism from players on the ATP Tour, the U.S. Tennis Association will remake the 1996 U.S. Open men's singles draw later on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;By remaking the draw, the USTA will protect the integrity of the draw process,&quot; USTA President and tournament chairman Les Snyder said in a brief advisory issued by the association.  </p>
<p>The USTA seeding committee was within its rights in deviating from the ATP Tour rankings in deciding the seedings, despite the departure from longstanding tradition.</p>
<p>However, in a radical departure from the usual process, the USTA completed the draw for all the non-seeded players before announcing the men's seedings, allowing for the perception of draw manipulation in favour of American players.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an insult to the players and to the ATP rankings and the game of tennis,&quot; said an angry Andrei Medvedev of Ukraine at the Hamlet Cup on Thursday before the reversal was announced.</p>
<p>&quot;Wimbledon has an unusual seeding system but it's fair, they list the seedings before they make the draw. At the U.S. Open they made the draw before they made the seedings,&quot; the 38th-ranked Medvedev complained.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we can allow this to happen. When it happens once, then the Australian Open will do the same for Australians and the French Open for the French. I believe if they don't change the (draw) we should not play,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>World number two Thomas Muster of Austria was also outspoken in his criticism of the process.</p>
<p>&quot;You can put the seeds in and then make the draw, but you can't make the draw and then put the seeds in. It's like cheating. In my opinion they should re-do the draw,&quot; Muster said from Toronto on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>Snyder said the USTA will not change the seedings but it will re-draw the entire 128 player field beginning at 4:00 PM (2000 GMT) to correct &quot;the perception that proper procedures may not have been followed.&quot;</p>
<p>(Corrects to make clear that the seeds were included in re-draw).</p>
<p>Medvedev, who would have played Frenchman Jean-Philippe Fleurian in the first round according to the original draw, was delighted when told that the USTA had caved in to pressure form the ATP Tour and its players.</p>
<p>&quot;It's great that the authorities are doing the right thing,&quot; he said. &quot;This way they avoid a lot of confrontation.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
