<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8580" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-BRAVES BEAT REDS IN BOTTOM OF NINTH.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-BRAVES BEAT REDS IN BOTTOM OF NINTH.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pinch-hitter Luis Polonia's sacrifice fly in the bottom of the ninth inning scored Ryan Klesko and lifted the Atlanta Braves to a 4-3 victory over the Cincinnati Reds Wednesday.</p>
<p>Jeff Brantley (1-2) gave up singles to Mark Lemke and Klesko. Marquis Grissom, who earlier extended his career-high hitting streak to 25 games, erased Lemke with a botched sacrifice, but a Brantley wild pitch sent Klesko to third.</p>
<p>Polonia, batting for Pedro Borbon (3-0), then lifted a sacrifice fly to right scoring Klesko.</p>
<p>Polonia was released by the Baltimore Orioles and re-signed Saturday by Atlanta, for whom he played in their World Series championship season last year.</p>
<p>&quot;It feels pretty good, especially when you come to the team like that, you want to push yourself to do something right away,&quot; Polonia said. &quot;I got an opportunity today, and it's really exciting.&quot;</p>
<p>Borbon, who gave up a pair of hits in 1 1/3 innings, got the win despite allowing an inherited runner to score for the first time in 20 chances this season.</p>
<p>Atlanta's John Smoltz allowed a pair of runs in seven innings, but missed his 21st win. He gave up seven hits and struck out five without issuing a walk.</p>
<p>&quot;I had so-so stuff. I didn't have my best stuff, but I was able to get some outs when I needed to,&quot; Smoltz said.</p>
<p>In San Diego, Ken Caminiti homered from each side of the plate to tie a National League record and Fernando Valenzuela (11-7) allowed three hits over six scoreless innings for his sixth straight win as the Padres beat the Montreal Expos 7-2.</p>
<p>Caminiti has homered from each side of the plate twice this season and six times in his career, tying him with Bobby Bonilla for the N.L. record.</p>
<p>Greg Vaughn had his second homer in as many games for San Diego.</p>
<p>Montreal lost for the sixth time in seven games.</p>
<p>In Los Angeles, Curt Schilling threw a two-hitter for his second shutout in 16 days and Scott Rolen drove in three runs with his first two major-league homers to pace the Philadelphia Phillies to a 6-0 triumph over the Dodgers.</p>
<p>Schilling (6-6), who four-hit the Pirates on August 5, helped Philadelphia to its third straight win and broke a personal two-game slide. He walked none and tied a season high with 12 strikeouts.</p>
<p>Schilling, who retired the final 14 batters and faced just one over the minimum, had a one-hitter against the Mets in 1992.</p>
<p>Hideo Nomo (12-10) gave up five runs -- three earned -- and seven hits in 6 2/3 innings for the Dodgers, who lost their third straight.</p>
<p>In San Francisco, left fielder Bernard Gilkey's error in the top of first opened the gates for a seven-run frame that included Jay Canizaro's first career grand slam, and the Giants hung on for a 12-11 victory over the New York Mets.</p>
<p>The Giants tied their high score for a single inning this season. Tom Lampkin and Glenallen Hill also homered for the Giants, who took the rubber game of the three-game series.</p>
<p>Mark Dewey (5-2) got the victory in relief and Rod Beck notched his 28th save despite allowing a two-run homer to Lance Johnson in the ninth. Robert Person (2-5) took the loss.</p>
<p>Giants star left fielder Barry Bonds left the game in the ninth with a mild strain of the left hamstring.</p>
<p>In Chicago, Frank Castillo allowed two runs over seven innings and Scott Bullett added a homer, three runs scored and three RBI as the Cubs defeated the Florida Marlins 8-3 in the rubber game of a three-game series.</p>
<p>Castillo (6-14) avoided becoming the first 15-game loser in the N.L.</p>
<p>Bullett was making his first start in place of N.L. home run leader Sammy Sosa, who was placed on the disabled list earlier in the day with a broken right hand.</p>
<p>At Colorado, Ellis Burks drove in three runs and Eric Young went 4-for-5 with two RBI as the Rockies coasted to their third straight win, 10-2 over the St Louis Cardinals.</p>
<p>Andres Galarraga added a run-scoring single and his 36th homer and Armando Reynoso (8-8) won his third straight decision for Colorado, which has won three in a row.</p>
<p>Cardinals starter Andy Benes (13-9) had his 10-game winning streak snapped. Benes was drilled for seven runs and 13 hits in 2 2/3 innings, his shortest start of the season.</p>
<p>In Houston, Denny Neagle allowed two runs over 6 2/3 innings and Jeff King recorded his fifth four-hit game of the season as the Pittsburgh Pirates snapped a five-game losing streak with a 5-2 victory over the Astros.</p>
<p>Neagle (13-6) won for the first time in six starts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
