<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8590" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: SOCCER-NEWCOMERS IN DANISH WORLD CUP SQUAD.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-NEWCOMERS IN DANISH WORLD CUP SQUAD.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Denmark's new Swedish-born coach Bo Johannsen mixes fresh blood with the experience of the Laudrup brothers in his 16-man squad announced on Thursday for the World Cup qualifer against Slovenia in Ljubljana on September 1.</p>
<p>Brian and Michael Laudrup have been complemented by young prospects Soeren Andersen, a forward, and midfielder Ole Bjur, who scored in the 1-0 victory over Sweden in a friendly earlier this month.</p>
<p>Johannsen succeeded Richard Moeller Nielsen after Denmark's disappointing defence of the European championship in June.</p>
<p>Squad:</p>
<p>Goalkeepers - Peter Schmeichel (Manchester United), Mogens Krogh (Brondby).</p>
<p>Defenders - Jes Hoegh (Fenerbahce), Marc Rieper (West Ham), Jakob Friis-Hansen (Hamburg), Jacob Laursen (Derby).</p>
<p>Midfielders - Thomas Helveg (Udinese), Ole Bjur (Brondby), Bjarne Goldbaek (FC Copenhagen), Allan Nielsen (Tottenham), Brian Steen Nielsen (Urawa Red Diamond, Japan), Michael Schjoenberg (Odense), Claus Thomsen (Ipswich).</p>
<p>Strikers - Brian Laudrup (Glasgow Rangers), Michael Laudrup (Vissel Kobe, Japan), Soeren Andersen (Aalborg).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
