<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8592" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-SPANISH TV KEEPS FANS GLUED TO THEIR SETS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SPANISH TV KEEPS FANS GLUED TO THEIR SETS.</headline>
<byline>Joelle Diderich</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A pact between broadcasters and clubs to put even more soccer on television is threatening to turn Spato a nation of couch potatoes and leave bars and restaurants deserted for up to six nights a week.</p>
<p>Bar owners have long complained that Saturday-night Spanish league matches keep their patrons glued to the television set at home instead of spending money on a night on the town.</p>
<p>Their anger deepened on Thursday when an agreement between television channels and football authorities was announced allowing private television channel Antena 3 to broadcast an extra league match on Monday nights from September 1.</p>
<p>&quot;Football is ruining our businesses,&quot; Ignacio Cabello, national president of restaurants at the Spanish Federation of Restaurants, Cafeterias and Bars, told Reuters on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't swim against the current. We say football, yes, but limit it to international matches on Wednesdays and domestic matches on Sundays,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Apart from Britons, Spaniards are the most television- addicted people in the European Union with an average 86 percent of the population watching television on a normal day, according to official statistics.</p>
<p>Football accounts for much of that time, with match broadcasts representing nine of 994, the latest figures available.</p>
<p>Bar owners say the Saturday night matches cost them an estimated 112 billion pesetas in 1995 and Cabello forecast that Monday night matches would add an extra 50 to 60 billion ($400-475 million) to that figure in the 1996-97 season.</p>
<p>The new deal between Antena 3, regional channels and private subscription channel Canal Plus establishes a steady diet of televised football on Saturdays, Sundays and Mondays for the next two years.</p>
<p>Add to this UEFA Cup matches Champion's League matches on Wednesdays and Cup Winner's Cup matches on Thursdays, and restauranteurs are not the only ones complaining.</p>
<p>Spanish coach Javier Clemente has attacked the new schedule, saying it interferes with international matches. The first match Antena 3 was due to broadcast on September 2 between Atletico Madrid and Celta is a case in point.</p>
<p>That Monday Spain is due to travel to the Faroe Islands to play its first qualifying match on Wednesday for the 1998 World Cup in France. Clemente is likely to play Aletico's Kiko and Caminero, and without them, the team won't play Celta.</p>
<p>&quot;The calendar is a disaster,&quot; Clemente told sports daily Marca. &quot;The clubs aren't looking after the sport, only after economics.&quot;</p>
<p>Football clubs are expected to earn 250 billion pesetas ($2 billion) for TV rights between now and 2003, including pay-per- view which Antena 3 and Canal Plus hope to introduce in 1998.</p>
<p>The Spanish Football Federation welcomed the idea of Monday night matches on condition they do not interfere with international commitments. Football clubs are due to iron out remaining problems and ratify the deal next Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
