<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8594" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-PACE-SETTERS LENS EXPECT TOUGH TEST AT NANTES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-PACE-SETTERS LENS EXPECT TOUGH TEST AT NANTES.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Vignal</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Early French league leaders Lens, one of four teams on maximum points after their first two games, face a tough test on Saturday at 1995 champions Nantes.</p>
<p>Lens, lead on goal difference from defending champions Auxerre, Paris St Germain and Bastia, while Nantes, who have lost key players Reynald Pedros and Nicolas Ouedec, are 16th with just one point.</p>
<p>But Lens, who have so far beaten the two newly-promoted sides Caen and Nancy, are expecting a difficult match.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not the favourites,&quot; trainer Slavo Muslin said. &quot;We have beaten two relatively weak sides. Against Nantes, it will be a different story.&quot;</p>
<p>But many in France believe Lens, a club with limited means from a small northern mining town, have a team strong enough to qualify for Europe, if not have a shot at the title.</p>
<p>They have spent money wisely, buying Czech striker Vladimir Smicer before he came to the world's attention during the European championships in England in June.</p>
<p>&quot;If we had waited until the end of the English tournament to make a deal, he would've had become too expensive for us,&quot; club president Gervais Martel said.</p>
<p>PSG, for whom new Brazilian midfielder Lenoardo has shone, have also started well and have little to fear from their visit to modest Nancy on Friday.</p>
<p>Reigning champions Auxerre will find it more difficult against Bordeaux, who drew 1-1 at Metz last week thanks to striker Jean-Pierre Papin's first goal for the club.</p>
<p>Bordeaux, UEFA Cup finalists last May, hope the arrival of Papin will compensate for the loss of their main assets from last season, notably the gifted Zinedine Zidane, now with European champions Juventus.</p>
<p>Corsican side Bastia will try to extend their suprise winning streak at Nice.</p>
<p>Bastia have held on to Montenegran striker Anto Drobnjak, who has formed what promises to be a devastating partnership with newcomer Lubomir Moravcik of Slovakia.</p>
<p>&quot;Anto received several offers and I was certain we would lose him but he said he was happy with us and decided to stay,&quot; Bastia trainer Frederic Antonetti said.</p>
<p>Monaco, among the favourites for the title despite being held 1-1 by Montpellier last week, travel to Guingamp, who qualified for the UEFA Cup on Tuesday by beating Russian side Rotor Volgrograd 1-0 in an Intertoto clash.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
