<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8597" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAFRICA COMMISSION PROPOSES DOUBLE STUDENT NUMBERS.</title>
<headline>SAFRICA COMMISSION PROPOSES DOUBLE STUDENT NUMBERS.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African universities and colleges should double student numbers within the next 10 years, a commission looking into higher education recommended on Thursday.</p>
<p>The National Commission of Higher Education handed its report to Education Minister Sibusiso Bengu on Thursday, recommending that student numbers double to 1.5 million by 2005.</p>
<p>Commissioner Rolf Stumpf told a news briefing the body had also proposed a new approach to funding studies, through targeting disciplines producing graduates in specific fields.</p>
<p>&quot;It is based on the premise of affordability and sustainability,&quot; he said, adding that this would allow the government help in producing graduates needed by the economy, such as engineers.</p>
<p>Stumpf gave as an example the possibility of setting targets for universities to train engineers and places would be allocated by Bengu on the advice of a higher education council.</p>
<p>This would take place in the framework of a plan which would take into account the human resource needs of the country.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
