<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8598" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: ZIMBABWE DOLLAR CLOSES WEAKER ON MOST UNITS.</title>
<headline>ZIMBABWE DOLLAR CLOSES WEAKER ON MOST UNITS.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Zimbabwe dollar closed on Thursday firmer on the mark but was quoted weaker against other hard units on the back of high importer demand for foreign currency, exchange dealers said.</p>
<p>They said most people were quoting wide spreads to protect their positions owing to uncertainty in the market as to how far the central bank was willing to go in support of the local dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;The Reserve Bank off-loaded a few (U.S.) dollars into the market in the morning but it was only a little bit and people are not sure what will happen next,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank doesn't seem keen to want to stop the depreciation...only to soften the fall,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Dealers dismissed any possible link between the depreciation of the currency and a nation-wide strike by Zimbabwe's civil workers for salary hikes.</p>
<p>&quot;The fall has nothing to do with the strike. It's just that this week there have been a lot of outflows towards loan repayments,&quot; one said in the morning.</p>
<p>At Thursday's close, the Zimbabwe dollar was trading at 10.0700/1200 against the U.S. dollar, down from Wednesday's 10.0450/0650, and also lost some points to 15.5800/6660 from 15.5620/6020 versus sterling.</p>
<p>Against the rand it was quoted at 2.2050/2180, down from the previous day's 2.2000/2070, but edged up on the mark to 6.7380/7730 from 6.7740/7890.</p>
<p>-- Stella Mapenzauswa, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 28/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
