<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8599" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: MINISTER SAYS S.AFRICA HOUSING PLAN SPEEDS UP.</title>
<headline>MINISTER SAYS S.AFRICA HOUSING PLAN SPEEDS UP.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's house-building programme is gathering momentum but is still too slow, Housing Minister Sankie Mthembi-Mahanyele said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I am satisfied that the framework for delivery is in place and is working,&quot; she told a news briefing.</p>
<p>But she said problems were still hampering the programme of housing the homeless.</p>
<p>&quot;While it is clear that our efforts are beginning to pay off, I am still impatient with the pace of delivery of housing in South Africa.&quot;</p>
<p>An average of 5,611 subsidies were approved each month between September 1995 and June this year, compared to less than a tenth of that between March 1994 and August 1995.</p>
<p>Five of the nine provinces are ahead of target in their duget spending and provincial task teams are being set up to monitor progress and provinces would be allowed to apply for more funds if they exceeded their budgets.</p>
<p>&quot;At the same time we are saying that we are not going to continue allocating money to provinces if they can't spend it,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Main problems hampering housing programmes include a lack of experience in processing subsidy applications and confusion among the poorest people about how to apply for subsidies.</p>
<p>Boycotts of bond and rent payments from the apartheid era were also continuing to affect the industry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010022">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
