<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8600" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICAN OPTION VOLS IMPLY FURTHER RAND RUCTIONS.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICAN OPTION VOLS IMPLY FURTHER RAND RUCTIONS.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rand volatility options have eased from highs of around 15 percent in late July, but continue to imply the currency faces further ructions in the short-term.</p>
<p>Options traders said on Thursday that implied volatility options in the one-month area were currently at between 11.25 and 12.75 percent.</p>
<p>That compared with levels of between 10 and 12 percent on Monday and 12 to 13 percent on Tuesday following the rand's fall to a record low of 4.59 in New York on Monday night.</p>
<p>&quot;Volatilities (in the one-month area) are at around 12.75 today after being paid at 12.25 yesterday,&quot; a trader said, &quot;which implies that there is still volatility out there.&quot;</p>
<p>A second trader was more optimistic that volatilities would ease further in the near-term if the spot rand market maintained the new-found stability of the past few days.</p>
<p>The spot rand has held steady in a narrow 4.55 to 4.57 range since Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Volatilities are expected to go back to around 11 to 12 percent, which is where they were before Monday's blow-off,&quot; the trader said. &quot;They may even go to around nine or 10 percent if it stays as quiet as it is.&quot;</p>
<p>In the forward market, the rand was last quoted at around 4.60 against the dollar in the one-month area.</p>
<p>Another trader noted that the current 1.5 percentage point spread in options also indicated nervousness in the market.</p>
<p>&quot;It normally gets down to about 0.5 but there is nervousness in the market which is why it is pretty wide at the moment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Implied volatilities are derivatives used by banks to hedge their options books and have risen to as high as 30 percent since the rand's devaluation against the dollar began on February 15 this year.</p>
<p>Before the rand's collapse they traded at around five percent.</p>
<p>Daily volumes on the implied volatility options market range between nil and up to $400 million, one trader said.</p>
<p>-- Paul Richardson, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
