<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8601" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>LESOTHO: SOUTHERN AFRICAN ECONOMIES WELL MANAGED - SADC.</title>
<headline>SOUTHERN AFRICAN ECONOMIES WELL MANAGED - SADC.</headline>
<dateline>MASERU 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most southern African economies are well managed but high inflation still hampers economic recovery in parts of the region, the Southern African Development Community (SADC) said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Ministers of the 12-nation group were meeting in the Lesotho capital Maseru on Wednesday and Thursday to assess progress made in the past year ahead of a SADC summit of regional leaders on Saturday.</p>
<p>SADC's council of ministers said in a statement on Thursday that it was satisfied that significant progress had been made during the past year in implementing the regional body's policies and programmes.</p>
<p>&quot;Council noted that on the whole, the economies of the region are well managed with structural adjustment programmes achieving some of the intended goals,&quot; the SADC statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;Council, however, noted that inflationary pressures continued to undermine economic recovery in some member states&quot;.</p>
<p>SADC groups Mauritius, Angola, Lesotho, Swaziland, Zambia, Zimbabwe, Namibia, Mozambique, Tanzania, Malawi, Botswana and South Africa.</p>
<p>The ministers said government expenditure in the region had decreased in the past five years as a result of stringent fiscal discipline by countries to improve the investment climate.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact, SADC countries have performed better than the rest of sub-Saharan Africa in attracting foreign direct and venture seeking investment,&quot; the council said.</p>
<p>It expressed some concern about a drought emergency declared in Namibia in June but said it was heartened by good rains in the region which boosted estimated 1995/1996 cereal production to 26.36 million tonnes, 62 percent up on the previous season.</p>
<p>Production of the region's staple food, maize, was forecast at 20.29 million tonnes, a 80 percent increase.</p>
<p>SADC was formed 16 years ago to lessen the region's economic dependence on then apartheid South Africa.</p>
<p>South Africa, the regional economic power, joined SADC in 1994 after the country's first all-race elections ushered in President Nelson Mandela's government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LESOT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MOZAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NAMIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SOUAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWAZD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MASERU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LESOTHO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
