<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8602" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: DALAI LAMA CALLS MANDELA SUCCESSOR TO GANDHI.</title>
<headline>DALAI LAMA CALLS MANDELA SUCCESSOR TO GANDHI.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's President Nelson Mandela has succeeded Mahatma Gandhi as a saviour of humanity through his struggle for peaceful change, Tibet's Dalai Lama said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The next century should be one of dialogue and peace...in the past Mahatma Gandhi was a very good example of this and now you (Nelson Mandela) are a great successor of that person,&quot; the religious leader told a news conference after meeting Mandela.</p>
<p>He said millions of people throughout the world admired Mandela for his selfless struggle against apartheid.</p>
<p>&quot;I am one of them and today my dream is fulfilled and I wish that all your hard work can succeed because it will not only benefit people in your country but all humanity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The two Nobel peace prize winners made no mention of China's occupation of Tibet during a joint news conference. China annexed Tibet in 1950 and the Dalai Lama fled to exile in 1959.</p>
<p>He runs a government-in-exile in the Himalayan Indian town of Dharamsala.</p>
<p>&quot;His holyiness is known throughout the world for his commitment to values to which every decent human being strives for,&quot; Mandela said. &quot;He stands for peace, justice and for all the concepts which make life worth living.&quot;</p>
<p>The Dalai Lama was in South Africa on a week-long visit until Saturday to deliver lectures on peace.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
