<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8603" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: ANC'S MBEKI DEFENDS &quot;JUST WAR&quot; AGAINST APARTHEID.</title>
<headline>ANC'S MBEKI DEFENDS &quot;JUST WAR&quot; AGAINST APARTHEID.</headline>
<byline>Anton Ferreira</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deputy President Thabo Mbeki on Thursday defended the &quot;just war&quot; of his African National Congress against white rule, telling South Africa's truth commission it could not be compared to the defence of apartheid.</p>
<p>Mbeki, heir-apparent to President Nelson Mandela, told Archbishop Desmond Tutu's Truth and Reconciliation Commission, or TRC, that the ANC resorted to violence in 1960 only after white rule had blocked all other avenues of protest.</p>
<p>&quot;In the end, the fundamental issue we would like to present to the TRC is that as a liberation movement, we engaged in a just war for national liberation.</p>
<p>&quot;The conduct of that war should not be any matter that should be the subject of these proceedings,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The ANC acknowledged in a statement handed to the commission in Cape Town that some agents had abused their positions and had violated human rights, but said &quot;none of such violations arose out of official policy.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There are instances where we could have acted more firmly and speedily to prevent or stop abuses, and for that the ANC accepts collective responsibility.&quot;</p>
<p>Mbeki, heading a delegation of 23 people, handed the 100-page text and a volume of supporting documentation to Tutu's commission on the final day of hearings for political parties.</p>
<p>The commission was appointed by Mandela to investigate so-called gross human rights violations under apartheid, to compensate victims and to pardon perpetrators.</p>
<p>Testimony during earlier hearings, including harrowing personal accounts of rape, torture and the killing of children, has at times reduced Tutu and his colleagues to tears.</p>
<p>This week, parties including the white separatist Freedom Front and former president F.W. de Klerk's National Party submitted documents explaining their actions under white rule.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be morally wrong and legally incorrect to equate apartheid with the resistance against it,&quot; the ANC said.</p>
<p>&quot;The mass of the people led by the liberation movement waged a just struggle against apartheid, which was designated by the United Nations as a crime against humanity.&quot;</p>
<p>Mbeki argued on Thursday that the ANC's guerrilla war was responsible for ending the scourge of apartheid.</p>
<p>&quot;The naked reality is that our country would not be free today if we had depended for our emancipation on legal parliamentary opposition,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>De Klerk, who ousted P.W. Botha, the last white hardliner, in 1989 and turned South Africa from apartheid to democracy said on Wednesday his National Party had much to apologise for, but insisted he had never sanctioned assassination or torture.</p>
<p>&quot;I should like to express my deepest sympathy with all those on all sides who suffered during the conflict,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While de Klerk argued that apartheid had been an honest, though misguided attempt to share the country amongst its ethnic groups, the ANC submission rejected any defence of segregation.</p>
<p>&quot;Apartheid constituted a deliberate and systematic mission of a ruling clique that saw itself as the champion of a super-race,&quot; the ANC statement said.</p>
<p>It acknowledged that some of its members had exceeded their orders and that the fight against government infiltration in ANC exile bases had been brutal.</p>
<p>The statement names 34 people executed on the orders of an ANC military tribunal between 1980 and 1989.</p>
<p>&quot;From around December 1985...a number of attacks on civilian targets with no connection to the state occurred...The ANC does not seek to justify such attacks, but insists that the context in which they occurred is relevant.</p>
<p>&quot;The ANC has acknowledged that in a number of instances, breaches in policy did occur and deeply regrets civilian casualties. The leadership took steps to halt operations in conflict with policy,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The ANC called for reasonable reparations to victims of the struggle, but stressed the need for confession and forgiveness.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
