<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8606" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: PRESS DIGEST - ZIMBABWE - AUG 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - ZIMBABWE - AUG 22.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Zimbabwe press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE FINANCIAL GAZETTE</p>
<p>- Zimbabwe's mining industry pension fund has in a landmark deal acquired property worth Z$23 million in the capital Harare's central business district from Zimbabwe Financial Holdings (Finhold).</p>
<p>- The government and the Public Service Association (PSA) on Wednesday agreed to end a nationwide strike by civil servants for salary rises that had paralysed public services since Monday, but the situation remained potentially explosive on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>- The town clerk in Zimbabwe's capital Harare on Wednesday accused the government of enacting a law with flawed provisions which led to the nullification of executive mayoral elections in Harare and the country's second largest city of Bulawayo.</p>
<p>- The Zimbabwean government will dispose of 13 percent of its stake in loss-making pharmaceutical company CAPS Holdings and seek a strategic joint venture partner to help revitalise the firm.</p>
<p>BUSINESS HERALD</p>
<p>- Multinational company Trans Zambezi Industry has injected Z$240 million into ailing Zimbabwean paper and packaging firm Art Corporation, saving 3,000 jobs.</p>
<p>- Zimbabwe's government is confident that the International Monetary Fund (IMF) will find its 1996/97 budget acceptable and pave the way of re-negotiations for funding of the southern African country's economic reform programme.</p>
<p>- German telecommunications firm Siemens International could emerge winner of a cellular telephone tender floated by Zimbabwe's Post and Telecommunications Corporation after results showed its bid was cheaper than that of its major rival Ericsson LM International of Sweden.</p>
<p>THE HERALD</p>
<p>- Zimbabwe's high court has ruled that people owed money by the government can keep back enough of what they owe in taxes to set off and settle the debt.</p>
<p>- Zimbabwe's Public Service Association (PSA) on Wednesday evening called off a nation-wide strike for pay hikes by its members after public service, labour and social welfare minister Florence Chitauro said she was willing to start salary negotiations if the strikers went back to work on Thursday morning.</p>
<p>- Workers at a beleaguered Zimbabwean textile firm, Fashion Industrial Holdings, which was liquidated two months ago, have agreed to use more than Z$50 million from their pension fund to buy out the company.</p>
<p>-- Stella Mapenzauswa, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 28/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
