<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8607" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - SOUTH AFRICA - AUGUST 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - SOUTH AFRICA - AUGUST 22.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Thursday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- The board of First National Bank Holdings Ltd has stopped just short of dismissing managing director Barry Swart after an internal investigation found he had given his daughter a contract to help decorate the bank's new headquarters.</p>
<p>- Inflation ticked up to 7.1 percent in July from 6.9 percent in June as an increase in food prices and a surge in property rates took their toll.</p>
<p>- Insurance group Liberty Life Association of Africa Ltd posted a 667 million rand attributable surplus for the six months to June, aided by a strong performance from offshore subsidiary Liberty International and a sharp rise in new business.</p>
<p>- National Party leader and former South Africa president F.W. de Klerk has accepted responsibility for all authorised abuses of human rights under apartheid and tendered an unequivocal and &quot;genuine&quot; apology for the suffering NP policies had caused.</p>
<p>- South Africa's leading trade partners warned that escalating violent crime was damaging prospects of new offshore investment in South Africa.</p>
<p>- A parliamentary probe has been unable to prove that banks colluded when they raised interest rates a percentage point on May 17.</p>
<p>- Seven former police generals, including three national commissioners, will be the first of the old guard security force officers to be summoned to testify before the truth commission.</p>
<p>- An agent contracted by the South African Defence Force to buy 500 kg of chemicals in Croatia for its secret chemicals weapons project pilfered $1.6 million in state funds, the South African National Defence Force chief told parliament's public accounts committee.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- Inflation hit 7.1 percent last month from 6.9 percent in June. It is the highest level of inflation in a year, largely because of a bigger than expected jump in food prices.</p>
<p>- Liberty Life, the insurer, reported a 57.9 percent surge in the net taxed surplus attributable to shareholders in the six months to June 30.</p>
<p>- Consolidated Metallurgical Industries Ltd , the world's largest producer of high-carbon ferrochrome, hit out at high railage costs, which it said hampered the 1.8 billion rand industry's ability to compete in the depressed world ferrochrome market.</p>
<p>- The Central Statistical Services and the private sector will work together to improve the quality and accuracy of some of the data released by the government's statistical service.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- Deputy president Thabo Mbeki will on Thursday acknowledge before the Truth and Reconciliation Commission that the ANC had committed gross human rights violations, including the execution of more than 30 suspected spies at the notorious Quatro camp in Angola.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
