<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8619" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: GROWING DOMESTIC CONSUMPTION FUELS POLISH GROWTH.</title>
<headline>GROWING DOMESTIC CONSUMPTION FUELS POLISH GROWTH.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rising real wages in Poland are spurring domestic consumption which has replaced exports growth as the main engine of economic expansion, the Central Statistical Office (GUS) said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Increasing demand of households...has become one of the major factors, if not the major factor, as far the creation of economic growth is concerned,&quot; GUS deputy president Janusz Witkowski told a news conference.</p>
<p>According to GUS, real wages increased 5.2 percent in the first half of this year, compared with the same period of 1995.</p>
<p>Retail sales were nine percent higher in the January-July period than in the first seven months last year.</p>
<p>&quot;What is important is that the growing dynamics of sales concern mainly non-food products, which shows that the economic condition of households is improving,&quot; Witkowski said.</p>
<p>In the January-June period of 1995, imports growth was not significantly bigger than the rise in exports and both exceeded 30 percent, with the trade deficit amounting to $473 million.</p>
<p>In the first six months of 1996, exports increased only 6.4 percent and imports 30 percent, generating a trade gap of $3.1 billion.</p>
<p>According to the government's Central Planning Office, gross domestic product should grow by about six percent this year.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
