<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8622" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: SLOVAK NPF SEES 10PCT SHARE OF NAFTA FOR EMPLOYEES.</title>
<headline>SLOVAK NPF SEES 10PCT SHARE OF NAFTA FOR EMPLOYEES.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Slovak National Property Fund (NPF) on Thursday said it would amend the recent sale of a major stake in oil and gas storage firm Nafta a.s. to include &quot;at least&quot; a 10 percent stake for company employees.</p>
<p>&quot;The (NPF) will propose an amendment to the contract with Druha Obchodna a.s., the new owner of 45.9 percent of Nafta, stipulating the firm will have to sell a stake representing at least 10 percent of Nafta's basic capital to Nafta employees,&quot; Oto Balogh, NPF spokesman, told Reuters.  </p>
<p>The NPF is the state privatisation agency charged with selling state property.</p>
<p>Earlier on Thursday, NPF President Stefan Gavornik told the official Slovak radio that he expected the NPF presidium, the agency's executive body, to approve the amendment to contract at its meeting on August 27.</p>
<p>The NPF raised eyebrows at the beginning of August when it sold its entire holdings in Nafta to the private, and little- known firm Druha Obchodna for 500 million crowns, far below market value.  </p>
<p>Analysts have said that the parcel of shares had a market value of some 3.2 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Nafta shares closed at 2,000 crowns on BSE on Wednesday while the NPF sale price averaged about 400 crowns per share.</p>
<p>Nafta was originally included on a government list of strategic companies which would not be privatised at all, or in which the government will retain a veto right over the key decisions.</p>
<p>Despite the sale, the government continues to hold the veto right its so-called &quot;golden share&quot;, which was approved by a Nafta shareholders' meeting this spring.</p>
<p>-- Peter Laca, Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
