<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8628" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: CZECH CHEMAPOL PLANS GDR ISSUE BY YEAR END.</title>
<headline>CZECH CHEMAPOL PLANS GDR ISSUE BY YEAR END.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czech trading and chemicals conglomerate Chemapol Group a.s. said on Thursday it was planning a minimum 600 million crown Global Depositary Receipts (GDR) issue by the end of the year.</p>
<p>Chemapol Director Vaclav Junek told a news conference that the Bank of New York would act as depositor for the issue of the receipts, which will carry voting rights for the shares to be registered in the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>The issue, which should be the last tranche of the company's equity expansion plan, would be aranged by the investment bank HSBC and Chemapol's own finance unit Expandia Finance, Junek said.</p>
<p>Details will be discussed at an extraordinary shareholders meeting called for September 20.</p>
<p>&quot;We are, together with HSBC and Expandia Finance ... preparing an international issue which should be realised before the end of the year,&quot; Junek said. &quot;The bottom limit, as proposed, is 600 million crowns.&quot;</p>
<p>Chemapol Group's current basic capital is 1.68 billion crowns. Six Czech banks hold more than 50 percent of the company's stock.</p>
<p>The company, which has holdings ranging from chemical production to media and arms and machinery trading units, also said it would seek listing on the Prague Stock Exchange between now and the first half of the next year.</p>
<p>It is one of the most tightly held large Czech groups, with primarily domestic shareholders and a small fraction of shares traded on the Czech OTC exchange RM-System.</p>
<p>The company declared on Thursday that it had built up an 80 percent stake in the former state arms trading company Omnipol.</p>
<p>The group reported consolidated sales of over 40 billion crowns in 1995 and 29 billion crowns in the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>Chemapol directly holds stakes in 67 companies, and through those companies it holds stakes in various other firms, Junek said.</p>
<p>-- Jan Lopatka, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
