<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8629" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: BUDAPEST BOURSE SUSPENDS DANUBIUS FOR TODAY.</title>
<headline>BUDAPEST BOURSE SUSPENDS DANUBIUS FOR TODAY.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Budapest Stock Exchange (BSE) confirmed floor traders' information and said trading in the shares for hotel chain Danubius was suspended for Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The reason is a news in daily newspaper Nepszabadsag which said that (Hungary's state privatisaton agency) APV sells HungarHotels to Danubius,&quot; a BSE spokeswoman told Reuters.</p>
<p>The bourse official said Danubius itself could not confirm the news.</p>
<p>&quot;At this moment one cannot decide whether the news is true or not and this seriously influences the price of the share,&quot; she said. &quot;That's why we suspended it for today.&quot;</p>
<p>Danubius was unable to confirm the news of the tender decision to Reuters.</p>
<p>Nepszabadsag reported today that the board of APV declared Danubius as the winner for the privatisation tender of Hungaria Szalloda Rt (former HungarHotels) at its meeting on Wednesday.</p>
<p>According to Nepszabadsag Danubius submitted the highest bid, offering more than eight billion forints for the chain which has 14 hotels.</p>
<p>Including the sale of Danubius employee shares APV will raise 8.8 billion forints, Nepszabadsag said.</p>
<p>APV will hold its regular press conference later today.</p>
<p>	 -- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
