<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8631" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: HUNGARIANS MUTED AS THEY MARK 1100 YEARS.</title>
<headline>HUNGARIANS MUTED AS THEY MARK 1100 YEARS.</headline>
<byline>Duncan Shiels</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The city of Budapest turned into a vast pleasure park for four days this week as celebrations to mark 1100 years since the first Hungarian tribes settled in the region reached their climax on the country's national day of August 20.</p>
<p>Streets normally snarled with traffic gave way to music, dance and fireworks while an island in the Danube hosted the biggest and longest pop festival in Europe this summer.</p>
<p>&quot;When the government said it was spending money on celebrating 1100 years of history I thought it could be used for something better,&quot; said Erszebet Kiralyi, as she walked her three children along the traffic-free Danube embankment.</p>
<p>&quot;But I'd forgotten what a beautiful city we have, especially without the cars, so it was probably worth doing.&quot;</p>
<p>Featuring on the two riverside stages -- one below the Royal Palace and the other beside the majestic Parliament built for the 1896 anniversary -- were Hungary's best in jazz and rock plus foreign acts ranging from Italian blues to a Chinese children's folk ensemble.</p>
<p>According to historian Zoltan Vigh, despite the relaxed atmosphere, the mood this year is hardly comparable with the Millenium Exhibition of 1896, when Hungary was one half of a world power, the Austro-Hungarian Empire.</p>
<p>&quot;One hundred years ago Hungary was at the height of economic prosperity,&quot; Vigh said. &quot;It revelled in being one of the great powers and wanted to leave its mark.&quot;</p>
<p>Grand public works sprang up around the city. Apart from a new Parliament, mainland Europe's first underground railway was inaugurated and a new Basilica was unveiled along with an exhibition park featuring replicas of the Empire's finest buildings, all of which survive to this day.</p>
<p>In the century that has passed since then Hungary has been on the losing side in two world wars, lost two thirds of its territory in the treaties of 1920 and for fifty years fell under the shadow of Soviet communism.</p>
<p>Five years after the last Red Army soldier left the country, hope has turned to disillusion for many as the country continues to knock on the closed door of European Union and NATO membership and market forces push real wages down.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1996, the atmosphere is very different from 100 years ago,&quot; Vigh said. &quot;I believe most people are not in the mood to celebrate at such a difficult time. We're independent again but living standards are falling.&quot;</p>
<p>Vigh said most Hungarians have been alienated by the high ticket prices of events such as a recent concert with Placido Domingo, Jose Carreras and Diana Ross, for which the average ticket price was the equivalent of a teacher's weekly salary.</p>
<p>Another dampener on the celebrations has been the furore caused by the last week's breakthrough in negotiations with Romania over a friendship treaty protecting the minority rights.</p>
<p>Opposition politicians have used the commemorations to accuse the government of failing in the treaty to protect ethnic Hungarians living in Romania's Transylvania region, which 100 years ago was part of Hungary.</p>
<p>According to Vigh everyone is probably celebrating the wrong date anyway.</p>
<p>&quot;A hundred years ago, historians found documents that suggested the arrival of the Magyar tribes from the Asian Steppes was actually 895,&quot; he said. &quot;But budgetary problems prompted the authorities to bend history a little.&quot;</p>
<p>Vigh added that a number of scholars have since suggested they could have arrived up to two centuries earlier.</p>
<p>Erzebet Kiralyi does not feel it matters too much if the date is right or not. &quot;For my generation it's myth rather than scientific history,&quot; she said. &quot;My daughter, who is seventeen, can't even relate to a number like 1100 anyway. She thinks it's all so stuffy.&quot;</p>
<p>In fact most of Hungary's youth seem to have spent the last week in a tent city on Obuda Island on the Danube north of the city at a ten-day music festival which offered an alternative to the more traditional fare in the capital.</p>
<p>Five stages and international acts including Therapy, Iggy Pop and the Stone Roses attracted an estimated 250,000 spectators, most of whom ate, slept and partied for the full ten days, cut off from the outside world.</p>
<p>&quot;They can keep their folk costumes and fanfares,&quot; said one reveller. &quot;This is real.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
