<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8636" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: BELGIAN OLOS SOAR, SPREAD WIDENS BUT AUCTION LOOMS.</title>
<headline>BELGIAN OLOS SOAR, SPREAD WIDENS BUT AUCTION LOOMS.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian OLOs climbed sharply across the yield curve on Thursday after the Bundesbank cut its repo rate by a surprise 30 basis points to 3.00 percent and the Belgian central bank followed swiftly with its own rate cuts.</p>
<p>The benchmark 2006 OLO yield tumbled to 6.56 percent from 6.64. Its spread over German paper narrowed by two basis points to 28 -- a result, dealers said, of the Belgian franc's ability to hold onto early strength after the domestic rate move.</p>
<p>However, dealers did not rule out some spread widening again in the days to come, with the prospect of the Treasury's monthly OLO auction looming on Monday.  </p>
<p>&quot;Our currency appreciated. That's why the spread came down today, but it should widen before Monday,&quot; one dealer said. The franc rose to 20.5970/90 to the mark from 20.6010/30 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Belgian bond futures closed 0.61 point up at 116.56 after hitting a contract high of 116.64. One dealer said the market had escaped profit-taking because &quot;a lot of people were taken aback at the size of the German rate cut.&quot;</p>
<p>The National Bank lopped 20 basis points off its central rate -- bringing it back to parity with the German repo -- and the same amount off its end-day-rate, taking that to 4.25.  </p>
<p>Belgian money market yields fell as soon as the Bundesbank move raised expectations of a domestic rate reduction.</p>
<p>Most dealers expected a Belgian cut of 10 to 20 bps. One said he felt happier the central rate was at parity again with the German repo after standing at a discount for several months.</p>
<p>The front-month Bibor future contract stood at the session high of 96.78, rising from 96.57.</p>
<p>One-week repos dropped after the Bundesbank move and closed at 3.03/08 percent, down from 3.22/24 on Wednesday. Three-month T-bill yields fell to 3.10/14 from 3.25/31 the previous session. -- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
