<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8649" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Arequipa not approached by other bidders.</title>
<headline>Arequipa not approached by other bidders.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Takeover target Arequipa Resources Inc said Thursday it has not been approached by any other bidders since it accepted a C$30 a share bid from Barrick Gold Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;The only reason I told Canada AM that I felt there was still a possibiity of a higher bid is that I continue to believe the company has great assets which should be valuable to another number of major international mining companies,&quot; Arequipa president Catherine McLeod said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;But we've not been seriously approached by any other bidder since the date of our agreement with Barrick.&quot;  </p>
<p>On Thursday morning, McLeod told Canada AM, a morning television show on CTV, there was a 40 to 50 percent chance of another bid appearing on Thursday or Friday.</p>
<p>McLeod clarified the comment later in the day.</p>
<p>&quot;Sometimes a surprise bid comes up at the last minute. We're not expecting one particularly,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's always a serious possiblity but we have not been approached by anyone.&quot;</p>
<p>A week ago, Arequipa accepted Barrick's C$30 a share offer.  </p>
<p>All Arequipa directors, including McLeod, and some shareholders have agreed to tender about 23 percent of shares under a lock-up agreement with Barrick.</p>
<p>Arequipa has not had a change of heart, McLeod said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're happy with Barrick,&quot; she said. &quot;We think it's a terrific company. We can't think of any better gold company to develop our assets.&quot;</p>
<p>Under Arequipa's deal with Barrick, Barrick will receive a fee of C$18 million if there is a rival bid of at least C$31.50 a share that Barrick does not match.</p>
<p>Analysts have said only a few companies could afford to match Barrick's offer, which gives shareholders a choice of all cash or a mix of cash and shares.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
