<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8653" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bank Canada rate cut seen as end of cycle-analysts.</title>
<headline>Bank Canada rate cut seen as end of cycle-analysts.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Hodgson</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Canada's lowering of short-term interest rates on Thursday likely marks the end of an easing cycle which began in May, 1995, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is basically the end of the line as far as further rate cuts in Canada. I believe the Bank made that point very clear in its press release,&quot; said Andrew Pyle, chief economist at financial analysis firm Path International.</p>
<p>The Bank of Canada cut its key Bank rate by 25 basis points to 4.25 percent and lowered the target range for its overnight lending rate to 3.75-4.25 percent.  </p>
<p>The move by the Bank of Canada followed an interest rate cut by Germany's Bundesbank which triggered rate reductions in other European countries. Many investors had expected the Bank of Canada to follow a move in German rates.</p>
<p>The Bank of Canada has cut short-term interest rates by a total of 400 basis points since May 8, 1995 and the bank rate is now at its lowest level since March, 1994.</p>
<p>In a statement following the rate cut, the Bank said that the cumulative monetary easing now in place is 'substantial' and can be expected to have a positive impact on the economy over the next year or so.  </p>
<p>&quot;They seemed to me to sending a signal that this is the last one,&quot; said Jim Webber, director of fixed-income research at TD Securities Inc. &quot;They think they've got monetary conditions to where they need to be to get the economy moving again.&quot;</p>
<p>The Bank of Canada's rate reduction was the seventh this year and the sixth done independent of any move by the U.S. Federal Reserve.</p>
<p>The Bank has now brought the center of the target range for its overnight lending rate 125 basis points below the U.S. Federal funds rate.  </p>
<p>Most investors expect the next move from the Fed to be a hike in interest rates. Analysts said the Bank of Canada is wary of allowing Canada-U.S. rate spreads to widen further because of the possibility the Canadian dollar will weaken.</p>
<p>The seven rate cuts the Bank has made this year are enough to stimulate economic growth in Canada, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think now Canada is well positioned to have quite a bit stronger growth,&quot; said Mark Chandler, senior economist with Goldman Sachs Canada. &quot;There is a general perception that this is the last move by the Bank.&quot;  </p>
<p>Further evidence that the Bank has made its last cut can be found in financial markets, analysts said. The Canadian dollar firmed after the rate move on speculation the Bank will not lower rates again. T-bill yields also remained little changed, suggesting the money market is not expecting another cut anytime soon.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea that the Bank is out of the way helped our currency and it's also caused a backup in our money market. Usually the two go in opposite directions,&quot; said Goldman's Chandler.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto bureau (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
