<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8656" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Teck to determine gain on DFR stake.</title>
<headline>Teck to determine gain on DFR stake.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Teck Corp said Thursday it expects to determine within the next few days the exact amount of its gain on its 10.4 percent stake in Diamond Fields Resources Inc, which was bought out by Inco Ltd.</p>
<p>Teck chief financial officer John Taylor said the mining company would likely issue a news release in the next few days. The gain would be booked in the third quarter. Teck acquired its stake in Diamond Fields for C$108 million.</p>
<p>Inco closed Wednesday its C$4.3 billion takeover of Diamond Fields. Teck said Thursday it would issue up to C$280 million of debentures exchangeable into Inco common stock.  </p>
<p>Under terms of the Diamond Fields takeover, Teck will receive a mix of securities and cash including 5.5 million to 5.8 million Inco common shares.</p>
<p>Taylor said calculating Teck's gain must await an announcement from Inco on the exact mix of cash and securities that shareholders will receive. Teck elected to receive the maxmimum cash possible under the offer but the exact ratios depend on balancing what all shareholders choose, he said.</p>
<p>Inco is expected to me an announcement on final terms soon.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
