<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8666" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Semiconductor laser maker SDL shares slide.</title>
<headline>Semiconductor laser maker SDL shares slide.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO</dateline>
<text>
<p>The stock of SDL Inc. lost nearly a third of its value Thursday after the semiconductor laser maker told analysts that third quarter sales would be flat with the prior quarter's because a manufacturing problem was reducing output.</p>
<p>SDL stock fell $9 to $19 on Nasdaq, where it was among the most active issues.</p>
<p>SDL said its yield, or the number of flawless dye -- the silicon squares that eventually become chips -- per wafer was down in three of its product lines. Also, executives said they had not yet found the root of the problem.</p>
<p>As a consequence, SDL said it would be late in delivering some orders and has had to turn away some new orders as well.</p>
<p>It said revenues should be about the same as the second quarter's $21.6 million -- a sudden halt for the high-flying company whose revenues grew 83 percent in the year's first half.</p>
<p>San Jose-based SDL makes semiconductor lasers, semiconductor optoelecronic integrated circuits and fiber optic related products. Its market is largely the telecommunications industry, which is fast upgrading its equipment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
