<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8667" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: States' suits expand to tobacco law firms.</title>
<headline>States' suits expand to tobacco law firms.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Gail Appleson, Law Correspondent</p>
<p>The attack on cigarette makers took a bold turn Thursday when the state of Oklahoma sued a powerful law firm that has been the tobacco industry's first line of legal defense for more than 40 years.</p>
<p>The lawsuit by Oklahoma, which became the 14th state to sue the industry, was the latest latest blow to tobacco companies still reeling from a $750,000 verdict against Brown &amp; Williamson Tobacco Corp. in a Florida case on Aug. 9.</p>
<p>Separately, just a day before the White House was expected to endorse tough new federal regulations on cigarettes, an Indianapolis jury started deliberations in an important smoker's wrongful death case.</p>
<p>The suit filed by Oklahoma Attorney General Drew Edmondson was a dramatic step because few lawyers have tried to take on the Kansas City, Mo., firm of Shook, Hardy &amp; Bacon, which has represented tobacco companies since 1954.</p>
<p>In its suit to recover more than $1 billion in state funds spent to treat smoking-related illnesses, Oklahoma named the nation's largest cigarette makers, the public relations firm of Hill &amp; Knowlton, Inc., two New York law firms, Chadbourne and Parke and Jacob, Medinger and Finnegan, and Shook, Hardy.</p>
<p>The suit accused the law firms of helping the tobacco companies conceal the health risks of smoking and alleged they kept documents confidential by claiming they were protected by attorney-client privilege.</p>
<p>Shook, Hardy has come under growing scrutiny since 1994 when internal Brown &amp; Williamson documents surfaced that suggested the law firm worked with tobacco companies to generate favorable scientific reports.</p>
<p>The documents led a group of congressmen to ask the Justice Department to investigate Shook Hardy as part of a criminal probe of the industry and the firm's records have since been subpoenaed in several civil cases.</p>
<p>Tobacco companies are currently the target of several federal investigations examining whether the industry hid information about the health hazards of smoking and whether its top executives lied about nicotine and addiction.</p>
<p>Despite the growing concerns about Shook Hardy's role, lawyers have been reluctant to name the firm in lawsuits. Oklahoma in its suit became the first state to do so.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very serious charge for an attorney to accuse his or her fellow professional with fraud and deceitful conduct,&quot; said Clifford Douglas, an Evanston, Ill., consultant to lawyers suing the tobacco industry. &quot;Attorneys just don't sue other attorneys.&quot;</p>
<p>He said there would need to be overwhelming evidence for lawyers to take such action.</p>
<p>Shook, Hardy had no immediate comment on the suit.</p>
<p>Last week Shook, Hardy was named in two lawsuits brought by individuals in New York and New Jersey. The plaintiffs' lawyer in those cases, Steven Kramer of New York City, said Thursday that he thought he was the only other lawyer to sue Shook, Hardy.</p>
<p>Kramer said he planned to file a similar case next month on behalf of former talk show host Morton Downey, Jr., who has lung cancer.</p>
<p>Shook, Hardy's relationship with the industry dates back to 1954, when Philip Morris hired the firm's prominent litigator David Hardy to defend it against a suit filed by a Missouri smoker who lost his larynx to cancer. The firm, which only had 16 lawyers at the time, is now one of the biggest in Kansas City, with some 250 lawyers.</p>
<p>The Oklahoma suit, filed in a state court in Cleveland County, named Philip Morris Cos. Inc., the world's largest cigarette maker, RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp.'s R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co.; Brown &amp; Williamson, a unit of B.A.T Industries Plc ; Loews Corp.'s Lorillard Tobacco Co. Inc. and American Brands Inc., among others.</p>
<p>The suit also named trade groups The Council for Tobacco Research USA and The Tobacco Institute. The suit followed litigation filed against the industry this week in Kansas, Arizona and Michigan. New Jersey has plans to sue the industry and Hawaii, Utah and Arkansas are considering actions.</p>
<p>In Washington, Clinton was expected to announce measures on Friday aimed at keeping youths from taking up the smoking habit. Under the original proposals made a year ago, cigarette companies would be barred from placing billboard ads near schools and playgrounds. Other measures would eliminate vending machines, free samples, sales of fewer than 20 cigarettes and mail-order.</p>
<p>Tobacco company stocks sank again as investors nervously eyed developments. Philip Morris fell 87.5 cents to $86.75 after sinking $3.875 on Wednesday, Lowes lost $1.50 to $75.125 after sliding $1.25 on Wednesday, and RJR lost 12.5 cents to $25.125 after falling $1.375 on Wednesday, all on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
