<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8668" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: UAW breaks tradition, delays strike target choice.</title>
<headline>UAW breaks tradition, delays strike target choice.</headline>
<byline>David Lawder</byline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>In a stunning break with tradition, the United Auto Workers Thursday delayed choosing  a strike target among Detroit's Big Three automakers and said it may try to hammer out new labor contracts simultaneously with all three companies.</p>
<p>UAW President Stephen Yokich said he postponed the decision to allow for unprecedented meetings Thursday and Friday with the chairmen of General Motors Corp., Ford Motor Co. and Chrysler Corp.. The CEOs normally do not join in the talks until days before a settlement.</p>
<p>Yokich said he would give each of the executives a chance to demonstrate their desire for a quick contract settlement and show why they should lead bargaining with the union.</p>
<p>&quot;There might not be a need&quot; for a target company this year, Yokich told a news conference after meeting with 500 UAW leaders from around the nation. &quot;We're not going to have a target per se.&quot;</p>
<p>However, he added that he may still choose a &quot;lead company&quot; as early as Sunday.</p>
<p>Bargaining with each of the automakers has been unusually productive this year, Yokich said, and he does not want to thwart that progress now by focusing on a single automaker.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a strategic move to gain a bit of leverage in the union's favor,&quot; said Harley Shaiken, a professor of labor relations at the University of California-Berkeley. He added that the move creates more suspense for the automakers.</p>
<p>&quot;It's good common, honest sense,&quot; Yokich said of his decision to continue bargaining with all three automakers. &quot;If you've got three companies that are moving along in their negotiations and these three companies want to reach agreement, you don't stop them,&quot; Yokich said. &quot;You meet with them.&quot;</p>
<p>Contracts covering over 400,000 UAW hourly workers are due to expire Sept. 14.</p>
<p>Historically, the union has focused its bargaining on a single automaker for an agreement that serves as a pattern for the other two to follow. The selection of the target is normally a major event in the triennial talks, and the UAW had raised expectations by scheduling its announcement Thursday.</p>
<p>Many analysts had said Chrysler's strong profits and lack of a need to shed jobs made it the front-runner to be the target, but Thursday's decision appeared to put each automaker on an equal footing. All of the companies have been unusually vocal about their eagerness to lead the talks.</p>
<p>The target firm faces the threat of a national strike if its contract expires with no new agreement, but Yokich said the union was focused on avoiding a strike this year.</p>
<p>Yokich, who became UAW president last year and has a reputation for breaking traditions, won praise for his strategy from UAW local leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;It's something different. This is Steve Yokich,&quot; said Bruce Perry, president of UAW Local 95 at GM's Janesville, Wis., truck plant. &quot;I think it's visionary. We're going to see which of the Big Three can best meet our needs.&quot;</p>
<p>Each of the automakers said they respected the UAW's decision, acknowledged progress in their talks and said they would continue to work toward a settlement.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to be the target and we believe the solid tradition of trust and openness between Ford and the UAW will serve us well throughout this bargaining process,&quot; Ford said in a statement.</p>
<p>Wall Street analysts said the UAW's unusual move was a positive sign.</p>
<p>&quot;Yokich is coming out and saying, 'We're pretty close to an agreement here, and if we are, let's just get it done,'&quot; said PaineWebber's Michael Ward. &quot;If that's true, that tells me it's pretty much a carryover contract and that's a positive development for the stocks.&quot;</p>
<p>GM's shares rose 37.5 cents to $51.50, while Ford rose 62.5 cents to $34 and Chrysler gained 25 cents to $29.75 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>UAW leaders attending Thursday's meeting said negotiators have a long way to go to resolve outsourcing and job security issues, which they singled out as the toughest on this year's bargaining table.</p>
<p>&quot;I cannot compete with somebody on the outside who is making less money than I am,&quot; said Edward McNulty, president of UAW Local 14 at GM's Toledo, Ohio, transmission plant. &quot;We have a major problem with global sourcing.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
