<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8683" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RESEARCH ALERT- DLJ cites SDL Q3 concerns.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT- DLJ cites SDL Q3 concerns.</headline>
<text>
<p>-- Donaldson Lufkin analyst Krishna Shankar said SDL Inc continues to have difficulties with manufacturing yields in its semiconductor chip production in the current quarter, according to research provided to Reuters.</p>
<p>-- As a result, Shankar expects the current third quarter's revenues to be flat sequentially at $22 million, with earnings of $0.21 per share, the report said.</p>
<p>-- He maintained his outperform rating on the stock.</p>
<p>-- The analyst said the company's third quarter product shipments and gross profit margins have come under pressure due to higher production costs, according to the research.  </p>
<p>-- However, he warned that the margin assumptions in his current quarter estimates could be aggressive &quot;given that the magnitude of the problems and their effect on operating results will not be known until later in the quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>-- The DLJ analyst maintained his fiscal year 1996 revenue estimate of $88 million and earnings estimate of $0.80 per share and the &quot;conservative&quot; estimates for fiscal 1997 of $115 million and $1.15 per share, the report said.</p>
<p>-- SDL stock tumbled as much as 13 points to a low of 15 in morning trading. By early afternoon the stock stood at 17-7/8, down 10-1/8 points since Wednesday's close.  </p>
<p>-- Shankar was not available for comment on the research report.</p>
<p>-- The manufacturing yield problem was discussed in the company's recent 10-Q filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, the analyst said in the report.</p>
<p>-- Shankar may consider raising his fiscal 1997 earnings estimate, depending on the speed of capacity additions and if demand for its products by telecommunications and cable companies remains strong, he wrote.  </p>
<p>-- The analyst maintained a 12-month target price on the stock based on a 30 times multiple of his calendar 1997 earnings estimate of $1.15 per share, according to the report.</p>
<p>-- He continued to project a five-year secular earnings per share growth rate of 35 percent for SDL, which he said was the dominant maker of high-power semiconductor lasers and integrated optoelectronics, with a 60 percent world share.</p>
<p>-- The analyst's comments coincide with a move by Cowen &amp; Co analyst Drew Peck to cut his 1996 per-share earnings estimate on SDL by $0.13 to $0.68 and to lower his 1997 estimate by $0.04 to $1.00, according to the brokerage.</p>
<p>-- DLJ was the underwriter of a recent offering of SDL stock and of previous share offerings by the company. Cowen was a co-manager of the recent offering.</p>
<p>-- Eric Auchard, New York Newsdesk 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
