<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8686" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RESEARCH ALERT - Acesita neutral rating maintained.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - Acesita neutral rating maintained.</headline>
<text>
<p>-- Merrill Lynch &amp; Co said it is maintaining its neutral rating on Brazilian steelmaker Acesita following release of the company's first-half earnings and raised its estimates for the firm's projected year-end loss.</p>
<p>-- The bank cited Acesita's worse-than-expected performance in the second quarter and a deterioration in the firm's total debt to total debt plus equity ratio.</p>
<p>-- Merrill Lynch said the firm posted a net loss of 8.4 million reais in the second quarter against a Merrill Lynch forecast for a 2.8 million real net profit.  </p>
<p>-- Slightly lower prices for Acesita's products were mostly to blame for the result, it said.</p>
<p>-- The brokerage also said it has raised its estimate for 1996 losses at the firm to 11.2 million reais from an earlier projection of a 1.2 million-real loss to reflect the poor quarterly performance.</p>
<p>-- &quot;Continued losses from the company's not-flat line also hurt profitability for the quarter,&quot; Merrill Lynch said.  </p>
<p>-- It added that a large short-term liability for its participation in CST has appeared on Acesita's balance sheet and has caused &quot;the total-debt-to-total-debt-plus-equity ratio to deteriorate from .27 in the first quarter to .46 in the second quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Acesita preferred was down 0.08 reais at 2.35 reais while its voting common was off 0.04 reais at 2.62 reais at 1311 local time/1611 GMT on the Sao Paulo bolsa.</p>
<p>-- James Craig, Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 232 4411</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
