<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8697" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bally's Grand holders grumble over merger.</title>
<headline>Bally's Grand holders grumble over merger.</headline>
<byline>Bob Tourtellotte</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>As the billion-dollar merger of Bally Entertainment Inc and Hilton Hotels Corp nears, a small group of Bally's Grand Inc shareholders are grumbling about the deal and the Bally chairman's nearly $16 million termination fee.</p>
<p>The group, including one member who is suing Bally Entertainment, says Bally Grand's sale of land for its Las Vegas &quot;Paris&quot; casino to Bally Entertainment for $60 million leaves Bally's Grand without any opportunity for growth.  </p>
<p>&quot;Without the land, (Bally's Grand) has no growth opportunity,&quot; said Russ Roth, publisher of The Las Vegas Investment Report, a small gambling stock newsletter. &quot;They would be a one site property for the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>News of the deal caused Bally's Grand shares to drop 16 percent to 36-7/8 on Wednesday from 43-3/4 on August 14. The stock bounced back on Thursday, gaining 2-1/8 to 39.</p>
<p>The shareholders complain that, while they lost millions in market value, Bally Entertainment Chairman Arthur Goldberg will receive millions in cash compensation.  </p>
<p>A Securities and Exchange Commission document filed Wednesday by Hilton, says Goldberg will receive a $15.8 million termination fee and become a Hilton consultant when the deal is done.</p>
<p>The cash and job are beyond the value of his Bally stock when it's swapped for Hilton shares.</p>
<p>A Hilton spokesman declined to comment beyond the SEC filing and Bally Entertainment officials were not available.</p>
<p>One Bally's Grand stockholder, Alan Kahn, amended an old suit against Bally Entertainment seeking to stop the sale of the Paris land, which could slow the merger.</p>
<p>Hilton's main goal in doing the deal is to expand operations and &quot;Paris&quot; is a big part of the plan. Whether Kahn can actually stop the deal, however, is another matter.</p>
<p>Bally Entertainment owns 85 percent of Bally's Grand, manages their casino, effectively controls their board. And in a 10-Q filing last week revealing the sale, it said the deal was approved by &quot;an independent special committee.&quot;</p>
<p>Hilton has set a shareholder meeting for September 19 to vote on the deal. Bally Entertainment's has been scheduled for one day earlier.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
