<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8707" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. crudes bounce to firm levels, grades weaken.</title>
<headline>U.S. crudes bounce to firm levels, grades weaken.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. crudes gained to the close Thursday, ignoring headline-based jitters on possible impending Iraqi oil sales, traders said.</p>
<p>Fundamental bullishness in the heating oil sector, and the threat of extended delays to Mexican crude exports due to Hurricane Dolly buffeted the market.</p>
<p>Domestic grades were sold at weaker levels in extremely thin business ahead of Friday's nominations.</p>
<p>September West Texas Intermediate/Cushing ended at $22.40-$22.55, figuring in the Sep/Oct roll at 20-25 cents. The roll retreated from earlier asking levels at 35 cents.  </p>
<p>Mexico's three main crude export ports: Pajaritos, Dos Bocas and Cayo Arcas, remained closed Thursday because of the threat from Dolly, which was reclassified as a hurricane.</p>
<p>Dolly gained strength late Thursday, forcing hurricane warnings to be issued along Mexico's northeast coast.</p>
<p>Developments at the United Nations seemed to indicate the implementation of the oil-for-food accord was within reach. Senior U.N. officials said the deal would be finalized in at least 10 days.</p>
<p>Domestic grades slipped to lower levels throughout the session, with October business looming over fading September.</p>
<p>Light Louisiana Sweet/St James was last heard traded at a 10 cents discount to WTI/Cushing, with Midland/WTI sold at 4 cents under the WTI price.</p>
<p>West Texas Sour/Midland traded late at minus $1.65, losing another 5 cents from early afternoon price levels.</p>
<p>The Sep/Oct roll was done at 20 and 22 cents, forcing the WTI/Cushing Posting Plus to under $2.00 by the end of the day.</p>
<p>Late Brent trading in the U.S. was confined to only partial outright deals, with a handful of paper spreads sold.</p>
<p>Traders said October Brent was done for a 250 lot parcel at $20.76, 3 cents higher than the IPE Brent close, and a second time at the same price for a separate 300 lot sale.</p>
<p>A further 50 lots were sold at $20.75 for October paper.</p>
<p>The Sep/Oct Brent spread was heard done at 55 cents, and the Oct/Nov at 46 cents in the aftermarket window.</p>
<p>--Patrick Connole, New York Energy Desk, +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
