<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8712" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Leucadia unit sues Nicaragua over $26 mln.</title>
<headline>Leucadia unit sues Nicaragua over $26 mln.</headline>
<byline>George Lerner</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nicaragua faced a fresh hurdle over its onerous debt burden Thursday when a creditor filed suit in U.S. federal court to recover long defaulted obligations.</p>
<p>LNC Investments Inc, a unit of Leucadia National Corp, sued Nicaragua to recover approximately $26 million of principal payments, plus interest and penalties accrued since 1986.</p>
<p>Nicaragua has long been in default on the payments, LNC said in its suit.  </p>
<p>Monetary authorities in Nicaragua were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>In its suit, LNC said that Nicaragua was in default of its obligations and had not paid LNC any of the amounts owed. The dates by which the full amount of the obligations were to have been paid have long passed, the complaint said.</p>
<p>LNC, which had bought the commercial debt on the secondary market, refrained from participating in settlement last year between Nicaragua and most of its creditors.  </p>
<p>In December 1995, Nicaragua used loans from the World Bank and other donors to buy back 81 percent of its commercial bank debt, paying creditors eight cents on the dollar to retire about $1.1 billion of debt obligations.</p>
<p>But LNC and other investors who altogether hold around $200 million of commercial debt did not participate in the buyback, preferring to hold out for a better deal.</p>
<p>&quot;We decided not to go into the buyback believing that sometime in the future something would be able to be done with the debt that would have more value than just 8 cents,&quot; said Peter Pessoa, the International Bank of Miami, which purchased some of Nicaragua's debt on behalf of clients.</p>
<p>Nicaragua, one of the poorest country's in the hemisphere, faces an uphill battle against a heavy debt burden. The World Bank and International Monetary Fund considered the country's debt, matched against its paucity of exports and miniscule gross domestic product to be unsustainable.</p>
<p>The country has managed to convince several lender nations to forgive or reduce the amount of Nicaraguan debt.</p>
<p>But the debt remains onerous, as Nicaragua struggles to emerge from economic ruin. Nicaragua said the economy would expand by about five percent in 1996, the third consecutive year of growth after a decade of declines.</p>
<p>The impoverished state of the nation, coupled with its dim prospects for recovery, meant that most Wall Street analysts saw little opportunity for Nicaragua to borrow funds from the international capital markets.</p>
<p>-- 212 859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
