<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8724" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: LDC debts edge higher, Ecuador slips on oil row.</title>
<headline>LDC debts edge higher, Ecuador slips on oil row.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most emerging market debt prices added small gains in featureless trade, but Ecuador debt retreated after the government's move to ban oil production by a U.S. company, traders said.</p>
<p>Maxus Energy Corp, which is owned by Argentina's largest energy company YPF, was told late Tuesday to stop oil production until a new production sharing agreement is signed. Although the government has pressed to renegotiate the contract, the abrupt ban unnerved foreign invenstors, said a Brady bond trader.  </p>
<p>&quot;The confidence in the Bucaram government was shaky to begin with,&quot; he said. &quot;This unilateral action struck a raw nerve.&quot;</p>
<p>Ecuador's Brady bonds tumbled when the populist candidate Abdala Bucaram won the run-off election in early July. Since then prices have recovered some lost ground, but remaining volatile.</p>
<p>Omar Borla, chief Latin America economist at Robert Fleming Inc, said now that the honeymoon period for the new government is largely over, the &quot;ideological problem&quot; will come under closer scrutiny.  </p>
<p>Bucaram may have made a brilliant move by retaining the ex-Argentine finance minister Domingo Cavallo as adivor, but his opportunism during the campaign and conflicting policy remarks during his visit to New York left the investment community wary, Borla said.</p>
<p>Ecuador Pars eased 1/4 to 37-1/5, and Discount lost 3/4 to 57-1/2.</p>
<p>Argentina FRB forces broke its recent losing streak, creeping up 1/4 to 76-7/8.  </p>
<p>The economic package now in Congress would undergo a protracted period of wrangling between political and econonomic forces.</p>
<p>&quot;The ball is on the political side,&quot; said Borla, who was concerned if the new economy minister Roque Fernandez could withstand the pressure.</p>
<p>With investors buying in Mexico's strong recovery -- as evidenced by its 7.2 percent gross domestic product growth in the second quarter -- Mexico Bradies continued climbing, traders said.  </p>
<p>Mexico Pars rose 3/8 to 67-3/4 and Discount gained 3/4 to 81-1/4.</p>
<p>Russia rebounded from Wednesday's selloff. The disbursement of the delayed $330 million aid by IMF helped, traders said.</p>
<p>Russia dollar Vnesh rose 7/8 to 60-1/2 and Min Fin 4 gained 1.00 to 48-7/8.</p>
<p>-- Nailene Chou Wiest, 212-859-1674</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
