<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8729" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US corporate bonds close flat, tobacco debt singed.</title>
<headline>US corporate bonds close flat, tobacco debt singed.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. corporate bonds were unchanged at the close with the marked exception of tobacco company debt, which fell further as the industry continued to feel legislative and litigous pressure.</p>
<p>RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp 8.75 percent notes widened more than 20 basis points by the close, although quotes were widely scattered. The notes were 30 basis points wider at mid-session, traders noted, at 300 bid, 280 offer.</p>
<p>Tobacco debt has been roiled by accumulating lawsuits from several U.S. states and news the White House will soon release rules resticting tobacco sales, traders said.  </p>
<p>White House officials said the pending curbs would range from banning cigarette vending machines to limiting cigarette sponsorship of sporting and entertainment events popular with young crowds.</p>
<p>The 8.75 percent notes have widened a stunning 77 basis points since last week when they traded at a 223 bid, 215 offer. They had moved out to a 245 offer by last Monday.</p>
<p>Spreads on higher-credit Philip Morris Cos Inc debt widened five basis points. The notes due 2006 were quoted at a spread of 98 bid, 93 offer.  </p>
<p>In ratings news, Moody's Investors Service downgraded the senior debt rating of Pacfic Bell to A1 from Aa3, citing the company's inability to generate consistent cash flows. The debt was already trading &quot;like a low single-A&quot; credit and was therefore unaffected by the downgrade, traders said.</p>
<p>Pacific Bell bullet maturity 7.125 percent debt due 2026 was quoted unchanged at 62 bid, 61 offer at the close. The debt widened slightly when the downgrade hit the tapes.</p>
<p>Investment grade trade was otherwise focused on Citicorp's $200 million 12-year subordinated note issue, priced to yield 7.362 percent, or 74 basis points over the 10-year T-note.  </p>
<p>The deal priced at the wider side of price talk, one trader said, and was said to be well-received.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the U.S. Agency for International Development priced $1.0 billion in a multi-tranche Yankee debt offering via Lehman Brothers and Merrill Lynch &amp; Co Inc. A total of $533 million fixed-rate debt was sold in four tranches to yield from 3.4 basis points to 18.6 basis points over Treasuries. Another $472 million (proceeds) zero coupon debt was priced in forty tranches to yield between 7.003 percent and 7.421 percent.</p>
<p>The entire deal is AAA/AAA rated.  </p>
<p>U.S. Treasuries came under significant selling pressure as players hedged the gilt-edged Israeli debt with 10- and 30-year U.S. government futures, analysts said. The benchmark 30-year bond was little changed overall, however, and closed down 2/32 to 98-27/32 to yield 6.84 percent.</p>
<p>Back in the corporate debt arena, investment-grade trade was quiet and spreads were mostly unchanged, dealers said.</p>
<p>The high-yield market overall was firm to up 1/8, dealers said, but volume was also thin in this arena.</p>
<p>Trading centered around Omnipoint Corp's new 144A issue of $150 million in 10-year senior notes which closed early on Thursday. The notes priced at par to yield 11.625 percent and traded up to a 101-1/8 bid, 101-3/8 offer market where they stood at the close.</p>
<p>The issue traded up despite mounting indigestion in the sector which has forced the cancellation or restructuring of several other deals in the past month.</p>
<p>The Omnipoint deal has a two-year interest reserve feature, one trader noted, giving it additional luster.</p>
<p>--Al Yoon, 212-859-1672</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
