<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8734" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Labor official rejects Phelps pay freeze at Chino.</title>
<headline>Labor official rejects Phelps pay freeze at Chino.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Steelworkers of America officials said they rejected a move by copper producer Phelps Dodge Corp to impose a wage freeze on workers at the company's Chino mine in New Mexico.</p>
<p>Robert Guadiana, USWA's lead negotiator said the union rejected a pay freeze, which he described as &quot;insulting&quot;, but added that on Thursday, the union scaled-back its pay demand.</p>
<p>The union wants a three-year pay deal and originally sought a hike of $2.00 per hour in the first year followed by a $1.00 per hour rise in the following two years.  </p>
<p>Guadiana said on Thursday the union scaled back the pay demand to $1.85 per hour in the first year, with a $1.00 in the second and third year.</p>
<p>Phelps Dodge wants a pay freeze for a contract ending on November 15, 2000 - over four years in length. The company originally wanted a six-year deal ending in 2002.</p>
<p>&quot;I am insisting on a three-year contract,&quot; Guadiana said.</p>
<p>The union has also scaled back its demand relating to pension benefits.  </p>
<p>The USWA was irked by Phelps insistence that increments paid to workers only kick in when copper prices are over $1.00 per pound instead of from 80 cents under the previous three-year contract which ended on June 30.</p>
<p>&quot;The company is adamant that the price of copper is going to go nowhere but down for the next few years, and yet they have cut the COMEX price grid to start paying at $1.00 per pound,&quot; Guadiana said.</p>
<p>Spot copper closed at 91.15 cents per pound on COMEX Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
