<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8736" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Investors grab Intel Corp calls.</title>
<headline>U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Investors grab Intel Corp calls.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Intel Corp call options attracted buyers as the semiconductor maker's stock rallied after the stock was upgraded.</p>
<p>Intel shares rose 2-3/4 to 83 on heavy volume of 7.2 million shares. It was the most active stock on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>The Intel September 80 call, which rose 1-5/8 to 4-5/8, drew the most attention, with 2,605 contracts changing hands.</p>
<p>The September 70 call traded 2,100 contracts and the September 85 call traded about 1,725, making the 70, 80 and 85 the most active. Farther out, the October 85 call traded nearly 1,150 contracts.  </p>
<p>Predictably, put activity was slim, with the most active issue the September 85 put. It fell 1-7/8 to 3-7/8 on turnover of 933 contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like we're getting a lot more call activity compared to puts,&quot; said Joseph Sunderman, an analyst at the Investment Research Institute in Cincinnati. &quot;That's reflecting the upside in the shares.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said the Intel options activity appeared to be investors buying calls and selling puts as the stock rallied.  </p>
<p>&quot;They're adding puts,&quot; one trader said, noting that technology stocks rallied across the board and contributed to a sharp rise in the Nasdaq composite index.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw the techs really pick up their heads,&quot; another trader said. &quot;That came as a shock.&quot;</p>
<p>Sunderman said that although Intel shares reached resistance at 83 and call buying was increasing, the stock should have more upside potential.</p>
<p>Over the last couple of weeks, investors had been largely liquidating call positions and adding puts -- a bullish sign from a contrarian standpoint, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We believe the shares still have further to rally,&quot; he added. Over the last couple of weeks, he said, the investors who liquidated calls and added puts on the view that the stock's rally had run its course were wrong.</p>
<p>He said the stock's upside momentum should help keep it on a rising track and that any downside consolidation should find support in the 77 region, a past resistance area.</p>
<p>--Gregory Crawford, (312) 408-8750</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
