<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8741" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Buba, Fed tactics won't halt dlr rise toward 1.60.</title>
<headline>Buba, Fed tactics won't halt dlr rise toward 1.60.</headline>
<byline>Alden Bentley</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite the Bundesbank's surprizingly large interest rate cut on Thursday, further widening of the dollar's short-term interest rate advantage may be some way off, economists said.</p>
<p>But the the dollar may still head to 1.55 or 1.60 marks by year end, regardless of the time or direction of the next interest rate moves, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are clearly looking for dollar/mark to rise further,&quot; said Citibank economist Robert Blake.  </p>
<p>But Blake said the bank's 1.60 mark year-end forecast is not simply a function of interest rate spreads, which the firm's year-end forecasts imply will stay relatively steady.</p>
<p>Spreads between short-term German and U.S. money market rates widened out almost immediatly after the Bundesbank cut its securities repurchase -- or &quot;repo&quot; -- rate 30 basis points on Thursday.</p>
<p>The German central bank punctuated a four-year easing cycle by fixing this key overnight borrowing rate to a record low 3.0 percent, leaving some pondering if German rates will next start heading back up.  </p>
<p>Its official discount and Lombard rates -- the floor and ceiling for German money market rates -- were left steady at 2.5 percent and 4.5 percent, respectively, as expected.</p>
<p>In the wake of the Federal Reserve's decision to leave U.S. interest rates unchanged on Tuesday, analysts said the next Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting on September 24 also will likely yield no action.</p>
<p>The earliest to expect a U.S. rate hike is after the November presidential election, they added.</p>
<p>The German repo stood steady at 3.3 percent since February and most market forecasts sought only a 10-basis-point cut.  </p>
<p>The dollar soared more than a pfennig, peaking at 1.4964 marks after the Bundesbank acted. This level remains a key technical hurdle for the growing camp viewing this as the last easing in a prolonged cycle.</p>
<p>But they seem to hold the minority opinion in the market.</p>
<p>In contrast, the dollar fell on Thursday after the Bank of Canada cut its Bank Rate 25 basis points to 4.25 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said for a country with virtually no inflation, falling interest rates combined with improving current account and fiscal deficits make the Canadian dollar an alluring North American option.  </p>
<p>&quot;You're probably going to get pretty good pick-up on the longer end on bonds, and you'll probably be able to get some currency appreciation,&quot; said David Durrant, senior currency strategist at I.D.E.A. Inc. &quot;So, if you like U.S. assets you're going to really like Canadian assets.&quot;</p>
<p>Even if the Buba has another easing in the pipeline, the dollar could suffer in the short-to-medium term if the market grows wary of waiting another several months for the next cut.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem is timing here,&quot; said Durrant. &quot;Possibly 90 days is too far forward to be currently in the equation.  </p>
<p>&quot;Short-term, the market will take a look at the Bundesbank cut and say that is it and probably begin to buy marks.&quot;</p>
<p>The release of U.S. August employment data on September 6 may be an important marker on the road to the next Fed action.</p>
<p>But strong non-farm payrolls data should only sharpen the focus on the November 13 and December 17 FOMC meetings.</p>
<p>Durrant said August payrolls will most likely be strong and unemployment should therefore decline.</p>
<p>&quot;On that, the market should start to change its way of looking at things and maybe look for an interest rate increase in the U.S.,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;But we'll also be in the heat of an election process at that point, and one has to question if it is November, post-election, before we see any sort of move in interest rates.&quot;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Citibank forecast no U.S. rate hike this year. But it does look for further easing in the Buba's repo rate, implying no change in yield spreads by year-end, Blake said.</p>
<p>Gabriele Lamers, international economist at Bank of Boston, agreed the Bundesbank has scope to cut the repo another 30 to 50 points, after a successful rate action.  </p>
<p>She cited falling German bond yields and widening spreads over U.S. bond rates as evidence the Bundesbank gained credibility Thursday by lowering the cost of capital in Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;Does this mean the end of the line for the Bundesbank? I would say no, because it was successful and because there is still a lot of room for the Bundesbank to go before hitting the floor of the discount rate,&quot; Lamar said.</p>
<p>&quot;By and large, this should be positive for the dollar between now and the end of year,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1667</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
