<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8750" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: No settlement talks in Lloyd's case - U.S. lawyer. [CORRECTED 22:08 GMT]</title>
<headline>No settlement talks in Lloyd's case - U.S. lawyer. [CORRECTED 22:08 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Lorrie Grant</byline>
<dateline>RICHMOND, Va. 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A federal judge on Thursday delayed for one day a decision whether to allow a reorganization for Lloyd's of London to go forward, but a lawyer in the case denied there were any negotiations going on to settle the matter out of court.</p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Robert Payne was expected to rule on whether to uphold an injunction blocking the financially-strapped markets' recovery plan of nearly $5 billion, but by mid-morning had decided to withold judgement until Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no settlement negotiations going on. I don't think (the delay)  bears any relation to the merits of the case or what the judge is deciding,&quot; said Chris Lyman, attorney at Kilpatrick and Cody, which represents 93 investors who brought the lawsuit.</p>
<p>Lyman told Reuters he expected a ruling between 1 p.m. and 5 p.m. EDT (1700 GMT and 2100 GMT) on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think think he's giving it careful thought and study,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;The opinion is expected to be issued in the afternoon of Friday, August 23,&quot; the federal court said in a one-sentence statement.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't discuss these things,&quot; Judge Payne said, when asked by a Reuter reporter about the delay.</p>
<p>Local lawyers for Lloyd's were not immediately available for comment and did not return telephone calls.</p>
<p>The 93 investors or Names -- individuals who pledge assets to back the insurance policies sold at Lloyd's -- are seeking to block the reorganization plan whereby Lloyd's would reinsure billions in liabilities by creating a new reinsurance company, Equitas.</p>
<p>(Corrects to indicate that investors are not from Virginia).</p>
<p>Under the plan, the investors are being asked to pay up to $150,000 to help fund Equitas. The Virginia investors filed suit instead after Lloyd's declined to provide detailed financial information about Equitas, as is required under U.S. securities laws.</p>
<p>Judge Payne indicated his concern was that U.S. investors were adequately protected. He also scolded the Securities and Exchange Commission for not taking up the matter.</p>
<p>Lloyd's chief executive, Ronald Sandler, admitted in court that the British Embassy had arranged a meeting in Washington between SEC and Lloyd's officials prior to the court hearing. Sandler testified he wanted to make the SEC aware of the August 28 deadline for Names to vote on acceptance of the recovery plan.</p>
<p>&quot;My particular purpose was to ensure the SEC understood we were dealing with a process in the reconstruction plan. I felt they needed to be aware of the time table,&quot; Sandler testified in court.</p>
<p>The SEC was asked to reconsider the issue, according to published reports. But it was not known whether that may have played a role in the judge's delay of the ruling.</p>
<p>In Washington, a spokesman for the SEC said the agency had no comment.</p>
<p>There are 2700 Names in the United States, and 33,500 worldwide.</p>
<p>Industry sources in London said that while the judge could grant some kind of relief to the U.S. Names, Payne said in court earlier this week that it was not his intention to stop Lloyd's worldwide recovery plan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RICHMOND, Va."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
