<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8758" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. September S&amp;P 500s end up, near 7-week high.</title>
<headline>U.S. September S&amp;P 500s end up, near 7-week high.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. September Standard and Poor's 500 futures finished near a seven-week high in a session of moderate trading, showing signs of life after slumbering earlier this week.</p>
<p>The firm tone began early in sync with a strong dollar and Treasury bonds after a German repurchase rate cut. As strength in those markets faded and stock index futures remained firm, dealer buying emerged.</p>
<p>Once September pierced resistance at 669.20 and 670.00 in late morning, buy stops and aggressive short-covering further built up the rally.  </p>
<p>September traded just below the day's high at 672.55 for the rest of the session. Resistance was now seen at 674.00 and 675.00.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there's still a little bit left to the upside and we could get through 675.00 and maybe to 676.00,&quot; an S&amp;P 500 trader said. &quot;But after that were going to have to have more good news,&quot; he added. &quot;Maybe durable goods can help us out.&quot; Traders were looking ahead to Friday's July durable goods report and consumer condifence next week, but some worried the market would continue its trend of lackluster action and thin pits heading into the Labor Day holiday.  </p>
<p>July durable goods orders were forecast to rise 0.3 percent against an 0.8 percent decline in June. Excluding defense, orders were seen up 0.8 percent compared with a 2.0 percent drop in June. That report will be released at 0730 CDT/1230 GMT on Friday.</p>
<p>Strength in technology stocks and technical bullishness aided gains during the session, but it was the German rate cut that set the tone early, traders said.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank cut its repurchase rate by 30 basis points to a historic low of 3.00 percent.  </p>
<p>Traders said S&amp;P 500 futures volume tapered off into the close compared with the brisk activity seen midday.</p>
<p>September S&amp;P 500 futures finished up 5.85 points to 671.85, Midcap 400 rose 2.05 to 233.90, Value Line ended up 4.35 points to 623.80, NYSE Composite rose 2.85 to 359.55, and Nikkei 225 rose 150.0 points to 21,405.0 -Derivatives desk(312)408-8750 E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
