<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8768" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton set to impose strict curbs on tobacco.</title>
<headline>Clinton set to impose strict curbs on tobacco.</headline>
<byline>Steve Holland</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The White House on Thursday denied President Bill Clinton was timing an announcement on strict new tobacco curbs to steer attention away from statistics that drug abuse among teen-agers has skyrocketed during his term.</p>
<p>Clinton was expected to announce measures on Friday aimed at keeping youths from taking up the smoking habit, just three days after his administration released a report saying drug use among teen-agers more than doubled between 1992 and 1995.</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry, responding to Republican charges that Clinton wanted to divert attention from the unfavorable drug report, said Clinton decided a long time ago to clamp down on tobacco products aimed at youth and was waiting for federal regulators to complete the new rules.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't hurry a regulatory process that has to be meticulous and by the book,&quot; McCurry said.</p>
<p>In addition, he charged that Clinton's Republican predecessor, George Bush, &quot;made an effort at one point to hide statistics about the rise in drug use among young people,&quot; while Clinton had &quot;very openly disclosed&quot; the negative report.</p>
<p>&quot;We care about the health of kids. And the health of kids can be ruined by addictive behavior of any number of sorts -- alcohol abuse, illegal substance abuse, tobacco addiction,&quot; he said, adding Clinton considered all of them top priorities.</p>
<p>Republicans also charged that Clinton was timing the announcement to gain maximum publicity ahead of next week's Democratic National Convention.</p>
<p>The Clinton campaign had ridiculed Republican presidential nominee Bob Dole for saying that tobacco was not necessarily addictive and that the Food and Drug Administration did not have the authority to regulate nicotine.</p>
<p>Dole did not answer questions about tobacco on Thursday. But his press secretary Nelson Warfield said that since lawsuits were already pending against the proposed regulations Clinton's plan was &quot;purely an election-year gimmick which could mean further delay in cracking down on teen smoking.&quot;</p>
<p>With anti-smoking sentiment rising, Oklahoma on Thursday became the 14th state to sue the tobacco industry to recover costs of treating smoking-related illnesses paid by the state.</p>
<p>Clinton's announcement, expected at midday on Friday, was to be an endorsement of the FDA's final recommendations on ways to reduce the number of young people who start smoking. The FDA says 3,000 a day start and 1,000 will die as a result.</p>
<p>White House officials said the FDA had made &quot;some changes&quot; in Clinton's own recommendations of a year ago but they did not appear to be significant. Under his proposals, cigarette companies would have been barred from placing billboard advertising near schools and playgrounds.</p>
<p>He also proposed to require age-verified and face-to-face sales and eliminate mail-order sales, vending machines, free samples, self-service displays and sales of fewer than 20 cigarettes. He also urged that sales or giveaways of caps or gym bags with tobacco company logos be prohibited, as well as brand-name sponsorship of sporting or entertainment events.</p>
<p>The union that represents most tobacco workers said the restrictions could cost thousands of jobs and eventually prompt tobacco companies to move operations out of America.</p>
<p>&quot;Thousands of well-paying American jobs are at risk of being lost to the FDA's ill-conceived new regulations of the tobacco industry,&quot; said Frank Hurt, president of the Bakery, Confectionery and Tobacco Workers International Union.</p>
<p>The Freedom to Advertise Coalition, a group of advertising and publishing associations, said the regulations were overly broad and unconstitutional and poorly targeted.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
