<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8774" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Allied Healthcare adopts rights plan.</title>
<headline>Allied Healthcare adopts rights plan.</headline>
<dateline>ST. LOUIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Allied Healthcare Products Inc said Thursday it has adopted a shareholder rights plan to assure shareholders fair value and equal treatment in the event of any proposed takeover of the company.</p>
<p>Allied Healthcare, which makes respiratory therapy equipment and emergency medical products, said this action was not taken in response to any effort of which management is aware to acquire control of the company.</p>
<p>However, the company said that its board felt it prudent and in the best interest of shareholders to establish a rights plan.  </p>
<p>Under the plan, a dividend of one preferred stock purchase right has been declared for each outstanding share of common stock to stockholders of record on September 4, 1996. The rights will be triggered when a person or group acquires, or commences a tender offer to acquire, more than 25 percent of Allied Healthcare's common stock.</p>
<p>Each right entitles the holder to buy one one-hundredth of a share of series A preferred stock for $40.</p>
<p>Upon the acquisition of 25 percent of Allied Healthcare's common stock without the consent of the board of directors, the holders of the rights may receive common stock having a value equal to two times the exercise price of the right.</p>
<p>The rights are redeemable by the board of directors for $0.01 per right. If not redeemed, the rights will expire on September 4, 2006.</p>
<p>-- Chicago newsdesk 312 408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
