<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8785" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US shrs end up as techs dazzle, Germany cuts rates.</title>
<headline>US shrs end up as techs dazzle, Germany cuts rates.</headline>
<byline>Betty Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. stocks were swept higher by a rally in technology issues and a surprising steep German rate cut, which bolstered European bourses and renewed bullish sentiment on Wall Street.</p>
<p>News that the Bundesbank lowered its repurchase rate by 30 basis points to a historic low of 3.00 percent &quot;was definitely a plus in a modest summer rally here, one that should take us to new highs,&quot; said Allen Sinai, chief economist at Lehman Brothers Global Economic Advisors.</p>
<p>After falling 31 Wednesday, the Dow rose 42 to about 5732.  </p>
<p>The gain left the blue-chip index ever closer to its previous record closing high of 5778.00, set May 22.</p>
<p>The tech-laden Nasdaq Composite surged 17 points, or 1.51 percent, to about 1144.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the bear market (in technology) is over. It's in a gut-wrenching bottoming process. High techs should be bought by aggressive investors. ... Six to nine months down the road they should be happy campers,&quot; said Alfred Goldman, technical research director at A.G. Edwards.</p>
<p>Stronger tech issues included Intel, up 2-3/4 to 83 after a Smith Barney upgrade, and Microsoft, up 1-1/2 to 125.  </p>
<p>IBM added 3/8 to 113, Cisco Systems was up 1-3/8 to 57-5/8 and Hewlett-Packard rose 1-1/8 to 43.</p>
<p>Gainers beat losers 7-4 on moderate NYSE volume of about 354 million shares. The long bond slipped 1/32 to yield 6.84 percent as the German rate cut provided only a fleeting early boost. France, Belgium, the Netherlands, Austria and Canada followed with their own easings.</p>
<p>Robert Stovall, president of Stovall/Twenty-First, said, &quot;The strength in foreign stock markets is due to the German rate cut. There's the expectation a further German cut will take the heat off other central bankers including our own.&quot;  </p>
<p>But Lehman's Sinai did not see the Federal Reserve delaying any possible year-end tightening because of the Bundesbank's move. The Fed's decision will be based on &quot;the question if there are any price inflation pressures percolating up. For fixed-income markets, the next big question is the August employment report.&quot;</p>
<p>Tobacco stocks remained under pressure as Oklahoma became the 14th state to sue the industry, and investors nervously awaited the outcome of a key tobacco liability case in Indianapolis. The case went to the jury Thursday. Philip Morris was the most-active NYSE issue, falling 3/4 to 86-7/8.  </p>
<p>RJR Nabisco, parent of R.J. Reynolds Tobacco, slipped 1/8 to 25-1/4, smokeless tobacco maker UST Inc fell 1/8 to 30-3/4, and Loews lost 1-1/2 to 75-1/8.</p>
<p>Among other issues, Zenith Electronics climbed 5-1/2 to 16-7/8 after programming venture Americast signed a $1 billion contract with Zenith to buy at least three million digital set-top boxes for its home entertainment service. Americast is a consortium comprised of Ameritech, South Corp, GTE, SBC Communications and Disney.</p>
<p>Kellogg lost 2-1/4 to 72-3/4. Prudential downgraded the stock to hold from buy.  </p>
<p>Hershey Foods fell 1-1/4 to 87-1/4. Merrill Lynch downgraded the stock on a price basis.</p>
<p>SDL Inc slumped nine to 19 after the company forecast that revenue in the third quarter would be &quot;at best&quot; unchanged from the second quarter's $21.6 million because of manufacturing difficulties. Cowen cut its earnings estimates.</p>
<p>Dura Pharmaceutricals climbed 5-3/4 to 32-1/2 after Eli Lilly agreed to give Dura exclusive U.S. marketing rights to Lilly's patented Ceclor CD and Keftab antibiotics. Lilly inched up 3/8 to 59-3/4.</p>
<p>Veritas Software climbed eight to 48-1/4.  </p>
<p>Veritas said it formed a strategic alliance with Microsoft for the delivery of its volume manager disk and storage management software in Microsoft's fast-growing operating system.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite rose 17.12 to 1143.96.</p>
<p>The S&amp;P 500 index rose 5.61 to 670.68.</p>
<p>(Figures official as of 1645 EDT/2045 GMT)</p>
<p>-- Wall Street desk, 212 859 1721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
