<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8791" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US CREDIT OUTLOOK - Durables, vacation and doldrums.</title>
<headline>US CREDIT OUTLOOK - Durables, vacation and doldrums.</headline>
<byline>Jose Paulo Vicente</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. credit markets will likely remain rangebound on Friday as a combination of summer vacation and a thin flow of fresh economic data has sent many players to the sidelines, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;I fully expect the market to continue to be rangebound. The fundamental issue is whether the economy is growing too fast or is slowing down as the Fed hopes,&quot; said Charles Lieberman, chief economist at Chase Securities Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;And that issue is not going to be solved, it's not going to be settled tomorrow,&quot; Lieberman added.  </p>
<p>July durable goods will be the only piece of fresh economic data the market is expected to get on Friday, and analysts said the report is unlikely to have enough strength to power prices out of their current trading range.</p>
<p>&quot;Durable goods may provide a little insight, but not an enormous amount. Probably because it happens to be a very volatile report anyway,&quot; Lieberman said.</p>
<p>July durable goods data will be released on Friday at 0830 EDT/1230 GMT. In a Reuters survey, economists on average expect the overall number to be up 0.3 percent. The ex-defense figures are expected to rise 0.8 percent.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the market is likely to remain in a range -- seen between 6.75 percent and 6.95 percent for the 30-year T-bond yield -- until significant new information is released.</p>
<p>The 6-3/4 percent benchmark bond was quoted down 3/32 at 98-26/32 in late trading on Thursday to yield 6.84 percent.</p>
<p>Pundits said the market's next hurdle will be the August employment report, slated for release on September 6.</p>
<p>They said the August National Association of Purchasing Management (NAPM) index will also be watched closely. The data are due out on September 3.  </p>
<p>&quot;The employment report is the real big hurdle,&quot; said Marilyn Schaja, money market economist at Donaldson, Lufkin &amp; Jenrette Securities Corp.</p>
<p>In the meantime, economists continued to express mixed opinions about where the U.S. economy is heading.</p>
<p>Some analysts said they believe the economy is still growing at a strong pace with a very tight labor market.</p>
<p>That perverse combination, they said, is likely to prompt the Fed to raise interest rates before the end of the year to pre-empt inflation. &quot;I think longer term we are going to end up with higher interest rates,&quot; Chase's Lieberman said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the economy is slowing down enough to enable the Fed to leave policy unchanged for any great length of time,&quot; said Lieberman, who expects a Fed tightening before the end of the year.</p>
<p>Another line of thought, however, believes the economy is slowing down gradually and that should be enough to keep the Fed at bay for the rest of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the economy is slowing, but it's slowing gradually,&quot; said DLJ's Schaja. &quot;I think there is a chance the Fed eases by the very, very end of the year but probably we'll see no Fed action throughout the rest of the year,&quot; she added.  </p>
<p>On Friday, the market will also take in the minutes for the July 2-3 Federal Open Market Committee meeting. Since then, the Fed's FOMC met again on Tuesday (Aug 20). The Fed left short-term rates unchanged in both gatherings.</p>
<p>Traders said they noticed some large deals Thursday, but added portfolio managers were mostly out of the market.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw some scattered deals today, but I believe most big players are still out of the market,&quot; said a trader at a primary dealership. &quot;A lot of people are still on vacation.&quot;</p>
<p>On Thursday, the Fed added reserves to the money market via seven-day fixed system repurchase agreements when the federal funds were at 5-1/8 percent, below the Fed's 5-1/4 percent target. Fed funds are seen opening at 5.13 percent on Friday. -- (212) 859-1676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
