<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8801" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMM currency futures end mixed after rate cuts.</title>
<headline>IMM currency futures end mixed after rate cuts.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>IMM currency futures ended mixed after several European countries lowered interest rates.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank initiated the rate reductions, which spread to Belgium, France and Austria and also occurred in Canada.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank cut its fixed 3.30 percent securities repurchase rate to 3.00 percent, a bigger cut than expected.</p>
<p>The Swiss National Bank, however, said it saw no reason to change its discount rate and instead said it added a &quot;significant quantity&quot; of liquidity to its money markets.</p>
<p>But marks began to recover as traders decided Bundesbank's ease, which had slapped marks lower, would be its last.  </p>
<p>&quot;It must be the last one,&quot; a floor analyst said of the German rate cut.</p>
<p>Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer said the decision to cut was in line with the general policy trend, that the development in M3 money supply was decisive for the cut and that it sees M3 gradually moving toward the target corridor.</p>
<p>September mark futures barely peeked below a support level near $0.6698 or about 1.4950 spot, but held the overnight low at $0.6690 and began battling back up.</p>
<p>They advanced to the day's peak on shortcovering as European trading wound down but stalled on the upside as well.  </p>
<p>Similarly, the Canadian dollar firmed after the Bank of Canada shaved 25 basis points from its key bank rate, which traders also viewed as the last Canadian rate cut.</p>
<p>Futures later stalled in ranges, with some waiting for the August U.S. employment report due September 6 for incentive.</p>
<p>Friday's U.S. July durable goods orders are seen up 0.3 percent overall, up 0.8 percent without defense orders.</p>
<p>Sept yen rose $0.000017 to $0.009268, marks lost $0.0042 to $0.6712, Swiss francs fell $0.0048 to $0.8298, sterling rose $0.0002 to $1.5500, Can dollar up $0.0014 to $0.7299, Aussie dollar up $0.0010 at $0.7906, Mex peso up $0.000325 at $0.132075. --Derivatives Desk 312-408-8750 E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
