<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8821" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: In Home Health to appeal payment denial.</title>
<headline>In Home Health to appeal payment denial.</headline>
<dateline>MINNETONKA, Minn. 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>In Home Health Inc said on Thursday it will appeal to the U.S. Federal District Court in Minneapolis a decision by the Health Care Financing Administration (HCFA) that denied reimbursement of certain costs under Medicaid.</p>
<p>The HCFA Administrator reversed a previously favorable decision regarding the reimbursement of costs related to the company's community liaison personnel, it added.</p>
<p>The company said it continues to believe the majority of the community liaison costs are coverable under the terms of the Medicare program.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are disappointed with the administrator's decision but we continue to be optimistic regarding an ultimate favorable resolution,&quot; Mark Gildea, chief executive officer, said in a statement.</p>
<p>In Home Health said it previously recorded a reserve equal to 16 percent of all revenue related to the community liaison costs.</p>
<p>Separately, In Home Health said the U.S. District Court in Minneapolis ruled in its favor regarding the reimbursement of certain interest expenses.</p>
<p>This decision will result in the reimbursement by Medicare of $81,000 in disputed costs.</p>
<p>&quot;This is our first decision in federal distrct court regarding a dispute with Medicare,&quot; Gildea said. &quot;We are extremely pleased with this decision and we recognize it as a significant step toward resolution of our outstanding Medicare disputes.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNETONKA, Minn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
