<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8823" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fidelity sells retirement plan through U.S Chamber.</title>
<headline>Fidelity sells retirement plan through U.S Chamber.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fidelity Investments said Thursday it will offer small businesses, through the U.S. Chamber of Commerce, a low-cost, streamlined retirement savings plan.</p>
<p>The U.S. Chamber of Commerce will inform its approximately 200,000 small business members, which employ 24 million workers, of the U.S. Chamberplan for Retirement, said Lawrence Kraus, senior vice president of the U.S. Chamber of Commerce.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll inform our members that this plan exists. If the member is interested, they call Fidelity,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Fidelity's small- and medium-size business unit in Covington, Kentucky will field the calls and provide investment management and record-keeping services, said Raymond Marcinowski, senior vice president of Fidelity Institutional Retirement Services Co.</p>
<p>Only about 25 percent of businesses with less than 100 employees have retirement plans, compared with 80 to 90 percent for businesses with 5,000, or more employees, Marcinowski said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're also looking at the possibility of offering it to our state and local chambers,&quot; Kraus said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're exploring the possibility that they may in turn offer it to their own members.&quot;</p>
<p>Kraus said the Fidelity plan is the only retirement plan offered to Chamber members. More than 2,000 small businesses have already contacted Fidelity since the initiative was first announced in April, he said.</p>
<p>The retirement products include 401(K), Keogh, SEP-IRA and SARSEP plans. The 401(K) plan will include eight Fidelity mutual funds, including Contrafund, Growth &amp; Income Portfolio, Puritan Fund, Blue Chip Growth Fund, Diversified International and Asset Manager, Marcinowski said.</p>
<p>-- Michael Ellis, Boston bureau (617) 367-4176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
