<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8831" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT - Internet index jumps, resistance ahead.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Internet index jumps, resistance ahead.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A sudden resurgence in Internet-related stocks will soon face a test as a sector index barrels toward key resistance.</p>
<p>The American Stock Exchange's Internet Index which includes 46 companies ranging from modem makers to online services, jumped seven points to 228 Thursday afternoon, a gain of better than three percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said the rally left the index at a key turning point.  </p>
<p>&quot;Right now it looks like the index is at a bit of a crossroads here after consolidating for a couple of weeks,&quot; said Frank Gretz, technical analyst at Shields &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Among the markers ahead is the index's 200-day moving average, a level it has not cracked since selling-off sharply in July.</p>
<p>&quot;After that its rally came up just short of the 200-day moving average and then drifted lower over the next week to 10 days,&quot; said Greg Nie, technical analyst at EVEREN Securities.  </p>
<p>Because of the index's failure to penetrate the average, which now stands at about 236.5, how it handles that level should signal whether this move is part of a legitimate break higher.</p>
<p>One possibly bullish sign, noted Gretz, is that as the index drifted lower early this month, it stayed well above the bottoms set during the July downward spike. Should the index surpass the 235 level, it will also have set a higher peak.</p>
<p>&quot;Anytime you make a higher low and a higher high you have to take that as a positive sign,&quot; Gretz said.  </p>
<p>Because of the extreme volatility of technology stocks, analysts warned against forming a judgment on one session's worth of gains and even with the gains, some remained generally pessimistic about a full-fledged run-up.</p>
<p>&quot;This still looks like a bit of a countertrend rally in an oversold market,&quot; said Global Market Strategists Inc analyst Chris Dickerson, who added that further rallies were likely to be very selective as investors continue to lean toward large cap, less volatile stocks.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1731</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
