<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8835" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Indiana jury begins deliberations in tobacco suit.</title>
<headline>Indiana jury begins deliberations in tobacco suit.</headline>
<dateline>INDIANAPOLIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A jury began deliberations Thursday in a damage suit against the tobacco industry being pursued by the family of a man who died of lung cancer after smoking for more than 40 years.</p>
<p>It was not known how long the deliberations in Marion County Superior Court would last. The suit is against R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co, a unit of RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp, Liggett Group Inc, a unit of Brooke Group Ltd, Philip Morris Cos Inc, and The American Tobacco Co, now owned by Brown &amp; Williamson Tobacco Corp, a unit of B.A.T Industries Plc.  </p>
<p>The case, similar to hundreds which have been filed across the country, follows one earlier this month in Jacksonville, Florida, where a jury awarded $750,000 to a man who smoked for 44 years before he was stricken with lung cancer.</p>
<p>The Indiana case involves the widow and three teen-aged children of Richard Rogers, an Indianapolis lawyer who died at the age of 52 in 1987. He began smoking at age six and the suit, which seeks an unspecified amount of damages, contends the industry was at fault for selling him an addictive product that caused the cancer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="INDIANAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
