<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8845" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Inmates, guard injured in Texas prison uprising.</title>
<headline>Inmates, guard injured in Texas prison uprising.</headline>
<dateline>EDEN, Texas 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least four inmates and a guard were injured during a 15-hour riot that was quelled at a privately run prison Thursday, officials said.</p>
<p>Four inmates were taken to a hospital with wounds from a shotgun blast fired by a prison guard and a guard's jaw was broken by a rock thrown during the melee at the Eden Detention Center, Texas Department of Public Safety spokeswoman Laureen Chernow said.</p>
<p>Eden is about 45 miles southeast of San Angelo in West Texas. Chernow said &quot;several more&quot; inmates were injured as well but she did not know the exact number. A spokeswoman for the Eden Police Department said local police also had not been told the number of casualties.</p>
<p>The facility is run by the Nashville, Tennessee-based Corrections Corp of America, but a spokesman for the company could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>The uprising started at midday Wednesday when inmates began protesting conditions, complaining about food and clothing, Chernow said. State police and Texas Rangers were called in about seven hours later and patrolled the prison's perimeter with helicopters and floodlights while guards inside worked to end the uprising, she said.</p>
<p>It was the second incident this month at a Texas prison operated by Corrections Corp. On Aug. 7, two convicted sex offenders escaped from a company-operated jail in Houston, raising concerns from local police who said they were not notified of the escape for several hours.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EDEN, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
