<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8849" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BHP Copper restarts its San Manuel smelter.</title>
<headline>BHP Copper restarts its San Manuel smelter.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>BHP Copper, part of Australia's Broken Hill Proprietary Co Ltd, said its San Manuel smelter in Arizona has been restarted and tonnage lost during the shutdown would be minimal.</p>
<p>&quot;It's back on stream - it started up last night and it's running well,&quot; a BHP Copper official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>BHP shut the smelter for nine days following electrical problems that resulted from the statewide power outage on August 10. A shutdown was originally scheduled for October but this was brought forward due to the power outage.</p>
<p>San Manuel produces just over 360,000 short tons of anode.  </p>
<p>The smelter produces anode which is converted into cathode at the refinery.</p>
<p>&quot;Through most of the shutdown we were producing cathode because we had anode available. We basically ran down our anode stockpile,&quot; the BHP official said.</p>
<p>Refinery cathode output was reduced slightly but will return to full output once anode production catches up. San Manuel normally produces more anode than the refinery can consume.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. market is holding pretty strongly, and the rod market is particular is good and cathode is tight,&quot; the BHP official said. &quot;Asian premiums at the moment are very strong - $130 a tonne is a good premium even with the Shanghai freight.&quot;</p>
<p>Most of San Manuel's cathode production is consumed by BHP's own rod mill.</p>
<p>-- New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
