<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8859" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mattel names Barad as CEO.</title>
<headline>Mattel names Barad as CEO.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mattel Inc said Jill Barad, company president and chief operating officer, will succeed John Amerman as chief executive officer, effective January 1, 1997.</p>
<p>Amerman will remain chairman of the board, Mattel said.  </p>
<p>The move had been expected by industry sources, who had said Barad was Amerman's most likely heir.</p>
<p>&quot;Jill Barad has contributed so much to our success during her 15 years with Mattel, and particularly during the four years she has served as my partner in running this company,&quot; Amerman said.</p>
<p>Barad was named president and chief operating officer in 1992.  </p>
<p>She joined Mattel in 1981 as a product manager and was named marketing director for the Barbie Doll brand in 1982. She was made a vice president in 1984, a senior vice president in 1985, executive vice president in 1986, president-girls and activity toys division in 1989, and president-Mattel USA in 1990.  </p>
<p>Barad was named to Mattel's board in 1991.</p>
<p>&quot;She has proven herself to be an excellent leader, marketer and manager. I have total confidence in Jill and know she will be an outstanding CEO,&quot; Amerman said.</p>
<p>Amerman has been CEO since 1987. He joined Mattel in 1980 as president of Mattel International.</p>
<p>Earlier this month Mattel named Sony Corp executive Bruce Stein as president of Mattel Worldwide as part of a realignment of top managers reporting to Barad.</p>
<p>Stein replaced James Eskridge, who resigned in March after realizing he would not succeed Amerman, industry sources said.  </p>
<p>Mattel also named Ned Mansour, president-corporate operations, and Stein to its board, which now has 13 members.</p>
<p>Other members of the top management team reporting to Barad are Byron Davis, president of Fisher-Price, Joseph Gandolfo, president-worldwide manufacturing operations, and Francesca Luzuriaga, chief financial officer.</p>
<p>&quot;With this team operating under Jill's leadership, Mattel will continue to produce record results,&quot; Amerman said.</p>
<p>For the 1996 second quarter Mattel reported net income of $66.3 million on revenues of $777.4 million, versus $67.5 million on revenues of $763.5 million a year earlier.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I49410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
