<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8875" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ZINC--U.S. demand motors along, eyes auto talks.</title>
<headline>ZINC--U.S. demand motors along, eyes auto talks.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Healthy demand for zinc metal and firm premiums look set to continue into the fall, but much will depend on whether a key market - the auto industry - escapes a strike, traders and producers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand is running out of control,&quot; said Martin Pede, sales manager at Canadian zinc producer Noranda Inc. &quot;We are seeing incredible tightness in the market place and everyone calling for contract maximums.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The only problem we have is trying to keep the pipeline filled - it's a good problem to have,&quot; Pede said. Production plants were operating flat out with no problems.  </p>
<p>Zinc premiums have risen to 5.5 to 6.0 cents per pound over LME cash, up from 4.75 to 5.25 in late July.</p>
<p>&quot;Consumers are not worried about premiums if the final price is still historically low. LME is under $1,000 per tonne so it's a bargain,&quot; a U.S.-based producer agent said.</p>
<p>LME zinc cash settled at $997 a tonne (45 cents/lb) on Thursday. Merrill Lynch forecast an average zinc price of 47 cents/lb this year and 53 cents in 1997.  </p>
<p>&quot;The bottom line has not changed in the last six months,&quot; a trader said. &quot;But the market is tight and will remain tight in the near term. There is material coming in from Europe, it's just a question of how much.&quot;</p>
<p>Premiums were still barely enough to import metal from Europe, though good freight rates would tip the balance.</p>
<p>The market was closely watching the labor talks at the Big Three U.S. auto makers. The United Auto Workers union Thursday delayed a choice of strike target to give more time for talks.  </p>
<p>&quot;People still wonder about whether there will be an auto strike or not, which could change the picture quickly,&quot; Pede said. &quot;Should there be no strike action then there would be nothing that would have the current market situation changed significantly.&quot;</p>
<p>Galvanized steel for auto bodies is a key market for zinc.</p>
<p>Meanwhile traders expected the U.S. Mint to enter the market mid-September for metal and may firm up premiums further. Higher LME zinc prices would, however, make premium hikes tougher to achieve, traders and producers agreed.  </p>
<p>A North American zinc miner said the concentrate market was balanced, and a big surplus has not appeared. Treatment charges rose about $15 to $190 per tonne in 1996 because excess mining capacity was forecast.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not expect major changes in treatment charges for next year,&quot; the miner said. &quot;Despite LME inventory, producer and consumer inventory is tight to short. We expect the (metal) price to go higher in ensuing months.&quot;</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch said, &quot;The absolute level of inventories remains relatively high at just over 1 million metric tonnes, equivalent to 8.7 weeks at current levels of consumption.&quot;  </p>
<p>It is general felt in the industry that stocks must fall to six-to-seven weeks supply to sustain a rally.</p>
<p>The U.S. General Accounting Office has issued its draft report on stockpile zinc sales, but will not make the details public until industry reaction has been received and a final report issued.</p>
<p>&quot;If the final report looks like the preliminary one, then I am in no hurry for it to come out,&quot; George Vary, the American Zinc Association's executive director, said.</p>
<p>-- Huw Jones, New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22471">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
