<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8888" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Merrill denies seeking higher fund fees.</title>
<headline>Merrill denies seeking higher fund fees.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Merrill Lynch and Co denied a report that it was seeking higher fees from mutual fund firms when it starts a program to sell their no-load mutual funds through a Merrill fund &quot;supermarket.&quot;</p>
<p>A Merrill spokesman described as &quot;untrue&quot; a report in the Wall Street Journal that it was seeking to negotiate higher fees that it collects from fund companies.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not seeking any enhanced payment from fund families beyond what they are paying other people,&quot; the spokesman said.  </p>
<p>Citing industry sources, the Journal reported that Merrill was seeking to collect as much as 0.4 percent point of all new dollars flowing into fund firms through its new program.</p>
<p>The fund companies are holding out for as little as 0.25 percentage point, the paper said.</p>
<p>Merrill currently is planning on expanding its mutual fund offerings, but a spokesman gave few details. &quot;We are in the process of exploring expanded areas of mutual fund selection for clients,&quot; said a Merrill spokesman. &quot;The details and timing are not yet finalized.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;We are looking to have something in place well before the end of the year,&quot; the spokesman said, adding that talks are under way with several fund companies.</p>
<p>A Merrill source said the offering would include no-load funds from other firms.</p>
<p>Merrill currently sells a variety of mutual funds, both their own and from other fund firms.</p>
<p>The Journal said Merrill is making little headway in trying to charge fund companies above the going rate for a variety of &quot;no-loan&quot; mutual funds.</p>
<p>Merrill, the biggest brokerage house on Wall Street, is expected to enter the no-load &quot;supermarket&quot; arena perhaps as early as next month, perhaps as soon as after the Labor Day holiday at the start of September, the newspaper said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
