<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8895" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT -- Dlr must clear hurdles before more gains.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT -- Dlr must clear hurdles before more gains.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dollar/mark needs to close at 1.4960 marks or higher before it can extend gains posted after Germany cut its repo rate by 30 basis points, analysts said.</p>
<p>A close of at least 1.4960 marks would put the dollar on track for a rise to 1.5070 and possibly 1.5130, while failure to close around that level would open the way for a retracment to 1.4860 marks or lower, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;In my opinion (1.4960 marks) is a big swing level. If we can close above 1.4960 I think we can have about another 80 to 100 points on the upside,&quot; said Ture Johnson, technical analyst at Bank of America.  </p>
<p>Analysts see the dollar in a 1.4860-1.4980 mark range over the next 24 hours, with key supports at 1.4900 and 1. and resistance at 1.4960 and 1.5000 marks.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as dollar/mark goes, I feel if we don't see some follow-through buying pretty quickly, we're going to see a little correction,&quot; Cynthia Cooley, foreign exchange analyst at United Gulf Bank of Bahrain, said.</p>
<p>&quot;The bottom of that correction is probably 1.4860 (marks). I think there's probably some interim support at 1.4900.&quot;</p>
<p>MMS International, in its written commentary, noted that 1.4960 was a 38.2 percent retracement from the May-July drop.  </p>
<p>Dollar/yen is more decidedly bullish but it must overcome hurdles at 108.60 and 108.80 yen, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel relatively bullish on dollar/yen but there's a little bit of a battleground. 108.80 is the next resistance above 108.60. It may come off 108.80 to 108.40. There may be some residual drag if dollar/mark comes off,&quot; Cooley said.</p>
<p>Johnson expects the U.S. currency to test resistance at 108.80 yen in the near term. A break above that level would clear the way for a move to 109.70-110.00 yen, he said.</p>
<p>Analysts see dollar/yen in a near-term range of 108.10-108.80 yen, with a possible extension to 109.00.  </p>
<p>&quot;I would think we'll hold 108.20 yen, so I would say you should take a shot at buying (dollars) ahead of 108.20 with a stop below 108.00,&quot; Johnson said.</p>
<p>Mark/yen, meanwhile, is seen stuck in a 72.30-73.30 yen range. 73.30 has proved tough resistance, analysts said.</p>
<p>Cooley noted that mark/yen has been making progressively lower tops and lower lows since July.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm looking for mark/yen to experience a nice correction,&quot; she said. &quot;I would say it's going to see in the short-term at least 72.20. Then I think 71.80 is going to provide some decent support.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Daniel Rosenblum, 212-859-1662</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
