<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8899" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Nynex, Teleport expand interconnect pact.</title>
<headline>Nynex, Teleport expand interconnect pact.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nynex Corp said on Thursday it signed a new interconnection agreement with Teleport Communications Group that expands on a similar pact, made in 1994, to connect the companies' telephone networks in New York.</p>
<p>The agreement aims to meet a 14-point checklist of conditions in the Telecommunications Act of 1996, as required for Nynex's entry into New York's long-distance market, the company said.  </p>
<p>In a separate statement, Teleport said the deal would enable it to compete for about $1.5 billion in fees that long-distance telephone companies currently pay Nynex for switched access services in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;TCG was the first competitive local exchange carrier to enter into an interconnection agreement with Nynex back in 1994, and now we are the first to introduce competition into the area of switched access rates paid by long distance companies,&quot; said Bob Annunziata, Teleport's chairman, president and chief executive.</p>
<p>Teleport said it would be able to act as a tandem or intermediate switch to terminate and originate calls between long-distance carriers and their customers. The company said a tandem switch links multiple central offices to interexchange carriers.</p>
<p>On June 30, 1994, Teleport and Nynex entered into the first U.S. interconnection agreement between competing local exchange carriers. Nynex said it expected the latest pact to serve as a template for negotiations with Teleport in other states in its service area.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
