<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8905" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Best sees Q2 loss similar to Q1 loss.</title>
<headline>Best sees Q2 loss similar to Q1 loss.</headline>
<dateline>RICHMOND, Va. 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Best Products Co Chairman and Chief Executive Daniel Levy said Thursday he expected the company's second-quarter results to be similar to the $34.6 million loss posted in the first quarter.</p>
<p>He also told Reuters before the retailer's annual meeting that the second quarter could be better than the first quarter ended May 4. &quot;We could do even better,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The second-quarter results are expected to be released in September.  </p>
<p>Levy said seeking bankruptcy protection was not under consideration. Best emerged from Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection in June 1994 after 3-1/2 years.</p>
<p>&quot;Bankruptcy is always possible, particularly when you lose what we are going to lose in the first half of this year,&quot; Levy said. &quot;But this is not something we are striving to do.&quot;</p>
<p>The Richmond-based retailer lost $95.7 million in the fiscal year ended February 3. That was the second-largest loss in the company's history.</p>
<p>Levy said that Best planned to open two new stores this fall. The company announced in March that it was closing seven stores and backing out of nine new lease agreements. At the time, Best said it did not plan to open any new stores this fall. It currently operates 169 stores in 23 states.</p>
<p>For last year's second quarter, which ended July 29, 1995, Best posted a loss of $7.1 million, or $0.23 per share, on sales of $311.9 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RICHMOND, Va."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
