<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8907" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lukens to shut melt shop for one week.</title>
<headline>Lukens to shut melt shop for one week.</headline>
<dateline>PITTSBURGH 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lukens Inc will shut its stainless steel melt shop and hot-strip mill for one week beginning August 26 due to poor market conditions, a company spokesman said Thursday.</p>
<p>The plant is located in Houston, Pa., near Pittsburgh.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the shutdown will affect about 250 workers. &quot;Some of them will be on vacation and some will be on temporary lay-off,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The company blamed the shutdown on a heavy level of steel imports that have deteriorated pricing in the domestic market.  </p>
<p>The spokesman declined to comment on how the shutdown will affect third quarter earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not going to quantify this or discuss the impact,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Stainless steel imports have increased this year in the domestic market because U.S. prices have been higher than prices overseas.</p>
<p>However, imports have pressured U.S. tags downward. For example, prices for cold-rolled stainless sheet are about 20 percent lower than prices seen last year, the Lukens spokesman said.  </p>
<p>He said operations at the Houston plant will restart September 3.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PITTSBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
