<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8919" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FPC's Crystal River 3 at full power today.</title>
<headline>FPC's Crystal River 3 at full power today.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Florida Power Corp's (FPC) 825 megawatt (MW) Crystal River 3 nuclear generating unit will reach 100 percent power today after output was scaled back late Tuesday, the company said Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to be 100 percent this morning,&quot; said company spokeswoman Melodie Hendrix.</p>
<p>The utility reduced the plant's power output to 60 percent of capacity to correct a condensate pump problem.</p>
<p>The utility earlier said the unit would likely resume full service late Wednesday, but Hendrix said more cleaning needed for the pump pushed back the unit's return to full output.</p>
<p>Crystal River 3 produces 15 percent of the electricity FPC delivers in its Florida service territory.</p>
<p>FPC, a subsidiary of Florida Progress Corp, is the operator and major owner of the Crystal River 3. Ten Florida municipal utilities own the remaining interests in the unit.</p>
<p>The Crystal River facility, in Red Level, Fla., also has four fossil-fuel units, with a combined capacity of 2,276 MW.</p>
<p>--New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
