<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8923" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ML Direct changes IPO terms, underwriter.</title>
<headline>ML Direct changes IPO terms, underwriter.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>ML Direct Inc has changed underwriters as well as terms of its planned initial public offering, according to underwriter Patterson Travis and regulatory filings.</p>
<p>The company originally filed with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission in May for an offering of one million shares at an estimated price of $7 each in an IPO to be underwritten by I.A. Rabinowitz. The company still listed Rabinowitz as its lead underwriter in an early June filing.</p>
<p>In August, ML Direct refiled for an offering of 480,000 shares to offered at $15 each with Patterson Travis as the new lead underwriter. Both underwriters confirmed the change but did not give a reason for the switch.</p>
<p>Patterson Travis said the deal has been submitted to regulatory officials and said trading could begin sometime next week.</p>
<p>ML Direct &quot;expands market opportunities&quot; for products marketed on direct response television such as infomercials and television shopping networks.</p>
<p>The company has proposed to trade on the Nasdaq under the symbol &quot;MLDR&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
