<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8925" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ferrell FX Index fell 0.1 pct in July.</title>
<headline>Ferrell FX Index fell 0.1 pct in July.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Ferrell FX Index was off 0.1 percent in July against a 0.4 percent rise in June, according to Ferrell Capital Management.</p>
<p>All 35 programs in the index reported in July, and 20 of the 35 said results were positive, Ferrell said.</p>
<p>&quot;The biggest market move was the dollar weakness in mid-month,&quot; said Ferrell's S. Waite Rawls. &quot;Most discretionary traders had small positive or negative returns.&quot;</p>
<p>Irvington, Connecticut-based Emcor's currency management program turned in the best performance for the month, rising 6.0 percent in July, Ferrell said.</p>
<p>&quot;Currency markets were vin July with the dollar falling sharply against the major European currencies,&quot; Gerhard Isele, an Emcor managing director, told Ferrell.</p>
<p>Kenzie Global Asset Management posted the second-largest gain for July, with its aggressive growth program rising 4.8 percent. Quantitative Financial Strategies placed third with a rise of 3.5 percent. the 115-month period from January 1987 through July 1996, the compounded annual return of the Ferrell FX Index is 17.7 percent, according to Ferrell.</p>
<p>The index is intended to be a benchmark for multi-advisor currency portfolios.</p>
<p>--N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1868</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
