<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8931" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: UAW delays choice of strike target.</title>
<headline>UAW delays choice of strike target.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Auto Workers union delayed its choice of a strike target for Big Three U.S. automaker contract talks to allow union leaders to meet a final time with the chief executive officers of the three companies, UAW officials said Thursday.  </p>
<p>Stephen Yokich, UAW president, said UAW officials will meet with the chairmen of General Motors Corp, Ford Motor Co and Chrysler Corp over the next two days and will decide at a future date whether to focus bargaining on just one of the companies.</p>
<p>For the timehe UAW intends to continue bargaining with each of the automecause talks are progressing at their strongest pace in years, Yokich said at a news conference.</p>
<p>Earlier, some UAW officials had said a strike target could be announced as early asweekend or on Monday.  </p>
<p>&quot;It could happen Sunday, it could happen next week, I don't know,&quot; Yokich said.</p>
<p>Separate contract talks between the UAW and Ford, GM and Chrysler began in June. Yokich said that he does not want to halt progress that his bargaining teams are making at any of the three companies.</p>
<p>&quot;It's good common, honest sense if you've got three companies that are moving along in their negotiations and these three companies want to reach agreement, you don't stop them,&quot; Yokich said. &quot;You meet with them.&quot;  </p>
<p>Kenneth Van Horn, shop chairman of the UAW Local 5960 in Lake Orion, Mich. and one of the 500 UAW leaders attending a meeting here, said Yokich told them that more progress is being made at Ford and Chrysler than at GM.</p>
<p>He said he supports the decision to delay the choice of a bargaining target. &quot;We're here to put bread and butter on people's tables, not put them out on strike,&quot; Van Horn said.</p>
<p>Ernest Lofton, UAW vice president in charge of Ford bargaining, said progress at the number two automaker is the best it has been since 1979.  </p>
<p>&quot;This set of negotiations, I believe that we have reached understandings,&quot; he said. &quot;The negotiations are going smoother and we're doing things at a more rapid pace.&quot;</p>
<p>UAW vice president Richard Shoemaker said bargaining at GM also has improved and has not been affected by a costly 17-day strike at GM's brake plant in March.</p>
<p>However, he said bargainers have a long way to go to reach an agreement. &quot;There aren't any simple problems left to resolve,&quot; Shoemaker said.</p>
<p>The substantive issues on the table involve job security and outsourcing of work done by UAW members.</p>
<p>The contract covering about 400,000 UAW hourly workers at the three companies expires September 14, 1996. Historically, the UAW has threatened a target company with a national strike if talks fail to reach an agreement by the expiration.</p>
<p>	     Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
