<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8937" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SDL off on concerns over yield -- traders.</title>
<headline>SDL off on concerns over yield -- traders.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of SDL Inc fell sharply on investor concerns over yields as well as the shipping of products, traders said.</p>
<p>Shares stood at 15 at mid-morning, down 13 from the Wednesday close at 28.</p>
<p>The company was to hold a telephone conference call Thursday morning, the traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The company is going to speak in a call momentarily,&quot; one trader said. &quot;There is a glitch in their numbers or one of their products.&quot;</p>
<p>Company officials could not be reached for comment.  </p>
<p>The company, a maker of specialized integrated circuits and semiconductor lasers, went public in February 1995 with an offering of 2.4 million shares at $13 each.</p>
<p>There was a secondary offering of 1.9 million shares at $34.50 each last August, followed by an offering of 1.7 million shares in June at $27 each.</p>
<p>Donaldson Lufkin &amp; Jenrette managed all three offerings.  </p>
<p>For the 1996 second quarter SDL reported earnings of $0.20 per share versus $0.12 in the year-ago period. Revenues grew to $21.6 million from $12.5 million.</p>
<p>In 1995 the San Jose, Calif., company reported a loss of $0.46 per share, or $2.8 million, after a fourth quarter charge of about $10 million related to the write-off of in-process research and development.</p>
<p>In 1994 SDL earned $0.44 per share.</p>
<p>Revenues for 1995 grew to $53.9 million from $33 million in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
