<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8944" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Measles exposure can lead to bowel disease - study.</title>
<headline>Measles exposure can lead to bowel disease - study.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Women who get measles while pregnant may have babies at higher risk of Crohn's disease, a debilitating bowel disorder, researchers said on Friday.</p>
<p>Three out of four Swedish babies born to mothers who caught measles developed serious cases of Crohn's disease, the researchers said.</p>
<p>Dr Andrew Wakefield of the Royal Free Hospital School of Medicine and colleagues screened 25,000 babies delivered at University Hospital, Uppsala, between 1940 and 1949.</p>
<p>Four of the mothers had measles while pregnant.</p>
<p>&quot;Three of the four children had Crohn's disease,&quot; Wakefield's group wrote in the Lancet medical journal.</p>
<p>Crohn's is an inflammation of the bowel that can sometimes require surgery. It causes diarrhoea, abdominal pain and weight loss. The researchers said the three children involved had especially severe cases.</p>
<p>Exposure to viruses can often cause birth defects. Most notably, women who get rubella (German measles) have a high risk of a stillborn baby.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
