<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8945" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: New pill does not carry stroke risk, study finds.</title>
<headline>New pill does not carry stroke risk, study finds.</headline>
<byline>Maggie Fox</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Women who take new low-oestrogen oral contraceptives do not run a significant risk of strokes, said an international study published on Friday.</p>
<p>Although women who use the pill do have a slightly higher risk of strokes they are in no great danger because the odds for all women are so low, said Dr Neil Poulter, an epidemiologist at University College London who coordinated the study.</p>
<p>The World Health Organisation sponsored the study of nearly 8,000 women aged 20 to 44 in 21 centres across the world. It compared stroke rates in women who did and did not use the pill and published its results in the Lancet medical journal.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, the use of oral contraceptives produced a small increase in the risk of stroke but the more modern low-dose oral contraceptives were associated with less risk...and the risks were further reduced in women under 35 years of age,&quot; Poulter said in a statement. Early versions of the pill increased the risk of strokes and blood clots in women who took them, but new versions using lower doses of hormones have since been developed.</p>
<p>Poulter said in a telephone interview he thought the study -- the biggest of its kind -- had vindicated the pill.</p>
<p>&quot;The risks are tiny and that's the key message,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Using oral contraceptives roughly triples the risk of stroke, but Poulter's group said the risk was very small to start out with.</p>
<p>&quot;In Europe, annual incidence rates range from one to three per 100,000 for women younger than 35 years, and rise to 10 per 100,000 for those older than 35 years,&quot; they wrote.</p>
<p>&quot;The incidence of ischaemic stroke (one caused by a blood clot) is low in women of reproductive age and any risk attributable to oral contraceptive use is small,&quot; they added.</p>
<p>&quot;The risk can be further reduced if users are younger than 35 years, do not smoke, do not have a history of hypertension, and have blood pressure measured before the start of oral contraceptive use.&quot;</p>
<p>Poulter said the risk of haemorrhagic stroke, caused by bleeding from a blood vessel in the brain, was no higher in pill-users under the age of 35.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a particularly reassuring finding as haemorrhagic stroke is the most common type of stroke in young women and the vast majority of pill users worldwide are below 35 years old.&quot;</p>
<p>He said it was very important to measure blood pressure before prescribing the pill, as it seemed that was why women over 35 had higher risks of stroke.</p>
<p>&quot;Our best guess is the mechanism for this is gradually increasing blood pressure,&quot; Poulter said. Blood pressure rises on average with age.</p>
<p>Last year the British government sparked a major scare when it announced that new, &quot;third-generation&quot; pills increased the risk of getting a blood clot in the leg.</p>
<p>Poulter said this was true, but it was important to note that risks were small to start out with -- and said pregnancy carried an even higher risk.</p>
<p>&quot;Compared with the alternatives, the pill is a better bet,&quot; he said. &quot;You've also got to put in the balance the benefits of the pill. Think about the downsides of being pregnant, or other forms of contraceptives.&quot;</p>
<p>Poulter said his group would be publishing a similar study into the risks of heart attack in women who use the pill.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
