<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8946" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LCE cocoa futures sag as traders await news.</title>
<headline>LCE cocoa futures sag as traders await news.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>London cocoa futures dropped below support levels in subdued volume on Thursday as traders awaited crop updates from West Africa.</p>
<p>Volume was sagging at 815 lots by midday but picked up to 3,792 by the close as benchmark December slid below support at 1,039 in late trading and closed 18 stg per tonne down on the day at 1,031.</p>
<p>September prices slid by 16 stg per tonne to close at 1,013.</p>
<p>Traders saw little significance in the slide and expected only limited activity before September, and fresh crop updates from West Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a pretty boring day. There's been a let down of prices since activity yesterday, some industry buying and fund short covering&quot;. &quot;Prices are in a tight range of 1,022 to 1,056...everyone's just waiting for West Africa,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>&quot;There've been a few options and March crosses...prices for December might go below support levels but there is no volume there...we are hoping it holds out above 1,039,&quot; said another trader before the market closed below that level.</p>
<p>Buoyant speculative buying and options-related activity on Wednesday drove September prices prices up to new resistance 1,056 stg per tonne, with overall volume at 8,915 lots.</p>
<p>But the midday expiry of September options on Wednesday passed without options being exercised by holders of large long postions..</p>
<p>&quot;People were long and wanted to push the market up,&quot; said one trader this morning, referring to Wednesday. &quot;All it has done is extending the range,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Technical analysts saw strong December support at 1,021 stg and resistance above Wednesday's high of 1,056 stg all the way up to $1,080.</p>
<p>-- Matthew Bunce, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8072</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
