<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8949" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Defecating man stars in campaign against dog mess. [CORRECTED 17:10 GMT]</title>
<headline>Defecating man stars in campaign against dog mess. [CORRECTED 17:10 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>London dog-lovers who let their pets foul the streets are being targeted by a cinema advertisement campaign showing a man defecating on the pavement.</p>
<p>The inner-London borough of Islington said on Thursday it planned to run an advertisement showing a middle-aged man dressed in pyjamas squatting down and fouling the pavement.</p>
<p>&quot;You wouldn't. Don't let your dog&quot; is the message, as the man's neighbour slips on the mess.</p>
<p>Around 17,500 dogs -- one for every 10 humans -- live in Islington, where local authorities reckon they fork out 32,000 pounds ($49,500) a year to clear up their mess.</p>
<p>&quot;We've tried the soft approach, but there are some people it clearly isn't getting through to,&quot; said Islington's director of leisure Ivan Loftman.</p>
<p>The ad is made by Saatchi &amp; Saatchi, which was behind four winning election campaigns for the Conservative Party but is no longer the party's advertising agency.</p>
<p>(Corrects to delete reference to the party's current advertising campaign, which is handled by another agency, M&amp;C Saatchi).</p>
<p>($1=.6460 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
