<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8958" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CBI sees steady, unspectacular UK growth in 1996.</title>
<headline>CBI sees steady, unspectacular UK growth in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's leading business federation expects steady, unspectacular growth to continue in 1996 and said there was no need for another interest rate cut.</p>
<p>In its Economic Situation report, the Confederation of British Industry (CBI) said on Friday it expected UK GDP to grow 2.0 percent in 1996 with activity picking up to 3.1 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Our stance is that interest rates should be left on hold,&quot; said Kate Barker, the CBI's chief economic adviser. &quot;The risk of a new recession is only slight.&quot;  </p>
<p>She said the outlook for inflation was very positive in the short-term, &quot;but our forecast suggests as output grows inflation will start to edge up. We would not oppose another rate cut if it was only a 1/4-point but are certainly not pushing for one.&quot;</p>
<p>Interest rates were last cut in June, by a quarter point to 5.75 percent. But there is widespread speculation that Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke will squeeze one more in the autumn to give the economy another push before the general election, due by May 1997.</p>
<p>The CBI said a strong upswing in the consumer sector underpins the growth forecasts for this year and next.  </p>
<p>It estimated consumer expenditure will grow by 3.2 percent in 1995 and reach 4.0 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>This represents an upwards revision from the CBI's previous round of forecasting in May when consumer spending was estimated to rise by 2.8 percent in 1996 and 3.5 in 1997.</p>
<p>But investment will also make a contribution to GDP growth. &quot;Although the consumer is expected to contribute the lions share to growth, stronger private capital spending will also underpin the recovery,&quot; said Sudhir Junankar, the CBI associate director of economic analysis.  </p>
<p>However, with the government keen to cut back expenditure, public capital spending will be limted.</p>
<p>The CBI forecasts a cut in overall government spending of 4.5 billion stg which will more than offset personal tax cuts of around 2.0 billion it expects to see in the November budget.</p>
<p>This fiscal tightening compares with the CBI's previous forecast of a one billion stg net tightening.</p>
<p>Barker said the government will come under increasing pressure to improve the state of the public finances which she said were in an unsatisfactory state so far into the economic recovery.</p>
<p>But even this fiscal rectitude estimated by the CBI will not be enough to bring government borrowing down to the 3.0 percent Maastricht target.</p>
<p>And Britain's beleaguered manufacturing sector, which narrowly avoided recession this year, will contribute significantly to output growth next year.</p>
<p>The CBI forecasts manufacturing output will grow by 3.9 percent next year, a marginal downward revision from its previous forecast, while its 1996 forecast has been revised down to 0.6 percent from 1.0 percent at the last round.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7950</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
