<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8960" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Brent ends firm, near highs, in heat-led rally.</title>
<headline>IPE Brent ends firm, near highs, in heat-led rally.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE Brent crude futures closed sharply higher on Thursday following a technical rally inspired first by local gas oil futures and then by NYMEX heating oil, brokers said.</p>
<p>Sept Brent closed 52 cents up at $20.73 a barrel, having touched, but failed to breach, key resistance at $20.80. The Sep/Oct backwardation widened six cents to 52 cents a barrel.</p>
<p>The market dipped in late afternoon trade amid confusion over the timing of Iraqi oil exports, but retraced gains when reports were clarified.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength is basically on technicals,&quot; said one broker.  </p>
<p>&quot;We were strong this morning and NYMEX's performance just confirmed the move,&quot; another said.</p>
<p>IPE gas oil, buoyed by low inventories, led up the oil complex before the NYMEX open.</p>
<p>September gas oil closed up $3.00 at $191.00 a tonne, just off a session and contract high of $191.50. The Oct Brent/gas oil crack spread ended higher at $4.73 a barrel.</p>
<p>Trading volumes for Brent and gas oil were reported thin.</p>
<p>Brokers said that news of a fire at Tosco's Bayway, New Jersey refinery and the brief closure of the Sumed crude oil pipeline lent only fleeting support to the market.  </p>
<p>Brent futures stumbled in late afternoon trade, sliding close to opening lows, on the perception that Iraqi oil exports could resume shortly.</p>
<p>A U.N. official said in New York that technical arrangements to implement the oil-for-food deal, which is set to release 700,000 b/d of Iraqi oil onto world markets, could be completed in 7-10 days. But he added that could be an optimistic assessment and the process could take longer.</p>
<p>Traders said that mention of Iraq still briefly spooked the market.</p>
<p>Rosalind Russell, London newsroom +44 171 542 5387</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
