<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8964" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: MINOR METALS - Slow ahead of fourth quarter 1996.</title>
<headline>MINOR METALS - Slow ahead of fourth quarter 1996.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Minor metals were becalmed again in the summer doldrums this week, apart from cobalt which saw pockets of buying activity.</p>
<p>Traders said consumer demand was starting to build up momentum, expecting demand within the sector to flourish in the busy fourth quarter of the year, but many were unable to agree outright price direction for several of the metals.</p>
<p>Tight nearby supplies and recent bullish sentiment continued to move cobalt higher, with several traders predicting further gains for the metal, especially Russian, near term.</p>
<p>&quot;It has the potential (Russian) to notch up another two or three dollars in the next three months,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>But another European trader aired caution, believing Russian cobalt now around levels of $22/$23 was to high.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not dispute the price rising, although I feel the market at the moment is running ahead of itself and is far too bullish,&quot; he commented.</p>
<p>He pegged the Russian metal at a more conservative $21.25/$22.0.</p>
<p>Cobalt's recent spike followed sizeable purchases from China and inquiry from India, factors which could be bolstered by trader anticipation of fresh consumer demand from major user Japan.</p>
<p>Low global stocks and unreliable production from Russia were cited as the main factor behind cobalt's recent bullish run</p>
<p>This has seen prices move from recent 23-month lows of around $18/$19.</p>
<p>Battery demand and a growth in the areospace industry is likely to keep the market on a buoyant footing medium-term.</p>
<p>But a backdrop of bearish sentiment hangs over the market.</p>
<p>Traders noted increased production from Zambia and Canada's Falconbridge, while others remained wary of the Defence Logistics Agency (DLA) sales policy for 1997.</p>
<p>High grade material was also moved higher, though outright business remained sluggish, traders said.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, market operators were building up for the fourth quarter flurry of consumer business.</p>
<p>Germanium oxide eased as stockpiled metal flowed out of the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Traders noted long liquidation and several believed prices could slip below $1,000 a kilo near-term, a level that even major producers would be comfortable with, according to one.</p>
<p>&quot;We are seeing metal being cranked out in pretty hefty proportions and the resulting decline in prices,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Molybdenum held steady after its recent slippage.</p>
<p>Concerns about restarts at Molycorp's various facilities in the U.S. that were shut down in 1991 helped to dampen upside potential.</p>
<p>Bulls and bears stood toe-to-toe in the magnesium arena.</p>
<p>But both sides of the market agreed business was slack.</p>
<p>One European operator said they were a moderate seller of high grade CIS ex-Rotterdam material at $2,600 a tonne, and that Chinese material was also sliding.</p>
<p>But this was disputed by traders at the higher end of the market as they believed the material sold was of poor quality.</p>
<p>&quot;Its probably oxidised,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Antimony held steady amid the lack of strong two-way business, though like all metals of the sector it was standing by for the fourth quarter rush of activity.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 71 510 8075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
