<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8969" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products firmer, futures add support.</title>
<headline>Med oil products firmer, futures add support.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mediterranean oil products were firm on Thursday.</p>
<p>Gasoline was notionally firmer with futures although the market remained long in comparison to northwest Europe.</p>
<p>Sources said Petrofina's 80,000 barrels per day (bpd) Rome refinery trimmed runs by around 10 percent because of poor margins. That followed earlier news that Isab cut runs at its 220,000 bpd refinery by some 20 percent.</p>
<p>High gasoline stock levels in the Mediterranean meant that run cuts could be accomodated easily by reducing inventories.</p>
<p>Naphtha was firmer in line with crude.  </p>
<p>Gas oil was buoyant supported by healthy demand.</p>
<p>At least five Russian cargoes were expected to arrive in the Med by end-Aug. Sellers and buyers remained distanced with premiums assessed at quotes cif high +75 cents/+$2.0.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of these cargoes have potential homes if the sellers don't get what they want on the spot market so they're pretty relaxed,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>A Turkish tender for three 25,000-tonne cargoes for September delivery also lent support to the market.  </p>
<p>A French refiner was due to lift a cargo out of Cagliari before the weekend offered it at quotes cif hi +$1.50, basis Lavera, traders said.</p>
<p>There was also talk that a 30,000 tonne cargo of Canadian 0.05 percent gas oil was bound for the Med and offered at IPE Sept +12.50, cif Lavera.</p>
<p>High sulphur cracked fuel oil supplies tight with product difficult to source. Dealers said the $98 cif Gibralter paid for a cargo of bunker spec material earlier in the week had been built upon and $92.50 fob Med was probably the best a buyer could hope to get away with if material could be found.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
