<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8978" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bradford wool market sees signs of life in merinos.</title>
<headline>Bradford wool market sees signs of life in merinos.</headline>
<dateline>BRADFORD 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>There were a few bright spots in the market for merinos, but otherwise wool prices at Bradford remained generally steady on Thursday, brokers said.</p>
<p>Top prices for 70s Super were up by around seven pence to 525 pence per kg, and 64s, both blended and Supers, saw increases of five pence.</p>
<p>But prices for coarser wools were mostly static, brokers said.</p>
<p>Competition was said to have been at its most intense between local traders, with buyers still pitching their offers extremely low.</p>
<p>Some brokers attributed the tight trading conditions to overcapacity despite the reduced influx of low-priced South American tops.</p>
<p>With UK prices holding firm and strengthening markets in the other major producing countries, several market sources were cautiously optimistic about the outlook for Bradford tops.</p>
<p>One broker described the market as &quot;reasonably sound&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It would only need a rise in Chinese demand for the market to gather strength,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom, +44 171 542 8071</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRADFORD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
