<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8979" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Sugar freight market quiet, Santos queue eases.</title>
<headline>Sugar freight market quiet, Santos queue eases.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Business was relatively calm on the sugar freight market on Thursday with few new orders emerging, shipbrokers said. Although no new inquiries were reported from south Brazil's key sugar exporting outlet of Santos, the line-up of vessels waiting outside the port is said to have eased.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there's much congestion there,&quot; one shipbroker said.</p>
<p>According to Lloyds Shipping Intelligence, nine sugar loaders are currently berthed at Santos, compared with nearly double that number a couple of weeks ago.</p>
<p>Of Thursday's firmer business, Mauritius Sugar fixed two bulk sugar orders on its usual Port Louis to London route -- 17,500 tonnes for 22/23 August at stg 16.00 and 18,000 tonnes for 5/15 September at stg 16.25.</p>
<p>C.Czarnikow was said to have fixed 18,000 tonnes of bulk sugar from Maputo to the US Gulf for 12/17 September at $22.50 and Farr Man fixed 20,000 tonnes from Beira to US Gulf/Atlantic for $30.00 for spot dates.</p>
<p>CSR was open for 17,000 tonnes of bulk sugar from Queensland to Hakata or Tokyo range and CSC came in with a small order for 4,800 tonnes of bagged sugar from Puerto Quetzal to the Dominican Republic for prompt onwards dates, shipbrokers said.</p>
<p>Cargill was also reported to have quoted recently for 3,000 tonnes of bagged sugar from Thailand to Indonesia or Karachi.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8064</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
