<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8981" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dollar eases grip on mark gains in late Europe.</title>
<headline>Dollar eases grip on mark gains in late Europe.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Reierson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar slipped from afternoon highs against the mark in late European trade, after struggling to break key resistance near 1.4960 marks as the Bundesbank aggressively cut 30 basis point off its repo rate earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;The size of the Bundesbank cut caught the market totally out, but the move today is probably all we're going to see,&quot; said a trader at a Swiss bank here. The &quot;1.4950-60 marks (level) is a very heavy area, and we may push up above 1.50... (but) there is still some reluctance to be long dollars even after today.&quot;  </p>
<p>The dollar against the mark stood 1.4910/20 by 1537 GMT down from the session high of 1.4964 marks seen soon after the Bundesbank cut rates but still almost a pfenning higher from late Wednesday's 1.4822/25.</p>
<p>Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer said a decisive factor in lowering the repo was the development of M3 money supply and its continuing approach toward the 4.0-7.0 percent corridor.</p>
<p>Pre-consumer inflation also posed no danger to price stability in the immediate future, he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the size of the cut also made it clear the Bundesbank wanted a weaker mark.  </p>
<p>The dollar against the yen stood at 108.20/30 at 1624 GMT against an earlier high of 108.70 yen and from late Wednesday's level of 108.31/41.</p>
<p>The Swiss National Bank left its key discount rate unchanged at 1.5 percent but said it was adding a &quot;significant quantity &quot; of liquidity to the Swiss money market in its ongoing effort to ease tight money conditions without lowering rates.</p>
<p>By 1632 GMT, the Swiss franc was trading at 1.2067/77 per dollar and 80.90/93 centimes per mark from 1.1998/08 and 80.95/97 late Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Buba cut was followed by similar cuts in France, Belgium, Austria, and the Netherlands. The mark was sold off heavily on the Eurocrosses but had recovered some ground by late European trade.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the sell-off we have seen in the mark is going to be transitory, it's enough to keep the Bundesbank happy but there are still big fundamental problems in Europe,&quot; said David Coleman, chief economist at CIBC Wood Gundy. &quot;All the budget, political and monetary union problems are still in place.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar was choppy against the yen but dealers said trade there was being led by dollar/mark. -- Andrew Reierson, London Newsroom +44 171 542 6745</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
