<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8989" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK wheat harvest rolls towards north, yields good.</title>
<headline>UK wheat harvest rolls towards north, yields good.</headline>
<byline>Clelia Oziel</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The British wheat harvest is nearing completion in southern and central regions and yields are generally ample despite an unfavourable spring, consultants and grain buyers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Farmers had feared severe crop losses in some areas where grains were deprived of moisture at their maturing stage.</p>
<p>Field activity is oftendisrupted by scattered showers but no damage has so far been reported as humidity is low.</p>
<p>Except for light soils where root formation has stayed behind this year, crops generally managed to catch up in the summer just before the harvest.</p>
<p>&quot;We got away with it,&quot; said one analyst for agricultural consultancy firm ADAS in East Anglia -- the top growing region.</p>
<p>But milling wheat scored lower than last year on protein levels, and malting barley varieties were generally poor.</p>
<p>Barley harvesting has been completed across the country, except the north and Scotland, and yields were impressive.</p>
<p>Here is a region-by-region update --</p>
<p>EAST ANGLIA</p>
<p>Some 60 to 70 percent of the wheat area is estimated to be harvested in East Anglia. The average yield could still be some 10 percent lower from 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Yields are all over the place,&quot; said one consultant.</p>
<p>But the outturn mproved just before the harvest and yields were generally better than first expected, he added.</p>
<p>On average, milling wheat yields are reported to be around 3.25 tonnes per acre, but losses are partly offset by high bushel weights around 70-80 kilos/hectolitre, grain buyers said.</p>
<p>Milling wheat proteins are just under 11 percent, while those of feed wheat are variable at just about 9.5 percent.</p>
<p>Many farmers have already completed wheat cutting and the rest are likely finish by the end of next week.</p>
<p>The region produced a poor malting barley crop this year with high nitrogen content at around 1.9-2.2 percent and high screenings, but yields were good at some 2.5 kilos per acre.</p>
<p>Despite the drop in quality farmers were confident the brewers would buy their crop. &quot;The trade may well take that material. They may not have any other choice,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Feed barley yields were impressive at 3-3.5 tonnes.</p>
<p>SOUTHEAST</p>
<p>Three quarters of the wheat area has been cut in the Southeast where impressive yields of up to a maximum of five tonnes per acre were reported. Most fell into the 3.5-4 range.</p>
<p>Milling wheat scored modestly on protein at 10.9 percent while feed wheat averaged around 9.8percent, farmers said.</p>
<p>Bushel weights were high around 80 kilos per hectolitre.</p>
<p>Barley harvest is completed and on malting barley, nitrogen contents improved with spring varieties scoring an acceptable 1.6 percent after a poor winter collection, grain buyers said.</p>
<p>EAST MIDLANDS</p>
<p>In East Midlands, about half of the southern wheat area and some 30 percent of the north have been harvested so far.</p>
<p>Feed wheat yields are said to be better than last year with an average of 3.8 tonnes per acre, but milling varieties showed lower protein at around 11 percent.</p>
<p>Farmers are expecting to complete wheat collection within the next week subject to weather conditions.</p>
<p>Barley yields held steady throughout the harvest, while grain size and nitrogen content improved with the spring crop.</p>
<p>SOUTHWEST</p>
<p>Very little wheat has been cut in the Southwest and no early quality assessments were yet available.</p>
<p>But malting barley qualities have improved as the season progressed and yields were reported to be generally good.</p>
<p>YORKSHIRE</p>
<p>Farmers in Yorkshire are just about to finish barley harvesting and move to wheat fields.</p>
<p>Excellent barley yields were reported, averaging three tonnes per acre on feed types, while feed wheat yields were forecast to be an impressive 3.5 tonnes per acre.</p>
<p>Barley showed high specific weights of around 67.2 kilos per hectolitre, farm experts said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8072</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
