<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8992" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Baltic Freight Index edges up, Capers help.</title>
<headline>Baltic Freight Index edges up, Capers help.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A fresh if modest gain, of four points to 1,117, on the Baltic Freight Index (BFI) on Thursday reflected a continuing tentative revival in rates in the dry cargo market, shipbrokers reported.</p>
<p>They said Capers continued firmer with the Panamax sector also seeing somewhat healthier volume.  But activity remained subdued by summer holidays and just ahead of a three-day UK holiday weekend.</p>
<p>Brokers' views were mixed on whether the positive trend for owners would be extended for very long.</p>
<p>Fixture rates in key routes such as the U.S. Gulf/Japan for grain and Hampton Roads/Rotterdam for coal had mainly lifted the BFI this week with the Far East showing less strength.</p>
<p>However, brokers said Far East Capers also looked firmer.</p>
<p>Timecharters reported on Thursday included Cape Africa 149,533 dwt delivery Kaohsiung mid-September trip via New South Wales re-delivery UK at $9,000.</p>
<p>This compared with $8,000 a week ago for a similar fixture on a slightly larger vessel.</p>
<p>Also among somewhat firmer timecharters, HMM fixed Giovanni Grimaldi 135,500 dwt delivery Continent Sept 8-13 La Cienaga redelivery Rotterdam at $10,400 daily.</p>
<p>In the Panamax sector, Docenave fixed Pacific Prospect 73,630 dwt delivery Hampton Roads September 7/14 two/four months redelivery Atlantic for $8,600 daily plus $100,000 bb which was a touch firmer than recent business.</p>
<p>Grains activity saw MSK fix 54,000/5 tonnes heavy grain U.S. Gulf/Japan with Ocean Ruby for September 10-17 at $20.90 no combo, 40 cents up on a Navios deal at the end of last week for comparable dates.</p>
<p>A focus of market interest is the decision announced on Wednesday of the Baltic Exchange to introduce a Handy-size Index on January 9, 1997, after a trail period beginning September 3.</p>
<p>Among reactions on Thursday, John Banaszkiewicz at Cargill Investor Services (CIS), which has been among brokers urging such an index, said he was optimistic it would find support.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the removal of the Handy Size routes from the Baltic Freight Index there has been no real mechanism for this substantial part of the freight market to protect its price risk&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 7729</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
