<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="8997" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK beet crop expected to recover after weak start.</title>
<headline>UK beet crop expected to recover after weak start.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's 1996/97 sugar beet crop looks to be on course for a recovery despite early field tests showing that sugar contents continue to be sharply lower than in 1995, beet analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;From the reports that have come through, it looks as if the beets are putting on weight but the sugar is still low,&quot; said an official at the National Farmers Union (NFU).</p>
<p>&quot;But it does look like things are going to go okay providing people take action against various aggressors and diseases at this stage,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Results of the first three beet tests conducted by British Sugar Plc since the start of testing on August 5 have showed sugar contents sharply down on the equivalent tests in 1995.</p>
<p>The last test, conducted on August 19, showed content at 16.04 percent after 19.39 percent last year.</p>
<p>While average root weights are up on last year, the amounts of sugar per root were still lower than in 1995 and also down on the five-year average.</p>
<p>Beet experts said the crop was still in need of more moisture after dry weather earlier in the summer.</p>
<p>&quot;The crop has reasonable potential but it does need some rain, there's no doubt. The populations are a bit low,&quot; said Simon Kerr of the National Institute of Agricultural Botany.</p>
<p>&quot;The crop has maintained an average growth rate and continues to be on course for an average result, but would benefit from some rain,&quot; said a spokesman for British Sugar after the release of the third test result.</p>
<p>Although this year's crop is believed to be generally healthy so far, with an absence of the principal virus yellows disease, analysts said it could still be threatened by moths from a plague earlier in the summer.</p>
<p>Kerr said incidence of such diseases as red spider and powdery mildew was low, although earlier in its growing cycle the crop had suffered an invasion of silver Y moths, which produce beet-grazing green caterpillars.</p>
<p>Experts have said Britain's beet areas are unlikely to see the same prolonged period of drought and high temperatures suffered last summer, which effectively crippled the crop, although the early developments of both crops looked similar.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a lack of moisture again this year...I'm surprised that we're so down compared with last year. I thought that conditions would have been more favourable this year,&quot; the NFU official said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8064</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100128">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
