<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9000" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: EMS/Mark closing report.</title>
<headline>EMS/Mark closing report.</headline>
<byline>Abigail Levene</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The mark was licking its wounds in late Europe after an aggressive 30 basis-point Bundesbank repo rate cut touched off a chain reaction of easings across Europe.</p>
<p>The German cut, which triggered copycat moves in France, Austria, Belgium and the Netherlands, caught out a market which had been braced for steady rates or, at most, a modest ease.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Bundesbank had clearly signalled its desire for a weaker mark. But the German unit was off its lows in late European trade as the market got to wondering whether the hefty Bundesbank cut meant German rates had now bottomed.  </p>
<p>The German move opened the way for the Bank of France to make a sorely-needed reduction in its intervention rate, which the bank duly trimmed to 3.35 percent from 3.55.</p>
<p>But market attention never strays far from French efforts to spur growth and trim deficits to shape up for European monetary union, and the franc is by no means home and dry, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The franc remains vulnerable because of continued uncertainty over the fiscal outlook, and we won't get that uncertainty diminished or removed until we see the French budget for 1997,&quot; said DKB International economist Nick Stamenkovic.</p>
<p>The franc was quoted at 3.4079/84 per mark by 1453 GMT.  </p>
<p>&quot;The risk is that people dismiss this as the last cut in the current cycle,&quot; said Julian Jessop, chief European economist at Nikko Europe in London.</p>
<p>Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer said the slowdown in German M3 and low inflation had allowed the repo cut. The reduction was in line with the central bank's general policy trend, he said in a telephone statement to news agencies.</p>
<p>He made no direct comment on possible future moves, but said today's decision had cleared the decks for the time being.</p>
<p>The fragile French franc breathed perhaps the biggest sigh of relief after the hefty German repo cut.  </p>
<p>That represented a sharp drop for the mark from late Wednesday's European level of 3.4209/13, though it was narrowly off a session low of 3.4041.</p>
<p>The Italian lira firmed to 1017.25/75 by 1515 GMT from the previous close here of 1022.75/23.25. It hit an intraday high of 1016.05.</p>
<p>The Dutch central bank said the strength of the guilder allowed it to trim its special advances rate by 20 basis points to 2.50 percent. The guilder was quoted at 112.11 per 100 marks in late trade compared to 112.17 late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Belgium cut its central rate to 3.00 percent from 3.20.  </p>
<p>Austria cut its repo to a fixed rate of 3.0 percent from 3.2, and shaved the Gomex to 3.4 percent from 3.5.</p>
<p>The Swiss National Bank, however, its discount rate already a low 1.50 percent, left policy unchanged at a weekly meeting of the board of directors.</p>
<p>But the board did decide to continue pumping liquidity into the Swiss money market. Traders said the SNB added overnight funds to the market at 2.00 percent.</p>
<p>The Swiss franc was quoted at 80.95/98 centimes per mark by 1528 GMT compared to late Wednesday's 80.93/95 and off the day's Swiss high of 80.75.  </p>
<p>Friday sees the release at 0700 GMT of August provisional CPI data by the German state of Hesse. Baden-Wuerttemberg and North Rhine-Westphalia are also due to publish their CPI on Friday at the earliest and Bavaria is due Monday or Tuesday.</p>
<p>The reports from the four states are used to compute provisional west German consumer price data.</p>
<p>In Italy, Perugia, Florence, Bologna and Naples made August CPI projections ranging from 2.7 to 3.5 percent. The first six cities on Thursday forecast CPI between 2.5 percent and 4.2.</p>
<p>Analysts projected overall Italian August CPI at 3.3/3.4 percent versus July's 3.6. -- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8968</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
