<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9003" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: W. African crude sales to Asia high again in Sept.</title>
<headline>W. African crude sales to Asia high again in Sept.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>West African oil producers will export about half a million barrels per day (bpd) of crude again in September to customers in Asia, traders said on Thursday.</p>
<p>While September exports are expected to be about 300,000 bpd lower than the exceptionally high flows seen in July, they should equal August volumes and will continue the recent trend of unseasonal purchases by Asian refiners, the traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;For the last couple of years the Far East has taken good volumes in the Oct-April period but usually very little in the summer,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Exports peaked at a record one million bpd in February this year before petering out almost entirely in May and June.</p>
<p>But traders said growing refinery capacity in the region and tighter emission standards for refined products had sparked fresh demand demand for low sulphur West African barrels.</p>
<p>&quot;I've been surprised by some of the things sold into Korea recently but it must be helping to fill up their new crude distillation capacity and produce the low sulphur products,&quot; said a trader for a major West African producer.</p>
<p>Others said an unattractive spread between Brent -- against which most West African spot sales are priced -- and Far East benchmark Dubai crude was not deterring buyers in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the Brent/Dubai spread they're still buying,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>&quot;They've taken a broad cross-section of crudes for September, so it can't be because of a particular product requirement. I can only think they're after the sulphur advantage.&quot;</p>
<p>Brent was almost $1.90 a barrel more expensive than Dubai on the forward paper markets on Thursday.</p>
<p>In addition to the Indian Oil Corp's regular purchase of three very large crude carriers (VLCCs) of Nigerian Qua Iboe, South Korea's Yukong has taken a VLCC of Nigerian Bonny Light/Medium and Odudu and another of Bonny Light/Medium and Forcados in September.</p>
<p>Two VLCCs have also gone to Taiwan's CPC, one containing cargoes of Angola's Palanca and Congo's Djeno and the other made up of Odudu and Djeno.</p>
<p>&quot;That makes about 13.5 million barrels so far, but September trade is not finished yet and there is still enough available for somebody to put another VLCC together for the east,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>-- Mark Thompson, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7930</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
