<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9005" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Zeneca shares gyrate on takeover talk.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Zeneca shares gyrate on takeover talk.</headline>
<byline>Debra Sherman</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in British pharmaceutical firm Zeneca Group set a record on Thursday amid renewed rumours Swiss giant Roche Holdings AG was nursing a takeover bid but the shares fell back as analysts dismissed the chatter.</p>
<p>&quot;It would have to be a very attractive deal for (Zeneca's) shareholders,&quot; Kleinwort Benson analyst Steve Putman said of a possible bid. &quot;I think it's unlikely for now. Whether the company disappears in two years time is a different story.&quot;</p>
<p>The worldwide drug industry has undergone dramatic consolidation over the last two years, making any medium size company a potential takeover candidate.</p>
<p>But a hostile bidder would have to pay as much as 20 pounds per share for Zeneca, said Steve Abbott, an analyst with Credit Lyonnais Laing.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there will be a hostile bid. Zeneca might find a partner to merge with in a few years time and the implied price (of Zeneca's shares) after a friendly merger could be around 1750p,&quot; Abbott said.</p>
<p>&quot;You could argue that Zeneca is trading at the top end of fair value,&quot; added Putman. &quot;The company should deliver at least 12 percent earnings growth for the next five years ... and that would put it in line with U.S. drug companies.&quot;</p>
<p>Putman figures 18 times 1997 earnings is close to fair value for Zeneca's shares. He's forecasting pretax profits of 1.130 billion stg in 1997 and 1.255 billion stg in 1998.</p>
<p>Shares in Zeneca, which reached an all-time intra-day peak of 1538p, gave up their early gains, but still were holding between 50p and 100p of takeover premium, analysts said.</p>
<p>Zeneca, Britain's third biggest drug company, declined to comment on the takeover speculation, but only two weeks ago, Zeneca's chief executive Sir David Barnes reiterated management's intention to remain independent.</p>
<p>&quot;The company has a glowing future in front of it. We are facing very strong prospects for organic growth. There is no strategic imperative to go scurrying for shelter (with another firm),&quot; he told Reuters in an interview earlier this month after reporting a 21 percent increase in first half profits.</p>
<p>&quot;Zeneca would be a big chunk for anyone to bite off. Roche could do it, but it's not Roche's style to launch a hostile bid,&quot; said one analyst who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;At this stage in the cycle, anything other than an agreed upon bid or a merger is unlikely. It wouldn't make sense for Roche to make an expensive and presumably dilutive acquisition,&quot; he added. &quot;But there's no smoke without fire. I think there's something going on somewhere.&quot;</p>
<p>Laing's Abbott added, &quot;That's not to say Zeneca might not find a partner to merge with in two or three years. There are a lot of smaller companies that are never mentioned that could be good partners.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
