<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9012" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Sports News - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Sports News - Aug 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Practicing at the Premadasa Stadium in Colombo, Australian batsman Mark Waugh drove a cricket ball onto a staffer's head more than 100 metres away. The Sri Lankan groundsman was knocked out by the ball and Australian team officials quickly came to his asistance. Page 24.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Defending his NEC World Series of Golf championship this weekend in Ohio, Australian golfer Greg Norman has sacked his long-time coach Butch Harmon after a season of indifferent form. Currently 10th on the 1996 US Tour money list, Norman admitted it was robably his lowest grade since 1991. Page 24.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Recovering from a knee injury, Perth Wildcats forward Scott Fisher will play against the Melbourne Tigers in the top-of-the-table National Basketball League clash tonight, after passing a fitness test yesterday. The Wildcats will back-up against the Adelide 36ers on Saturday night. Page 22.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Soccer Australia and rebel soccer clubs Marconi Fairfield, Sydney United and Melbourne Knights had reached some form of compromise on the logo issue by the time yesterday's 5pm deadline passed. While club officials returned to their boards with recommendations about new uniforms, SA board chairman David Hill said SA would allow the clubs to use European nationalistic colours in their logos. Page 42.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Paralympian John Lindsay won a gold medal in the 100-metre wheelchair race on Wednesday. Lindsay beat the rest of the field in 15.22 seconds, finishing strongly after his hand slipped off the wheel at the start of the race. Page 41.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After two weeks ago refusing to grant rugby league club South Queensland a loan to cover a reported A$4 million debt, the Australian Rugby League has been identified as the benefactor responsible for guaranteeing Crushers' players payments for the remainder of the season. Page 41.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>For the fourth time in the past five grand slams, Australian tennis player Mark Philippoussis and world number one Pete Sampras have been drawn precariously close to each other, with a third-round clash in the US Open likely.  Page C6.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Melbourne Tigers centre Mark Bradtke has denied suggestions that he is set to join Shane Heal in the US National Basketball Association, saying there is only a 10 per cent chance that he will sign with the Philadelphia 76ers. Page C6.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Former Hawthorn star Dermott Brereton has boosted the anti-merger group, Operation Payback's, chances of reaching its A$1.7 million financial target, after announcing that he would be interested in joining a new-look board if the AFL club's merger with Mebourne should fail. Page C10.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>HERALD SUN</p>
<p>Melbourne and Monaco are both challenging the Friday Formula One ban in grand prix racing which is attempting to restrict the races to weekends-only in 1997. Melbourne and Monte Carlo are seeking to keep the extra day of driving practice because of the nuture of their temporary circuits. Page 106.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Champion Carlton centreman Greg Williams' football future is in doubt because of chronic problems with his right knee which will force him to miss his second AFL game in a row tomorrow. Carlton officials must at least face the possibility that the 33-yea-old may not play again for the rest of the season. Page 110.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The AFL's decision to take no action against Richmond's John Howat has infuriated Geelong, who must meet North Melbourne tonight without star ruckman John Barnes who was forced out because of concussion sustained in a behind-the-play incident last weekend Page 112.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>Australia will face England in the semi-finals of the world youth netball championships after beating the Cook Islands 89-21 in their final round match yesterday. Australia and New Zealand are the only two undefeated teams at the World Youth Cup in Canada. Page 106.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Irish rugby union officials are expected to resist Australia's plan to bring the November 30 Test against Ireland forward one week. The Wallabies are scheduled to play Tests against Italy, Scotland and Ireland during their seven-week European tour, but the Australian Rugby Union is also trying to fit in a Test against Wales. Page 110.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Nigerian officials are outraged after World Junior Athletics Championships organisers played the wrong national anthem for Nigeria's sprinters during the medal presentation for the men's 100 metres event. The mistake has proved very embarassing for Athletics Australia. Page 112.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
