<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9014" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: RTRS-Tennis-Muster upset, Philippoussis wins, Stoltenberg loses.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Tennis-Muster upset, Philippoussis wins, Stoltenberg loses.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top-seeded Thomas Muster of Austria was beaten 6-3 7-5 by 123rd-ranked Daniel Nestor of Canada on Wednesday in his first match of the $2 million Canadian Open.</p>
<p>A lefthander with a strong serve, Nestor kept the rallies short by constantly attacking the net and the tactic worked in the second-round match against Muster, playing his first match after receiving a first-round bye along with the other top eight seeds.</p>
<p>The tournament also lost its second seed on the third day of play when second-seeded Goran Ivanisevic of Croatia was beaten 6-7(3-7) 6-4 6-4 by unseeded Mikael Tillstrom of Sweden.</p>
<p>Other seeded players advancing were number three Wayne Ferreira of South Africa, number four Marcelo Rios of Chile, number six MaliVai Washington of the United States and American Todd Martin, the seventh seeed.</p>
<p>Eighth seed Marc Rosset of Switzerland was eliminated in a one hour, 55 minute battle by unseeded Mark Philippoussis of Australia. Philippoussis saved a match point at 5-6 in the third-set tie break before winning 6-3 3-6 7-6 (8-6).</p>
<p>Philippoussis's compatriot, 13th seed Jason Stoltenberg, was not as fortunate. He held one match point at 9-8 in a marathon third-set tie break but was beaten 5-7 7-6 (7-1) 7-6 (13-11) by unseeded Daniel Vacek of the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>&quot;I knew I had to serve well and keep the points short and that's what I was able to do,&quot; said Nestor, who ranks 10th in doubles.</p>
<p>There were only two service breaks in the match. The lanky Canadian broke Muster at 4-3 in the first set and 5-5 in the second before ending the match on his third match point when the Austrian hit a service return long.</p>
<p>&quot;I probably didn't hit five ground strokes in the whole match,&quot; said Muster, only partly joking. &quot;The way he was chipping and charging and serving and volleying I didn't really get my timing playing from the baseline.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;He played a good match, took a few chances, and every time he was down he was able to come up with a big first serve.&quot;</p>
<p>Playing at night was not Muster's preference. &quot;I asked for a day match and they gave me a night match,&quot; he said. &quot;I don't like playing under the lights but maybe it would not have made any difference.&quot;</p>
<p>Ivanisevic rallied from a 2-5 deficit in the first set but then played erratically against the 44th-ranked Tillstrom, who was a surprise winner over his famous compatriot Stefan Edberg in the second round at Wimbledon.</p>
<p>Ivanisevic hit 32 aces but was outplayed from the back court by the 24-year-old Tillstrom.</p>
<p>The sixth-ranked Ivanisevic, who lost in the final at Indianapolis to world number one Pete Sampras of the U.S. last Sunday, made a quick getaway after his loss but did say: &quot;Something was not there when I arrived (in Toronto). I didn't feel good. And I didn't have a good feeling as soon as I lost in my doubles (on Tuesday).&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I thought he looked a little unfocused at certain times on his ground strokes,&quot; said Tillstrom.</p>
<p>The 19-year-old Philippoussis, who beat Sampras in the third round of this year's Australian Open, stayed calm in a nervy third-set tie break against Rosset.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm pleased because I didn't play that great today, but I fought really well,&quot; he said. &quot;When I was down 2-5 in the tiebreak (in the third set), I just thought about winning my two serves and hoped that he might get tight. Then he shanked a forehand at to make it 5-all and that helped me back.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
