<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9015" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: NZ SPORT- All Blacks announce unchanged side.</title>
<headline>NZ SPORT- All Blacks announce unchanged side.</headline>
<byline>Andy Colquhoun</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The confident All Blacks announced an unchanged team on Thursday in their bid to become the first New Zealand side to win a series in South Africa.</p>
<p>Even though flyhalf Andrew Mehrtens has made a rapid recovery from a cartilage operation they retain the side which won in Durban last week for the second test in Pretoria on Saturday.</p>
<p>Simon Culhane keeps the number 10 jersey as coach John Hart sticks to his policy of consistency in selection.  </p>
<p>This is the ninth successive international in which Hart has named an unchanged pack and in all he has used only 19 players.</p>
<p>The Springboks will not whittle down their 23-strong squad until shortly before the kick-off and changes are expected. Seven were made before last week's 23-19 test defeat.</p>
<p>Lock Mark Andrews said: &quot;We've had a few new players come in because of injuries or whatever and it's been hard for us but that's no excuse.&quot;</p>
<p>Andrews is likely to move back to South Africa's problem position of number four in the line-out with Kobus Wiese coming in at number two to replace Hannes Strydom.  </p>
<p>Centre Japie Mulder should return after a back problem, with Andre Snyman, Mulder's replacement in Durban, expected to be given a second cap on the wing in place of Pieter Hendriks. Justin Swart would make the positional move to the left wing.</p>
<p>Scrumhalf Joost van der Westhuizen is likely to oust Johan Roux for the number nine jersey in front of his home crowd at Loftus Versfe's the ultimate challenge,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's certainly going to be tougher than last week because South Africa will have taken heart from their performance in Durban. I think it will be a lot more open game than that one.&quot;  </p>
<p>The third and final test is in Johannesburg on August 31.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>South Africa (probable): Andre Joubert; Andre Snyman, Japie Mulder, Danie van Schalkwyk, Justin Swart; Joel Stransky, Joost van der Westhuizen; Gary Teichmann (captain), Andre Venter, Ruben Kruger, Mark Andrews, Kobus Wiese, Marius Hurter, Henry Tromp Os du Randt.</p>
<p>New Zealand: Christian Cullen; Jeff Wilson, Walter Little, Frank Bunce, Glen Osborne; Simon Culhane, Justin Marshall; Zinzan Brooke, Josh Kronfeld, Michael Jones, Ian Jones, Robin Brooke, Olo Brown, Sean Fitzpatrick (captain), Craig Dowd.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
