<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9016" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Rugby union-New South Africa image suffers off the field.</title>
<headline>Rugby union-New South Africa image suffers off the field.</headline>
<byline>Andy Colquhoun</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>An uneasy calm has fallen over South African rugby -- off the field at least -- as the game's administrators hope that Black August is behind them.</p>
<p>Minister of sport, Steve Tshwete, and Rian Oberholzer, chief executive of the South African Rugby Football Union (SARFU), met on Tuesday in an attempt to mend their differences which have seen the sport's image suffer.</p>
<p>Tshwete, normally a moderate and conciliatory voice, had said on Saturday that the Springboks had &quot;taken everyone for a ride&quot; last year when they projected a spirit of national unity in winning the world cup under the slogan &quot;one team, one country&quot;.</p>
<p>In a statement issued to the press he also said SARFU had failed to deliver on their promises of rugby development.</p>
<p>By Tuesday afternoon he had taken it back although SARFU clearly remains on trial. Rugby, he said, was perceived as a white sport but he accepted they were taking steps to change that image.</p>
<p>On Saturday coloured flanker Sean Plaatjies will make history when he becomes the first non-white to captain the South African Schools team when they meet Scottish Schools in a curtain-raiser to the second test against the All Blacks in Pretoria.</p>
<p>&quot;South African rugby has nothing to hide,&quot; SARFU press officer, Alex Broun, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It has certainly been a difficult month and a number of off-the-field incidents, many of which we have had no control over, have attempted to disrupt the Springbok team.&quot;</p>
<p>The problems started with the selection of 29-year-old hooker Henry Tromp as a replacement for the August 3 test against Australia in Bloemfontein.</p>
<p>Tromp is seen as representing the worst of the old South Africa. In 1992 he and his father were convicted of beating 16-year-old Daniel Bongone who later died from internal injuries.</p>
<p>Both men were found guilty of assault with intent to do grievous bodily harm but outrage at the incident was heightened when Tromp served only nine months in prison while on remand.</p>
<p>His selection re-opened old wounds which were exacerbated by the re-appearance of the old flag of the republic, the &quot;vierkleur&quot; (four colour) in the Bloemfontein test.</p>
<p>Springbok manager Morne du Plessis issued a statement in the name of the team condemning those who carried it.</p>
<p>But later the issue snowballed when Pienaar was reported on Afrikaans radio as saying: &quot;The crowds will be welcome even if they bring the old flag, they may still come and watch.&quot;</p>
<p>The stony silence of SARFU's unpopular president, Dr Louis Luyt, on all the issues fuelled the belief that the game was happy to turn its back on new the South Africa.</p>
<p>Team discipline has also troubled the Springboks.</p>
<p>Prop Os du Randt was &quot;severely reprimanded&quot; for feigning injury in order to be replaced in the Cape Town test on August 10.</p>
<p>Winger James Small was not considered for selection for the following test in Durban on August 17 after he was seen in a nightclub at 2:00 a.m. on the eve of the Cape Town match.</p>
<p>At a subsequent disciplinary hearing Small admitted being in the club and he has again been overlooked for Saturday's test against the All Blacks in Pretoria.</p>
<p>If the Springboks lose that game it will become an All Black August for they will have suffered the fate of becoming the first South African team to lose a home series to New Zealand.</p>
<p>And should it happen, SARFU will be under pressure again, but this time to replace Springbok coach Andre Markgraaff for whom it would be a fifth defeat in seven matches this season.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
