<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9024" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada court rules for loggers against Greenpeace.</title>
<headline>Canada court rules for loggers against Greenpeace.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Canadian Supreme Court ruled on Thursday in favor of a major forestry company, dismissing an appeal from the Greenpeace environmental group that tried to stop logging in a pristine rain forest in British Columbia.</p>
<p>The group challenged the use of sweeping injunctions to ban unnamed people from blocking roads used by MacMillan Bloedel Ltd loggers around Clayoquot Sound on Vancouver Island, but the court said the injunctions were acceptable.</p>
<p>The injunctions have expired and Clayoquot Sound is now quiet but experts said the case was relevant for possible future clashes between environmentalists and loggers.</p>
<p>&quot;I conclude that the British Columbia Supreme Court has jurisdiction to make orders enjoining unknown persons from violating court orders,&quot; Justice Beverley McLachlin wrote in the 9-0 decision.</p>
<p>Between 1991 and 1993, more than 1,000 people were charged with criminal contempt of court and fined or sent to jail for impeding MacMillan Bloedel's clear-cutting around Clayoquot. The firm had governmental authority to log there despite environmental concerns by groups such as Greenpeace.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the Canadian public will be surprised to find that they don't have the right to protect the public's forest,&quot; Greenpeace forest campaigner Tamara Stark said. &quot;We are disappointed the court has decided to protect private interests at the expense of the interests of the public.&quot;</p>
<p>Stark said Greenpeace would continue to campaign to end the logging of pristine rain forests, although she said there were no immediate plans to blockade roads.</p>
<p>MacMillan Bloedel welcomed the decision, which it said would help secure forest industry jobs and the economic viability of logging operations.</p>
<p>&quot;We're pleased. This...will reassure workers who were concerned about their continued ability to do their jobs&quot; because of protest blockades, a company spokesman said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
