<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9028" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks close up as golds surge.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks close up as golds surge.</headline>
<byline>Lydia Zajc</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toronto stocks closed stronger in active dealings on Thursday, as heavily weighted gold issues and a rally in New York pushed the key 300 Index higher.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold stocks were the principle area,&quot; said Maison Placements Canada trader Rolie Bradley. &quot;New York was up 43 points, that helped a bit.&quot;</p>
<p>Toronto Stock Exchange's key 300 Composite Index rose 15.02 points to close at 5182.10 points, while the Dow Jones Industrial Average jumped 43.65 points to 5733.47 points.</p>
<p>Toronto's gold sector gained 1.1 percent.</p>
<p>Trading was active in turnover of 96.2 million shares valued at C$1.27 billion ($927 million).</p>
<p>Advancing stocks out numbered declining ones 483 to 390, with 306 issues unchanged.</p>
<p>Of Toronto's 14 sub-indices, half rose led by golds, forestry products, industrial products and transports. Falling sectors included base metals, retail issues and consumer products.</p>
<p>In related news, the Bank of Canada dropped the key bank rate by 25 basis points to 4.25 percent, a move which prompted Canada's major commercial banks to lower their prime lending rates to 5.75 percent from 6.00 percent.</p>
<p>Gold issues dominated Toronto's most actives list. Arequipa Resources Ltd. jumped C$0.40 to C$30.50 on more than 2.3 million shares, aided by more takeover discussion, while Bema Gold Corp. gained C$0.35 to C$11.55.</p>
<p>Aur Resources Inc. fell C$1.15 to C$7.80 in active trading, bucked the rising trend of golds today.</p>
<p>Inco Ltd. dropped C$0.80 to C$44.95 after clinching its C$4.3 billion (US$3.1 billion) deal with Diamond Fields Resources. It was the first day of trading for Inco's VBN shares, which give investors who accepted the tender offer direct participation in the nickel disovery Voisey's Bay. The new shares closed at C$42.95.</p>
<p>Potash Corporation of Saskatchewan Inc. was also active, gaining C$4.50 to C$104.00 in heavy dealings. The fertilizer firm is in talks with BASF AG to buy 51 percent of German potash group Kali und Salz AG.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
