<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9033" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Saro-Wiwa's brother calls for Nigeria oil embargo.</title>
<headline>Saro-Wiwa's brother calls for Nigeria oil embargo.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The brother of executed Nigerian human rights activist Ken Saro-Wiwa on Thursday called on Canada to urge fellow Commonwealth nations to impose an oil embargo on Nigeria in a bid to end human rights abuses there.</p>
<p>&quot;We are grateful for the stand taken by the Canadian government and we wish that they will continue to urge other Commonwealth nations to take similar stands and effectively announce an oil embargo on Nigeria,&quot; Saro-Wiwa's brother, Owens Wiwa told a news conference.</p>
<p>After a June Commonwealth meeting in London, Canada imposed some sanctions against Nigeria but stopped short of boycotting Nigerian oil. However, the government has recommended Canadian oil companies should reduce or halt Nigerian imports.</p>
<p>&quot;We within this country are moving in effect close to a de facto embargo anyway. A full oil embargo, of course will take major international support to be successful,&quot; said Foreign Affairs spokesman Rodney Moore.</p>
<p>A group of Commonwealth ministers had proposed a visit to Nigeria next week to examine the human rights situation there. The Nigerian government initially opposed the visit by the Commonwealth Ministerial Action Group (CMAG), but later invited it to visit Abuja on Aug.29-30.</p>
<p>However, Nigeria on Thursday set strict terms for the visit, which diplomats said could put the mission in jeopardy. CMAG is comprised of Canada, Britain, Ghana, Zimbabwe, South Africa, Malaysia, Jamaica and New Zealand.</p>
<p>&quot;Their (the group's) findings should call for no less than a full oil embargo of Nigeria and a recommendation for the expulsion of Nigeria from the Commonwealth,&quot; said Diana Wiwa, the slain Nigerian poet's sister-in-law and acting coordinator of the Canada-based Movement for the survival of the Ogoni People.</p>
<p>Nigeria was suspended from the Commonwealth after the executions of poet Ken Saro-Wiwa and eight other Ogoni activists for murder last November. The Commonwealth group links Britain to its former colonies. Nigeria has barred Saro-Wiwa's lawyer, Olisa Agbakoba, from attending a Commonwealth legal conference in Vancouver next week.</p>
<p>Nigeria has been gripped by a political crisis since a previous military government anulled presidential elections in 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
