<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9045" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Doctors, magistrates join Zimbabwe strike.</title>
<headline>Doctors, magistrates join Zimbabwe strike.</headline>
<byline>Cris Chinaka</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwean doctors and magistrates joined thousands of civil servants on Thursday in a strike that has crippled key social services.</p>
<p>The three-day strike continued despite calls by union leaders for a return to work and pledges by the government to discuss wage rise demands of up to 60 percent.</p>
<p>Economic analysts warn, however, that such hikes would be unhealthy for the southern African country's economy and would fuel inflation which the government has vowed to reduce considerably in the current financial year ending next June.</p>
<p>Some public servants heeded a Wednesday night call by their union leaders to end the damaging strike but thousands across the country refused to return to their jobs.</p>
<p>In the capital Harare, about 5,000 workers milled in a central city park throughout the day, some shouting belligerent slogans against President Robert Mugabe's government, and thousands of others were scattered around the town.</p>
<p>The civil servants -- who suspect their Public Service Association (PSA) union leaders were bullied into calling off the strike -- said they wanted to be addressed by their leaders who were holding exploratory talks with the government.</p>
<p>State media reported that junior state doctors in many centres and magistrates in at least one town have joined the strike.</p>
<p>The PSA executives were unavailable for comment, but on Wednesday night they appealed to their members to go back to work after squeezing firm promises from Public Service, Labour and Social Welfare Minister Florence Chitauro that she would open talks with them on their salary demands.</p>
<p>The workers have rejected salary increases of up to eight percent awarded by the government as &quot;an unacceptable insult&quot; and have further been incensed by unconfirmed reports that newly-wed Mugabe went on a honeymoon with his former presidential secretary Grace Marufu at the start of the strike.</p>
<p>On average, civil servants earn Z$1,000 (U.S.$99) a month and PSA union leaders justify their 60 percent pay rise demand on grounds salaries in the public service have fallen way below the cost of living over the years.</p>
<p>The union also says their wages are on average 120 percent below wages for similar grades and jobs in the private sector.</p>
<p>Economist John Robertson said although the civil servants deserved decent wages, their numbers at around 180,000 made their demands difficult to meet.</p>
<p>&quot;If they are met in whole, the government can forget about its targets on inflation. The health of the whole economy, including efforts to get interest rates down, will be at stake.&quot;</p>
<p>The government -- facing accusations of spending nearly 40 percent of the country's gross domestic product (GDP) on financing a political patronage system  -- hopes to lower annual inflation to 16 percent by next June from 22 percent in July.</p>
<p>Another bank economist also urged the government to find ways of rationalising the civil service, saying that was the only way to point the national economy onto a healthy path.</p>
<p>$1 = 10.12 Zimbabwe dollars.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
