<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9046" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa's ANC sorry for killing civilians.</title>
<headline>S.Africa's ANC sorry for killing civilians.</headline>
<byline>Anton Ferreira</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's ruling African National Congress apologised on Thursday for having killed civilians in the apartheid war but said its cause, against whites who regarded blacks as &quot;sub-human&quot;, had been just.</p>
<p>&quot;The apartheid system could not but integrate in its world vision the concept of humans with a right to govern and sub-humans privileged to be governed,&quot; Deputy President Thabo Mbeki told Archbishop Desmond Tutu's Truth and Reconciliation Commission.</p>
<p>&quot;This paradigm allows those who enjoy the right to govern the ethical framework...to use maximum force against any sub-human,&quot; said Mbeki, heir apparent to President Nelson Mandela.</p>
<p>Tutu's commission is hearing from political parties their views on the historical context of South Africa's race conflict so it can form as full a picture as possible of human rights abuses during apartheid.</p>
<p>Mbeki said most of the actions of ANC guerrillas during the struggle to topple white-minority governments could not be described as human rights violations, because the movement was fighting a just war for national liberation.</p>
<p>&quot;It was said that this was a terrorist war ... We say it was not a terrorist war but a legitimate resort by the majority of the people in this country to a form of struggle imposed on them because there were no other channels,&quot; Mbeki said.</p>
<p>He said ANC guerrillas had orders to avoid harming civilians but some had been caught &quot;in the crossfire&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The leadership of the ANC would want to express its regret and sorrow,&quot; he said. &quot;I'm sorry for the loss of life of those who might not have been members of the security forces.&quot;</p>
<p>Mbeki said he was referring to attacks like a car bomb which killed several white civilians at a Durban beachfront bar in 1986.</p>
<p>But he accused security forces of planting other bombs in restaurants which were blamed on the ANC to give it a bad name.</p>
<p>Mbeki admitted that ANC officers in military camps in exile had committed &quot;excesses&quot; in rooting out spies within their own ranks. Previous inquiries have found that suspected agents were tortured and in some cases killed.</p>
<p>Mbeki said South Africa's political leaders had to account fully for what happened under apartheid, when the National Party government detained tens of thousands without trial in attempts to crush black resistance.</p>
<p>&quot;It will not do merely to seek excuses, to make comparisons as to who was more evil than the other,&quot; he said. &quot;The ghost that needs to be laid to rest is the ending of the domination of the black by the white, in all spheres of social existence.&quot;</p>
<p>Mbeki said the ANC never supported the &quot;necklace&quot;, the burning-tyre killings of suspected sellouts by fellow blacks.</p>
<p>Tutu's deputy on the commission, Alex Boraine, told reporters the commission might call former hardline president P.W. Botha to testify if he refused to appear voluntarily.</p>
<p>Botha's successor, F.W. de Klerk, told the commission on Wednesday that Botha had refused to contribute to drafting the National Party's hindsight overview of apartheid.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
