<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9048" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ANGOLA: Mideast and African port conditions - Lloyds.</title>
<headline>Mideast and African port conditions - Lloyds.</headline>
<text>
<p>Port conditions from Lloyds Shipping Intelligence Service --</p>
<p>ANGOLA, Aug 20 - Luanda - minor berthing delays at general cargo berths due to reduction of transport collecting cargoes from quays by private receivers. Container and ro/ro berths operating normally. Lobito, Namibe - no delays. Cabinda - delays reported for discharge at anchorage. Soyo - no delays for cargoes for Kwanda base. All crude oil terminals loading according to programme.</p>
<p>ISRAEL, Aug 20 - Haifa - eight vessels due, 2-3 days delay expected. Loading/discharging at berth - general cargo up to 3 days delay, bulk cargo up to 3 days delay, containers 3 days. No vessels discharging at anchorage. Waiting at anchorage for load/discharge - general cargo up to 4 days delay, bulk 1-4 days delay. 1 vessel bunkering. 4 under repairs/drydock. 4 awaiting orders. Ashdod - two to four days delay. Loading/discharging at berth general cargo 1-10 days delay. Bulk 2 days. Containers 4 days. Waiting at anchorage to load/discharge general cargo up to 3 days delay, bulk 2-4 days. Containers 3 days. 1 vessel awaiting orders. Eilat - vessels loading/discharging at berth bulk and containers 1 days delay. Bulk vessel waiting at anchorage to load/discharge, 1 day's delay. 1 vessel bunkering.</p>
<p>JORDAN, Aug 17 - Aqaba three vessels loading at berth, 9 discharging, 3 waiting at anchorage to load, 1 waiting at anchorage to discharge. 1 vessel awaiting orders.</p>
<p>MAURITIUS, Aug 20 - Port Louis two container vessels alongside for discharging and reloading. 1 vessel at Buoy berth discharging bagged rice into lighters, 2 general cargo vessels alongside discharging bulk fertiliser and general cargo. No idle vessels, approx 13 due by 27/8.</p>
<p>MOZAMBIQUE, Aug 199 - Nacala - port working normally (first come, first served basis). No restriction on berthing/sailing at night subject to gratuity to the pilot. Draft restriction 9.5 metres plus height of tide at general cargo berths, 14 metres at container berths. One tug available. Beira general cargo berths working normally (first come, first served. Container/other terminals working normally. Pilotage restricted to daylight. Two tugboats fully operational. Night navigation by special arrangement, restricted to loa 130 metres. Maputo - pilotage restricted to daylight. Two tugs available, one out of order. All berths working normally and expected to remain so (first come, first served). Draft restriction in channel 8.5 metres less 0.5 metre plus rise of tide.</p>
<p>NAMIBIA, Aug 199 - Walvis Bay working normally.</p>
<p>SOUTH AFRICA, Aug 19 - Richards Bay - general cargo berths working normally, bulk import congested, delays in excess of 72 hours. Bulk export berths working normally. Bulk coal berthing delays approx 12 hours. Eight vessels due in week, berthing on arrival. Coal berths working normally to 28/8. Durban container terminal delays up to 48 hours. Point/New Pier/Maydon Wharf berths working normally. Maize terminal (Maydon wharf 8) 2 loaders for August. Citrus terminal busy. Bunkers working normally but delays in supplying of bunkers expected due to bunching. Due to congestion at bunker berths, delays of 12-24 hours expected. Drydock and floating dock fully booked. East London - general cargo/combi terminal berths extremely busy but no delays. Drydock booked for August and November. Copper - moving in small parcels of 2,500 tonnes per month. Elevator - Slow arrival of cargo and bunching of vessels, delays 5-6 days. Gas oil pipeline under-utilised. Log loaders 15,000 CBM loose pine logs awaiting shipment. Scrap steel - 5,500 tonnes awaiting shipment. Port Elizabeth - five vessels in port, working normally, no delays at general, fruit or tanker berths. Ore berth 2 vessels due 20/8, one will have delay until berth clear. Container berths 3 gantry cranes available from 21/8. 3 vessels due 21/8, will work one gantry each. 1 vessel due 21/8, expect 6-7 hours delay. Cape Town - breakbulk berths no delays, vessels working on arrival. Container terminal no major delays expected. Bunker berths delays 24-36 hours coming week due to limited berths available. Drydock and repair quay fully occupied, booking essential. Saldanha Bay - working normally.</p>
<p>TUNISIA, Aug 17 - Sousse - no vessels due, no delays expected. No vessels loading at berth or anchorage, 2 discharging, 1 timber, 1 paper bales. 1 awaiting orders. Gabes - two vessels loading at berth, 1 bulk fertiliser, 1 phosphate. 2 discharging at berth, 1 bulk sulphur, 1 bulk alumina. 1 waiting at anchorage to discharge. No vessels under repairs, 1 awaiting orders at anchorage. Aug 19 - Tunis - vessels in port 1 general cargo, 1 discharging marble blocks, 1 awaiting instructions. Rades - five in port, 3 ro/ro, 1 loading containers, 1 discharging potatoes. Goulette - north side 1 passenger vessel. South side 1 discharging grain, 1 in roads. Bizerta - five operating, 2 loading bran, 1 discharging marble, 2 steel. No delays/congestion. Zarzis - no vessels, no delays/congestion.</p>
<p>TURKEY, Aug 19 - Istanbul, Haydarpasa 10 vessels operating of which 3 dry cargo, 5 containers, 2 ro/ro. No delays except heavy lift cargoes. Galata 10 vessels operating, port congested. Ambarli 13 operating, no delays. Iskenderun - two discharging of which 1 fuel oil, 1 seeds. Yazicilar - discharging 2 timber, 2 scrap, 1 steel. Ekinciler - one discharging scrap. 2 anchored. Isdemir - two discharging coal, 1 loading steel billets, 1 anchored. Toros - one discharging coal, 2 anchored. Mersin - 15 operating, loading 2 cement, 1 soda, 1 cartons. Discharging 1 general cargo, 1 cotton, 1 paper, 1 spirits, 1 flour, 1 pyroxylin, 1 sugar. Import/export 2 vehicle and 2 container vessels. 14 anchored. Izmir - vessels waiting at anchor 5 container, 3 general cargo. Aug 20 - Mersin 12 operating of which loading 2 pulses, 1 container, 1 general cargo, 3 cement, 1 chrome ore. Discharging 1 cotton, 1 chemicals. Loading/discharging 1 vehicle, 1 container/vehicle/general cargo. 12 awaiting orders. Seka - one discharging fertiliser.</p>
<p>UAE, Aug 18 - Dubai - Vessels operating Aug 11-17 - 78 containers, 11 general cargo, 7 general cargo/containers, 5 bulk carriers, 1 car carrier, 1 livestock carrier, 13 tankers, 5 naval vessels, 2 UAE naval, 1 bunkers/repairs/stores, 5 dhows, 11 barges, 12 tugs, 1 lpg tanker, 26 supply boats, 1 crane ship, 2 chemical tankers. No waiting time.</p>
<p>YEMEN, Aug 19 - Hodeidah - All berths occupied except no 1. 7 vessels alongside of which 2 bulk wheat, 1 wheat flour, 1 container, 1 steel, 1 timber, 1 general cargo. 4 vessels anchored of which 1 bulk wheat, 1 wheat flour, 1 container vessel, 1 e up to 2 days for general cargo, up to 4 days for bagged cargo, up to 6 days for bulk cargo, up to 1 day for containers. Mokha - one vessel alongside discharging palm oil, no vessels anchored, no delays.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFRICA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEAST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ANGOLA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
