<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9051" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: ANC gives first official history of apartheid fight.</title>
<headline>ANC gives first official history of apartheid fight.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African President Nelson Mandela's ANC on Thursday published the first official history of its struggle against white rule -- a saga of bravery, bungling, brutality and ultimate triumph over apartheid.</p>
<p>The 100-page document prepared for Archbishop Desmond Tutu's Truth and Reconciliation Commission records the history and strategies of the African National Congress from its formation in 1912 to its 1994 victory in South Africa's first democratic elections.</p>
<p>But most of the statement is devoted to the party's years in exile, when its armed wing, UmKhonto weSizwe (MK, Spear of the Nation), waged a David-and-Goliath war against the sophisticated white army of successive apartheid governments.</p>
<p>&quot;The ANC is immensely proud of the bravery, discipline and selfless sacrifices of its MK combatants,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;If captured, they faced the possibility of being tortured to death, abduction and secret execution, combined with intense pressure to become collaborators or be murdered.</p>
<p>&quot;Given these conditions, it is remarkable that very few attacks by MK personnel violated ANC policy with regard to targets with no direct connection to the apartheid regime.&quot;</p>
<p>The document defines the command structures that existed across southern Africa, records the rules of engagement adopted by the ANC and reveals the fears of its exiled community.</p>
<p>&quot;The efforts by the South African state to destroy the ANC and MK were unceasing and massively financed...methods included infiltration by state agents and spies; cross-border raids and kidnapping,&quot; the document says.</p>
<p>In one case, state agents poisoned an entire ANC training camp in Angola, almost killing 500 men. In another South Africa bombed the Catengue camp with precision the ANC believes could only have been based on intelligence from within.</p>
<p>In 1981, the ANC uncovered an intelligence ring reaching to high command of that camp. And in the aftermath, young ANC security staff were given an almost free hand to root our spies.</p>
<p>&quot;The difficult conditions under which we had to operate led to a drift in accountability and control away from established norms, resulting in situations in which some individuals... began to behave as a law unto themselves,&quot; the document says.</p>
<p>Suspected infiltrators, some later cleared, were beaten and tortured and detained in inhuman conditions. The ANC names 34 members executed on the orders of a military tribunal between 1980 and 1989, and 50 more who committed suicide.</p>
<p>For almost half-a-century from its founding, the ANC tried to engage South Africa's white masters in a discussion about social and political rights for the overwhelming black majority.</p>
<p>In the early decades it stuck to peaceful and legal methods such as boycotts, strikes and civil disobedience.</p>
<p>But the Sharpeville massacre of 69 unarmed black protesters by police on March 21, 1960, led to a rethink that brought the launch on December 16, 1961, of its armed campaign.</p>
<p>The guerrilla war targeted the state, despite calls within the ANC to abandon restraint in the face of state brutality.</p>
<p>The ANC reassessed its definition of legitimate targets at a 1985 conference in Zambia, leading to an intensification of the war, including the use of landmines and bombs.</p>
<p>&quot;A resolution was adopted which acknowledged that there would be unavoidable civilian casualties,&quot; it says.</p>
<p>Some attacks, such as the bombing of a half-built nuclear power plant near Cape Town, dented the white nation's pride.</p>
<p>Others, like a 1983 car bomb at Air Force headquarters that killed 19 people and hurt more than 200, had ambiguous results.</p>
<p>&quot;Both the cadres who set up the car bomb were killed in the blast,&quot; the report says.</p>
<p>The document also records the decline in discipline as young radicals inside the country took up the campaign in the ANC's name, but often outside the movement's direct control.</p>
<p>One consequence was the rash of executions in the late 1980s by township youths of alleged informers or collaborators using the flaming, petrol-soaked car tire known as a &quot;necklace&quot;.</p>
<p>The document records that leaders of the ANC and its United Democratic Front condemned necklacing and all forms of lynching.</p>
<p>&quot;Necklacing was never the policy of the ANC.... Evidence is beginning to emerge that this gruesome form of reprisal may have been initiated by the state...the direct result of the work of agents provocateurs,&quot; it says.</p>
<p>&quot;The fundamental issue we would like to present...is that as a liberation movement, we engaged in a just war for national liberation,&quot; Deputy President Thabo Mbeki said when he delivered the document to Tutu's commission in Cape Town.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
