<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9054" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: U.N. refugee agency hopes to empty Burundi camp.</title>
<headline>U.N. refugee agency hopes to empty Burundi camp.</headline>
<byline>Christian Jennings</byline>
<dateline>KIGALI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.N. refugee agency said it hoped that on Thursday the last few thousand Rwandan refugees who want to return home would be leaving a refugee camp in northern Burundi.</p>
<p>But it remained unclear what would happen to a hardline core of Hutu refugees who refuse to return to Rwanda, saying they fear they will be killed or detained in reprisal for genocide in 1994.</p>
<p>An official with the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) in the Rwandan capital Kigali told reporters: &quot;We expect to empty Magara camp of people leaving voluntarily today.&quot;</p>
<p>An estimated 6,000 Rwandan Hutu refugees were left in Magara on Thursday after 4,800 refugees abandoned the camp on Wednesday and were taken by truck back to southern Rwanda, UNHCR officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are concerned and remain in contact with the governor of Ngozi province and the Burundian military authorities to establish what will happen to those refugees in Magara who do not want to return,&quot; UNHCR spokesman Paul Stromberg said.</p>
<p>Groups of hardline Hutu refugees in Magara stoned troops of Burundi's Tutsi-dominated army last Sunday after refusing to take apart parts of the camp that had already been abandoned.</p>
<p>Troops later on Sunday shot dead three refugees as they tried to leave the camp. The military said its soldiers only opened fire after a refugee pulled out a handgun and started shooting.</p>
<p>Burundian army officers have accused the Rwandan Hutu refugees of backing Burundian Hutu rebels infiltrating Burundi.</p>
<p>Refugees have accused Burundian troops of harassing them and say they decided to leave because they feared for their lives.</p>
<p>The Rwandan refugee refugee exodus from Burundi began after Burundi's army toppled Hutu president Sylvestre Ntibantunganya on July 25 and installed retired army major Pierre Buyoya.</p>
<p>Buyoya, who is trying to break down international opposition to the army coup, has pledged not to force Rwandan refugees in Burundi to return home and ordered a halt to forced expulsions by the Tutsi army earlier in July.</p>
<p>The return from camps in Burundi is the biggest movement back since some two million Rwandan mostly Hutu refugees fled to Burundi, Zaire and Tanzania during the 1994 killing of up to one million Tutsis and moderate Hutus by Hutu troops, militia and mobs.</p>
<p>In another development, the U.N. Human Rights Field Office for Rwanda said on Thursday that 271 Rwandan refugees returning from Burundi in July and August were arrested by Rwandan authorities.</p>
<p>In a report, it said 62 of the 217 had been released.</p>
<p>Rwandan authorities screen returning refugees and arrest any suspected of involvement in the 1994 genocide.</p>
<p>After the last refugees in Magara leave, UNHCR officials say they plan to move the repatriation operation on to the last Rwandan refugee camp in Burundi at Rukuramigabo, which has some 13,000 Rwandans.</p>
<p>There were some 135,000 Rwandan refugees in Burundi at the start of the year.  </p>
<p>&quot;The last convoy left with about four trucks. The camp of Magara is now empty except for these 220 people. These people do not want to return home for one reason or another,&quot; Stromberg said.</p>
<p>Asked about what would happen to those who had refused to go back, Stromberg said: &quot;They are still refugees and will be treated as such. One option is to move them to another site and this can be done without government approval.&quot;</p>
<p>He said said a total of 6,000 Rwandan Hutus went back home on Thursday and a total of 50,000 refugees from Magara camp would have returned once the last convoy reached south Rwanda.</p>
<p>Refugees have accused Burundian troops of harassing them and say they decided to leave because they feared for their lives.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIGALI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
