<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9059" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUINEA: Guinea calls two days of prayer.</title>
<headline>Guinea calls two days of prayer.</headline>
<dateline>CONAKRY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The West African state of Guinea declared Thursday and Friday days of national prayer.</p>
<p>A government statement, broadcast repeatedly by state radio, said the two days of prayer were &quot;for the dead, for peace and prosperity in Guinea, the victory of the new government and the health of the head of state&quot;.</p>
<p>The precise reason for the call was not immediately clear.</p>
<p>Guinea's president, Lansana Conte, vice-president of the Organisation of the Islamic Conference, left for Kuwait on August 16 to prepare the next OIC summit in Pakistan in 1997.</p>
<p>Koranic reading sessions and prayers were to be held in the farming town of Badi-Tondon, near his home about 60 km (40 miles) from the capital Conakry.</p>
<p>Conte, an army general, survived a February army pay revolt which at the time he described as a veiled attempt to topple him. He has since named a prime minister for the first time since early in his rule and ordered a crackdown on corruption.</p>
<p>Conte seized power in 1984 after the death of veteran Marxist leader Ahmed Sekou Toure. He won elections in 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CONAKRY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUINEA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
