<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9061" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ANGOLA: Angola's civil war is over for UNITA -- Savimbi.</title>
<headline>Angola's civil war is over for UNITA -- Savimbi.</headline>
<byline>Lesley Wroughton</byline>
<dateline>BAILUNDO, Angola 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Angola's civil war is over for the UNITA former rebels, their leader Jonas Savimbi said on Thursday.</p>
<p>He told delegates to a crucial party congress that UNITA, which fought for nearly two decades against the Angolan government, would work to change itself into a political party.</p>
<p>&quot;UNITA's soldiers are not preparing for war...we don't want war. War has finished...there is no political advantage in war,&quot; he said in an address to around 1,500 members at the movement's headquarters.</p>
<p>Savimbi appealed for delegates to the party's supreme decision making meeting to reject &quot;extreme decisions&quot;.</p>
<p>The congress is intended to debate the future of the movement that spent 20 years trying to topple Angola's formerly Marxist MPLA rulers after independence from Portugal in 1975.</p>
<p>Delegates must also decide on the government's offer for Savimbi to take the job of vice president.</p>
<p>The two sides signed a peace deal in 1994 and agreed to integrate their troops into a single national army under a government of national unity.</p>
<p>The government has agreed to integrate nine UNITA general into the top brass of a united national army, including the post of deputy force commander and Savimbi said this left more than 50 other UNITA generals with uncertain futures.</p>
<p>Savimbi, 63, said UNITA had handed in all heavy weapons and artillery, referring to 870 tonnes of materiel including tanks and missiles handed to U.N. peacekeepers last month.</p>
<p>&quot;Absolutely, we have no more (weapons),&quot; he said, adding that UNITA had met its obligations under terms of the peace pact. That included disarming 60,000 UNITA fighters.</p>
<p>He accused President Jose Eduardo dos Santos's government of not keeping its side of the accord, alleging that not all troops and special police had been confined to barracks.</p>
<p>The government had failed to expel all foreign mercenaries and was still buying weapons, Savimbi said.</p>
<p>Despite the shaky peace, Angola has remained largely divided into MPLA-controlled areas centred on the capital Luanda, and UNITA territory that includes northern diamond areas whose riches helped to pay for its war effort.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAILUNDO, Angola"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ANGOLA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
