<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9064" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Cement shares lead bullish Nigerian bourse.</title>
<headline>Cement shares lead bullish Nigerian bourse.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strong demand for top cement company shares led bullish trade at the Nigerian stock exchange on Thursday.</p>
<p>The all-share index closed at 6068.92 from 6059.89 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Ashaka Cement gained 23 kobo to 14.10 naira while West African Portland Cement climbed by 15 kobo to 27.05 naira.</p>
<p>Traders said the two were enjoying a good spell due to healthy account books and the perception that they have bright prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;The assumption is that they are far from peaking,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Buying interest remained strong in the food and petroleum marketing sectors.</p>
<p>Flour Mills of Nigeria gained 20 kobo to 10.90 naira on the back of good full year results, while Union Dicon Salt rose 12 kobo to 30.72 naira.</p>
<p>Nigerian Tobacco Company, rising after months on the slide, was quiet as traders awaited its half-year result. It was unchanged at 2.10 naira.</p>
<p>In the petroleum marketing sector National Oil rose 15 kobo to 42.40 naira. Total closed 10 kobo higher at 42.40 naira, while Unipetrol rose by the same margin to 32.70 naira.</p>
<p>Conglomerate Lever Brothers ended eight kobo up at 23.80 naira, but in the same sector John Holt fell five kobo to 11.50 naira.</p>
<p>Tyre manufacturer Dunlop and Nigerian Breweries also lost out, both down five kobo to 12.35 naira and 13.80 naira, respectively.</p>
<p>Wema Bank went ex-dividend and ex-scrip at 5.19 naira from 6.50 naira on Wednesday.</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>--Lagos newsroom +234 1 263 03 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
