<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9073" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Felixtowe port wins management contract in Kenya.</title>
<headline>Felixtowe port wins management contract in Kenya.</headline>
<dateline>MOMBASA, Kenya 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The British port of Felixstowe on Thursday won a two-year contract to manage a three-berth container terminal at the Kenyan port of Mombasa.</p>
<p>Kenya Ports Authority Executive Chairman Robert Brenneisen and Felixstowe Port Consultants Chief Executive Officer Derrek Harrington signed the contract that is effective on September 1 and under which Felixtowe will be paid $1.1 million per year.  </p>
<p>Under the contract, Felixstowe will train Kenya Ports Authority staff both locally and abroad, help in the setting up of a container tracking system to be acquired from the Port of Mauritius in Port Louis and supervise a major rehabilitation programme of ships to shore cranes.</p>
<p>The new team will be represented in Mombasa by five staff from Felixstowe port and aims at a productivity target after 12 months of 375 crane lifts per day per crane average with a bonus if the target is exceeded. Mombasa port now does between 200 and 250 moves per day, causing a low turnaround for vessels.</p>
<p>Felixstowe will be responsible for maintenance of the equipment at the container terminal, an area that has been largely blamed for the inefficiency that has sometimes included purchasing of wrong spares, low staff morale and corruption.</p>
<p>Felixstowe was one of seven companies that tendered for the contract. Others were the Port of Singapore Authority, Portia Management Services, Port of Boston, Hamburg Port Consultancy GmbH of Germany, Saga Group of France and P&amp;O Australia Ports.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOMBASA, Kenya"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
