<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9076" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Nairobi bourse lower on lack of foreign interest.</title>
<headline>Nairobi bourse lower on lack of foreign interest.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Nairobi Stock Exchange (NSE) 20-share index fell again on Thursday on lack of foreign investor interest, brokers and bourse officials said.</p>
<p>The index fell 22.53 points to stand at 3064.68. Market turnover rose to 28.060 million shillings on 1,063,168 shares from 9.700 million shillings on 304,531 shares on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A dealer at a leading brokerage house said the Nairobi bourse had been on a downward trend for some time because foreign investors had shown very little interest.</p>
<p>The dealer added that it appeared foreign interest had fizzled with the poor performance of national carrier Kenya Airways, whose price has gone below its June 1996 flotation price of 11.25 shillings.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of these foreign investors come into the market when there is a big issue to be dealt, but with nothing exciting so far in the market they seem to lack interest and wait by the sideline to see what will happen next,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A primary issue of Kenya Commercial Bank is now awaited on the bourse but government officials have not indicated when it will arrive. Only about 20 percent of Kenya Commercial Bank stock is traded on the Nairobi bourse.</p>
<p>Another dealer said that most counters had already made their mid-year announcements and with only a few more announcements expected until December, trade was lacklustre.</p>
<p>A broker said present share prices a consequence of higher supply compared to demand. A floor dealer saw strong activity driven by heavy buying in two major financial stocks.</p>
<p>Housing Finance Company traded a total of 606,319 shares at 26, eased to 24 but corrected to close at 25 while National Bank of Kenya dealt 235,270 shares at 18.50, 17.40 and 18 shillings.</p>
<p>National Bank has attracted a lot of investor interest lately on the back of rising orders from state pension agency National Social Security Fund (NSSF). The agency already owns around 42 percent of the bank and would appear to be seeking an overall controlling shareholding of 51 percent.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Barclays Bank of Kenya rose 2.0 shillings to 112, Diamond Trust fell to 36.25 from 42.75 and Jubilee Insurance eased to 40.25 from 42.</p>
<p>Kenya Airways traded 70,687 shares at 10.40 and 10 from 9.95, Nation Printers &amp; Publishers shed 2.0 to 101 and Standard Newspaper Group eased to 9.05 from 9.30.</p>
<p>Among plantations, Kakuzi fell to 90 from 91 while Brooke Bond was unchanged at 173. Sasini Tea &amp; Coffee at 51.</p>
<p>Oil concern Total Kenya was steady at 75.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom ++ 254-2 330261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
