<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9078" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Amic, Mitsubishi in 100 mln rand venture.</title>
<headline>Amic, Mitsubishi in 100 mln rand venture.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anglo American Investment Corporation Ltd and Mitsubishi Corp announced a 100 million rand investment fund joint venture on Thursday.  </p>
<p>The companies said in a joint statement they had formed a strategic alliance leading to the establishment of a 100 million rand development capital fund, called MCA Investments.</p>
<p>The fund would be aimed at stimulating the development of small to medium-sized enterprises in South Africa.  </p>
<p>The fund will look for capital investment opportunities in the three to 15 million rand range in South Africa.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi president Minoru Makihara said although his company and Amic had their origins in areas other than venture capital both companies realised the importance of venture capital as a way to stimulate business expansion.</p>
<p>&quot;Together with Amic we look forward to supporting this exciting joint venture and would encourage companies to make use of the potential offered by the venture to enhance their potential for growth both locally and internationally,&quot; Makihara said.</p>
<p>Amic chairman Leslie Boyd said his company was a strong believer in joint ventures and partnerships.</p>
<p>Boyd added that the two companies' difference in regional experience could compliment the new alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;Amic will play an important role in assisting as a local advisor to the South African fund. We will correspondingly be fortunate to benefit from Mitsubishi's experience in east Asia to open other new opportunities for our group companies,&quot; Boyd said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27-11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
