<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9079" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Burundi rules out foreign military intervention.</title>
<headline>Burundi rules out foreign military intervention.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bigg</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burundi's military-appointed government on Thursday said foreign military intervention would not solve the problems of the nation, where a war between the army and rebels is killing up to 1,000 people monthly.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign military intervention in Burundi will not solve a bad situation, instead it will only make it worse,&quot; Foreign Minister Luc Rukingama told reporters in the capital Bujumbura.</p>
<p>&quot;As we have seen in Somalia, in Liberia and in Bosnia, (military intervention) failed to bring answers,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>U.N. Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali in a report to the Security Council this week recommended countries assemble a force of 50,000 to intervene in Burundi if it plunged into genocide, like neighbouring Rwanda in 1994 when up to one million people died.</p>
<p>The force would be outside U.N. command. But Boutros-Ghali, who has repeatedly urged creation of such a foreign force, said of more than 50 countries approached only four offered troops.</p>
<p>More than 150,000 people -- mainly civilians -- have been killed in Burundi since 1993 in massacres and the vicious war between the Tutsi-dominated army and Hutu rebels.</p>
<p>Boutros-Ghali had failed to receive sufficient support for his proposals before the Burundian military overthrew Hutu President Sylvestre Ntibantunganya on July 25.</p>
<p>Regional African states, which were preparing to respond to a request from Ntibantunganya for &quot;security assistance&quot;, reacted to the coup by clamping sanctions on landlocked Burundi on July 31.</p>
<p>Sanctions have had limited impact in Burundi, which produces much of its own food, but have produced a siege mentality in the Tutsi minority determined to resist rule by the Hutu majority.</p>
<p>The French wing of the medical charity Medecins Sans Frontieres (MSF) said on Thursday it would send a cargo plane full of drugs, medical and surgical material to provide for the needs of the populations of four Burundian regions.</p>
<p>The plane, carrying 25 tonnes of drugs to supply dispensaries and hospitals, will be the first relief flight since the sanctions were imposed by Tanzania, Kenya, Uganda, Rwanda, Ethiopia, Zaire and Zambia.</p>
<p>But the regional states since the coup have quietly backed off their plan for military intervention, arguing it cannot be implemented without the approval of the Burundian authorities.</p>
<p>Keen to force Burundi's leaders into negotiations, diplomats say several U.N. Security Council member want to threaten sanctions and promise aid if Burundi does not end its conflict.</p>
<p>A proposed resolution, initiated by Chile and Botswana, was to be circulated on Thursday in a bid to halt violence between Tutsis and Hutus and deal with the coup.</p>
<p>Burundi leader Pierre Buyoya has rejected demands for unconditional peace talks with Hutu rebels, banned political parties including the Hutu-dominated Frodebu party and suspended the national assembly.</p>
<p>A senior Frodebu official said on Thursday talks between Buyoya and Frodebu members had stalled because both sides disagreed over who was Burundi's true president.</p>
<p>Ntibantunganya, holed up in the U.S. ambassador's residence in Bujumbura since two days before the coup, has refused to step down and maintains he is the legal head of state. He has called for a popular campaign for his restoration.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
