<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9083" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa union leader accepts need for budget cuts.</title>
<headline>S.Africa union leader accepts need for budget cuts.</headline>
<dateline>DURBAN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African trade union leader Sam Shilowa said on Thursday he endorsed the government's desire to reduce the country's budget deficit but warned against damage to basic services.</p>
<p>&quot;We said yes, we need the budget deficit reduced, but key issues like health and education should not be affected,&quot; the Congress of South African Trade Unions (Cosatu) general secretary told a workers and management conference.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to make sure that services to the broader community are not going to suffer because of this strategy,&quot; Shilowa said.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Trevor Manuel's macroeconomic strategy, released in June, intends to reduce the budget deficit from over five percent of GDP this budget year to four percent next year and three percent by 1999.</p>
<p>The budget targets, described by Manuel as &quot;non-negotiable,&quot; are part of a broad strategy to double economic growth to an annual six percent by the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;The debate is not whether it is negotiable or not. The debate is to ensure that the macroeconomic framework constraints the government faces are better understood,&quot; said Shilowa.</p>
<p>&quot;Are there alternatives? If there aren't, then how do we move forward?&quot; he asked.</p>
<p>Shilowa said the ongoing debate about privatisation of state assets should not be interpreted simply as a pro- and anti- issue.</p>
<p>&quot;The debate should be about what the new mandate of state-owned enterprises should be...and what role the state sector could play in the productive sector of the economy,&quot; Shilowa said.</p>
<p>Cosatu supported the state's retaining control of its assets, but this did not mean it was on a collision course with the ruling African National Congress (ANC), whose leader President Nelson Mandela has firmly endorsed privatisation.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever our criticism, we are not in opposition to the ANC. We are allies and our aim is not to undermine ANC policies,&quot; Shilowa said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DURBAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
