<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9085" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Mauritius rupee firms on dollar, stable on pound.</title>
<headline>Mauritius rupee firms on dollar, stable on pound.</headline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mauritian rupee firmed against the dollar but was stable versus the pound on Thursday, commercial banks' forex dealers said.</p>
<p>The rupee was fixed at a mean commercial rate of 20.3145 against the dollar on Thursday from 20.3310 on Wednesday, and at 31.4835 to the pound, unchanged from Wednesday's rate.</p>
<p>Forex dealers said the rupee's fixing against the dollar was done in line with international trends.</p>
<p>They added the Mauritius Sugar Syndicate made a tender for the sale of pounds in the forex interbank market on Thursday morning. Results were expected in the central bank's monthly report.</p>
<p>As from the 1996 sugar harvest season, the Mauritius government is allowing the Syndicate to sell 25 percent of the Indian Ocean island's sugar forex earnings directly to banks.</p>
<p>Formerly, the central bank kept all the proceeds and paid the equivalent amount in rupees to the Syndicate.</p>
<p>Sugar exports are the country's largest hard currency earner in terms of net value added.</p>
<p>--Mike Chung, Port Louis ++230 212-6870</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
