<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9087" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria says Commonwealth visit not to be inquiry.</title>
<headline>Nigeria says Commonwealth visit not to be inquiry.</headline>
<dateline>ABUJA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria's military government on Thursday said a proposed Commonwealth visit to discuss the country's supension from the organisation would not be a fact-finding mission.</p>
<p>&quot;The invitation should not be construed as a request for a Commonwealth fact-finding mission,&quot; a foreign ministry statement said.</p>
<p>Nigeria has consistently refused to allow a Commonwealth Ministerial Action Group (CMAG) fact-finding mission to investigate alleged human rights abuses that led to its suspension from the club of Britain and its former colonies.</p>
<p>But this month Nigeria invited the Commonwealth to visit the capital Abuja from August 29-30 to continue discussions begun in London in June.</p>
<p>There has been no official response to the invitation.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth suspended Nigeria after author Ken Saro-Wiwa and eight other minority rights activists were executed for murder last November. The group criticised Nigeria's plan to restore democracy by 1998 as inadequate.</p>
<p>When the two sides met for the first time in London the Commonwealth ministers decided not to impose further sanctions on Nigeria pending more talks, a decision which angered pro-democracy activists.</p>
<p>The foreign ministry statement said CMAG had no mandate to carry out a fact-finding mission and that the United Nations had already carried out its own investigation.</p>
<p>The U.N. team, which visited at Nigeria's invitation in April, suggested the reform of draconian laws but backed the transition plan of military ruler General Sani Abacha.</p>
<p>U.S. officials on Wednesday said the United States had begun its own attempts to engage Nigeria in a discussion of human rights and democracy.</p>
<p>CMAG comprises Malaysia, Zimbabwe, Jamaica, Ghana, Britain, New Zealand, South Africa and Canada.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COMWH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABUJA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
