<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9088" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe central bank cuts key rate to 27.5 pct.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe central bank cuts key rate to 27.5 pct.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwe's central bank has cut its rediscount rate by two percentage points to 27.5 percent, citing a downward trend in annual inflation, the bank said in a statement released on Thursday.  </p>
<p>&quot;Current projections show the rate of inflation falling to about 20 percent in December 1996 and further down to about 16 percent by June 1997,&quot; the Bank said.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe's annual consumer inflation rate dipped to 22.0 percent in July from 28 percent in January, helped down by a fall in food prices on the back of a good harvest this year.</p>
<p>&quot;In line with this trend and in accordance with stated policy, the bank's rediscount rate has been reduced by two percentage points to 27.5 percent with immediate effect,&quot; it said in the statement dated August 20 but released on Thursday.</p>
<p>The bank last cut its lending rate in November 1994 -- to 29.5 percent from 30 percent -- but has maintained a tight monetary policy over the past two years to fight resurgent inflation, blamed by local economists on high state spending.</p>
<p>-- Emelia Sithole, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
