<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9093" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe civil servants continue strike for pay.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe civil servants continue strike for pay.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some Zimbabwean civil servants returned to work on Thursday but thousands of others defied a call by their union to end a three-day strike for higher wages which has crippled critical social services.</p>
<p>The Public Service Association (PSA) union executive called off the strike on Wednesday night after assurances from Public Service, Labour and Social Welfare Minister Florence Chitauro that her government would open serious talks over their revised demands for between 30 and 60 percent salary increases.</p>
<p>In the capital Harare on Thursday, about 5,000 workers milled around a central city park and others were scattered through the city.</p>
<p>The civil servants said they suspected their leaders had been intimidated into calling an end to the strike and were waiting for an address from them.</p>
<p>Union and government officials were not available for comment, but some senior officers who have been offering skeletal services during the strike reported that a few strikers had returned to their jobs.</p>
<p>The government said it had posted some police officials around government offices to protect workers from being intimidated by the strike leaders.</p>
<p>Many state hospitals were still handling emergency cases only, using the services of army and Red Cross medical corps, as many nurses stayed away from work.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
