<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9096" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: Zairean prime minister in Rwanda refugee talks.</title>
<headline>Zairean prime minister in Rwanda refugee talks.</headline>
<dateline>KIGALI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zairean Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo began talks with Rwandan officials on Thursday on security and the fate of 1.1 million Rwandan refugees in Zaire since Rwanda's 1994 genocide.</p>
<p>A Rwandan foreign ministry official said Kengo would discuss the problems with Rwandan Prime Minister Pierre Celestin Rwigema, Vice-President and Defence Minister Major-General Paul Kagame and Interior Minister Colonel Alexis Kanyarengwe.</p>
<p>&quot;The talks are expected to centre around the problem of the refugees on the Rwandan-Zairean border. Security and refugees are going to be central to their talks,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>Kengo arrived in the Rwandan capital Kigali on Wednesday on the first visit to Rwanda by such a senior Zairean official since before the three-month genocide of up to one million people by the Hutu majority and civil war in Rwanda in 1994.</p>
<p>He was scheduled to give a news conference in Kigali before returning to the Zairean capital Kinshasa later on Thursday.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Kengo visited a massacre site at Murambi near the southwestern town of Gikongoro where bodies of victims have been exhumed from a mass grave and returned to a school where they were killed.</p>
<p>Kengo, who has repeatedly stressed the need for the Rwandan Hutu refugees in Zaire to return home, is visiting Rwanda while it receives back thousands of Rwandan refugees from its southern neighbour Burundi.</p>
<p>Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko has intervened in the past two years to stop Kengo from ordering, in violation of international law, the deportation from Zaire of the 1.1 million Rwandan Hutus.</p>
<p>Last August, Zairean troops forcibly expelled some 15,000 Rwandan and Burundian Hutus. The expulsions were stopped only after Mobutu stepped in following an international outcry.</p>
<p>Together with the refugees, eastern Zaire is home to Rwanda's 40,000-strong former Hutu army and Hutu militiamen who infiltrate Rwanda and are a major security problem for Kigali.</p>
<p>Rwandan officials said they wanted assurances that Zaire would take action against rebels operating from its territory.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIGALI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
