<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9098" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Mandela's ANC defends &quot;just struggle&quot;.</title>
<headline>Mandela's ANC defends &quot;just struggle&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Anton Ferreira</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Nelson Mandela's African National Congress on Thursday defended its &quot;just struggle&quot; against apartheid, telling South Africa's truth commission it could not be compared to the defence of white rule.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be morally wrong and legally incorrect to equate apartheid with the resistance against it,&quot; the party said in a 100-page statement handed in by Deputy President Thabo Mbeki.</p>
<p>&quot;The mass of the people led by the liberation movement waged a just struggle against apartheid, which was designated by the United Nations as a crime against humanity.&quot;</p>
<p>The ANC acknowledged in the statement that some agents had abused their positions and violated human rights, but said &quot;none of such violations arose out of official policy&quot;.</p>
<p>It said it regretted the killing of civilians in the fight against a ruling clique that believed it came from a super-race.</p>
<p>&quot;There are instances where we could have acted more firmly and speedily to prevent or stop abuses, and for that the ANC accepts collective responsibility.&quot;</p>
<p>Mbeki, heading a delegation of 23 people, handed the statement and a volume of supporting documentation to Archbishop Desmond Tutu's statutory Truth and Reconciliation Commission on the final day of a special sitting for political parties.</p>
<p>Testimony during earlier hearings, including harrowing personal accounts of rape, torture and the killing of children, has at times reduced Tutu and his colleagues to tears.</p>
<p>This week, parties including the white separatist Freedom Front and former president F.W. de Klerk's National Party submitted documents explaining their actions under white rule.</p>
<p>De Klerk, who ousted P.W. Botha, the last white hardliner, in 1989 and turned South Africa from apartheid to democracy, said on Wednesday his National Party had much to apologise for, but insisted he had never sanctioned assassination or torture.</p>
<p>While de Klerk argued that apartheid had been an honest, though misguided attempt to share the country amongst its ethnic groups, the ANC submission rejected any defence of segregation.</p>
<p>&quot;Apartheid oppression and repression were...not an aberration of a well-intentioned undertaking that went horribly wrong.</p>
<p>&quot;The ideological underpinning and the programme of apartheid constituted a deliberate and systematic mission of a ruling clique that saw itself as the champion of a super-race,&quot; the ANC statement said.</p>
<p>The ANC, outlawed after protests against the Sharpeville massacre of 69 black demonstrators by police in 1960, initially directed its armed opposition to white rule against agents and facilities of the state.</p>
<p>&quot;Military struggle was seen as forming only part of, and being guided by a broader political strategy to ensure that the battle against apartheid was fought on all possible fronts.&quot;</p>
<p>But the ANC statement acknowledged that some agents had exceeded their orders and that the fight against government infiltration in ANC exile bases had been brutal.</p>
<p>The statement names 34 people executed on the orders of an ANC military tribunal between 1980 and 1989.</p>
<p>The statement also explained the bombing of so-called &quot;soft inside South Africa, including a beachfront bar and a shopping centre near Durban.</p>
<p>&quot;From around December 1985...a number of attacks on civilian targets with no connection to the state occurred...The ANC does not seek to justify such attacks, but insists that the context in which they occurred is relevant.</p>
<p>&quot;The ANC has acknowledged that in a number of instances, breaches in policy did occur and deeply regrets civilian casualties. The leadership took steps to halt operations in conflict with policy,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The ANC called for reasonable reparations to victims of the struggle, but stressed the need for confession and forgiveness.</p>
<p>&quot;The catalogue of legal discrimination and injustice that occurred under apartheid needs to be acknowledged if a human rights culture is to flourish in the new South African legal system,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
