<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9104" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: FEATURE - The Hutu-Tutsi beat goes on in Burundi.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - The Hutu-Tutsi beat goes on in Burundi.</headline>
<byline>Elif Kaban</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Once a week a band of ragged Hutu musicians descend from the hills and trek into Burundi's ethnically cleansed capital for jam sessions with fellow enthusiasts from the Tutsi tribe.</p>
<p>While Tutsi soldiers jog through the streets in formation singing: &quot;We'll fight to the death and we'll win,&quot; the small group of Hutu and Tutsi musicians sing of love, cows and wayward wives.</p>
<p>The common culture between Burundians despite their ethnic divisions is a glimmer of hope amid the hatred on both sides and the killing of more than 150,000 people since 1993 in war and massacres.</p>
<p>But no one thinks singing will end bloodshed in Burundi, where the Hutu majority of 85 percent of the 5.6 million population has been ruled since before colonial days by the Tutsi minority.</p>
<p>&quot;We sing blues about cows, songs about love. Everyone loves good music. You can unite people with music,&quot; says Gilbert Ndakoze, a Tutsi known as &quot;Ginda&quot; and the head of the eight Hutu and eight Tutsi musicians who tour the country when they can.</p>
<p>&quot;Hutu rebels sing before they attack villages because singing is a spiritual drug to kill. Soldiers sing. Everyone sings  Burundi,&quot; adds Ginda, whose group meets weekly despite sanctions on Burundi to press for a return to civilian rule.</p>
<p>When security allows it, Ginda and his musicians travel to Burundi's villages, documenting traditional songs, some of which date back 800 years. They are recorded in a digital studio in Bujumbura.</p>
<p>Their music is a mainly wild mesh of traditional flutes, drums, violins, drums, the citar, harmonicas, the double bass and the piano. Voice however is the predominant instrument.</p>
<p>Their whispers in songs are usually about love.</p>
<p>A voice from deep in the throat is about violence, common even before the start of war in 1993 in one of Africa's most densely-populated countries where Tutsi and Hutus lived side-by -side on the same hills.</p>
<p>Many have been driven off and forced to seek refuge in camps for the displaced or inaccessible areas in the last three years.</p>
<p>Songs about women, frequently portrayed as poisoners or witches in traditional tales, are mean and full of violence.</p>
<p>&quot;Let me linger&quot; is about the  wife of a farmer in the hills of Burundi who &quot;cultivates&quot; other men when her husband is out.</p>
<p>&quot;In the morning, she puts water on the fire. Then she spends hours putting make-up on. After making herself nice, she puts on her shoes and goes out to wander,&quot; the song says.</p>
<p>&quot;I came home and asked her where she had cultivated. She smiled and showed her teeth. I jumped and kicked her in the teeth. I pulled her teeth out. I pulled them by the roots.&quot;</p>
<p>In war songs, Ginda said his men dance with machetes and pangas. &quot;Violence is a big theme in our traditional songs. It's our history. Ever since I was born, we've been at war.&quot;</p>
<p>Burundians also sing the lyrics to songs such as: &quot;If you tickle the feet of a Hutu, he'll scoop your eyes out.&quot;</p>
<p>Another goes: &quot;Hutu is stocky and carries load, he eats too much. Tutsi is thin and drinks milk, he thinks too much. Tutsi is quiet but if you disturb him, he will sting you like a snake.&quot;</p>
<p>They are also some happy songs in Burundi, usually about cows, the traditional sign of wealth. When a Burundian man wants to compliment a woman, he says: &quot;You have the eyes of a cow.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
