<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9111" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Kiev says China overreacted to Taiwan VP visit.</title>
<headline>Kiev says China overreacted to Taiwan VP visit.</headline>
<byline>Rostislav Khotin</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukrainian Foreign Minister Hennady Udovenko said on Thursday that China had over-reacted to a three-day visit by Taiwan's Vice-President Lien Chan to the former Soviet republic earlier this week.</p>
<p>China has cancelled a visit to Ukraine by a VIP delegation.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know whether this is going to be accepted with pleasure but I think the (Chinese reaction) was out of proportion,&quot; Udovenko told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It wasn't even a visit but a trip, a private journey.&quot;</p>
<p>He also denied Taiwanese media reports that Lien had met President Leonid Kuchma.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no meeting and there would have been no meeting even if someone had wanted such a meeting,&quot; he said. &quot;From our side there was not even a thought about that. I have spoken personally to the president.&quot;</p>
<p>The 14-member Taiwanese delegation, headed by Lien, visited the Ukrainian capital at the invitation of the chancellor of Kiev State University and left for Taipei on Wednesday evening.</p>
<p>In Taipei, Lien said on Thursday he had talked to people &quot;of all levels&quot; during the secretive visit but declined to confirm reports he had met the Ukrainian president.</p>
<p>&quot;I met the people I wanted to meet and discussed the things I wanted to discuss,&quot; Lien told reporters at Taipei's international airport.</p>
<p>&quot;But I cannot identify who I met by name. That would not live up to the agreement I made before visiting.&quot;</p>
<p>Udovenko said Ukraine was interested in developing trade with Taiwan and wanted to open a trade mission in Taipei. He said he already asked the Ukrainian Trading House, a Ukrainian investment organisation, to open an office in Taipei.</p>
<p>&quot;Ukraine never in its policy made a step away from support of China's territorial integrity. We consider Taiwan as an integral part of China and we will follow this line further,&quot; Udovenko said.</p>
<p>&quot;But life changes. There should be no objections to our scientific, cultural, trade and economic cooperation with Taiwan. We already have established close economic cooperation with China's other provinces.&quot;</p>
<p>Beijing regards nationalist-ruled Taiwan as a rebel province ineligible for foreign ties and has sought to isolate it diplomatically since a civil war separated them in 1949.</p>
<p>Lien indicated in Taipei that Taiwan also wanted to open a representative office in Kiev. Taiwanese offices have been already established in Moscow and the Belarussian capital of Minsk.</p>
<p>China is Ukraine's second largest economic partner with annual bilateral trade at $1 billion. Ukrainian-Taiwanese trade stands at less than $100 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
