<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9117" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Europe and CIS port conditions - Lloyds.</title>
<headline>Europe and CIS port conditions - Lloyds.</headline>
<text>
<p>Port conditions from Lloyds Shipping Intelligence Service --</p>
<p>BULGARIA, Aug 8-18 - Bourgas - 31 vessels operating of which 13 loading. 1 general cargo, 3 fertiliser, 1 barite concentrate, 1 trucks, 4 steel, 1 tanker, 2 chemicals. 9 discharging. 2 GAR, 2 fishmeal, 1 paper, 1 coal, 1 iron ore, 1 wheat, 1 petrol. 2 discharging/loading. 1 containers/general, 1 containers/marble. 2 discharging/loading general/fertiliser. 2 discharging/loading containers. 3 military vessels. 13 vessels waiting in roads of which 8 to load. 2 cars, 2 tankers, 2 general, 2 steel. 1 vessel in drydock. 2 empty vessels. 2 awaiting orders. 12 vessels due of which 9 to load. 1 clinker, 1 steel, 1 copper/zinc, 5 fertiliser, 1 marble. 2 To discharge. 1 iron ore, 1 coal. 1 passenger vessel.</p>
<p>Varna - twenty-eight vessels operating of which 12 loading. 2 SAS, 2 clinker, 2 cement, 1 fertiliser, 2 soda, 2 quartz sand, 1 EDC. 8 discharging. 2 wheat, 1 equipment, 3 coal, 1 coke, 1 rice. 1 discharging containers/metal. 2 loading containers/trucks. 5 discharging/loading containers. 4 vessels waiting in roads of which 2 to discharge. 1 wheat, 1 coal. 2 Cargo not nominated.</p>
<p>Aug 19 - Varna - East - Two vessels loading at berth. 3 vessels loading at anchorage. 1 vessel waiting at anchorage to load. West - 2 vessels due. 3 vessels loading at berth. 3 vessels discharging at berth. 2 vessels waiting at anchorage to load. Lesport - 1 vessel due. Bourgas - East - 11 vessels due. 10 vessels loading at berth. 1 vessel discharging at berth. 12 vessels waiting at anchorage to load. 7 vessels under repairs/drydock. 2 vessels awaiting orders. West - 1 vessel discharging at berth.  </p>
<p>CROATIA, Aug 19 - Rijeka - one vessel discharging at berth. 2 vessels loading at berth. 6 vessels under repairs/drydock. 2 vessels anchored. 3 vessels due and delays expected. Split - two vessels discharging at berth. Pula, Rasa, Zadar, Sibenik, Ploce, Dubrovnik - no vessels.</p>
<p>ESTONIA, Aug 19 - Tallinn - City port - 3 vessels due. No delays expected. 2 vessels loading at berth of which 1 timber, 1 STE. 1 vessel waiting at anchorage to load. 2 liner vessels. Kopli - three vessels due. No delays expected. Muuga - no vessels due. 5 vessels loading at berth of which 1 oil, 2 timber, 1 fertiliser, 1 paper. 2 ferries in port. Parnu - one vessel due. No delays expected. 1 timber loading at berth.</p>
<p>ITALY, Aug 20 - Genoa commercial port - no vessels in roads. No delays. 35 vessels berthed. 1 vessel in drydock. Multedo oil harbour - no vessels in roads. No delays. 2 vessels berthed. Savona, Vado Ligure, Gaeta, Naples, Salerno, Palermo, Leghorn, Ancona/Falconara, Venice, Trieste, Taranto - no vessels in roads. No delays. La Spezia - no vessels in roads. No delays. 4 vessels berthed. Civitavecchia - two vessels in roads. No delays. Augusta oil harbour - four vessels in roads. 1 vessel berthed. Syracuse oil harbour - five vessels in roads. 5 vessels berthed. Sarroch -no vessels in roads. 13 vessels berthed. No delays. Ravenna - six vessels in roads. No delays.</p>
<p>LATVIA, Aug 20 - Riga - nineteen vessels in port of which 17 operating - 6 timber loaders, 2 cotton loaders, 3 fertiliser loaders, 2 tanker loaders, 1 metal loader, 1 scrap metal loader, 2 chicken dischargers. 2 vessels awaiting operations. No delays. 15 vessels due. Ventspils - nine vessels in port of which 5 operating - 2 steel loaders, 1 pig iron loader, 1 ferrous loader, 1 MOP loader. 4 awaiting operations. No delays. 5 vessels due. Liepaja - seven vessels operating, no delays. 1 Vessel due.  </p>
<p>LITHUANIA, Aug 19 - Klaipeda - vessels loading in port - 3 metal, 2 scrap, 4 fertiliser, 1 steel framework. Discharging - 4 fish, 1 bananas, 2 soya pellets, 1 malt grain, 2 sugar. 1 vessel loading/discharging, 4 vessels in roads, 26 vessels due.</p>
<p>POLAND, Aug 20 - Szczecin - eighty vessels due, 49 vessels loading at berth, 25 vessels discharging at berth, 1 vessel waiting at anchorage to load, 3 vessels waiting at anchorage to discharge, 14 vessels under repairs/drydock, 1 vessel awaiting orders. Gdynia - five vessels loading at berth (1 coal, 4 general cargo). 3 vessels discharging at berth (1 ore, 2 general cargo). 3 vessels under repairs/drydock. 20 vessels due of which 1 for shipyard. Gdansk - eight vessels loading at berth (2 coal, 2 bulk, 4 general cargo), 1 vessel discharging at berth (corn), 3 vessels under repairs/drydock, 17 vessels due.</p>
<p>PORTUGAL, Aug 19 - Leixoes - vessels operating - 6 general cargo, 4 container vessels. No vessels awaiting berth. Places vacant - 8 piers with cranes, without cranes.</p>
<p>ROMANIA, Aug 20 - Constantza - forty-six vessels operating of which 24 generals (22 loading, 2 discharging), 5 bagged chemicals loading, 10 bulkers (5 loading, 5 discharging), 4 bagged cement loading, 1 tanker discharging, 2 containers discharging. 7 vessels waiting in roads of which 5 bulkers (4 loading, 1 discharging), 2 generals loading. Constantza South (Agigea) - five vessels loading. Mangalia - no vessels. Midia - three livestock carriers loading. Vessels waiting.  </p>
<p>RUSSIA, August 19 - Baltic ports - St. Petersburg - 24 vessels operating of which loading - 7 non-ferrous, 2 machinery, 3 container vessels, 5 fertiliser, 2 coal. Discharging - 1 bagged sugar, 2 frozen chicken, 2 container vessels. 7 vessels awaiting operations. 11 vessels due. Kaliningrad - four vessels operating of which 1 cellulose loader, 1 fertiliser loader, 1 coal loader, 1 feed additive discharger. No delays. 1 Vessel due. Vyborg - no vessels in port. 3 vessels due.</p>
<p>Far East ports - Vladivostok - 25 vessels in port of which 3 passenger vessels, 10 vessels loading (8 metal, 1 timber, 1 container). 2 vessels discharging (1 general cargo, 1 sugar. 10 Vessels waiting. Nakhodka - 21 vessels in port of which 12 loading (2 general cargo, 8 metal, 2 timber). 9 vessels waiting. Vostochniy - 16 vessels in port of which 4 loading (1 container, 1 coal, 1 timber, 1 metal). 3 vessels waiting. Posyet - no vessels in port. Khasan - two vessels loading metal. 1 vessel waiting. No delays. No strikes. No congestion.</p>
<p>Black Sea - Novorossiysk - 14 vessels operating of which 8 loading - 1 scrap, 3 steel, 1 non-ferrous metals, 1 saltpetre, 1 cellulose, 1 seeds. 6 discharging - 3 rice, 3 various. 4 vessels waiting in roads of which 2 to load - 1 scrap, 1 wheat. 2 to discharge - 1 rice, 1 copper concentrate. 11 vessels due of which 8 to load - 1 cement, 1 scrap, 4 steel, 1 copper, 1 paper. 2 to discharge - 1 sugar, 1 luggage. 1 to load paper/containers. Oil terminal - August 20 - 1 tanker loading crude. 1 tanker waiting in roads to load diesel oil. 9 tankers due of which 8 to load crude, 1 diesel oil.  </p>
<p>Conditions Aug 20 - White Sea - Archangel - 18 vessels in port of which loading at berth - 1 oil products, 3 sawn timber, 2 general cargo, 2 woodpulp. 1 vessel discharging gravel at berth. 3 passenger vessels. 4 vessels under repairs. 2 vessels awaiting orders to load. 6 vessels due. No congestion in port.</p>
<p>Northern Basin - Murmansk - two vessels operating of which 1 apatite, 1 alumina. 1 cabotage loader waiting. 6 vessels due of which 4 loaders (2 apatite, 1 cabotage, 1 NPK), 2 dischargers (1 alumina, 1 general cargo).</p>
<p>SLOVENIA - Koper - August 19 - 15 vessels due during next 2 days of which 4 containers loading/discharging, 2 bulk carriers to load, 2 bulk carriers to discharge, 2 reefers to discharge, 3 general cargo to load, 1 car carrier to discharge, 1 tanker to discharge. 10 vessels berthed of which 1 general cargo loading, 4 container vessels loading/discharging, 3 bulk carriers discharging, 1 bulk cargo vessel loading, 1 livestock vessel loading. No delays expected in port.</p>
<p>SPAIN, Aug 19 - Aviles - 10 vessels operating of which 7 discharging (5 alumina, 2 coke/steel/blend), 3 vessels loading (zinc/fertiliser/steel). Gijon - four vessels discharging (steel/iron ore/petroleum/gas). No delays. No congestion in ports. Sagunto - 13 vessels operating of which 5 discharging steel products, 1 loading fertiliser, 4 ro/ro discharging/loading, 2 vessels loading steel product, 1 discharging logs. No vessels berthed outside commercial wharf. No berthing delays.</p>
<p>Conditions Aug 20 - Pasajes - seven vessels in port of which 3 discharging scrap, 1 discharging fertiliser, 1 discharging general, 1 discharging magnesite, 1 loading steel. No delays. Cadiz - 13 vessels operating of which 4 ro/ro, 2 containers, 2 cement, 1 semolina, 1 oil, 3 under repairs. no delays.  </p>
<p>UKRAINE, August 19 - Mariupol - nine vessels loading at berth (metal products, fertiliser, coal). 2 general cargo discharging at berth. 1 coal waiting at anchorage to load. 2 vessels waiting at anchorage to discharge of which 1 sunflower seeds, 1 general cargo. 9 floating storehouses (sulphur, urea, fertiliser). 1 vessel under repairs/drydock. 17 vessels due (metal products for loading, general cargo for discharging, coal and fertiliser for loading, potatoes for discharging). Kerch - two metal products loading at berth. 4 vessels under repairs/drydock. 1 vessel due to load metal products.</p>
<p>Berdiansk - three vessels loading metal products at berth. Mariupol - twelve vessels operating of which 10 loading - 1 sunflowerseeds, 3 steel, 2 fertiliser, 4 coal. 1 discharging/loading equipment. 1 discharging/loading containers. 3 vessels waiting in roads of which 1 to load coal, 1 each to discharge sunflowerseeds, containers. 17 vessels due of which 10 to load - 2 steel, 4 coal, 2 fertiliser, 1 slabs, 1 metal. 3 to discharge - 2 equipment, 1 potatoes. 4 to discharge/load containers.</p>
<p>Odessa - sixteen vessels in port of which 10 loading - 4 metal, 2 paper, 1 sugar, 1 barley, 1 oil, 1 fuel oil. 2 discharging - 1 sugar, 1 diesel oil. 4 vessels under repairs. 9 vessels in roads of which 4 to load - 1 fuel oil, 1 peas, 1 oil, 1 metal. 2 to discharge - 1 diesel oil, 1 general cargo. 1 vessel waiting. 1 vessel for technical and food supply. 1 to discharge/load containers. 12 vessels due of which 7 to load - metals, 1 paper. 2 to discharge - 1 sugar, 1 citrus. 3 to discharge/load containers.</p>
<p>Aug 20 - Odessa - vessels to load steel cargoes - 5 vessels alongside. No vessels anchored. 5 vessels due - containers - no vessels alongside. 1 anchored. 2 vessels due. Vessels to load/discharge grain - 1 vessel anchored. Vessels to discharge sugar - 1 alongside. 1 vessel due. Tankers to load - 2 alongside. 1 anchored. Tankers to discharge - 1 alongside, 1 anchored. Vessels to load/discharge general cargo - 2 alongside. 1 anchored.</p>
<p>YUGOSLAVIA, Aug 20 - Bar - five vessels berthed of which 1 discharging bananas, 1 discharging aid, 1 discharging gasoline, 1 loading metal, 1 loading steel coils. Zelenika/Bijela - one vessel discharging gasoline. 4 under repairs. No delays.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
