<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9125" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Aug 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>24 CHASA</p>
<p>-- The International Monetary Fund (IMF) is concerned about the weakening of the Bulgarian lev which reflects unsufficient financial discipline, the IMF mission leader Anne MgGuirk said on arrival in Sofia.</p>
<p>The IMF mission is in Bulgaria to review the progress of its reform programme within a funging agreement approved last month.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria is expected to become a member of the World Trade Organisation by the end of the year, deputy trade minister Petar Stefanov said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's state-run transport companies posted 2.854 billion levs loss in the first half of 1996, the transport ministry said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's central bank (BNB) could cut 10 points off its record high main interest rate of 108 percent in September if the lev steadies against the dollar on the local forex market and commercial banks meet the targets set in their stabilisation programmes, central bank officials said.  </p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's private Slavyani bank is in merger talks with several other private credit institutions in a bid to meet new central bank minimum capital requirements, Slavyani board chairman Borislav Tsonev said.</p>
<p>The BNB last week that banks should raise their capital to 1.4 billion levs or 2.2 billion levs by March 31, 1997 for a domestic and a full licence respectively.</p>
<p>STANDART</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's air traffic controllers at the airports in Sofia, Varna and Bourgas threatened a strike from August 29 if the transport ministry fails to meet their demand for a $1,200 monthly salary by that date.</p>
<p>-- The main opposition Union of Democratic Forces said it would ask the Constitutional Court to rule whether Socialist foreign minister Georgi Pirinski, whose Bulgarian citizenship has been disputed, can be a cabinet member.</p>
<p>The U.S. born Pirinski is also the candidate of the ruling Socialist Party for the country's presidential elections due on October 27.</p>
<p>PARI</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria is expected to import some 100,000 tonnes of grain worth $25 million from the United States to replenish its state reserves, trade minister Atanas Paparizov said.</p>
<p>-- Some twelve debt-ridden state firms, slated for liquidation, could be restructured, stabilised or privatised, trade union leader Krastyo Petkov said, adding that he would raise the issue in talks with the visiting IMF mission.</p>
<p>TROUD</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's national carrier Balkan Airlines posted 1.8 billion levs loss for the first half of 1996, transport ministry said.</p>
<p>-- The trade ministry imposed new minimum export prices on pork, chicken meat and cheese in a move to prevent exports at artificially low prices, trade minister Atanas Papariziv said. -- Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 981 8569</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
