<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9127" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovakia - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovakia - Aug 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - Slavomir Hatina, director of oil refiner Slovnaft, said the company was still negotiating on $250 million syndicated loan with Citibank which should cover a major part of investment for its EFPA modernisation programme.</p>
<p>- Slovnaft said it would sign the last contracts for EFPA by the first half of September at the latest.</p>
<p>- One of the world's leading producers of plastic fibres, Rhone-Poulenc of France, plans to aqcuire by the end of this year 100-percent control of major plastic materials producer Chemlon Humenne. The french firm already holds 56.8 percent of Chemlon.</p>
<p>- Some 42.5 percent out of 5,737 companies posted a profit in 1995, totalling about 72 billion crowns. Overall losses at unprofitbale firms totalled 29 billion crowns.</p>
<p>- Production of coal is expected to total around 3.8 million tonnes this year, slightly up from 3.6 million tonnes in 1995.</p>
<p>NARODNA OBRODA - Economics Minister Jan Ducky said a bank specialised in supporting exporters could begin operation at the beginning of next year. Ducky said the bank would be state-owned with contributions from exporting firms.</p>
<p>- Slovak ambassador to Vatican, Alexander Neuwirth, has not yet returned to Vatican, some four months after he was recalled to Bratislava for &quot;consultation with foreign ministry.&quot;</p>
<p>- One of the leading construction firms, Hydrostav, wholly- owned by a manager-employee joint-stock company, posted a gross profit of 95 million crowns in first half, an increase of 30 percent over the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>- Brigita Schmognerova, an economics analyst with the opposition Party of Democratic Left (SDL), said VSZ steel's acquisition of a 43.7 percent stake in bank IRB violated the banking law, as the purchase was not approved by the central bank and finance minsitry.</p>
<p>- Schmognerova warned that VSZ's entry into financial institutions, which also include Dopravna Banka, could be a serious danger for these banks due to the company's extensive debts.</p>
<p>- Schmognerova said the Slovak banking sector has entered a similar stage of decline of financial institutions as the Czech banking sector witnessed over the recent past.</p>
<p>PRAVDA - Shell said it would build about 10 petrol stations in Slovakia within next two years. Shell said about 70 percent of motor fuels it sells in Slovakia are supplied by Slovnaft.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
