<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9128" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Aug 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - According to the Czech National Bank, 22 percent, or 219 billion crowns, of the 980 billion crowns in total loans at banks will likely have to be written off.</p>
<p>- The Czech Republic posted a trade surplus to the countries of the CEFTA, comprised of the Czech Republic, Poland, Hungary, Slovakia and Slovenia.  Exports to these countries totalled 6.113 billion crowns, while imports from these countries totalled 3.751 billion crowns.</p>
<p>- According to the German Institute for Economic Research, trade between the EU and the countries of Central and Eastern Europe is predicted to increase by 250 percent in the next few years.</p>
<p>- EuroTel GSM telephones can be used in Germany in spite of the fact that EuroTel has no existing contract with any German operators.  Calls placed in Germany on EuroTel GSM phones are free.</p>
<p>- Anheuser Busch Int.'s actions on the German market have been described by the director of Budejovicky Budvar n.p. as a classic case of a parasite.  The American company has been marketing it's Anheuser-Busch B beer on the German market with advertisements featuring the name Budweiser, which is a trademark owned by Budvar in Germany, the third-most imported beer in Germany.</p>
<p>- The National Property Fund, which owns 22 percent of Cukrovar Prosenice, wants to know the reasons why the supra-national Eastern Sugar company, which owns 55 percent, has decided to close the refinery, though the NPF admits that they will not be able to influence the situation.</p>
<p>PRAVO - CEZ is continuing to supply six regional companies with energy in spite of the fact that they owe a total of two billion crowns to the company.</p>
<p>- Anheuser Busch has offered its proposal for the privitisation of Budejovicky Budvar to the Minstry of Agriculture, which is to decide on the method of Budvar's privatisation at the beginning of September.</p>
<p>MLADA FRONTA DNES - The flow of direct investment from foreign countries on the Czech market is expected to reach $420 million or 11.2 billion crowns in the first half of 1996, 2.5 billion crowns behind last year's record high.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, +42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
