<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9132" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Who is the joker behind Chechnya's latest crisis?</title>
<headline>Who is the joker behind Chechnya's latest crisis?</headline>
<byline>Philippa Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian security chief Alexander Lebed has silenced the guns which were pounding Grozny and reined in the generals who were threatening to flatten the city.</p>
<p>But his cynical dismissal of the Russian military's ultimatum to the rebels this week to leave the Chechen capital or be carpet-bombed as a &quot;bad joke&quot; raises two vital questions: Whose joke was it and might they have more up their sleeves?</p>
<p>The answers could mean life or death for the civilians cowering in Grozny basements, breathing wary sighs of relief on Thursday that no bombs were falling. They will be sorry to learn that no one in Moscow seems to have the responses to hand.</p>
<p>Lebed and his protege, Defence Minister Igor Rodionov, have said they had nothing to do with the bombardment threats which brought condemnation from governments around the world.</p>
<p>Chechen rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov, with whom Lebed was said to be on the verge of a detailed peace settlement on Thursday, took them at their word.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope Lebed will be able to conqunt to conclude the war,&quot; Maskhadov said after agreeing a ceasefire with Lebed on Wednesday evening, just hours before the bombardment had been due to start.</p>
<p>What is not clear is just who &quot;those in Moscow&quot; are.</p>
<p>Maskhadov told Reuters he knew their names and so did Lebed. But he was not about to say who they were.</p>
<p>In just two months in the Kremlin, Lebed has upset the status quo, accusing high-placed figures of profiting from the war and securing the sacking of the defence minister, Pavel Grachev, and other leading hawks.</p>
<p>Last week, he said Interior Minister Anatoly Kulikov should be sacked for bungling the defence of Grozny.</p>
<p>New Defence Minister Rodionov said on Wednesday that the acting army commander in Chechnya, Konstantin Pulikovsky, had been &quot;given a dressing down&quot; for announcing the ultimatum on Monday.</p>
<p>He said &quot;someone&quot; had provoked Pulikovsky, but gave no clue as to who that someone was. Pulikovsky is still in his job.</p>
<p>His superior, Vyacheslav Tikhomirov, who backed his deputy on his return from holiday on Tuesday, has not received the slightest public reprimand.</p>
<p>The liberal Izvestia newspaper asked on Thursday why, if Pulikovsky was out of line, no one had said anything earlier, pointing out that for two days, as the crisis loomed, all top officials, including the president, kept their heads down.</p>
<p>&quot;Paralysis of Power&quot; ran the headline on its front-page commentary on Thursday alongside photographs comparing the exodus from Grozny with the floods of refugees in World War Two.</p>
<p>Emil Pain, a former presidential adviser on Chechnya, said on Wednesday he doubted the generals were really acting alone.</p>
<p>&quot;If an ultimatum was presented then there must have been a nod from on high,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>Izvestia pointed out that, far from being out of control, they could merely have been fulfilling Yeltsin's orders.</p>
<p>Last week Yeltsin gave the command for the situation in Grozny to be returned to how it was on August 5, the day before the rebels captured large parts of the city.</p>
<p>This is Lebed's problem as he considers how to turn his dramatic political success into a lasting peace while saving face for Moscow after the humiliation of its army that has left the rebels still firmly ensconced in Grozny.</p>
<p>&quot;Lebed's mandate is completely contradictory. On the one hand he has to bring peace, and on the other he has to reproduce the situation on August 5 before the Chechens came in,&quot; said a western diplomat who declined to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;Will Russia give in?&quot; asked the popular daily Moskovsky Komsolets, giving a hint of the likely outrage in Moscow to any sign Lebed had given in to the rebels.</p>
<p>Defence commentator Pavel Felgenhauer said that the latest crisis resembled the 1992 civil war in the former Soviet republic of Moldova, where Lebed's successful peace efforts were preceded by a Russian offensive against the Moldovan army.</p>
<p>He said the latest offensive was meant to send a message to the rebels that they had better be flexible -- or else.</p>
<p>&quot;The army generals and Lebed who seem to be acting independently of one another are playing in the same team,&quot; Felgenhauer wrote in Thursday's Sevodnya newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;The aim is to make clear to the Chechen separatists that... a ceasefire must mean a total end to any hostile acts, otherwise Lebed will not be able to stop Moscow's &quot;party of war'.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
