<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9134" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Serbs, Croats oppose unified Bosnia -- U.S. poll.</title>
<headline>Serbs, Croats oppose unified Bosnia -- U.S. poll.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. Information Agency poll shows very few Bosnian Serbs and Croats support the Dayton peace agreement's goal of a unified, multi-ethnic Bosnia and documents strong separatist sentiments.</p>
<p>Ninety-five per cent of the Bosnian Serbs surveyed in the poll voiced opposition to a unified Bosnia, as did two thirds of the Croats.</p>
<p>In contrast, Moslem support for a unified Bosnia was near-unanimous at 97 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Bosnian Serbs, Croats and Moslems have grown further apart -- not closer together -- in their visions for the country,&quot; the U.S. Information Agency (USIA) said in an analysis of the poll issued in Sarajevo on Thursday.</p>
<p>The poll, conducted in mid-to-late July among 2,763 Bosnian residents, provided a number of insights into the political mood of the country in the run-up to September 14 national elections.</p>
<p>Three-quarters of Croats polled felt the Croat-dominated Herzegovina region of Bosnia &quot;should really be part of Croatia&quot;.</p>
<p>Ninety per cent of Croats thought it &quot;inevitable that the country will be partitioned into three ethnic communities&quot;, a statement agreed to by 96 per cent of Serbs.</p>
<p>Eight Moslems in ten felt differently, endorsing the proposition that &quot;we will ultimately be able to live in peace together&quot;.</p>
<p>Not surprisingly, backing for nationalist parties among Croats and Serbs was strong.</p>
<p>The hardline Croat nationalist HDZ won the backing of 81 percent of the Croats interviewed, giving it what appears to be an insurmountable lead in the forthcoming elections.</p>
<p>Support for the ruling Serb nationalist SDS party among Serbs in Bosnia's Serb republic was less solid, standing at just 54 per cent. The rival Socialist Party won 25 percent backing.</p>
<p>Regardless of which party they backed, however, virtually all Serbs (96 per cent) surveyed agreed with the statement that the &quot;Bosnian Serb republic should be part of Serbia&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The results of this poll reveal why there was a war in Bosnia and why the peace is so fragile,&quot; said a Western diplomat in Sarajevo who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;They make it clear just how deeply the country is divided and how difficult it will be to realise Dayton's aspirations regardless of the outcome of elections.&quot;</p>
<p>A USIA poll of residents in the predominantly Moslem region of central Bosnia showed Alija Izetbegovic leading Haris Silajdzic in the race for the Moslem seat on Bosnia's new collective presidency.</p>
<p>Silajdzic, the former Bosnian prime minister, was favoured by 33 per cent of those interviewed as against 44 per cent for Izetbegovic, who is the country's current president.</p>
<p>Analysts say that, if those figures hold, the split Moslem vote could ensure that a Serb gets the most votes for president and emerges as chairman of the three-man body.</p>
<p>In the Serb republic, 47 per cent of 1,158 Serbs interviewed said they doubted next month's elections would be free and fair.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
