<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9135" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russians, rebels due to cease fire in Chechnya.</title>
<headline>Russians, rebels due to cease fire in Chechnya.</headline>
<byline>Dmitry Kuznets</byline>
<dateline>NOVYE ATAGI, Russia 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian troops and separatist rebels are due to cease fire in Chechnya on Friday and are expected to form joint patrol groups to protect the devastated regional capital Grozny against looters.</p>
<p>Moscow peacemaker Alexander Lebed and rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov struck a military deal on Thursday in the village of Novye Atagy, some 20 km (12 miles) south of Grozny.</p>
<p>The deal also provides for withdrawing Russian troops from Grozny -- much of which has been controlled by rebels since August 6 -- to bases outside the city and a later withdrawal of Moscow troops from the rest of Chechnya.</p>
<p>&quot;I made this decision on behalf of Russian mothers whose sons have died and continue to die in Chechnya,&quot; Lebed, whom President Boris Yeltsin had ordered to end the 20-month war in the breakaway province, told reporters after signing the deal.</p>
<p>Interfax news agency said the truce will be launched at midday (0800 GMT) on Friday. On the same day the sides are expected to form joint military administrations in Grozny which will run the city.</p>
<p>Lebed and Maskhadov also agreed to swap prisoners of war.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands people died in Chechnya after Moscow sent troops to quell the region's independence bid. Rebels fight for full independence from Moscow, while the Kremlin wants Chechnya to remain part of the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>Lebed said after signing he would be back in Chechnya in two days to sign a political pact which would clarify the future status of Chechnya. He made no hint, though, on what sort of compromise might be reached.</p>
<p>Truces have come and gone in 20 months of the Chechen conflict, and it was too soon to say whether the new deal would bring respite for civilians who have been fleeing Grozny in tens of thousands since the raid began.</p>
<p>The latest bout of fighting, in which rebels seized much of Grozny, followed a deal which foresaw rebel disarmament in return for step-by-step troop withdrawals from the mainly Moslem region to be completed by September 1.</p>
<p>It was also unclear whether Lebed had enough power and support from Yeltsin to press on with his peace deal.</p>
<p>The ex-paratrooper's Kremlin chief sent him a discouraging message on Thursday complaining of a lack of progress just hours before the deal with Maskhadov was signed.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not completely satisfied with Lebed's performance in Chechnya,&quot; Yeltsin said in a televised interview with RIA news agency.</p>
<p>Some of Russia's top brass also appeared sceptical about the deal.</p>
<p>&quot;These are the third talks since I started serving in Chechnya,&quot; Itar-Tass news agency quoted the commander of Interior Ministry forces, Colonel-General Anatoly Shkirko, as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;Earlier talks had ended in nothing,&quot; added the general whose troops form the backbone of Russian forces in Chechnya. &quot;Moreover they had incurred new casualties.&quot;</p>
<p>News of the truce had apparently failed to reach Grozny fast enough. Interfax news agency said at least 50 Russian servicemen have been killed in a battle which erupted at Grozny's Minutka square on Thursday and continued after the truce deal was signed. The report could not be independently confirmed.</p>
<p>Lebed said he was ready to face criticism.</p>
<p>&quot;I predict attacks by jingoistic patriots and jingoistic democrats for signing the accord,&quot; he said referring to radicals on different sides of the political spectrum in Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;Anyone who is unhappy is welcome to complain, including the president and God Almighty himself,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NOVYE ATAGI, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
