<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9136" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: War mafia must go to normalise Mostar in Bosnia - EU.</title>
<headline>War mafia must go to normalise Mostar in Bosnia - EU.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Powerful paramilitary gangs must be removed from Mostar if efforts to reunify its Moslem and Croat communities are to succeed, the European Union envoy in the Bosnian city said on Thursday.</p>
<p>On August 14, Moslems and Croats who wrecked Mostar in a 1993-94 war convened a new joint council and elected a single mayor after Western threats of sanctions that ended a Croat boycott of the EU-sponsored reunification process.</p>
<p>But EU envoy Sir Martin Garrod said politically connected rightist gangsters in the Croat-run western sector of town would have to be stripped of power and influence to normalise life in Mostar, which is about 80 km (50 miles) southwest of Sarajevo.</p>
<p>&quot;There are two fundamentally important things -- one is that is we achieve the unified administration of Mostar and the second, that we get rid of the scum from Mostar,&quot; he said at a ceremony reopening the main city bus station.</p>
<p>&quot;By that I mean the thugs and the gangs and the criminals who instil fear, who instil anguish, who instil intimidation into the innocent citizens of Mostar,&quot; he said in comments carried by Bosnian state television.</p>
<p>&quot;And that scum has got to be removed if we're going to move back to normal life in Mostar.&quot;</p>
<p>Profiteering nationalist warlords played a big role in the separatist Croat war to seize Mostar &quot;capital&quot; of a breakaway Croat &quot;republic&quot; in western Bosnia, which is to be abolished under U.S. pressure on September 1.</p>
<p>Persecution of Moslems -- firebombings of property and violent evictions of residents -- was pervasive in Croat-held west Mostar during the war and has continued sporadically even under EU administration since 1994.</p>
<p>New Croat mayor Ivan Prskalo missed the bus station ceremony because of what were described as &quot;other obligations&quot;, but his Moslem deputy Safet Orucevic, previously mayor of east Mostar, did attend alongside Garrod.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sure Mr Prskalo and I will have the opportunity and honour to jointly open many such facilities which would serve to unify Mostar so that we can revive the trust and tradition of joint living of all citizens of this city,&quot; Orucevic said.</p>
<p>Rebuilding of the bus station cost $260,000 in EU funds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
