<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9138" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria laggs behind few IMF reform targets - c.ban.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria laggs behind few IMF reform targets - c.ban.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's implementation of the reform plan agreed with the International Monetary Fund last month has fallen behind schedule, central bank governor Lyubomir Filipov said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We were either more optimistic than the situation called for, or the (stabilisation) measures were not implemented properly,&quot; Filipov told reporters after the weekly central bank meeting. &quot;We were too optimistic about restoring confidence in the banking system.&quot;  </p>
<p>On Wednesday, IMF mission leader Anne McGuirk said the fund was concerned about the general stance of monetary and fiscal policy. She saw the weakening Bulgarian currency as a sign of insufficient financial discipline.</p>
<p>Bulgaria has fulfilled some of financial policy commitments like cutting uncollateralised refinancing by the central bank and reducing blocked interbank settlements, said Filipov.</p>
<p>But inflation is higher than targetted, which indicates that some factors were underestimated.  </p>
<p>The cumulative inflation for the first seven months already stands at 82 percent after monthly inflation recorded its highest monthly rise ever of 23.3 percent in July.</p>
<p>The socialist government, battling a financial crisis triggered by slow market reforms, has in July raised utility prices and taxes in a bid to stabilise the state budget in line with pledges made to international lenders.</p>
<p>The government projected annual cumulative inflation at 105 percent, however, the National Statistics Office saw this year's consumer price inflation at around 150 percent.</p>
<p>Bulgaria has pledged to bring monthly inflation down to 2.5 percent by the end of 1996. Closing scores of loss-making state firms and restructuring its ailing banking sector are also essential elements in the reform plan.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
