<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9139" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Chechens hail Lebed as saviour but rebels cautious.</title>
<headline>Chechens hail Lebed as saviour but rebels cautious.</headline>
<byline>Brian Killen</byline>
<dateline>GROZNY, Russia 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chechen civilians hailed Russian security chief Alexander Lebed as a saviour on Thursday for preventing a threatened all-out assault on the capital Grozny, but separatist fighters doubted peace had come to stay.</p>
<p>A flood of refugees from this devastated city was reduced to a trickle after Lebed described as &quot;a bad joke&quot; an ultimatum by a senior Russian commander for people to leave the city within 48 hours or face a massive attack.</p>
<p>&quot;Lebed is our great hope,&quot; said Wakha Israilov, a 36-year-old man who had stayed behind to protect his home from looting. &quot;He's our only hope,&quot; chorused a crowd of women at a nearby marketplace.</p>
<p>Lebed, President Boris Yeltsin's special envoy to Chechnya, appeared to have opened the door to new period of relative calm in the breakway region by striking a deal with rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov.</p>
<p>As the two men ended talks at a village south of Grozny, only a few cars and buses flying white flags carried refugees along a dusty &quot;safe&quot; corridor leading out of the northeast suburb of Staraya Sunzha.</p>
<p>After another night of mortar and sniper fire, some people ventured cautiously into the streets in search of food and water. The occasional rifle shot and rattle of a machine gun reminded them of the dangers.</p>
<p>Bearded Moslem fighters wearing green headbands and wielding Kalashnikovs patrolled the district, calmly demonstrating their control. They were sceptical about the latest peacemaking initiatives, but they intended to obey the ceasefire.</p>
<p>&quot;We are under strict orders not to shoot,&quot; said field commander Ruslan Masayev at one of the fighters' bases in the city. &quot;If they respect it, we will not fire.&quot;</p>
<p>Masayev, in camouflage fatigues and bedecked with weapons he said had been captured from his Russian enemies, answers directly to Shamil Basayev -- the rebel commander who masterminded the August 6 offensive on Grozny.</p>
<p>&quot;We are at home in our city and we don't plan to leave,&quot; Masayev said, adding that he was ready to fight to the death and had little faith in the Russians, even Lebed.</p>
<p>&quot;I only have faith in Allah,&quot; he said. &quot;This is not my first day of war. I've heard many promises and none of them have been fulfilled.&quot;</p>
<p>Masayev's men said they were holding several Russian prisoners and they showed journalists two young servicemen captured five day ago.</p>
<p>The two frail and frightened-looking soldiers, wearing civilian clothes, had light bruises around their eyes but said they had been treated well.</p>
<p>They identified themselves as Ravil Zinorov, 27, and Serei Balashov, 21.</p>
<p>Both had been serving in Chechnya under contract for only a matter of weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope this war finishes soon and they will send us home,&quot; Balashov said with his Chechen captors looking on.</p>
<p>He wrote his address and a message in this correspondent's notebook. It read: &quot;Grandma, everything is alright. I hope to return home soon. I kiss you, Sergei.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GROZNY, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
