<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9142" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine govt not behind grain lock-up-deputy PM.</title>
<headline>Ukraine govt not behind grain lock-up-deputy PM.</headline>
<byline>Irene Marushko</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior Ukrainian minister on Thursday denied charges by traders that the government had officially ordered state-owned elevators to keep grain locked up until state grain purchase contracts are fulfilled.</p>
<p>But Deputy Prime Minister Mykhailo Zubets told a news conference such orders may have been issued informally by lower levels of government in some provinces, and acknowledged that there were some restrictions on grain movements.</p>
<p>&quot;The Ukrainian government has not forbidden anything,&quot; Zubets said. &quot;Legally we are not allowed to do this, and this will never happen.&quot;</p>
<p>Without written government orders as evidence of force majeure, brokers are liable for breach of contract. Traders say there is an order in practice restricting movements of grain across oblast (provincial) boundaries.</p>
<p>After the government fills its order the provinces will allow the elevators the full right to export grain wherever they want, Zubets said.</p>
<p>Asked by reporters whether the government would intervene to release grain, he replied &quot;in a day or two&quot;.</p>
<p>A formal order by the government to restrict grain movements would break agreements with the International Monetary Fund and World Bank, which have urged Ukraine to liberalise its farm sector.</p>
<p>Grain trading on Ukraine's 22 exchanges ground to a halt about two weeks ago, and industry sources accused the government of quietly ordering the provinces to hold on to this season's limited supply of grain.</p>
<p>Much of the grain in the elevators which traders say is being held back had been purchased in May and June in forward contracts of up to 10,000 tonnes, and brokers said it may not be released until November, by which time the state will have bought all the grain it needs.</p>
<p>Angry brokers have written a letter to Prime Minister Leonid Kuchma and Prime Minister Pavlo Lazarenko asking them to release the grain, and have also published letters in newspapers saying the government's move has paralysed the exchanges.</p>
<p>&quot;Don't believe those who have said we've intervened to raise grain prices,&quot; Zubets said.</p>
<p>Ukraine has forecast the 1996 grain harvest at 28 million tonnes -- the lowest since the late 1940s. It hopes to export about three million tonnes this year.</p>
<p>Zubets said the state must buy about five million tonnes of grain from domestic farmers to ensure people have enough to eat.</p>
<p>Only about eight percent of grain is bought and sold on the relatively new exchange system, and the majority is bartered for fuel and machinery, used directly as animal feed or sold straight to the government.</p>
<p>--Irene Marushko, Kiev Newsroom +380 44 229 2264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
