<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9143" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Voter registration problems snowball into crisis.</title>
<headline>Voter registration problems snowball into crisis.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>International mediator Carl Bildt expressed &quot;deep disquiet&quot; on Thursday over reports of serious Serb manipulation of voters ahead of the Bosnian elections, and the main Moslem party is pondering a boycott.</p>
<p>The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), which is overseeing Bosnian post-war elections, and independent monitors say the registration of Bosnian Serb refugees has been marred by serious irregularities.</p>
<p>Figures released on Thursday confirmed OSCE anecdotal reports that Serb refugees were directed to register in &quot;target&quot; communities from which the pre-war Moslem majority was expelled during the 43-month Bosnian conflict.</p>
<p>Bildt, international High Representative to Bosnia, said registration figures for two municipalities, Brcko and Srebrenica, looked particularly suspect.</p>
<p>&quot;I have expressed my deep disquiet over these figures to OSCE and told them they must come up with a plan of action,&quot; Bildt told Reuters. &quot;One option is to annul the registrations for towns like Brcko and Srebrenica as obviously rigged. The figures are simply not credible as voluntary acts. They fly in the face of common sense.&quot;</p>
<p>OSCE and independent monitors reported that Serb officials had actively discouraged refugees from registering to vote by absentee ballot or in person from the community in which they lived before the war.</p>
<p>Human rights workers said the obvious intent of this &quot;electoral engineering&quot; was to cement Serb control over key depopulated towns by ensuring a Serb majority even if all expelled Moslems somehow showed up to vote on election day.</p>
<p>Leaders of the Moslem nationalist ruling SDA party were scheduled to meet in Sarajevo on Thursday evening to discuss the voter registration problem.</p>
<p>Bosnian government radio on Wednesday reported the SDA would ask the OSCE for revisions to the registration process for refugees, or for a postponement of municipal elections.</p>
<p>The radio said if the OSCE refused the request the SDA would consider calling for a boycott of the elections.</p>
<p>The Dayton peace agreement proposed the elections as a balm to heal the country's war wounds but Western officials say the Serbs were using them as a knife to dismember Bosnia along ethnic lines.</p>
<p>On Thursday figures for refugee registrations from Serbia were released, making the extent of the manipulation apparent, diplomats and human rights monitors said.</p>
<p>The strategic municipality of Brcko had a pre-war population of 87,332, of which 44 percent was Moslem and 21 percent or about 18,000 Serb.</p>
<p>Brcko is now virtually a pure Serb community due to ethnic cleansing during the war and has a current population estimated at 20,000. But OSCE reports that another 31,278 Serb refugees in Serbia have also registered to vote in Brcko.</p>
<p>In the Srebrenica municipality, where 37,211 people lived before the war, of whom 73 percent were Moslem and 25 percent or 9,300 were Serb, at least 10,000 Serbs now live. Another 19,700 Serbs recently registered in Serbia to vote there.</p>
<p>Officials said the registration figures for these two communities were the most obviously suspect but that there were numbers for other towns in Bosnia's Serb republic which seemed inflated as well.</p>
<p>The OSCE could decide to suspend municipal elections without prejudicing the rest of the September 14 ballot because voting for local offices was not a requirement of the Dayton peace agreement.</p>
<p>The OSCE's Provisional Election Commission, which promulgates election rules, was meeting on Thursday and officials said its agenda included the issue of registration irregularities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
