<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9146" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia's Lebed, Chechens sign military deal.</title>
<headline>Russia's Lebed, Chechens sign military deal.</headline>
<byline>Dmitry Kuznets</byline>
<dateline>NOVYE ATAGI, Russia 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alexander Lebed, the Kremlin's new peacemaker in Chechnya, and rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov agreed on Thursday to disengage their forces in the breakaway province after two weeks of bitter fighting.</p>
<p>Lebed, President Boris Yeltsin's security adviser, said Russian troops would leave the capital Grozny -- they were largely pushed out by the rebels in the last offensive -- and would start withdrawing from the rest of Chechnya.</p>
<p>He promised to return in two days to strike another deal, on the highly sensitive issue of Chechnya's political status.</p>
<p>&quot;I will come back with a draft political agreement in two days. We will discuss it and sign it,&quot; Lebed told reporters after signing the pact on military issues.</p>
<p>He gave no details of the planned political deal.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands have died since Moscow sent troops and armour in December 1994 to quell Chechnya's independence bid.</p>
<p>A series of attempts to end fighting have collapsed as the sides could not agree on the future of the mountainous region. The separatists seek full independence from Moscow while the Kremlin wants Chechnya to remain part of the Russia Federation.</p>
<p>Ex-paratroop general Lebed, whom Yeltsin last week ordered to restore peace, told reporters that he and Maskhadov agreed that Russian troops will start leaving Grozny on Friday. Most of the city has been in rebel hands since August 6.</p>
<p>&quot;Troops will be withdrawn from Grozny because constitutional order cannot be introduced using air and artillery strikes,&quot; Lebed told reporters in this village some 20 km (12 miles) south of Grozny. &quot;They will be withdrawn from the whole of Chechnya.&quot;</p>
<p>Only on Wednesday, Lebed had blocked a plan by the Russian army commander in the region to bomb the city flat on Thursday.</p>
<p>He said that the capital will be run by joint military administrations. Lebed did not say whether the pro-Moscow Chechen administrators, whom the rebels regard as traitors, would stay on in the city.</p>
<p>Lebed said that the the troop withdrawal from the hilly southern parts of Chechnya, where rebel positions are especially strong, would start on Friday. But he said it was too early to set any deadline for a complete pullout.</p>
<p>&quot;Let us stop fighting first and then deal with deadlines,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Maskhadov stood side by side with Lebed in the yard of a large three-storey house facing around 100 journalists, guards and local residents where the signing took place.</p>
<p>The rebel commander was far more reserved in his comments.</p>
<p>&quot;The basic principle of the agreement is joint action,&quot; said Maskhadov, for whom talks with Lebed are by no means his first negotiations with Russians.</p>
<p>Lebed said that he was ready to face criticism in Moscow for a deal which many could see as a national humiliation.</p>
<p>&quot;I predict attacks by jingoistic patriots and jingoistic democrats for signing the accord,&quot; he said referring to radicals on different sides of the political spectrum in Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;Anyone who is unhappy is welcome to complain, including to the president and God Almighty himself,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NOVYE ATAGI, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
