<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9152" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania candidate in king row scorns call to quit.</title>
<headline>Romania candidate in king row scorns call to quit.</headline>
<byline>Sean Maguire</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's leading opposition hopeful in November presidential elections on Thursday rejected calls to abandon his campaign after stinging attacks on his support for the return of the country's exiled king.</p>
<p>Emil Constantinescu, an academic who is running a close second to incumbent Ion Iliescu in opinion polls, said the ruling leftist Party of Social Democracy (PDSR) had been frightened by his popularity into starting a smear campaign.</p>
<p>The row is a foretaste of bitter campaigning, officially due to start on September 4, for November 3 presidential and parliamentary elections. Iliescu, in power since the bloody 1989 fall of communism, launches his manifesto next Wednesday.</p>
<p>The PDSR on Wednesday said remarks by Constantinescu made in the United States showed that if elected he would breach the constitution by reinstalling King Michael, kicked out in 1947 and allowed to return to his home country only once.</p>
<p>Local media on Thursday said Constantinescu had been badly hurt by the charges and called on him to quit, saying he was damaging the electoral chances of the Democratic Convention (CDR), the loose centrist alliance that he leads.</p>
<p>Even supposed political allies who hope to govern in coalition with the CDR warned it they would oppose changes to the constitution.</p>
<p>&quot;This is in essence nothing but a poor political manoeuvre,&quot; Constantinescu, 56, told Reuters. He said his U.S. interview had been distorted by the PDSR and its author had come forward to acknowledge fabricating elements.</p>
<p>He denied he would restore the monarchy but said Michael, whose home is now in Switzerland, had a right to live in Romania.</p>
<p>&quot;This (attack) shows the PDSR is not only worried it is in panic,&quot; said Constantinescu, who lost in 1992 to Iliescu.</p>
<p>&quot;If anything good comes from this situation it is that we can see clearly, very shortly before the electoral campaign, how the PDSR will campaign on the themes of 1990 and 1992.&quot;</p>
<p>Communist-style PDSR attacks on the CDR as the party of land-owners, capitalists and royalists cost the opposition the 1992 election. The PDSR, made up mainly of ex-communist functionaries, has held power since the 1989 revolution.</p>
<p>Constantinescu said the Romanian electorate, facing its third set of post-communist polls, was now too sophisticated to fall for PDSR scaremongering.</p>
<p>&quot;The mentality of Romanians has changed a lot. They now reject all such tactics based on hatred and disinformation,&quot; the bearded geology professor said, denying that his electoral chances had suffered a telling blow.</p>
<p>&quot;By having this scandal now and proving it is nothing more than a diversion it will again compromise the ruling party and the issue will not be returned to in the campaign.&quot;</p>
<p>The issue of the monarchy still has resonance in Romania, where less than 10 percent support the king's return to power but many more hold him in affectionate regard. Michael has been refused a visa since his one triumphant visit in 1992.</p>
<p>But analysts say the PDSR can profit by portraying the CDR as the party of privilege in a society suffering from the economic pain of a sluggish transition to a market economy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
