<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9154" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: Tajik rebel forces accused of new attack.</title>
<headline>Tajik rebel forces accused of new attack.</headline>
<dateline>ALMATY, Kazakhstan 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Islamist rebels in Tajikistan launched an attack against government forces to strengthen their grip on a strategic highway, a Tajik defence ministry source in Dushanbe said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The source told Reuters opposition fighters had attacked late on Wednesday near the the village of Childara, around 160 km (110 miles) east of the capital, to try to secure a bridge on a strategic road between government and rebel-held territory.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a battle for the bridge and there have been casualties on both sides,&quot; he said by phone from the Tajik capital Dushanbe.</p>
<p>He said attacks had been stepped up elsewhere in the region but gave no further details.</p>
<p>Tajik opposition leader Akbar Torajonzoda, who spoke with Reuters by telephone from the Iranian capital Tehran, denied the clash, saying opposition forces already held the area.</p>
<p>&quot;This bridge has already been taken by our detachments, it has been under our control for some time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On Monday, the Tajik government confirmed that the town of Tavildara, 200 km (120 miles) east of Dushanbe, had fallen to rebel forces in fierce fighting last week.</p>
<p>Neither the fall of Tavildara or Thursday's fighting around Childara have been independently confirmed.</p>
<p>Torajonzoda said he had met the United Nations special representative to Tajikistan, Gerd Merrem, in Tehran on Thursday -- Merrem is trying to rescue a shaky U.N. sponsored ceasefire agreed in peace talks last month -- but gave no details of the talks.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no plans to step up our actions, we only take defensive measures,&quot; Torajonzoda said.</p>
<p>The four-year civil war in Tajikistan, a remote mountainous nation which borders Afghanistan and China, has costs tens of thousands of lives and displaced many more.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TADZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY, Kazakhstan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
