<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9155" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo govt services blamed for 6.6 pct inflation.</title>
<headline>Yugo govt services blamed for 6.6 pct inflation.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of leading Yugoslav economists on Thursday blamed a huge hike in the price of government services for dragging July's inflation to what they described as an alarming rate of 6.6 percent.</p>
<p>According to the Statistics Office, government services rose an average of 10.4 percent in July, helping to blow out the previous month's inflation of 3.3 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore we suggest that the government abstain from any further price increases in services,&quot; said Miroljub Labus, a chief economist at the Belgrade-based Economic Institute.</p>
<p>According to the Institute, the price of services, including those controlled by the state, climbed 114.2 percent from January to July.</p>
<p>The same seven month period shows consumer prices rising by 28 percent and industrial goods by 26.7 percent. No separate figures were available for state-supplied services.</p>
<p>&quot;(Monthly) inflation must not enter double digits. The government must try to keep the dinar exchange rate stable and retain both fiscal and monetary stability,&quot; said Jurij Bajec, another member of the Institute and a professor at the Belgrade School of Economics.</p>
<p>Both Labus and Bajec said the government should stick to its current monetary and fiscal policies without sacrificing stability of the country's economy.</p>
<p>The two economists said provided there were no unforseen catastrophies, the government could reign in August's inflation to 3 percent by controling the cost of services. -- Gordana Filipovic, Belgrade newsroom, +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
