<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9162" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Fifty Russians die in clash with rebels-Interfax.</title>
<headline>Fifty Russians die in clash with rebels-Interfax.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least 50 Russian servicemen have been killed in a battle with separatist rebels which erupted in the Chechen capital Grozny on Thursday and continued after Russia and the rebels agreed a truce, Interfax news agency said.</p>
<p>Interfax quoted Russian military command in Chechnya as saying that about 200 interior ministry forces, sent on reconaisance mission, clashed with rebels at Minutka Square. The Interfax report could not be independently confirmed.  </p>
<p>Moscow peacemaker Alexander Lebed and rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov signed an agreement earlier on Thursday under which the two sides would cease all hostilities at noon (0800 GMT) on Friday.</p>
<p>Interfax made clear that the interior ministry detachment had been sent on the mission before the truce deal had been signed at the local equivalent of 1500 GMT. But fierce fighting still raged at 1600 GMT, Interfax said.</p>
<p>It quoted a source in the Russian command in Chechnya as saying that the servicemen were outnumbered by the rebels.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
