<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9165" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Trade gap, public deficit hurt Yugo growth - analysts.</title>
<headline>Trade gap, public deficit hurt Yugo growth - analysts.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslav economists said on Thursday the country's economy was plagued by a growing trade deficit, a rise in public spending and high inflation.</p>
<p>Whatever the government intends to do, analysts said maintaining economic stability should take precedence over changes in fiscal and monetary policies to promote growth.</p>
<p>&quot;Stability is a top priority, it comes before any economic growth,&quot; said Jurij Bajec, economy professor at the Belgrade School of Economics.</p>
<p>According to analysts at the Economic Institute, higher-than-expected July inflation, which surged to 6.6 percent from 3.3 percent in June, was only the most obvious problem.</p>
<p>Other problems included the foreign trade gap, which topped $1 billion in July, and the strong 14.4-percent growth in public spending over the same month.</p>
<p>&quot;The trade gap and the public deficit are key problems, but (the government) has either delayed the solution or sought it in some other way,&quot; Bajec said.</p>
<p>In a bid to reign in the trade deficit, Bajec proposed a special government agency to promote Yugoslav exports.</p>
<p>To ease fiscal deficit pressures, he suggested the government transfer some obligations into the 1997 budget. He also said the government should introduce new mechanisms for financing pensions and health insurance and watch money supply.</p>
<p>&quot;Monetary authorities had to be very careful with money supply growth,&quot; Bajec said, adding he did not see much space for aditional money supply until the end of 1996.</p>
<p>July M1 money supply rose to 4.34 billion dinars ($883 million) from four billion dinars at the end of June.</p>
<p>July industrial output fell 3.1 percent from June but was still unexpectedly 15.7-percent higher than year ago levels, said Miroljub Labus, a chief economoist at the institute.</p>
<p>&quot;The good results are due to (July's) 8.9-percent rise in energy production, particularly electricity, coal and oil products, but it was not accompanied by the same rise in other industrial sectors,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;January and July are the worst months for industrial output and having July more successful than expected gives reason for some optimistic forecasts on a further rise in industrial production,&quot; Bajec said. -- Gordana Filipovic, Belgrade newsroom, +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
