<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9172" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Gazprom rises to 2,891 rbls at auction.</title>
<headline>Gazprom rises to 2,891 rbls at auction.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A stake of 11.25 million shares in Russian gas monopoly RAO Gazprom was sold at auction on Thursday at an average 2,891 roubles a share, up from 2,871.2 roubles a week ago, the Federal Securities Corporation (FFK) said.</p>
<p>Then starting price at the regular auction was 2,728 roubles a share and the 30 lots sold for between 2,852 and 3,054 roubles a share, the FFK said in a statement.</p>
<p>The stake represented 0.047 percent of Gazprom's capital. The FFK said that since auctions began, 129.75 million shares, equivalent to 0.55 percent of Gazprom, have changed hands.</p>
<p>Gazprom, Russia's biggest company by market capitalisation, has massive reserves and potentially huge earnings. However, its 23.6 billion shares are highly illiquid and management permission is required to sell them.</p>
<p>The company has organised regular auctions of its shares to create an orderly market in the paper.</p>
<p>At the first auction on March 6, shares sold for an average 406.6 roubles each, and prices have been rising steadily since then, but the rise in price this week was much less than in previous auctions.</p>
<p>Vera Sevruk, manager of international sales at Alfa-Kapital, said the slowdown in the rise in price was more the result of the complexity of trading Gazprom than a perception that a ceiling had been reached.</p>
<p>&quot;The price will rise because obviously Gazprom is a very interesting share,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Gazprom stood at $0.540 on the Russian Trading System, down from $0.575 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I cannot say it is undervalued but it is definitely one of the most potentially interesting shares but people have to realise how to trade it again,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Sevruk said Gazprom recently tightened control over its shares, limiting permission to sell them.</p>
<p>Gazprom said in July it would issue its first American depositary receipts or Global Depositary Receipts, covering nine percent of its shares, in September or October.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems that they are trying to increase liquidity by the auction and the ADR issue but, at the same time, they do not want to leave the market to be self-regulating,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Thursday's auction, of shares belonging to investment companies, brought in 32.52 billion roubles.</p>
<p>The FFK said that at the next auction, on August 29, 10 million shares would be offered at a starting price of 2,746 roubles each.</p>
<p>-- Nigel Stephenson, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
