<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9178" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish PBG bank seeks more say in merger scheme.</title>
<headline>Polish PBG bank seeks more say in merger scheme.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's  Powszechny Bank Gospodarczy SA (PBG) has agreed to take part in the government scheme to consolidate four state-owned banks but is seeking more say in the planned group, PBG president said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We face consolidation...and everyone has adopted a clear opinion about that. But during negotiations there are differences because all sides want make sure their position is equal,&quot; Andrzej Szukalski told a news conference.</p>
<p>PBG group will be led by Pekao SA bank and will also include smaller  Bank Depozytowo-Kredytowy SA w Lublinie and  Pomorski Bank Kredytowy SA w Szczecinie.</p>
<p>The group is to be partially sold off and the government wants to allocate some of its shares to pension funds, to be created under a planned reform of the social security system.</p>
<p>Szukalski said the banks, which were negotiating terms of the consolidation agreement, still needed to hammer out details about their position in the group.</p>
<p>He said PBG opposed a plan to make all banking products uniform within the group.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not like this (the plan)...because in particular segments (of operation) there can be demand for various products,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The head of PBG board Ryszard Kokoszczynski, also present, said Pekao, the group's leader, should not dominate all aspects of management, although running the group needed to be centralised to be effective.</p>
<p>&quot;The consolidating bank does not need to dominate in all group's operations,&quot; Kokoszczynski said.</p>
<p>Szukalski also unveiled the bank's audited financial report for 1995, which showed PBG netted 50.7 million zlotys, compared with 88.7 million zlotys in 1994. The gross profit was 115.8 million zlotys and 109.9 million zlotys respectively.</p>
<p>In the first six months of 1996, the bank's gross profit was 85.3 million zlotys and net profit was estimated at 72 million zlotys.</p>
<p>Szukalski said PBG expected to have a 140 million zloty gross profit this year.</p>
<p>-- Jacek Ramotowski +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
