<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9181" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian lev ends softer at 198.80/199.00 per dlr.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian lev ends softer at 198.80/199.00 per dlr.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bulgarian lev closed at 198.80-199.00 per dollar, a touch softer than the 198.50 at mid-morning and in a narrower spread than the 197.80-199.40 at the opening of the interbank market, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The lev consolidated in a narrow range as dollar demand, which was moderate and came mainly from clients, was matched by supply,&quot; a bank dealer said, adding that no large final clients were detected in the market today.</p>
<p>Traders said the central bank bought and sold dollars today either directly or through several selected commercial banks.</p>
<p>Traders said they expected the lev to trade stable on Friday but an underlying downward trend for the national currency would pressure it in the months ahead despite central bank restrictions.</p>
<p>It was foreign currency demand from big importers and not speculative pressure from banks that pushed the lev down, said another dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;Any new monetary curbs could just slow down the lev's fall but not reverse it because forex reserves are low but the country could not go without wheat and energy imports,&quot; said the second dealer. -- Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 981 8569</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
