<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9182" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: Estonian share volumes stay at lower levels.</title>
<headline>Estonian share volumes stay at lower levels.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share trade in the Baltic state of Estonia remained subdued on Thursday, with only Forexbank and Hansabank standing out with active trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>Overall market turnover was 3.44 million kroons, compared with yesterday's 4.57 million kroons. The Tallinn stock exchange index dipped 0.35 percent to 95.69.</p>
<p>Forexbank slipped to 77 kroons from 77.20 kroons as it made trade of 1.18 million kroons.</p>
<p>Hansabank was active on business of 1.04 million kroons and its shares were slightly higher at 92.20 kroons versus 92.0.</p>
<p>Dealers said they saw little corporate news on the horizon that would provide an impetus to trade but were keeping their eyes on Savings Bank and its progress in merging with smaller bank, the Bank of Industry.</p>
<p>Savings Bank stock was little traded, turning over just 254,635 kroons with a closing price of 34.95 kroons, versus 35.25 kroons.</p>
<p>On the free market, Norma plastics was again active on trade of 793,000 kroons and closing slightly higher at 20.70 kroons, up from 20.35 kroons.</p>
<p>Overall free market turnover was 1.24 million kroons.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
