<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9183" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria may import 150,000 T wheat from EU.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria may import 150,000 T wheat from EU.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria hopes to negotiate an import deal for 150,000 tonnes of wheat with the European Union next week, agriculture minister Krastyo Trendafilov said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan to negotiate with the EU deliveries of 150,000 tonnes of grain and we hope to agree on preferential conditions during the visit of EU representatives to Sofia on August 26-17,&quot; Trendafilov told reporters.</p>
<p>Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler said in Sofia last month the EU was prepared to help Bulgaria but first needed to analyse the country's agricultural problems and estimate opportunities for investment credits.</p>
<p>Bulgaria, already battling an acute grain shortage due to excessive exports last year, faces a poor harvest this year and will have to import large quantities of wheat.</p>
<p>The agriculture ministry has said it expected to buy 1.2 million tonnes of wheat from local producers, although the country needs 1.6 million tonnes a year for domestic human consumption.</p>
<p>So far 415,000 tonnes of wheat have been purchased from local producers, said Trendafilov.</p>
<p>Bulgaria expects to import around 100,000 tonnes of grain under the U.S. Export Credit Guarantee Program (GSM-102).</p>
<p>Trendafilov rejected trade minister's Atanas Paparizov's statement on Wednesday that Bulgaria planned to apply for funds to meet grain import payments from an IMF facility extended to countries with short-term balance of payments problems.</p>
<p>&quot;My pledge to the cabinet is not to burden further the country's balance of payments,&quot; said Trendafilov. -- Roumiana Tikholova, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
