<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9184" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovaks say seeks larger Chemlon stake.</title>
<headline>Slovaks say seeks larger Chemlon stake.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Slovak economics minstry on Thursday said French chemical group Rhone-Poulenc is interested in acquiring 100 percent of leading plastic fibre producer Chemlon Humenne a.s..</p>
<p>&quot;Our ministry has held talks with top representatives of Rhone-Poulenc Slovakia Holding N.V., and the French firm said it had eminent interest in purchasing the state's stake in Chemlon,&quot; Jaroslav Novotny, head of the ministry's chemical and pharmaceutical department told Reuters.</p>
<p>He added that the French company has yet to present a concrete bid for the stake.</p>
<p>Rhone-Poulenc already holds a 56.8 percent stake in the Slovak firm through its subsidiary Rhone-Poulenc Slovakia Holding N.V. The remaining Chemlon shares are still state-owned.</p>
<p>Company officials were not immediately available for comment, but the official Slovak news agency TASR earlier on Thursday quoted Chemlon Director Michal Halko as saying that he expected talks (on selling the state's stake) to be completed &quot;by the end of this year&quot;.</p>
<p>Chemlon was originally included in the government list of strategic companies which would not be privatised at all, or in which the state would retain veto right over key decisions.</p>
<p>Novotny said the eventual selloff of the state's stake in Chemlon would require changes to the law on strategic companies.</p>
<p>He added it was premature to talk about possible ways of maintaining state interests in Chemlon.</p>
<p>In the past, the economics ministry has concluded agreements with owners of the privatised property to ensure the state maintains it veto right.</p>
<p>Last year Chemlon was the country's 19th largest industrial company in term of revenues, with sales totalling around 4.5 billion crowns.</p>
<p>The company, which has an annual production capacity of 60,000 tonnes of plastic fibres, plans to increase its sales to around five billion crowns, of which some 4.5 billion crowns should be derived from exports.</p>
<p>-- Peter Laca, Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
