<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9186" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary forint eases vs dlr on BUBA rate cut.</title>
<headline>Hungary forint eases vs dlr on BUBA rate cut.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's forint closed lower against the dollar reflecting the U.S. currency's rally against the mark after the Bundesbank cut its repo rate, dealers said.</p>
<p>The forint finished at 151.48/53 to the dollar, compared with 151.12/22 at the opening and 151.07/12 at the end of the morning session. The Hungarian unit bottomed at 151.57/62 when the afternoon session began following the Bundesbank repo cut which came during the break.</p>
<p>&quot;We remained at the central bank's resistance level. The forint was influenced by the dollar/mark,&quot; Altalanos Ertekforgalmi Bank's Agnes Nagy said.  </p>
<p>The forint floats within the National Bank of Hungary's 4.5 percent intervention range, against a currency basket made up 30 percent of the dollar and 70 percent of the Ecu.</p>
<p>Trade was slow as the market awaited news from Germany in the morning and a correction in the dollar/mark in the afternoon, Nagy said.</p>
<p>The Ecu was the most active currency in futures deals on the Budapest Commodity Exchange, which are traded on one single morning session. Mark and the Ecu futures closed mixed, while the dollar eased for two maturities.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom (36 1) 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
