<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9188" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Bucharest stocks up in thin volumes.</title>
<headline>Bucharest stocks up in thin volumes.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most Bucharest share prices posted gains on Thursday but trading, dominated by retail investors, was modest in volume, brokers said.</p>
<p>Overall turnover dropped by almost 30 million lei to 68.5 million, with the total number of shares traded slipping to 12,575 from 14,075.</p>
<p>Seven stocks rose, four fell, one was flat and one had no trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices extended recent gains on the back of half-year reports which for most stocks are healthy,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Buying activity focused on state fertiliser maker Azomures SA  -- which had 26.9 million lei in turnover -- and on Artrom SA  state engineering company -- which accounted for 22 percent of overall turnover.</p>
<p>&quot;Azomures touched a high 13,100 lei in early trading in a deal involving a larger share package but with no interest at that price its quote dropped afterwards,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Azomures ended at 12,100 lei, 200 lei down from Tuesday's close. Artrom also fell, closing 100 lei weaker at 2,550.</p>
<p>The session's biggest gainer was syringe maker Sanevit SA SNVT.BX, the exchange's sole private company, which gained 1,700 lei closing at 14,200.</p>
<p>The Bursa de Valori Bucuresti said on Thursday it was cutting pre-market trading to half an hour from two hours starting next Tuesday, extending the continuous trading session by an hour and a half to three and a half hours. Brokers welcomed the move saying it meant more time for deals.</p>
<p>The unofficial VAB Index -- a value-weighted index of all stocks computed by  Vanguard SA securities -- was 2.3 percent up from the previous session, closing at 371 points. Its base was 1,000 points when it was created last November.</p>
<p>	    Aug 22   Aug 20   Week's change  1996 high  1996 low</p>
<p>VAB-Index 371.0    362.8	+12.77	  879.29     297.12</p>
<p>($=3,157 lei) -- Luli Popescu, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
