<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9191" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Bosnian opposition harassed despite police pledges.</title>
<headline>Bosnian opposition harassed despite police pledges.</headline>
<byline>Sabina Cosic</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations said on Thursday local police in northwestern Bosnia are failing to stop violence against opposition voters despite pledges to support free and fair elections, scheduled for September 14.</p>
<p>The intimidation suffered by people affiliated with opposition parties may leave them too frightened of reprisals to vote in the country-wide elections, the U.N. said.</p>
<p>Spokesman Alex Ivanko told reporters in Sarajevo: &quot;It seems that some people don't know better and we're still continuing to get reports...of continued violence against supporters of opposition parties.&quot;</p>
<p>Three explosions damaged houses of supporters of political parties opposed to the ruling Moslem nationalist SDA party in the town of Cazin, in the northwestern Bihac area of the Moslem-Croat federation, Ivanko said.</p>
<p>The authorities of the Moslem-controlled Bihac region have been scolded by the U.N. consistently in recent weeks for attacks on opposition voters, often using explosive devices.</p>
<p>Active harassment and intimidation of the political opposition in the area began in June when an SDA loyalist struck Bosnia's former prime minister Haris Silajdzic on the head with an iron pipe.</p>
<p>Silajdzic is now the chief rival to Bosnian President and SDA chief Alija Izetbegovic. One of the houses damaged in Wednesday's blasts belonged to a supporter of Silajdzic's Party for Bosnia, Ivanko said.</p>
<p>U.N. monitors recently received a letter from a local opposition party accusing nine police officers and eight SDA supporters of intimidation.</p>
<p>Last week U.N. police Commissioner Peter Fitzerald won assurances from top Moslem-Croat and Serb police officials that they would instruct their forces to support free and fair elections.</p>
<p>Exasperated by security promises constantly being broken, Ivanko said it was &quot;disheartening to see that statements and agreements made at the level of ministers of interior...for some reason do not materialise at the local level.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems that the situation is not getting better, it's getting worse,&quot; he said. &quot;It's very tense in Cazin and the local police are not doing anything...to try to change the situation.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman for the international community's High Representative to Bosnia said Carl Bildt was considering a trip to Cazin to inspect the abuses.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
