<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9192" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian stocks mixed, traders expect rise.</title>
<headline>Croatian stocks mixed, traders expect rise.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks were mixed on Thursday and brokers predicted general rise of prices as market becomes more lively in the next weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;I think all prices will keep rising mildly as the activities pick up in the following week,&quot; one trader told Reuters.</p>
<p>* Of seven active issues three rose, two were flat, one was down and one traded for the first time.</p>
<p>* Most actively traded food processor Podravka gained 15 kuna to 230 on volume of 3,056 shares.</p>
<p>* Fully listed Zagrebacka banka was up 20 kuna to 690 with 670 shares changing hands.</p>
<p>* Brewery Karlovacka Pivovara edged up two kuna to 180 selling 126 units.</p>
<p>* Both hoteliers which traded today were flat.</p>
<p>- Arenaturist traded 955 shares at 100 kuna.</p>
<p>- Laguna Porec sold 30 shares at 800 kuna.</p>
<p>raded for the first time and sold 33 shares at 442.6 kuna.</p>
<p>* The only loser, drugs firms Pliva, was down 250 kuna at 11,100 kuna, but only 32 shares were sold.</p>
<p>* Public debt refinancing bonds were down at 14.5 percent above par on total turnover of under 8 million kuna. They were of August.</p>
<p>* Daily turnover down at 10.1 million kuna, volume also lower at 4,340 shares.</p>
<p>* Central Bank's exchange rate: 5.2556 = $ 1. -- Metka Jelenc, Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
