<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9199" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Zloty flat vs basket despite mark fall, depos down.</title>
<headline>Zloty flat vs basket despite mark fall, depos down.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish zloty finished today's light session nearly flat from Wednesday with wide spreads in reaction to volatile dollar/mark swings in Europan trade.</p>
<p>The zloty gained more than half a pfennig to the mark and lost nearly a cent versus the dollar after the German unit tubled following the Bundesbank's deep repo rate cut.</p>
<p>&quot;The market did not have its own trend, it just adjusted to dollar/mark swings after Buba slashed the German repo rate,&quot; said Marcin Stefaniuk from BDK SA.</p>
<p>The zloty closed at 1.83/1.67 percent from the trading band centre, virtually flat from Wednesday's 1.81/1.78 percent.  </p>
<p>The zloty closed at 2.7420/60 per dollar, down from 2.7335/65 at 0700 GMT and Wednesday's close at 2.7330/40.</p>
<p>It was at 1.8330/85 to the mark, up from against opening's 1.8425/40 and Wednesday's 1.8425/30.</p>
<p>Interbank deposits rates fell on increased liquidity as monthly tax payments ended and the central bank again refrained from draining the market through short-term reserve-repos and opted for longer-term outright fixed bond sales instead.</p>
<p>&quot;Outright sales do not clear all excess cash from the market and with no short-term drainages available, rates are easing,&quot; said Pawel Kowalski from Creditanstalt SA.  </p>
<p>Overnight rates were quoted at 15.0/17.0 percent, down from 17.4/18.1 at 0645 GMT, and tomorrow/next rates were at 12.0/16.8 percent, down from 17.70/18.35 percent.</p>
<p>At today's outright fixed bond sale the National Bank of Poland sold 83 million zloty of the bonds after banks bid for 151 million zlotys of the paper.</p>
<p>The minimum price of the 17-percent two-year bonds inched up 0.05 point to 99.19 from Wednesday's outright and the average price rose 0.02 point to 99.22.</p>
<p>The minimum price for the 14-percent five-year paper rose 0.05 point to 90.04 and the average price fell 0.05 to 90.04.  </p>
<p>Investors bid for 757 million zlotys of 16-percent two-year bonds and for 295 million zlotys of 12-percent five-year bonds at the Treasury's joint 800 million zloty tender.</p>
<p>-- Krzysztof Wojcik +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
