<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9200" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: War sees Chechens return to land of Soviet exile.</title>
<headline>War sees Chechens return to land of Soviet exile.</headline>
<byline>Chris Bird</byline>
<dateline>ALMATY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chechens are returning east to Central Asia to escape fighting in the breakaway republic more than 50 years after Soviet dictator Joseph Stalin exiled them to the frozen Kazakh steppe in cattle wagons.</p>
<p>Drawn with exhaustion, 26-year-old Khavash Isayev sat on the edge of a sofa in a basement flat in the Kazakh capital Almaty, the office of a Chechen-owned trading company, as he recounted his escape from Grozny 10 days ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The fighting was the worst I'd ever experienced. Planes bombed us at night and we couldn't walk the streets in daylight for fear of being shot,&quot; said Isayev.</p>
<p>He decided to try and make for Almaty where he had an uncle.</p>
<p>Stalin deported the Chechens en masse in the bitter winter of 1944 for supposed &quot;collaboration&quot; with German invaders.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands died of hunger and cold on the way. Bodies, tossed from unheated railcars, littered the steppe.</p>
<p>Nikita Khruschev allowed them to return to Chechnya in 1957. Around 80,000 remain in Kazakhstan.</p>
<p>Isayev said he ran a gauntlet of Russian checkpoints -- few young Chechen men leave Chechnya for fear of being interned in Russian camps camps -- and waited at an airport in southern Russia, for a flight to Almaty.</p>
<p>&quot;They (airport guards) made me undress in front of everyone, they took my money and were then going to arrest me,&quot; Isayev said. &quot;The women (Chechen refugees) started crying, they gave the guards their ear-rings and necklaces and I was freed.&quot;</p>
<p>His flat in Grozny destroyed, Isayev does not know where the rest of his family are or what he will do next.</p>
<p>The United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) in Almaty estimates around 6,000 Chechens have fled to Kazakhstan since the start of the conflict.</p>
<p>The Chechen-Ingush Cultural Association in Almaty puts the number of refugees at around 10,000.</p>
<p>The Chechen owner of the trading company, Vakha Saltabayev, had been torn away from his business the last few days trying to find food and shelter for the refugees starting to trickle in.</p>
<p>&quot;Some refugees who came after the fighting in 1995 returned to Chechnya. But they are starting to come back again,&quot; said Saltabayev.</p>
<p>Anatoly Puzhai, the UNHCR representative in Kazakhstan, says his organisation provides some basic aid to &quot;vulnerable groups&quot; among the Chechen refugees but said most have to rely on relatives or fend for themselves.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing is provided by the Kazakh government for the refugees,&quot; Puzhai said.</p>
<p>Two days after the last separatist attack on Grozny on August 6, Albeka Adirkhanova, 38, wanted to get her nine-year-old daughter out of the city.</p>
<p>&quot;The bombing, the corpses, it was terrible. I didn't want my daughter to see this,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She said Russian troops stopped the bus she and other refugees had escaped in and demanded money. Unable to pay and her documents destroyed in her gutted apartment in central Grozny, she said she was forced off the bus and told to walk.</p>
<p>She took a train to Kyrgyzstan, where she was born in exile, but was told to move on, ending up in Almaty where she and her daughter are staying with Saltabayev and four other refugees.</p>
<p>Adirkhanova's brother was killed in the recent fighting, her husband has been missing since January last year and she said she had no idea where her relatives were.</p>
<p>Adirkhanova was composed as she told of her escape. But tears welled up in her eyes when she recalled a conversation she overheard on a bus in Almaty on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;They were talking about a bank robbery and someone said 'it was the Chechens',&quot; she said. &quot;We are blamed for everything but we are not bad people. We live cleanly,&quot; Adirkhanova said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
