<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9201" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary delays energy price hike - spokesman.</title>
<headline>Hungary delays energy price hike - spokesman.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Hungarian government has postponed until January 1, 1997 an energy price rise previously announced for October 1, a government official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The cabinet could not accept the results of the study on which it would have based the price rise,&quot; government spokesman Elemer Kiss told a news conference following Thursday's regular cabinet meeting.</p>
<p>Kiss declined to reveal figures about the amount of any proposed increase, but press reports said that the National Energy Office had proposed a 40 percent energy rise.  </p>
<p>A government official will review the study, Kiss added.</p>
<p>He said the January date still meets a deadline stipulated in the energy law, by which time companies which bought stakes in formerly state-owned regional distribution companies are guaranteed an eight percent profit margin.</p>
<p>The rejected study was done by the Industry and Trade Ministry whose minister Imre Dunai resigned last week, quoting health problems.</p>
<p>On the day of his resignation Hungarian radio said Dunai, an independent named to the post by Horn's Socialist Party, may have wanted a bigger hike than the government thought would be acceptable to the general public.  </p>
<p>Last December Hungary sold stakes in the six regional electricity distribution companies and two power stations to such western giants as RWE of Germany and Electricite de France (EDF).</p>
<p>The government is bound by a decree passed in 1995 to introduce market prices at the start of next year. The prices, calculated using a complex formula, are supposed to guarantee the investors an eight percent profit.</p>
<p>-- Denes Albert, Budapest newsroom ++ 36 1 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
