<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9202" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia's Sibneft plans 500 billion rouble bond.</title>
<headline>Russia's Sibneft plans 500 billion rouble bond.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian oil company  OAO Sibirskaya Neftyanaya Kompaniya (Sibneft) said on Thursday it planned to issue a 500 billion rouble two-year bond paying annula interest of 18 percent.</p>
<p>A Sibneft statement said the company's board had decided to propose the issue to a shareholder's meeting likely to be held in September.  </p>
<p>Bondholders will have two options during the term of the bond to swap it for crude oil from Sibneft. Terms of the conversion were not yet available.</p>
<p>The bond is open to both foreign and domestic investors.</p>
<p>Denominations will be five million, 25 million and 50 million roubles, and interest would be paid once a year.</p>
<p>Sibneft is one of a dozen vertically integrated Russian oil groups. Its main operating unit is AO Noyabrskneftegaz NYGS.RTS.</p>
<p>The privatisation authorities are auctioning 34 percent of Sibneft over the next few months in two investment tenders, in which they are seeking investment of more than $77 million.</p>
<p>The Federal Property Fund plans to tender a stake of 19 percent of the company next month, with the winner announced on September 20, and a second stake of 15 percent will be tendered separately.</p>
<p>Foreign ownership in Sibneft is restricted to 15 percent of the capital. The previously unknown ZAO Neftyanaya Kompaniya and Stolichny Bank Sberezhenii won control of a 51 percent stake in Sibneft at the end of last year under the government's shares-for-loans scheme, in a bid backed by Bank Menatep.</p>
<p>--Olga Popova, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
