<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9206" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Rouble dips after T-bill auctions, o/n rates high.</title>
<headline>Rouble dips after T-bill auctions, o/n rates high.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW</dateline>
<text>
<p>The rouble eased on Thursday as demand for funds ebbed following Wednesday's Treasury bill auctions but dealers said overnight credit rates remained relatively high on lower supply from some banks.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar has risen as it always does on Thursdays, with overnight rates usually falling on lower rouble demand (after the T-bill auctions),&quot; United Investment Bank chief dealer Alexander Suchkov said.</p>
<p>&quot;But today credit rates may be quite high because the banks which usually offer roubles on the credit market preferred today to convert them to dollars and rouble supply has become narrower,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Overnight rouble credits yielded 45-60 percent compared with the same in early trading and Wednesday's late 30-45 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Overnight rates are relatively high but they are not moving... Trading is otherwise active both thanks to arbitrage and client operations,&quot; an Interbank Finance house dealer said.</p>
<p>He added the rouble had found brief support earlier on client dollar selling.</p>
<p>Roubles for today settlement were quoted at 5,319-22 per dollar compared with an early 5,316-19 and 5,310-13 late on Wednesday. Tomorrow roubles edged down to 5,322-25 per dollar from yesterday's late 5,317-20.</p>
<p>The central bank said it had set 5,291-5,331 as its bid and offer rates against the dollar on Thursday.</p>
<p>--Artyom Danielyan, Moscow newsroom (095) 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
