<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9212" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: BA-GiroCredit rates Danubius long-term buy. [CORRECTED 14:30 GMT]</title>
<headline>BA-GiroCredit rates Danubius long-term buy. [CORRECTED 14:30 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>An analyst report by Bank Austria-GiroCredit Budapest said that as a result of better-than-expected first half figures, it recommended shares in Danubius Hotels as a &quot;long-term buy&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on the (first half year) results... we maintain our long-term buy recommendation on the stock,&quot; analyst Antony Vago said.</p>
<p>Danubius, which released its first half results two weeks ago, said it boosted its consolidated net profits to 1.30 billion forints from 839.8 million in the same period of 1995.</p>
<p>Vago said he had revised the net profit figure for 1996 upwards to 2,039.7 million forints.</p>
<p>With respect to the Danubius's widely reported bid for the Hungaria Szalloda (formerly HungarHotels) hotel chain, the report suggested that if the company won the tender and financed it using a capital increase, the earnings per share (EPS) would increase to 284.9 (corrects from 316.3) forints, whereas if the deal were financed with debt the EPS could fall to 244.3 forints.</p>
<p>The Budapest daily Nepszabadsag reported on Thursday that State Privatisation Agency APV had declared Danubius the winner of the privatisation tender for Hungaria Szalloda at its meeting on Wednesday.</p>
<p>According to Nepszabadsag, Danubius submitted the highest bid, offering more than eight billion forints for the chain which has 14 hotels.</p>
<p>The Budapest Stock Exchange (BSE) on Thursday suspended trading in Danubius shares on the strength of the report.</p>
<p>APV is expected to make an announcement on the sale later on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- Duncan Shiels, Budapest newsroom +361 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
