<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9213" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Jailed Albanian Socialist renews release efforts.</title>
<headline>Jailed Albanian Socialist renews release efforts.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A lawyer representing jailed Albanian opposition leader Fatos Nano has contacted the European Court of Human Rights in an effort to ensure Nano's release, a newspaper reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>Koha Jone quoted Nano's lawyer Perparim Sanxhaku as saying he had approached the Strasbourg court where he planned to launch an appeal against the Socialist leader's prison sentence.</p>
<p>&quot;We had direct contacts with the Strasbourg court concerning Fatos Nano's release from prison,&quot; Sanxhaku said.</p>
<p>Albania's parliament last month ratified the European Convention on Human Rights, from which the court draws its authority.</p>
<p>Nano, 43, was arrested in 1993 and jailed for 12 years in 1994 on charges of embezzlement during his brief stint as prime minister in 1991.</p>
<p>President Sali Berisha has resisted international calls for Nano's release from the high-security Benca jail in a remote part of southern Albania.</p>
<p>Socialist leaders have accused Berisha of perverting the course of justice in order to sideline Nano, his main political rival.</p>
<p>&quot;The party cannot appeal to Strasbourg because Nano has to do that personally. His release remains one of the party's main aims, however,&quot; Socialist party spokesman Kastriot Islami told Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
