<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9220" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatia-Serbia normalisation treaty set for Friday.</title>
<headline>Croatia-Serbia normalisation treaty set for Friday.</headline>
<byline>Mark Heinrich</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatia said on Thursday it expected to sign a landmark normalisation treaty with Serbian-led Yugoslavia on Friday, dispelling concern that the deal might be delayed.</p>
<p>Last-minute talks this week on the legal fine print of the pact to end five years of hostility after Croatia's secession from federal Yugoslavia had been troublesome, officials of both sides reported.</p>
<p>But Croatian state radio, announcing Foreign Minister Mate Granic would go to Belgrade on Friday. signalled the deal would be signed on August 23 as envisaged by the presidents of Croatia and Serbia, the main republic in rump Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>&quot;It is expected that the agreement on normalisation of relations between the republics of Croatia and Yugoslavia will be signed,&quot; the Foreign Ministry said in a brief statement read on the radio's 0700 GMT news bulletin.</p>
<p>Presidents Slobodan Milosevic of Serbia and Franjo Tudjman of Croatia agreed at a surprise meeting in Athens earlier this month to have their foreign ministers sign a mutual recognition accord on August 23.</p>
<p>Experts negotiating the treaty text have have been trying to resolve issues including a stubborn territorial dispute over the Prevlaka peninsula on the Adriatic coast, the legal succession to old Yugoslavia, war damages and protection for Serb refugees trying to return to Croatia.</p>
<p>The main state-run Croatian newspaper Vjesnik said on Thursday three days of talks this week apparently yielded &quot;understanding&quot; on sticking points from Prevlaka to a war amnesty for former rebel Serbs in Croatia.</p>
<p>&quot;Precisely what kind of agreement was reached could not be learned since the Yugoslav side demanded absolute secrecy,&quot; said Vjesnik, which reflects official Croatian policy.</p>
<p>&quot;During the talks there was a strong possibility that the two sides would not be able to reach a level of understanding that would be enough for Granic to travel to Belgrade on Friday,&quot; the Zagreb daily added.</p>
<p>But it said this week's talks had cleared the way for a treaty based on mutual recognition within internationally recognised borders and establishment of diplomatic relations.</p>
<p>Some legally intricate issues which some analysts had said might scuttle the August 23 signing, such as rights to the assets of old socialist federal Yugoslavia, would probably be resolved at a later date.</p>
<p>Western powers regard diplomatic normalisation between Croatia and Serbia, the twin pillars of old multinational federal Yugoslavia, as perhaps the most crucial step towards a lasting peace in the Balkans.</p>
<p>War broke out in 1991 after Croatia declared independence to escape creeping domination by Milosevic-led nationalist Serbs in the Balkan federation. Fighting spread to Bosnia when its Moslem-led government broke away in 1992.</p>
<p>Rebel minority Serbs armed by Milosevic seized almost a third of Croatia in the 1991 war but lost almost all of it to a Croatian government army counter-offensive over U.N. truce lines a year ago.</p>
<p>Eastern Slavonia, the last Serb-held enclave in Croatia, is to revert to Croatian government rule next year after a transitional period under U.N. administration.</p>
<p>By signing a normalisation treaty with Zagreb, Belgrade would definitively renounce its claim to oil-rich Eastern Slavonia which abuts the Danube River border with Yugoslavia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
