<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9229" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria's Balkan Airlines losses deepen in H1 96.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria's Balkan Airlines losses deepen in H1 96.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's state-run Balkan Airlines slipped deeper into the red in the first six months of 1996, a Transport Ministry official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>She said Balkan had losses of about 1.8 billion levs for the first six months of the year, which exceeds losses in the first half of 1995 by 650 million levs.</p>
<p>The drastic weakening of the Bulgarian lev, which lost 80 percent of its value against the dollar earlier this year, is the main reason for the airline's losses, Deputy Transport Minister Svetla Toshkova told the Troud daily newspaper.</p>
<p>Toshkova was not immediately available to give further details.</p>
<p>The Balkan Airline is among 70 indebted state companies due to be isolated from credits while they are restructured under a government austerity programme agreed with the International Monetary Fund (IMF).</p>
<p>Balkan's debts are estimated at $13.4 million and will increase to $15 million this year, ministry officials said, adding that the company would try to reschedule its debts.</p>
<p>Last year the national carrier incurred losses under leasing contracts signed between 1990 and 1992 with Japanese leasing firm Orix Corp, Australia's Ansett and Air France. Two of the airline's three leased Airbuses were detained last year for unpaid rent.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's air traffic controllers threatened to launch a strike by the end of this month demanding an increase in their monthly wages to $1,200 from a current level of up to $546.</p>
<p>The transport ministry said negotiations were under way.</p>
<p>-- Liliana Semerdjieva, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
