<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9235" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Belgrade press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>POLITIKA</p>
<p>- Federal government submits to Yugoslav parliament its report on the normalisation of relations with the IMF and other international financial organisations.</p>
<p>- Serbian local elections scheduled for November 3, the same day as federal elections and republican and local elections in Montenegro.</p>
<p>- Belgrade Zmaj factory concludes $9.2 million deal with Chinese firm Haifa for the sale of agricultural machines.</p>
<p>- Yugoslav government to sign a number of Yugoslav-Macedonian agreements which will promote bilateral economic cooperation. Prime Minister Radoje Kontic to visit Macedonia early in September to sign the deals.</p>
<p>- Federal government is drafting a bill on foreign currency savings blocked since 1991 to try to find a way to settle the 6.5 million German mark internal debt.</p>
<p>- Teachers agree to start school year regularly on Sept 1 if their June wages are paid by that date.</p>
<p>- Deputy Speaker of the lower house of the Yugoslav Parliament Radmilo Bogdanovic expects ethnic Albanians to participate in this year's parliamentary elections.</p>
<p>NASA BORBA</p>
<p>- Seven thousand workers of the Kragujevac Zastava weapons factory protest in front of the municipal building demanding outstanding wages.</p>
<p>- U.N. Administrator in Eastern Slavonia Jacques Klein says another year needed to complete peaceful reintegration in the area.</p>
<p>- Representatives of Panturist from Osijek and Lasta from Belgrade plan to open direct bus line between Belgrade and Zagreb by the beginning of autumn.</p>
<p>POLITKA EKSPRES</p>
<p>- So far 35 parties signed the agreement on media representation for the forthcoming elections. The deadline for its signing is October 6.</p>
<p>- Domestic banks again facing solvency problems and shortage of dinars.</p>
<p>BORBA</p>
<p>- Deputy Speaker of the Lower House of the Yugoslav Parliament Radmilo Bogdanovic says in an interview it is time for ehtnic-Albanians in Kosovo to ask for talks but not in the presence of a third party.</p>
<p>-- Belgrade newsroom 381 11 +2224305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
