<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9236" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>CAPITAL</p>
<p>- State Ownership Fund has privatised total 2,210 state companies so far</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Troubled  Banca Dacia Felix SA sold its Chisinau branch for $500,000 to  Victoria bank in Chisinau.</p>
<p>- Farmers will have to spend some 530,000 lei per hectare to sow wheat this autumn. Cost includes fertilisers and seeds. Agriculture Ministry expects government to grant allocations so per-hectare wheat sowing cost may go down.</p>
<p>AZI</p>
<p>- Area to go under wheat this autumn will extend on some 2.3 million hectares, Agriculture Ministry sources said.</p>
<p>- Romania plans to increase amount of processed crude oil output to some 18 million tonnes next year from around 14 million tonnes in 1995, Romanian Oil Company sources said.</p>
<p>ZIUA</p>
<p>- Government plans to import nuclear fuel for Cernavoda nuclear power plant although Romanian nuclear fuel, now in stock, is fit for utilisation.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- Distribition of shareholder's certificates under mass selloff scheme which goes slow due to summer holidays is expected to go beyond an end-August deadline.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Alexandru Oproiu, who allegedly supported Nicu Ceausescu, son of late dictator Nicolae Ceausescu, and sentenced to jail for killings in the December 1989 revolution, to be freed from prison on health grounds, and could take over the health ministry after Iulian Mincu resigned, says the newspaper.</p>
<p>- The big European rivers -- Danube, Dnepr, Don -- flowing through East European countries which have no environment protection laws, turned the Black Sea into Europe's garbage can, says the newspaper presenting excerpts from an international conference in Istanbul.</p>
<p>- Newspaper publishes excerpts from an interview with President Ion Iliescu in the French Figaro magazine saying he &quot;believes the values of communism are values impregnated with European humanism.&quot;</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- President Ion Iliescu and Foreign Minister Teodor Melescanu would present draft of Romanian-Hungarian treaty to parliamentary parties next week, said foreign ministry spokesman Sorin Ducaru.</p>
<p>- Opposition Democratic Convention (CDR) bloc can no longer win the November polls unless it nominates another candidate for presidency, said political analyst Silviu Brucan. He said the pro-monarchy statement by CDR presidential candidate, Emil Constantinescu, &quot;ruined his chance and affected the CDR&quot;.</p>
<p>- Gheorghe Funar, head of National Unity Party (PUNR) says scandal around Constantinescu's statement is a diversion to draw attention away from much more grave problems, like the Romanian-Hungarian treaty.</p>
<p>- Of the six percent of Romania's youngs who take drugs, 1.4 percent use marijuana and hashish, says public health care institute.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- The scandal on the pro-monarchist statement by Emil Constantinescu is a diversion, says the newspaper wondering why and how the interview published three weeks ago in an unknown Romanian-language magazine in the U.S. was published in Romanian media.</p>
<p>- Workers in the Renel electricty authority are obliged to sign lists of support for President Iliescu's candidacy for a new presidential term.</p>
<p>CRONICA ROMANA</p>
<p>- FBI manager Louis Freeh said he would open an office in Romania along with other offices in 23 capitals across the world to help crack down on terrorism, drug traffic and crime.</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Teodor Melescanu to be appointed Romania's envoy at the UN mission in Geneva after the November 3 polls, said sources close to the presidency.</p>
<p>JURNALUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- &quot;I am candidate for presidency so I can not be a monarchist&quot; says Emil Constantinescu in interview.</p>
<p>DIMINEATA</p>
<p>- National confederation of Romania's revolutionaries appeals to all political parties to withdraw their support for CDR leader Emil Constantinescu in the campaign for the November 3 polls due to his &quot;irresponsible&quot; statement on the monarchy. ($=3,157 lei) -- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
