<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9237" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the reports carried by Estonia's newspapers on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- President Lennart Meri received the 1996 Coudenhove-Calergi European Award as a recognition of his efforts for integrating independent Estonia into the EU.</p>
<p>- A luggage handler in Tallin Airport was killed by the spinning propeller of a Karair ATR-72 airliner on Wednesday.</p>
<p>SONUMILEHT</p>
<p>- Meri received a letter from French President Jacques Chirac on European security and amendments to the CFE treaty.</p>
<p>- Two notorious prisoners have provoked a protest action in the Parnu prison although the living conditions in the facility are the best in Estonia.</p>
<p>- Reform Party secretary general Heiki Kranich rejected claims that the party has banned Foreign Minister and party leader Siim Kallas from running for president.</p>
<p>EESTI PAEVALEHT</p>
<p>- The security police hope to destroy completely the so-called Kazan gang of organized criminals. Seven members have already been detained.</p>
<p>- The privatisation agency board re-elected Viino Sarnet for another five years as its director general.</p>
<p>- Assistant director of Criminal Police Koit Pikaro, reputedly one of the most competent investigators in Estonia, will receive a new and lower post as a result of his failure to report an illegal pistol shooting by his subordinates.</p>
<p>POSTIMEES</p>
<p>- Representatives of the Constantinople and Moscow orthodox churh patriarchs met in Tallinn to discuss the future of the two churches in Estonia.</p>
<p>- The Country People's Party has gathered the 21 signatures needed for putting Arnold Ruutel up as presidential candidate.</p>
<p>- The Development Party faction met President Lennart Meri, but has decided which way to vote in Monday's presidential election.</p>
<p>ARIPAEV</p>
<p>- The Social Bank financial office, which attempted to pay the bank's debts, will announce its bankruptcy tomorrow.</p>
<p>- Police will by 2.4 million kroons worth of new communications systems from Japanese firm ICOM.</p>
<p>- Privatisation Agency permitted Estonian Railway to form a joint venture with the German firm Hermann Koehne.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom  +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
