<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9239" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Croatian newspapers on Thursday.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- It now seems certain that Foreign Minister Mate Granic will pay a visit to Belgrade on Friday to sign the agreement on normalisation of relations between Croatia and Yugoslavia -- in last minute talks the two managed to resolve disputing issues.</p>
<p>- Military court in Serbia charges four Croats with spying.</p>
<p>- Some 117,421 Bosnians residing in Croatia will cast their ballots on August 31 and September 1, two weeks ahead of the Bosnian elections.</p>
<p>- State-owned firms from the Croatian Privatisation Fund portfolio in 1995 recorded a loss of 3 billion kuna, accounting for two thirds of total economy losses.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- There are no Croats in Yugoslavian prisons, says Pavle Todorovic, head of the Yugoslav delegation holding discussions with Croatia on detained and missing persons.</p>
<p>- Of 130,000 firms registered in the country, more than a half are trading companies.</p>
<p>- To encourage production in former Serb-held enclaves, state investment bank HBOR granted more than 600 loans worth 58 million kuna.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- Croatia Airlines will have regular flights to Sarajevo from August 26.</p>
<p>- German NATO soldiers, stationed on the Adriatic coast, are a good commercial for Croatian tourism. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
