<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9240" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in Latvian newspapers on Thursday. Prepared for Reuters by the Co-operation Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- Politicians, journalists and participants of the events of 1991 commemorated the fifth anniversary of the restoration of Latvia's independence.</p>
<p>- The parliament committee for foreign affairs asked parliament to delay ratifying the oil exploration agreement between Latvia and AMOCO. The appeal was joined by the ruling board of the Baltic Assembly. It came in response to a call by Lithuanian deputies to delay ratification until the Latvian-Lithuanian sea border is fixed.</p>
<p>- The governing factions believe that the coalition treaty draft, submitted by Prime Minister Andris Shkele, should be improved. They have created a working group which will sum up proposals by the factions on the coalition treaty.</p>
<p>DIENA</p>
<p>- Diena received an anonymous letter, supposedly from a former member of the OMON group which fought against Latvia's independence in 1990-1991. The letter contains threats to kill officers of the police and public prosecutor's office who are investigating the activities of the OMON.</p>
<p>NEATKARIGA RITA AVIZE</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Aivars Kreituss and Bank of Latvia president Einar Repshe object to the proposal of the parliamentary commission which investigated the Banka Baltija crisis to issue state bonds to the stricken bank's depositors.</p>
<p>- Lithuania will not reply to the Latvian memorandum of August 19 on the building of an oil terminal in Butinge.</p>
<p>BIZNESS &amp; BALTIYA</p>
<p>- Shareholders of the Latvian state-owned railway company discussed results of the first half of the year and the next year's draft budget.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
