<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9246" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: FEATURE - Baltic wolves have farmers, hunters howling.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Baltic wolves have farmers, hunters howling.</headline>
<byline>Ed Stoddard</byline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A surging wolf population in the Baltic states of Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania has farmers and hunters howling for the age-old predator's hide.</p>
<p>Once pushed to the brink of extinction, the wolf has successfully -- some would say savagely -- re-established itself in the region's vast forests.</p>
<p>&quot;We really have too many wolves now,&quot; said Jaak Tammpets, a senior conservation officer with the Estonian Environment Ministry.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to bring them under control before they kill too many wild boar and domestic animals,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The precise number of wolves is all but impossible to gauge, but Estonia and Lithuania, home to just a few dozen in the 1960s, are believed to have between 500 and 700 wolves each, while Latvia's population is put at close to 1,000.</p>
<p>By contrast, equally heavily forested Sweden has only around 40 wolves, while Norway lacks even a breeding population.</p>
<p>&quot;Outside of Russia, Latvia probably has the largest wolf population in all of Europe,&quot; said Ilona Lodzina, head of the nature protection division at the Latvian environmental protection ministry.</p>
<p>Baltic wolves were ruthlessly hunted with poison and traps during the Soviet era since the animal's fondness for venison was frowned upon by the Communist elite, whose penchant for big game hunting was widely ridiculed.</p>
<p>&quot;Bounties were placed on the wolf's head during the Soviet era because they eat roe deer and wild boar, animals which the nomenclature loved to hunt,&quot; said Albertas Stanislovaitis, head of the wildlife protection and hunting department at the Lithuanian Ministry of Forestry.</p>
<p>But even as they waged war on the wolf, the Soviet authorities inadvertently paved the way for the animal's remarkable come-back in the region, biologists say.</p>
<p>The commissars who ruled the Baltics with an iron fist provided the wolf and its prey with new habitats when they collectivised agriculture and deported hundreds of thousands of peasants to Siberia in the 1940s and 1950s.</p>
<p>Farms abandoned in the wake of the brutal forced migrations were eventually reclaimed by the surrounding wilderness.</p>
<p>The forests of Latvia and Estonia have almost doubled in size since World War Two to cover 42 percent and 50 percent of the countries' area repectively. Lithuania's have grown by 50 percent to cover almost 30 percent of the country.</p>
<p>Deer, moose and boar flourished in this spreading wilderness on the eastern rim of the Baltic sea. In Lithuania, wild boar soared from 3,800 to almost 20,000.</p>
<p>This plentiful supply of wild prey has in turn led to a sharp increase in the number of wolves, much to the chagrin of farmers and hunters and the delight of conservationists.</p>
<p>The wolf population has also been pushed up by &quot;migration&quot; from neighbouring Russia and Belarus, a fact not lost on the Baltic peoples, for whom it is an article of faith that nothing good comes from the East.</p>
<p>At least 30 cattle were killed by wolves in western Lithania in July this year, Stanislovaitis said.</p>
<p>&quot;The females teach their young to hunt at this time of the year and cattle are easy prey,&quot; he said, adding that an exceptionally harsh winter killed off many weak deer, so wolves were showing more of an appetite for easily caught beef.</p>
<p>&quot;We have organised hunting parties, but it's very hard to hunt wolves in the summer. It's much easier in winter, when they can be tracked,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Last winter, Lithuanian hunters bagged more than 90 wolves, while their Estonian counterparts tracked and shot more than 300.</p>
<p>Poisoning is outlawed under the Bern Convention, though local animal activists say they suspect some farmers still resort to the practice to protect their herds and flocks.</p>
<p>Conservationists say that the wolf, historically portrayed and persecuted as a bloodthirsty menace, gets little favourable press in the Baltics.</p>
<p>&quot;Public debate is now dominated by the hunters. Few people are defending wolves here,&quot; said Robert Oetjen of the Estonia Fund for Nature.</p>
<p>But farther afield, the wolves have their advocates.</p>
<p>&quot;The Baltic states are a natural treasure,&quot; said Ola Jennersten, conservation officer with the World Wide Fund for Nature in Sweden.</p>
<p>&quot;It's amazing. Animals that are rare or have vanished in the Nordic countries are common in the Baltics. The wolf is an example of this, and deserves protection.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BALTST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
