<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9248" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile report reveals new military regime deaths.</title>
<headline>Chile report reveals new military regime deaths.</headline>
<byline>Margaret Orgill</byline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Chilean human rights panel has uncovered a further 899 cases of people who died or disappeared during General Augusto Pinochet's rule, bringing the total to nearly 3,200, officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The report was the final step in a six-year investigation into political repression under the military regime which ruled Chile with an iron grip from 1973 to 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;The most serious result of the deep and painful conflicts experienced by Chilean society in recent years was...human rights violations,&quot; said board president Alejandro Poblete who presented the report to President Eduardo Frei.</p>
<p>The Reconciliation and Compensation Corporation said the new cases were in addition to the 2,298 victims named in an official 1990 investigation into human rights violations during Pinochet's government.</p>
<p>The new figures bring the number of victims of political repression to 3,197, of whom 2,095 are known to have died and 1,102 are officially classified as &quot;disappeared&quot; -- meaning no trace of them has been found since they were abducted.</p>
<p>Investigations into human rights violations have been a frequent source of friction between the country's civilian authorities and the powerful armed forces since Chile returned to democracy in 1990. Despite ceding power to civilians that year, Pinochet remains commander-in-chief of the army.</p>
<p>Interior Minster Carlos Figueroa said the government was looking into setting up a permanent body to defend human rights and would set up a special unit to take up the search for the bodies of people who have disappeared.</p>
<p>&quot;The families of human rights violation victims can be reassured that they will continue to be helped in their search for the truth about their loved ones,&quot; said Figueroa.</p>
<p>Most victims were left-wing opponents of Pinochet, many of whom were killed and tortured by the regime's feared security services.</p>
<p>An amnesty law dictated by the armed forces in 1978 has meant that few cases have been tried with only a handful of military officers behind bars for human rights crimes.</p>
<p>Pinochet, now 80, came to power in a bloody coup in September 1973 which overthrew Marxist President Salvador Allende.</p>
<p>The lower house of Congress last week voted to create a national holiday, Day of the Disappeared and Detained People, to be celebrated on August 30 to commemorate those who died during the Pinochet years. The bill's fate will be decided in the Senate, where majority pro-military rightists have said they oppose it.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
