<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9252" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chilean stocks end mixed, seen opening firmer.</title>
<headline>Chilean stocks end mixed, seen opening firmer.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chilean stocks ended mixed with investors encouraged by economic data showing a cooling in the economy's robust growth with the optimism expected to boost shares at Thursday's opening, said traders.</p>
<p>&quot;These figures are calming the market and allowing prices to rise,&quot; said Henry Rudnick, research director at brokerage CB Capitales.</p>
<p>The selective IPSA index closed up 0.23 percent at 98.22 points. The general IGPA index declined a scant 0.03 percent to 5,385.31 points. Turnover rose to 11 billion pesos, up two billion pesos on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Traders reported buying from pension funds and rising demand for Chilean stocks from foreign investors.</p>
<p>Figures from the National Chamber of Commerce showed retail sales growth slowing to 3.2 percent in July on a year ago from 4.9 percent recorded in June.</p>
<p>&quot;The sales figures show clearly that the adjustment is taking place,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The Central Bank has pursued a tight credit policy for nearly a year to slow the economy and has vowed not to ease rates until inflation has been brought firmly under control.  </p>
<p>But traders warned the data does not mark a permanent change of course for the bourse as high local interest rates continue to undermine turnover. Losers included brewery and soft drinks company CCU, which fell on foreign selling following poor first half results, said traders.</p>
<p>CCU has also been hurt by fears over the impact of financial woes of Argentine's Buenos Aires Embotelladora on the firms' joint venture to bottle Pepsi Cola in Chile, they said.</p>
<p>CCU's stock fell 4.73 percent to 1,610 pesos, while its American Depositary Receipts fell 2.4 percent to 20-3/8.  </p>
<p>Other decliners included telecoms company Telex, down 2.42 percent at 1,210 pesos, forestry firm Masisa, down 0.98 percent at 203 pesos and telephone carrier CTC, which lost 0.85 percent to 2,320 pesos.</p>
<p>Winners included pension fund manager Provida, up 2.72 percent at 9,450 pesos, drug-maker LabChile, up 1.57 percent at 325 pesos and power utility Enersis, which rose 0.98 percent at 256-1/2 pesos.</p>
<p>-- Margaret Orgill, Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595 x212</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
