<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9253" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian stocks end lower, led by cement stocks.</title>
<headline>Colombian stocks end lower, led by cement stocks.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian stocks ended lower as cement shares fell on profit-taking and concerns about this week's move by Mexico's Cemex to grab controlling interest in another Colombian cement manfacturer.</p>
<p>Medellin's IBOMED general price index dropped 0.95 percent to 13,149.30 on a lower-than-average volume of 660 million pesos. Bogota's IBB fell 0.47 percent, ending the day at 847.76.</p>
<p>Volume in Bogota, totalling 2.2 billion pesos, was inflated by a cross trade of 900 million pesos of shares in the Suramericana de Seguros insurance company, brokers said.  </p>
<p>Suramericana, part of the powerful Sindicato Antioqueno industrial group, closed unchanged at 18,000 pesos per share.</p>
<p>Banco Ganadero has posted steady gains over the last week in the run-up to next week's deal in which a 40 percent stake in the bank will be sold to Banco Bilbao Vizcaya of Spain. Its preferential shares dropped 2.22 percent in Thursday's trade, however, ending at 220 pesos a share.</p>
<p>Banco de Colombia slipped lower as well, ending down 1.14 percent at 430 pesos a share. But Banco de Bogota extended its previous day's gains, closing up 0.18 percent at 5,560 pesos per share.  </p>
<p>The day's biggest loser was Cementos Paz del Rio, which fell 8.75 percent to close at 800 pesos a share in Bogota. It was joined by Cementos Caribe, which shed 3.97 percent of its share value.</p>
<p>Some brokers attributed the drop to profit taking. But others pointed out Cemex's purchase of Industrias e Inversiones Samper earlier this week has put in a position to become a dominant player in the Colombian cement market.</p>
<p>Cemex, the world's third-largest cement company, had already purchased controlling interest in Cementos Diamante earlier this year. -- Javier Mozzo, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
