<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9256" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HAITI: Haiti television station attacked in latest violence.</title>
<headline>Haiti television station attacked in latest violence.</headline>
<byline>Nicole Volpe</byline>
<dateline>PORT-AU-PRINCE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Haiti's national television station was hit by gunshots on Thursday, the latest incident in a week of violence that has threatened Haiti's fragile stability.</p>
<p>U.N. spokesman Eric Falt said shots from small calibre weapons were fired early on Thursday morning at the offices of National Television of Haiti just outside the capital. No one was hurt.</p>
<p>Two political killings and an attack on a police station that killed one civilian have raised concerns this week that the tenuous order established by U.S. troops and a U.N. peacekeeping mission could be falling apart.</p>
<p>Equally disconcerting to those backing efforts to maintain democracy after years of repressive military rule were growing accusations from opposition politicians that the Haitian government was behind Tuesday's assassinations.</p>
<p>Pastor Antoine Leroy, a top official of the Mobilisation for National Democracy (MDN) party and MDN member Jacques Florival were killed outside of Florival's house on Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>Evans Paul, former mayor of Port-au-Prince and leader of the Opposition National Front for Democratic Change, called a news conference on Thursday and accused the Haitian government of plotting the assassinations.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear to everyone it was the Lavalas government that assassinated the two important men of the MDN,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Port-au-Prince Mayor Joseph Emmanuel Charlemagne, a Lavalas supporter and outspoken folk singer, said he believed the government was behind Monday's attack on a police station, in which a group of men wearing military fatigues fired automatic weapons and threw grenades, killing a nearby shoeshiner.</p>
<p>Charlemagne suggested the government had staged the attack to justify ongoing arrests of former members of the Haitian military.</p>
<p>Palace sources discounted the accusations and said Tuesday's assassinations may have been the result of MDN infighting.</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy spokeswoman Meg Gilroy said the U.S. &quot;deplored the criminal acts and we reaffirm our firm support for the democratically elected government.&quot;</p>
<p>U.N. special representative Enrique Ter Horst issued a statement late on Wednesday condemning the violent acts and calling for calm.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT-AU-PRINCE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HAITI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
