<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9263" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine bonds end flat, concerns around measures.</title>
<headline>Argentine bonds end flat, concerns around measures.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine bonds finished flat Thursday after another session spent worrying about the political will to push through measures aimed at reversing the widening budget deficit.</p>
<p>The 5.5 percent dollar-denominated Bocon Previsional 2 due 2001 was flat at 114.50. Argentina's FRB due 2005 rose 3/8  to 77.00.</p>
<p>Initially the market was unnerved by growing concerns that the economic measures, mainly including tax increases unveiled a couple of weeks ago, would not be passed in full by Congress.  </p>
<p>Government officials have been warning that delays in Congress in passing the measures could result in less savings than the $1.2 billion the package was seeking to make.</p>
<p>Still, Economy Minister Roque Fernandez said Thursday he will seek to cut $1.0 billion in spending by year's end. Market players have been hoping for actual expenditure cuts rather than increased revenue through tax hikes.</p>
<p>Despite all the market concerns surrounding the measures, a bond analyst with a large Argentine bank said &quot;in the end, these measures should help the fiscal front, which is good for bonds.&quot;</p>
<p>And, a trader predicted that &quot;the market will find a floor and stay there until the measures are passed.&quot;</p>
<p>In the money markets, one day call money was unchanged at 9.75 percent.</p>
<p>-- Axel Bugge, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 54 1 3180668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
