<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9265" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine unions said postponing strike vote.</title>
<headline>Argentine unions said postponing strike vote.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine unions, who were to meet Friday to vote on plans for a general strike in September, will postpone the meeting until the end of this month, a union spokesman said Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have agreed with our fellows from the (main union federation) CGT to suspend the Central Confederal Committee, which was due to meet tomorrow, for eight or nine days,&quot; bus drivers union leader Juan Palacios told the independent DyN news agency.  </p>
<p>Argentina's trade unionists consider the Central Confederal Committee a kind of &quot;workers parliament.&quot;</p>
<p>Palacios, whose union belongs to the hard-line splinter group MTA, said the CGT and the MTA would hold a joint news conference at 1900 local/2200 GMT.</p>
<p>He added the two sides, whose leaders first postponed a strike vote last Tuesday after a gunfight in which seven workers were injured, have since declared a truce and were now ready to discuss their plans to protest against the government's austerity measures.  </p>
<p>The daily Clarin said Thursday morning the CGT was now considering a 24-hour strike without demonstrations rather than the 36-hour walkout with worker mobilization it was contemplating before.</p>
<p>It quoted CGT spokesman Carlos West Ocampo as saying the change was due to security reasons after Tuesday's shootout.</p>
<p>-- David Haskel, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
