<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9268" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Cuba says U.S. diplomat circulated hostile literature.</title>
<headline>Cuba says U.S. diplomat circulated hostile literature.</headline>
<byline>Pascal Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Foreign Ministry, offering details of its decision to expel a U.S. diplomat, unveiled on Thursday what it called anti-government literature and publications she had distributed to Cuban dissident groups.</p>
<p>They included books from right-wing U.S. organisations such as Freedom House and the International Republican Institute with titles like &quot;Guide to resources for a transition in Cuba&quot; and &quot;How to organise a trade union meeting.&quot;</p>
<p>Also shown was a miniature paperback with a Spanish translation of British writer George Orwell's political satire &quot;Animal Farm,&quot; which attacks totalitarian ideology, and a work by an anti-communist Cuban exile, Carlos Franqui.</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry spokeswoman Marianela Ferriol said Robin Meyer, a second secretary at the U.S. Interests Section in Havana whose visa was revoked last week, &quot;gave advice to and organised&quot; groups opposed to Cuba's one-party communist government.  Meyer flew out of Cuba on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;She dedicated herself to distributing material and literature to the leaders and members of small groups manipulated, encouraged and financed by the government of the United States,&quot; Ferriol told a news conference in Havana.</p>
<p>She said the aim of Meyer's activities was to &quot;destabilize (Cuba's) socio-political regime&quot; and that this was completely incompatible with her status as a diplomat as defined by the Vienna Convention on Diplomatic Relations.</p>
<p>The U.S. State Department, which denied that Meyer had violated the Vienna Convention in her monitoring of human rights in Cuba, announced on Monday it was expelling a Cuban diplomat from Washington in retaliation. The two countries do not have formal diplomatic ties but maintain Interests Sections in each others' capitals.</p>
<p>Ferriol said the U.S. retaliatory expulsion was &quot;absurd and unfair&quot;. Among the publications she displayed were works published by Freedom House and written by Cuban dissidents such as Roberto Luque Escalona, who lives in Miami.</p>
<p>There were also works about the Cuban Independence hero Jose Marti, which Ferriol said &quot;distorted&quot; his life and views. She did not explain how Cuban authorities obtained the books.</p>
<p>&quot;No self-respecting state allows actions of this kind. We do no permit and we will never permit activities of this kind by diplomats from the United States or diplomats from any other country,&quot; she said, referring to Meyer's activities.</p>
<p>Cuban authorities, invoking the island's constitution and laws defending the existence of a one-party state, treat internal political opposition groups as illegal and often persecute their members, accusing them of being &quot;counter- revolutionaries&quot; in the service of the United States.</p>
<p>Citing public statements by U.S officials, the government has said Washington channels funds through organisations like Freedom House to support dissidents on the island with the intention of toppling the communist government.</p>
<p>The tit-for-tat expulsions further strained relations that are already tense following Cuba's downing of two small U.S. planes in February and the passage in March of U.S. legislation that seeks to curb foreign investment in Cuba.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
