<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9271" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Cuban party urges members to win &quot;war of ideas&quot;.</title>
<headline>Cuban party urges members to win &quot;war of ideas&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cuba's ruling Communist Party urged its members on Thursday to take a more active role in defending Cuba's socialist system, saying the country was engaged in a battle pitting socialism against capitalism.</p>
<p>&quot;More than before, the war being waged against our nation is one of a confrontation of ideas, an attempt to make us renounce our revolutionary ideology ... in short, to try to make us abandon socialism and adopt capitalism,&quot; the party's Central Committee said in the seventh and final instalment of a lengthy analysis published in the party newspaper Granma.</p>
<p>The document sets out the party's view of new ideological challenges it faces and how to respond. Thursday's instalment said current economic reforms and increased hostility from enemies like the United States meant Cuban communist militants needed to be more active than ever in upholding the party's political line.</p>
<p>&quot;Each militant must feel that he has a permanent mandate to practice politics in favour of the Revolution,&quot; the party said. It called for strengthening of the country's ideological defences and invoked key figures in Cuban history such as independence hero Jose Marti and Ernesto &quot;Che&quot; Guevara, the Argentine revolutionary who fought in Cuba's 1959 Revolution.</p>
<p>It also cited &quot;the example of (Cuban President) Fidel (Castro), united with the principles of Marxism and Leninism.&quot;</p>
<p>As examples of the new conditions and pressures that could cause what it called &quot;deviation&quot; by officials, it cited &quot;a greater presence of market relations among us, the psychology of capitalist business, as well as habits of consumption.&quot;</p>
<p>It said the party should ensure that those elected to positions of responsibility have, as well as technical aptitude, &quot;a clear revolutionary commitment and personal behaviour characterised by austerity and modesty&quot;.</p>
<p>Party militants should also be permanently on the alert against &quot;any manifestations of bribery and corruption&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
