<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9280" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine senators relent, decide to pay taxes.</title>
<headline>Argentine senators relent, decide to pay taxes.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine senators have relented on their decision not to pay income tax &quot;like ordinary citizens&quot; and will pay on all their parliamentary income and allowances, Vice-President Carlos Ruckauf said Thursday.</p>
<p>Ruckauf, who is also president of the upper house of the Argentine Congress, said senators of the ruling Peronist Party and the main opposition Radical Party had requested to be taxed on their income and the Senate approved the proposal late Wednesday.  </p>
<p>&quot;Legislators have always been exempt from paying income tax but they have now decided to consider themselves the same as other citizens,&quot; the Peronist official told local radio.</p>
<p>Senators provoked President Carlos Menem's wrath last week by voting to continue their income tax exemptions in defiance of government attempts to eliminate it along with other tax exemptions in an attempt to boost fiscal revenues.</p>
<p>Menem slammed the senators' vote last week as &quot;a huge and inadmissible mistake&quot; and vowed to veto it.</p>
<p>Their reluctance to pay taxes was especially controversial at a moment when Congress is deliberating government austerity measures aimed at plugging the budget deficit, including more taxes on fuel and for self-employed workers, while family allowance benefits are being reduced.</p>
<p>The lower house of Congress voted late Wednesday a motion clarifying that in its view there was no law actually freeing legislators from paying taxes, merely &quot;authorizing the heads of the Senate and Chamber of Deputies to regulate on which items of lawmakers' allowances income tax is paid.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Stephen Brown, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0695</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
