<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9285" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian coffee federation clarifies costs. [CORRECTED 22:35 GMT]</title>
<headline>Colombian coffee federation clarifies costs. [CORRECTED 22:35 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombia's National Coffee Growers Federation took issue Thursday with a Reuter story highlighting the gap that exists between the country's internal coffee price and the much higher price paid for Colombian excelso beans in New York.</p>
<p>At Colombia's official &quot;representative&quot; exchange rate as of Wednesday, when the the new internal price was announced, growers are to be paid about 80.00 cents a lb. That compares to about 140.00 a lb that Colombian excelso beans have fetched in New York this week.  </p>
<p>But John Naranjo noted that there are many hidden costs involved and that no one has been making anything like a 60.00 cent profit on each pound of Colombian coffee sold in New York.</p>
<p>To begin with, Naranjo said it takes 1.3 pounds (corrects from 1.3 kg) of parchment (corrects from green) Colombian coffee to produce a single pound of excelso.  </p>
<p>That brings the raw material cost of each pound of excelso produced in Colombia up to 108.55, Naranjo said in a statement to Reuters. When you factor in processing and financial costs, along with packaging and transportation from Colombia to port in New York, you arrive at a total cost of 126.12 per pound, he said.</p>
<p>Stictly speaking, he said it was not incorrect to refer to a 60.00 cent difference between the price paid to local growers and the price set by the market in New York.</p>
<p>But he said the comparison, as made in a weekly column filed by the Reuter bureau in Colombia Wednesday, could lead to erroneous conclusions because it failed to mention the additional costs that stand between growers and the global market.</p>
<p>-- Juan Guillermo Londono, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42390">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
