<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9289" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Talks stall on bill to scrap Brazil export tax.</title>
<headline>Talks stall on bill to scrap Brazil export tax.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Voting to speed up a bill to remove a tax on Brazilian exports will take place August 27 at the earliest after federal and state governments failed to reach an accord on terms, a Planning Ministry spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Planning Minister Antonio Kandir and the Parana and Rio Grande do Sul governments have yet to agree on compensation following the proposed elimination of the so-called ICMS tax, which applies to products such as coffee, sugar and soyproducts.  </p>
<p>The elimination of the tax should inject at least $1.5 billion into the agribusiness sector in its first year, Fernando Homem de Melo, researcher at the Sao Paulo Institute of Economic Research, said in local business daily Gazeta Mercantil.</p>
<p>In the long-term, this will increase to between $2 billion and $2.5 billion, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>&quot;The elimination of the ICMS on exports is, in the long-term, the most important agricultural policy measure in recent times,&quot; Homem de Mello told the newspaper.  </p>
<p>The Lower House of Brazil's Congress had been due to vote on a motion making the bill a priority on Wednesday afternoon but the session was suspended as negotiations continued.</p>
<p>The bill would offer state governments 3.6 billion reais ($3.56 billion) in compensation during the first year of the new system, of which 25 percent would be paid in cash.</p>
<p>The remainder would be paid in securitised government debt paper which would be used to reduce state-level debts to the federal government, the spokeswoman said, adding, &quot;The differences are no longer technical, they are political.&quot;  </p>
<p>Almost all of this is exported from the north/northeast sugar producing region while exports from the center-south are principally of crystal sugar which make up 55.1 percent of total exports, said an association spokesman.</p>
<p>The elimination of the tax still comes as welcome news to center-south producers however as it will totally rule out attempts by the state government to levy the tax on crystal sugar, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a question of how the legislation is interpreted. The tax is not supposed to apply to industrialised products such as refined or crystal sugar,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Parana and Rio Grande do Sul are opposed to the scheme because they have little debt with the federal government.</p>
<p>The two states are the largest producers of soybeans and soyproducts. So far this year revenue from soymeal exports has been the star performer in federal export revenue, accounting for almost six percent of all exports in January to July.</p>
<p>The government hopes to abolish the ICMS tax, doing away with its 13 percent levy on most exports, and another charge on electrical power and goods used in the production of manufactured goods which varies from state to state.  </p>
<p>Coffee exporting officials have already welcomed the proposal, which has long been sought by the Brazilian Federation of Coffee Exporters (FEBEC).</p>
<p>The soycomplex is expected to benefit most, with additional revenue of up to $1 billion if prices remain at current levels, estimated the Brazilian Vegetable Oils Industry Association.</p>
<p>For sugar, the ICMS tax applies only to demerara sugar which accounts for around 22 percent of total exports, according to the Association of Sugar and Alcohol Industries in Sao Paulo.  </p>
<p>&quot;But this year the state government has started to say that crystal sugar is semi-elaborated and therefore liable to ICMS,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The elimination of the tax has also been sought by orange and orange juice producers. Processors have said the scrapping of the tax would be one way they could pay more to orange producers who earlier this year complained about low prices.</p>
<p>-- William Schomberg, Brasilia newsroom, 5561 2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
