<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9291" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil govt aid to states at 3.2 bln reais - paper.</title>
<headline>Brazil govt aid to states at 3.2 bln reais - paper.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Brazilian federal government has already awarded 3.2 billion reais ($3.2 billion) in aid to financially troubled states and the figure is expected to be much higher by the end of the year, a newspaper said.</p>
<p>The government aid has been disbursed in the form of loans from federal banks, Caixa Economica Federal and Brazil's National Development Bank (BNDES), O Globo said.</p>
<p>State debts have already helped undermine the federal government's 1996 public sector deficit target of 3 percent of gross domestic product (GDP).  </p>
<p>The BNDES has already signed loan agreements with Rio de Janeiro, Minas Gerais, Rio Grande do Sul, Bahia and Alagoas states, and is negotiating with Rio Grande do Norte, Sergipe, Maranhao, Mato Grosso and Mato Grosso do Sul.</p>
<p>The BNDES loans are not enough, however, to cover the states' deficits and the situation is expected to get worse with the costs involved in the upcoming municipal elections, O Globo said.</p>
<p>-- Simona de Logu, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 507 4151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
