<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9293" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil cenbank/gov't debt grows 6.4 pct in June.</title>
<headline>Brazil cenbank/gov't debt grows 6.4 pct in June.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The internal debt stockpile of the Brazilian Central Bank and the federal government grew 6.4 percent in June over May, reaching 111.9 billion reais from 105.2 billion reais, the bank said.</p>
<p>The bank said in a statement that 3.4 billion reais of the increase was due to the Central Bank having written off as a loss credits owed to it following the 1985 liquidation of two small banks, Comind and Auxiliar.  </p>
<p>The credits had been listed in the bank's accounts as an asset but following a recent court ruling against the bank, had been transformed into liabilities, explained Altamir Lopes, head of the bank's economic department.</p>
<p>Lopes also said the main expansionary pressure on the monetary base in July came from a burst in the use of rediscount lines by the banking sector.</p>
<p>Rediscount operations and special credit lines under the government's Proer programme for encouraging bank mergers totalled 4.636 billion reais in July, with Proer amounting to 414 million reais.  </p>
<p>Lopes said the surge in rediscount operations followed July's setting up of the Basic Interest Rate (TBC) and changes in the conditions for granting rediscount lines intended to make them less punitive.</p>
<p>&quot;Rediscount operations are now perfectly normal operations. They do not represent in any way a bailout for banks,&quot; he told reporters. &quot;They no longer have a punitive character.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom 55-61-2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
