<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9301" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru electric shares light up dull month on bolsa.</title>
<headline>Peru electric shares light up dull month on bolsa.</headline>
<byline>Eduardo Orozco</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The three electricity companies traded on the Lima stock exchange stole the limelight in August as a burst of enthusiasm for this growth sector distracted investors from blue-chip stocks, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;They are the companies of the future,&quot; said Arnaldo Fiorani of local brokerage Interfip. &quot;Their operations are capable of expanding to give a full service to sections of the population, whose demand currently far outstrips its supply.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;The attraction of these has reduced the volume traded in Telefonica,&quot; Aleman added.</p>
<p>The telecom, which only last month made a spectacular debut in New York when its stock started trading as American Depositary Shares (ADSs), has seen its volume this month consistently account for less than 20 percent of Lima trade, compared to its usual 50 percent or more.</p>
<p>In part, the slump in Telefonica is due to the lack of foreigners, who are looking elsewhwere to make their investments because for the short-term the Lima exchange is generally seen as offering little upside.  </p>
<p>&quot;The holders of these stocks have got a good buy, since they are going to provide a healthy profit in the medium-term,&quot; said Jose Marquez of brokers Abila y Calpe.</p>
<p>Lima, the principal market for the three companies, shows the biggest room for growth as 45 percent of the capital's 7.4 million population does not yet receive electricity services, according to state electricity company Electroperu.</p>
<p>At a national level, Peru's annual electricity consumption per capita is 545 kilowatts hours (KWh), compared to Latin America's average of 1.166 kwh, according to the Energy and Mines Ministry.  </p>
<p>Utility Edegel and distributors Edelnor and Luz del Sur dominated the Lima equities market, which lacks in foreign players during a sluggish August.</p>
<p>With local investors dictating which stocks have been bought, the trio's popularity has generally squeezed funds from the blue-chip companies and, in particular, left benchmark Telefonica del Peru in the wings.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of investors have been drawing on their positions in other stocks to provide themselves with cash that they can put into the electricity shares,&quot; said Marcial Aleman of the local brokerage Abaco.  </p>
<p>But the drain away from Telefonica has been especially pronounced due to the electricity sector's attraction.</p>
<p>The appetite to buy the three utilities is based on their solid first half performances and their ability to expand to meet the sector's strong growth potential, brokers said.</p>
<p>The generator Edegel's first half net profit was 73.4 millones soles compared with 53.2 million soles in the same period in 1995. In the case of the two distributors' first half performances, Edelnor's net was 52.9 million, compared to 28.3 million soles in the same period last year, and Luz del Sur's was 51.4 million soles up from 31.8 million soles.  </p>
<p>This consumption is expected to grow 5.5 percent a year as companies plan to meet demand by investing $1.6 billion over the next ten years in the sector, the ministry said.</p>
<p>Edegel, which supplies Edelnor and Luz del Sur, has a current installed capacity of 700 Megawatts, which it hopes to increase to 1000 MW in the medium-term with investments of around $135 million, a company source said.</p>
<p>Edelnor has announced it will complete a $300 million six- year investment program in 2000 to improve its service principally in the Lima area.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in the next four years, Luz del Sur plans to invest $200 million and is also looking for a supply company to provide a further 600 MW capacity by Novemeber 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;What the electric companies are looking for with all of these investments is a consolidation to guarantee themselves the business they bet Peru will generate,&quot; said Miguel Bondy of the local brokerage JPBT.</p>
<p>-- Lima newsroom, 511 221-2134</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
