<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9306" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Fernandez to seek $1.0 bln spending cuts this year.</title>
<headline>Fernandez to seek $1.0 bln spending cuts this year.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine Economy Minister Roque Fernandez Thursday told Congress he will seek to cut $1.0 billion in public spending by year's end to help bridge an expected $6.6 billion fiscal deficit.</p>
<p>The minister said a tax hike package he sent to Congress Wednesday could result in some $600 million in savings. An extra $1.0 billion would come from privatizations and the remaining $4.0 billion would come from increased debt.  </p>
<p>Fernandez originally hoped to slash $1.2 billion from the deficit but his chief aide said Wednesday delays in Congress meant only half that target would be made. Ruling Peronist Party deputies say they cannot pass it before October.</p>
<p>&quot;Of that $6.6 billion deficit we are calculating this (tax package) will bring us below $6.0 billion. Then we intend to work on $1.0 billion of spending measures and there would be $5.0 billion left to finance somehow,&quot; the minister said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are asking for a $4.0 billion increase in indebtedness and another $1.0 billion would be linked to possibly doing some privatizations,&quot; said Fernandez.  </p>
<p>He gave deputies a breakdown of this projected deficit, saying $4.7 billion came from falls in revenue and $1.9 billion from increased spending on interest payments, social security and revenue-sharing with the provinces.</p>
<p>Fernandez wants Congress to approve a package for the rest of 1996 and for 1997 including new taxes on fuel, increases in taxes for the self-employed, the elimination of tax refunds and a controversial rise in women's retirement age to 65 from 60.  </p>
<p>&quot;What we are proposing is a system to generalize value added tax and income tax, a scheme where everyone pays and which will strengthen the tax-paying culture in Argentina,&quot; said Fernandez, linking this to plans for jail terms for tax dodgers who cost the public purse up to $24 billion a year.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that there are so many tax exemptions makes it easier for people to avoid paying taxes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>With a mind to Congress' concerns about the impact on Argentina's 17.1 percent unemployment, the minister said he was trying to avoid taxing labor and $2.3 billion of his package &quot;is linked to reducing taxes on employment.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Stephen Brown, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0695</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
