<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9313" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Storm Dolly picks up steam in Gulf of Mexico.</title>
<headline>Storm Dolly picks up steam in Gulf of Mexico.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tropical Storm Dolly, upgraded again overnight from a tropical depression, is gradually picking up steam in the Gulf of Mexico, National Meterological Service said Thursday.</p>
<p>Currently centered 200 km (125 miles) north of the port of Frontera in Tabasco state, Dolly is moving west-northwesterly at a speed of 24 km/h (15 mph), packing sustained winds of 85 km/h (53 mph) and gusts of 100 km/h (63 mph).</p>
<p>Storm alerts are out in the Gulf of Mexico from Puerto Progvreso in the state of Yucatan to La Pesca in the state of Tamaulipas, the service said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Tropical Storm Dolly will continuing gaining force during the day and it will be centered at 1300 local (1800 GMT) in the Gulf of Mexico around 300 km (188 miles) north of the port of Coatzacoalcos in Veracruz state, 225 km (141 miles) northeast of the port of Veracruz,&quot; the service said.</p>
<p>Dolly is seen reaching sustained winds of 100 km/h (63 mph) and gusts of 120 km/h (75 mph), the weather service added.</p>
<p>The weather front is expected to dump further rains along most parts of the Gulfm coastline, possible causing landslides and flooding.</p>
<p>Dolly slammed Tuesday into the state of Quintana Roo after racing through the Caribbean. It edged Wednesday across the Yucatan Peninsula before leaving land for the shallow waters of the Gulf of Mexico.</p>
<p>The state-owned oil and gas monopoly Petroleos Mexicanos (Pemex) said Wednesday that its three crude export ports in the Gulf had been forced to close because of the threat posed by Dolly. The company also took precautions on its offshore platforms in Campeche Bay.</p>
<p>The ports, namely Pajaritos, Dos Bocas and Cayo Arcas, are the company's main exit points for shipments to the United States and Europe.</p>
<p>--Chris Aspin, Mexico City newsroom (525) 7289530.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
