<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9314" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - Aug 22.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the highlights of the main Sao Paulo and Rio de Janeiro newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>GAZETA MERCANTIL</p>
<p>-- BRAZIL'S TBC CUT TO 1.88 PERCENT IN SEPTEMBER</p>
<p>Brazil's Monetary Policy Committee (Copom) has cut the Basic Interest Rate of the Central Bank (TBC) for its operations in the financial markets to 1.88 percent in September.</p>
<p>-- END TO ICMS INJECTS $1.5 BLN INTO AGRIBUSINESS SECTOR</p>
<p>The exemption of semi-finished goods exports from the ICMS tax can increase earnings in Brazil's agribusiness sector by at least $1.5 billion in the first year and $2 to $2.5 billion in the next three years.</p>
<p>-- BAMERINDUS ORDINARY SHARES FALL 4.4 PERCENT</p>
<p>Ordinary shares of Brazilian private bank Bamerindus fell 4.4 percent yesterday after the bank announced first half profits of 20.4 million reais.</p>
<p>O GLOBO</p>
<p>-- RIO'S CRIMINAL YOUTHS CONCENTRATED IN SEVEN NEIGHBORHOODS</p>
<p>Rio de Janeiro's state government says the city's most dangerous streetchildren are concentrated in 11 critical areas located in seven neighborhoods of the city.</p>
<p>-- SOCIAL SECURITY DEFICIT IN 1996 TO BE 6 BLN REAIS</p>
<p>Brazilian social security is to post a 1996 deficit of 6 billion reais, the first deficit in five years.</p>
<p>-- GOVT AID TO BRAZIL'S STATES ALREADY OVER 3 BLN REAIS</p>
<p>Brazilian federal government aid to help states in financial trouble has already reached 3.2 billion reais and is expected to rise by the end of the year. FOLHA DE SAO PAULO</p>
<p>-- SAO PAULO GOVERNOR TO DISCUSS VIOLENCE WITH FIESP</p>
<p>Sao Paulo Governor Mario Covas, who criticized industrial federation FIESP for its support of an anti-crime campaign, is meeting the heads of industrial and commercial federations to discuss the fight against crime.</p>
<p>-- ROAD CRASH IN MINAS GERAIS LEAVES SEVEN DEAD, 20 INJURED</p>
<p>Seven people were killed and 20 injured when a bus and a truck crashed in Minas Gerais state near the town of Pouso Alegre Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- SAO PAULO'S ROSSI FALLS AND PITTA INCREASES LEAD</p>
<p>A survey of Sao Paulo's mayoral candidates shows Francisco Rossi of the PDT at 12 percent of the vote, down 4 percentage points, while leading candidate Celso Pitta of the PPB managed to expand his lead by 2 percentage points to 37 percent.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified the stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- Simona de Logu, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 507 4151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
