<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9316" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>COSTA RICA: Two Cuban sportsmen defect in Costa Rica, Guatemala.</title>
<headline>Two Cuban sportsmen defect in Costa Rica, Guatemala.</headline>
<byline>Jose Lorria</byline>
<dateline>SAN JOSE, Costa Rica 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two Cuban sportsmen defected in separate incidents in Costa Rica and Guatemala on Wednesday, one a major soccer player and the other a young baseball star on the Cuban &quot;B&quot; team.</p>
<p>Goalkeeper Fernando Grinon Russeaux, who was due to play in the Cuban soccer team in a World Cup qualifier against El Salvador next month, gave the slip to teammates before they left Costa Rica, saying he was seeking to escape a lack of freedom on the Communist-ruled island.</p>
<p>&quot;I had taken the decision a long time ago, but I was waiting for the best circumstances to carry it out,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview at the San Jose offices of the Committee for the Defence of Human Rights in Cuba.</p>
<p>Dressed in his national team track suit, which he said was all he could take with him without arousing suspicion, Grinon said he left a wife and two children in Cuba and that he feared reprisals against them from the Cuban government.</p>
<p>&quot;From now, it (the Cuban government) is responsible for anything that could happen (to them),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>His defection coincided with the disappearance of 21-year-old Jesus Ramon Valvidia, second baseman on the Cuban &quot;B&quot; team playing friendly matches in Guatemala who has been a part of Cuba's top adult and youth teams since he was 12.</p>
<p>&quot;We all went to bed last night. In the morning we woke up and he wasn't there. He left very early,&quot; coach Juan Diaz told Reuters. The coach also said Valvidia's belongings had disappeared. &quot;He is definitely not with the team anymore.&quot;</p>
<p>Rene Guim, a spokesman for Miami sports agent Joe Cubas, told Reuters Valvidia called Cubas four days ago and the agent flew to Guatemala City on Monday to make contact with the baseball player.</p>
<p>Cubas was planning to help Valvidia make contact with a foreign embassy in Guatemala. But spokesmen at the embassies of the United States, Panama and the Dominican Republic said Valvidia had not sought asylum there. The Guatemalan Interior Ministry said he had not left the country.</p>
<p>Both cases suggested that defecting while under the watchful eye of one's teammates is not easy for a Cuban.</p>
<p>&quot;When you think about deserting, you don't let any of your colleagues know, because the atmosphere of repression in which we live makes us see each one of them as a policeman or a mole for the Communist regime,&quot; Grinon said in Costa Rica.</p>
<p>He said that besides the 18 players on the national soccer team, there were also seven party officials who tagged along in Costa Rica to keep an eye on behaviour.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ELSAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN JOSE, Costa Rica"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COSTA RICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
