<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9317" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUATEMALA: Guatemala rebels deny they intend to stay armed.</title>
<headline>Guatemala rebels deny they intend to stay armed.</headline>
<byline>Fiona Ortiz</byline>
<dateline>GUATEMALA CITY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Guatemalan guerrillas on Wednesday denied recent reports that they did not intend to lay down their arms in peacetime and insisted they were abiding by a ceasefire declared earlier this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Since declaring a halt to military offensives, we have rigorously complied (with the cease-fire),&quot; leaders of the Guatemalan National Revolutionary Unit in exile in Mexico said in a statement.</p>
<p>Last weekend all four of Guatemala's daily newspapers carried front-page stories saying the leftist Revolutionary Unit (known by the Spanish acronym URNG) had sworn in a recent document to stay armed after peace accords are signed.</p>
<p>&quot;We reject ... the way a recent URNG publication was twisted and taken completely out of context trying to say that the URNG would not disarm after peace accords are signed,&quot; said the URNG.</p>
<p>The rebels have met regularly with government peace negotiators since January, and both sides plan to sign a definitive peace agreement this year, ending 36 years of civil war in Guatemala.</p>
<p>The URNG declared a unilateral ceasefire in March and the Guatemalan army is under presidential orders to cease all counter-insurgency measures.</p>
<p>The guerrillas also denied charges by political leaders that they had stepped up propaganda campaigns, which usually consist of handing out pamphlets in rural areas.</p>
<p>President Alvaro Arzu made a public call to the URNG this month to cease the campaigns.</p>
<p>In July, URNG propagandizing sparked right-wing criticism after armed guerrillas entered a building of the capital's major university and spoke to students for about half an hour.</p>
<p>The populist Guatemalan Republican Front party is trying to bring criminal proceedings against President Arzu and his defence minister for not stopping the propaganda campaigns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUATEMALA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUATEMALA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
