<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9318" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PANAMA: FEATURE-Panama's prisons are &quot;small-scale hells&quot;.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Panama's prisons are &quot;small-scale hells&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Laurens Grant</byline>
<dateline>PANAMA CITY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prison guards beating nude inmates with batons is nothing new, says convicted murderer Eurpe Herrera, jailed in Panama's worst prison. &quot;It happens all the time. The difference is this time it was shown on TV.&quot;</p>
<p>Herrera spoke during a government-organised press tour of Panama City's Modelo prison where guards were filmed last month herding naked prisoners into a courtyard and beating them with nightsticks.</p>
<p>They were quelling a riot that killed two inmates, left a dozen prisoners and guards wounded and caused a national uproar. President Ernesto Perez Balladares condemned the beating and ordered an investigation. The prison director and 12 other officials were suspended.</p>
<p>&quot;There are torturers here. The guards beat us all the time,&quot; Herrera said, showing scars on his forearms through his cell bars. With four months left of his 12-year sentence, he wondered whether he would survive in his cramped urine- and feces-infested cell. Built for seven, it now holds nearly 50.</p>
<p>Modelo has a capacity of 275 prisoners but contains nearly 3,000. Panama's 46 packed, violent and filthy jails hold a total of nearly 7,000 prisoners, 75 percent of whom have not been sentenced.</p>
<p>Prisons in Latin America are notorious for squalid conditions, overcrowding and gang rule, and Panama is no exception. Jail riots rocked Argentina and Brazil this year in protest againt inhumane and degrading conditions, while Venezuelan prisons have been described officially as hellish.</p>
<p>Giovanni Niedda, head of the Panama branch of Prison Fellowship International, a human rights group working to improve prison conditions around the world, said years of military rule were often to blame for the situation.</p>
<p>&quot;Many countries, especially in Central America, that are coming out of civil wars have prison systems where military officials are mixed with civilian staff. Abuses are often committed by military officials and civilians don't have enough power to stop them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Panama abolished its army in 1994 along with the Panama Defence Forces, henchmen of former military strongman Manuel Antonio Noriega. But Niedda said many were re-hired by the penal system.</p>
<p>Otilia Tejeira Koster of Panama's Human Rights Investigation Centre said the government failed to make prison reform a priority because most prisoners were poor and black. &quot;Many don't know their rights so they are left there.&quot;</p>
<p>In a quick reaction to the Modelo riot, authorities began transferring some 1,000 prisoners to other jails in the capital and in the Atlantic port city of Colon. &quot;We will close Modelo sometime this year. We realise it has to be closed,&quot; an Interior Ministry spokesman said.</p>
<p>He said the penitentiary system budget had increased sixfold in three years to some $12 million in 1995. A new prison was built in Colon and two in Panama City, La Joya and Renacer, have been rehabilitated. But international and local human rights groups charge that Panama's prisons are like Nazi concentration camps and have not changed since military rule under Noriega and his predecessors.</p>
<p>&quot;In Modelo they still have 'la chiquita,' a small cell used to punish prisoners. They are put in there for weeks at a time. It's so small they cannot stand or lie down, they have to stay in a crouched position,&quot; a human rights leader said.</p>
<p>Romulo Emeliani Sanchez, Roman Catholic bishop for Panama's prisons, called Modelo a &quot;cemetery for the living and a small-scale hell.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Rats are bigger than cats,&quot; a guard there said. Prisoners often cut themselves with homemade knives in order to get permission to leave their cells to see the doctor. Rape of new prisoners is frequent and condoms are not available, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I came in without AIDS. Now I have AIDS and tuberculosis,&quot; said one prisoner who has spent 14 years of a 20-year murder sentence in Modelo.</p>
<p>Homosexuals, who are locked up together in one cell, complained they are denied medical attention.</p>
<p>Guards said they feared for their lives and admitted beatings were frequent. In the Modelo riot, they confiscated more than 300 homemade knives made of copper and iron torn from cell doors.</p>
<p>&quot;When there are hundreds of them running around armed, what are we supposed to do?&quot; asked one guard.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PANAMA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PANAMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
