<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9319" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Japan grants Mexico credits worth $960 mln.</title>
<headline>Japan grants Mexico credits worth $960 mln.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan on Wednesday granted Mexico credits worth $960 million for environmental and trade projects, part of visiting Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto's drive to open up a new trade front for Japanese industry.</p>
<p>&quot;Among the countries in the Group of Seven, Japan is the one that exports more capital than it takes in,&quot; Mexican President Ernesto Zedillo said.</p>
<p>&quot;Proof of that is the credit supports that Mexico has received,&quot; Zedillo said during a banquet for Hashimoto on the second day of the Japanese prime minister's three-day visit.</p>
<p>The other industrial nations in the Group of Seven are Britain, Canada, France, Italy, Germany and the United States.</p>
<p>A transcript of the president's comments was issued by his office.</p>
<p>The accords were signed at a ceremony at the Los Pinos presidential residence. Mexican Foreign Minister Jose Angel Gurria listed them as follows:</p>
<p>- an environmental credit agreement for $460 million aimed at helping clean up pollution in Mexico City</p>
<p>- an accord between Mexico's foreign trade bank Bancomext and Japan's Eximbank for $250 million</p>
<p>- an accord between Mexico's development bank Nacional Financiera and Japan's Eximbank, also for $250 million.</p>
<p>Hashimoto was here on the first leg of a 10-day, five-nation tour of Latin America, where he hopes to drum up trans-Pacific trade with the region's emerging economies.</p>
<p>The Mexican government is keen to court Asian business, and Japan is currently its third largest trade partner with trade flows this year expected to top $6 billion.</p>
<p>Japan has long seen Mexico as a launching pad for increased exports to the United States and Canada under the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA). Some 300 Japanese businesses are currently located in Mexico, many set up along its bustling border with the United States.</p>
<p>On the day before Hashimoto's arrival on Tuesday, a potential cloud was lifted when a top Japanese executive at electronics firm Sanyo was freed after being held captive for nine days in the border town of Tijuana. The ransom was $2 million.</p>
<p>Tokyo has invested nearly $60 billion in Latin America over the past 14 years and its economic aid doubled between 1990 and 1995 to $1.14 billion.</p>
<p>Mexico was the first stop on a trip that will also take Hashimoto to Chile, Brazil, Peru and Costa Rica.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
