<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9320" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SURINAM: Former Surinam rebel leader held after shooting.</title>
<headline>Former Surinam rebel leader held after shooting.</headline>
<dateline>PARAMARIBO, Surinam 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Flamboyant former Surinamese rebel leader Ronny Brunswijk was in custody on Wednesday charged with attempted murder, police said.</p>
<p>Brunswijk turned himself into police after Freddy Pinas, a Surinamese-born visitor from the Netherlands, accused Brunswijk of trying to kill him on Sunday after a bar-room brawl in the small mining town of Moengo, about 56 miles (90 km) east of Paramaribo, said police spokesman Ro Gajadhar.</p>
<p>Pinas, showing cuts and bruises on his face, told reporters the former head of the feared Jungle Command had tried and failed to shoot him after Pinas objected to Brunswijk's advances toward his wife. Pinas said Brunswijk then ordered his bodyguards to beat him up.</p>
<p>Brunswijk, 35, denied the charges and said he had merely defended himself when Pinas attacked him with a bottle.</p>
<p>It was the second time Brunswijk had been charged with attempted murder in less than two years. In 1994 he served two months in prison for shooting a thief in the buttocks.</p>
<p>Brunswijk led a rebel group of about 1,000 in a 1986 uprising against the regime of military strongman Desi Bouterse.</p>
<p>The conflict, which killed more than 500 and caused thousands to flee to neighbouring French Guiana in the late 1980s, eventually paved the way to democratic elections in 1991.</p>
<p>Despite numerous problems with authorities, Brunswijk went on to become a successful businessman with mining and logging interests. He also manages and occasionally plays for one of the leading local soccer teams.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SURM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARAMARIBO, Surinam"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SURINAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
