<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9322" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian General News - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian General News - Aug 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Former National Crime Authority chairman Peter Faris QC called for a judicial inquiry into all NCA investigations and Federal Attorney-General Daryl Williams said the Supreme Court ruling raised serious doubts about the operations of the NCA, following yesterday's acquittal of criminal charges against businessman John Elliott, resulting from a four-year NCA inquiry. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian Democrats have committed themselves to passing the Government's new industrial relations legislation by the end of the year, however, Democrats industrial relations spokesman Andrew Murray said yesterday while he supported the end of compulory unionism and closed shops, he was against the proposed repeal of the &quot;conveniently belong&quot; rule, which limits the number of unions in workplaces. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following last night's meeting with union officials, Qantas Airways Ltd managing director James Strong announced staff would be issued with A$500 worth of Qantas shares under the company's employee share ownership scheme. However, unions are pushing for guarantee that all employees will be entitled to a further two tranches of shares over the next two years. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Despite yesterday's commitment from the Democrats to pass an amended Workplace Relations Bill, the Government is still likely to have little hope of implementing its labour market deregulation program if has to rely on the Democrats in the Senate. The Democrats reaffirmed their opposition to restricting the Industrial Relations Commission's power in a Senate inquiry report. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Announcing a review of the National Crime Authority's failed investigation into former Liberal Party president and Elders chairman John Elliott, Federal Attorney-General Daryl Williams said the legal ruling, which found Elliott not guilty of an alleged A$6.5 million fraud of Elders shareholders, raised &quot;serious questions&quot; about the operations of the NCA. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Delivering the inaugural Vincent Lingaiari Lecture at the Northern Territory University, Governor-General Sir William Deane urged all Australian Parliaments to pass resolutions supporting the national reconciliation process and the work of the Council for Reconciliation, claiming that Australia would remain a diminished nation until there was true reconciliation with indigenous and non-indigenous people. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Local residents and environmental groups have threatened legal action to stop the development of Keith Williams' A$100 million Port Hinchinbrook resort in north Queensland, which was given the go-ahead by the Federal Government yesterday under a strict new set of environmental guidelines. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In the latest development of the Carruthers inquiry into electoral bribery, Queensland Criminal Justice Commission tapes revealed that National Party operative Matt Heery admitted in private conversations to deceiving the inquiry, plotting to burn documents and boasting that he had information to down Queensland Premier Rob Borbidge and Liberal leader Joan Sheldon. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>The Federal Government has ordered an inquiry into the National Crime Authority's handling of the John Elliott case, after charges against Elliott, Peter Scanlon and Kenneth Biggins for defrauding Elders shareholders of A$66.5 million were dropped because the bulk of the prosecution evidence was ruled inadmissible. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Sydney police were last night conducting a massive search for a woman who abducted a nine-week-old boy from his cot in the New Children's Hospital at Westmead. The woman is believed to be unrelated to the boy, who was recovering in the hospital after sufering breathing problems. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The New South Wales Police Royal Commission yesterday announced there was no evidence to suggest that Council of Civil Liberties head John Marsden had ever been protected from investigation or prosecution by the police. However, Marsden said the commission had not gone far enough to clear his name of paedophile allegations. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Justice Frank Vincent's ruling that the National Crime Authority had acted outside its powers to obtain evidence against businessman John Elliott was the key to victory for Elliott, as the ruling had a flow-on effect which ruled out evidence from other winesses supporting prosecution allegations. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Federal Attorney-General Daryl Williams last night announced a review of the role of the National Crime Authority after Justice Frank Vincent of the Supreme Court found that the NCA had stepped outside its terms of reference to investigate theft and fraud allegations against businessman John Elliott. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Some of the Government's key Budget plans are at risk, following Federal Opposition Leader Kim Beazley's announcement last night of Labor's intention to block Higher Education Contribution Scheme changes worth A$1.1 billion over four year, upfront charges for nursing homes worth A$308 million and higher prescription charges valued at A$503 million. Democrats Leader Cheryl Kernot said her party would also vote against increased prescription charges and HECS changes. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Public hearings for the Victorian Casino Inquiry scheduled for next month were indefinitely postponed last night because of confusion over the Commonwealth's powers to investigate State Government officials. Inquiry chairman Senator Bruce Childs said the committee wished to clarify the matter before proceeding with the public hearings. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Although the Northern Territory Parliament yesterday rejected a bill to repeal the world's first pro-euthanasia legislation, the law will face a further challenge on September 9 when Victorian Liberal backbencher Kevin Andrews introduces a bill to Federal Parliament to override the Territory's Rights to the Terminally Ill Act. Page A3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
