<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9323" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Business News - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Business News - Aug 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>As a final stage of WMC Ltd's three-year restructuring plan, the company will sell its A$350 million petroleum division to help fund the A$1.25 billion expansion of the Olympic Dam mine and a A$600 million fertiliser project based in Queensland. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Tax consultants have slammed the new thin capitalisation rules announced in this week's Budget papers. Ian Farmer of Coopers &amp; Lybrand claims because the new rules add to the cost and trouble of investing in Australia, many foreign investors would be reluctant to invest into major assets such as the airports or Austel. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>News Corp Ltd predicts that unprecedented takings from its Hollywood feature Independence Day, high TV advertising returns and lower newsprint prices will bring forward up to a 20 per cent increase in profit following the group's 25.3 per cent slump in 1995-96. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>US mining group Battle Mountain Gold has initiated proceedings with Niugini Mining Ltd aimed at buying out Niugini's remaining share of 49.6 per cent which it does not already own. The move is expected to cost the US miner at least A$290 million. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Once again the future of embattled Pay-TV operator Australis Media is under threat from the group's bond holders and Optus Vision shareholder the Seven Network. Doubts are being raised about the Kerry Packer-Optus Vision rescue package which include concerns that Australis' assets were sold too cheaply and Seven's rival, Kerry Packer, was being granted a larger stake in Optus-Vision. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Alan Newman's Futuris Corp Ltd has posted a record net profit which could see it expand its operations in the rural service sector. The Perth-based industrialist lifted its net profit in 1995-96 to A$52 million, up 30 per cent from the previous year. Page 30.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Emerging triumphant after his acquittal on theft and conspiracy charges, businessman John Elliott said yesterday the National Crime Authority investigation into Elders IXL Ltd in 1990 had cost the company's shareholders billions of dollars. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Although it reported its first fall in profit since 1990 yesterday - a six per cent decline after tax and abnormal items to A$1.26 billion in the year to June - News Corp Ltd said lower newsprint prices, solid forward advertising bookings for its US TV network and record box-office takings for its film Independence Day had set the company on track for a 20 per cent rise in profit this financial year. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Reporting a higher-than-expected A$246.2 million net profit for the year to June 30, Qantas Airways Ltd chairman Gary Pemberton said yesterday any attempt to maintain market share by expanding the fleet would place Qantas' profitability and capital at risk. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australis Media Ltd's US bondholders are believed to have rejected key components of the A$367 million rescue package headed by Kerry Packer, jeopardising the pay TV operator's latest recapitalisation plan. A long-standing impasse with the US noteholders would force Australis' two regional licensees, United International Holdings Inc and Century Communications, back to the negotiating table. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>With production expected to begin in the second quarter of 1998 and the first full year of production expected to average 26,200 barrels a day of low gravity, low sulphur crude oil, Santos Ltd yesterday announced the A$200 million development of the Stag oil field near Dampier. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>WMC Ltd is set to offload most of its petroleum division assets, including a 30 per cent stake in the East Spar offshore gas and condensate project in Western Australia, Greenhill Petroleum Corp in the US and a gas development project in New Zealand, to support key growth projects such as Olympic Dam. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Boosted by cost reductions and interest savings, Qantas Airways yesterday announced a net profit of A$246.7 million for the year to June 30. The result was A$9.7 million above the prospectus forecast and 36.8 per cent up on last year's figure. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Higher world paper prices and a sharp drop in earnings from the group's book publishing operations have contributed to News Corp's 25 per cent fall in annual net profit to A$1.02 billion. Falling almost A$100 million short of its target, the result was well down on 1995's record of A$1.36 billion. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>According to the Reserve Bank's annual report, the Federal Government's A$4 billion in spending cuts announced in the Budget could make a useful contribution to boosting national savings and the economy. The central bank reported a large increase in net profit to A$2.5 billion, up by A$714 million on the previous year. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australis Media's largest US junk bond holder, investment bank Merrill Lynch, has reportedly expressed concern over the pay TV operator's A$133 million rescue package which involves the sale of assets to rival pay TV group Optus Vision. If Australis' debt raising fails it could be forced into liquidation. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>West Australian-based industrial group Futuris Corp has reported a 30 per cent rise in net profit after abnormals to A$52 million and has forecast an improved year ahead. Futuris predicted a buoyant automotive sector and an upswing in the building industry would help boost profits for 1997. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>St George Bank subsidiary St George Investment Services will apply for registration as a life insurer following St George's decision to dump plans to acquire an insurer to launch its own product on the market. St George managing director Jim Sweeney said the move &quot;will provide the insurance business with an excellent foundation and profile from which to grow&quot;. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Despite reporting a 37 per cent increase in net profit to A$246.7 million for the year to 30 June, Qantas Airways has predicted another year of heavy cost-cutting to offset an expected softening in revenues for the air industry. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>WMC yesterday announced it was selling all but the strategic components of its petroleum division. The expected A$350 million sale follows WMC's failure to make international impact in the copper/gold, alumina and nickel sectors. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In its annual report the Reserve Bank of Australia has warned Australian companies will have to get used to the idea of lower profit growth in exchange for low inflation. The Bank also expressed concern that unions and global investment markets are yet to accept Australia's long-term low inflationary levels. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After the fifth month of the planned 45-month contract, the Transurban group's A$1.8 billion City Link project has been declared &quot;on track&quot;, with costs and construction running to schedule according to the company's chairman Laurie Cox. Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Rupert Murdoch has predicted his News Corporation will make a comeback after last financial year's 25.3 per cent slump in net profit from A$1.37 billion to A$1.02 billion. Murdoch claims the group will be back by a 20 per cent increase this financial year Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Cement and lime producer Adelaide Brighton believes the pick-up in the construction industry will not occur until at least the second half of next year. This will make Adelaide's year even harder after the company yesterday posted a net loss of A$49.3 milion for the last financial year. Page C3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
