<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9325" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: World's first euthanasia law faces new challenges.</title>
<headline>World's first euthanasia law faces new challenges.</headline>
<byline>Michael Perry</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The world's first voluntary euthanasia law survived a challenge in Australia's Northern Territory parliament on Thursday when opponents failed to repeal the assisted suicide legislation.</p>
<p>But euthanasia opponents vowed to continue fighting the law, which came into effect on July 1 but has not yet been used.</p>
<p>The next challenge is scheduled for September, when Australia's national parliament will be asked to override the territory's law.</p>
<p>Another challenge is also expected in Australia's High Court, with euthanasia opponents seeking a ruling on the legislation's constitutional validity.</p>
<p>National government backbencher Kevin Andrews on Thursday said he would introduce his anti-euthanasia private member's bill in parliament on September 9.</p>
<p>The territory's parliament defeated the &quot;Right to Human Life&quot; bill 14 to 11 in a free vote after a five-hour debate. Last month, the law survived a territory court challenge.</p>
<p>The law allows terminally-ill patients to end their life by lethal injection or pill as long as they meet strict conditions.</p>
<p>Doctors have been warned they may face murder charges if they assist a patient to die and the euthanasia law is repealed.</p>
<p>Territory opposition backbencher Neil Bell, who introduced the right to life bill, said he was disappointed with the vote, but that the matter was far from resolved.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a lot of people out there who are concerned and a lot of other people who don't understand it,&quot; Bell told Reuters by telephone from Darwin, the territory's capital.</p>
<p>Right to Life Australia chairwoman Margaret Tighe said the group would throw its weight behind any move in the national parliament to have the law repealed.</p>
<p>&quot;Right to Life will continue to support any initiative aimed at overturning this insidious piece of legislation,&quot; Tighe said.</p>
<p>Both Prime Minister John Howard and opposition Labor leader Kim Beazley have signalled their support for the anti-euthanasia bill, on which all members of the national parliament will be given a conscience vote.</p>
<p>Northern Territory Chief Minister Shane Stone said on Thursday the challenge in the national parliament could succeed, with support for the bill at present seemingly split.</p>
<p>National government parliamentarian Chris Gallus and opposition member Anthony Albanese on Thursday signed a joint letter calling for support of the euthanasia law.</p>
<p>&quot;The legislation which prevails in the Northern Territory is safe and based on noble notions of compassion, personal dignity and the rights of individuals to control their lives,&quot; they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
