<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9326" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>Australia: Australian port conditions - Lloyds.</title>
<headline>Australian port conditions - Lloyds.</headline>
<text>
<p>Australian port conditions from Lloyds Shipping Intelligence Service --</p>
<p>Aug 19 - COAL - Queensland, Abbot Point - coal mine workers on 24 hour strike from 2300 hours 18/8 in protest against industrial relations reforms. Small delays expected. Towage crews attended rally on 19/8 from 1200-1400 hours. No disruption to towage services experienced. Berth vacant 3 Vessels due by 19/9 No delays.</p>
<p>Dalrymple Bay - coal mine workers on 24 hour strike from 2300 hours 18/8 in protest against industrial relations reforms. Small delays expected. Towage crews attended local rally on 19/8 from 1200-1400 hours. No disruption to towage services. One vessel loading, 9 waiting 7 due by 2/9. Approx 5-6 days delay. Hay Point - coal mine workers on 24 hour strike from 2300 hours 18/8, small delays expected. Towage crews attended rally on 19/8, no disruption to towage services. Berth no.1 still undergoing repairs, expected completion 23/8. Berth no.2 operating normally. One vessel loading, 6 waiting, 8 due by 30/8. Approx 3-4 Days delay.</p>
<p>Blair Athol - Miners remain on strike indefinitely. Eight vessels anchored awaiting cargo, 1 due 21/8. Gladstone - Union members at Queensland coal mines began 24-48 hour stoppage from 2300 hours.</p>
<p>Barney Point - Major shutdown to upgrade terminal plant and equipment from 5/8 to 23/10. No shiploading and train unloading operations during this time. R.G. Tanna 2 vessels loading, 2 waiting, 29 due by 25/9. Approx 2-3 Days delay.</p>
<p>Brisbane - Union members walked off at 1000 hours 19/8, will not return until 2200 hours 19/8. MUA seamen on tugs also stopped at 1000 hours and will return 1600 hours 19/8. Berth vacant, 10 vessels due by 14/9. No delays.</p>
<p>New South Wales - Newcastle - Kooragang supporting the ACTU action, will stop work on day shift 19/8 0600-1600. Two vessels loading, 5 waiting, 16 due by 2/9. Approx 8-9 Days delay. Dyke 4+5 - shiploading affected 0500-1300. Tugs and linesmen stopped work 19/8 0001-2359. Two vessels loading, 10 waiting, 11 due by 1/9. Approx 10-11 days delay.</p>
<p>Port Kembla - Linesmen and tugs advise crews will not be available for 24 hours commencing 0700 hours 19/8. Coal terminal advises it has allowed 10% of workers to attend protest rally on 19/8. Coal ship loading operations will remain unaffected, provided there is a vessel at berth. One vessel loading, 1 waiting, 11 due by 8/9. Approx 1-2 Days delay.</p>
<p>IRON ORE - Western Australia. Port Hedland - Mt. Newman (Nelson Point) Berth A 6 vessels due by 28/8. Berth B 6 vessels due by 28/8. 4 other vessels due with no eta. Goldsworthy (Finucane Island) 3 vessels due. Dampier - Parker Point 1 vessel due. E.I. Island 4 vessels due by 21/8. Dampier lineup 11 vessels due by 3/9. Port Walcott - two vessels loading, 7 due by 31/8.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
