<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9327" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ poll seen as bad news for National government.</title>
<headline>NZ poll seen as bad news for National government.</headline>
<byline>Vernon Small</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The latest National Business Review-Consultus poll released on Friday showed eroding support for the the government and an overwhelming victory for the opposition in prospect if the numbers are translated into support on election day, a pollster said.</p>
<p>The UMR-Insight poll showed party support at 34 percent for the ruling conservative National Party, 21 percent for the economic nationalist New Zealand First Party, 20 percent for the main opposition Labour Party and 16 percent for the five-party left wing grouping the Alliance.  </p>
<p>The Alliance appears to have gained from its campaign against the privatisation of Forestry Corp, sold on Tuesday by the government for $2.026 billion last week.</p>
<p>Exacerbating the National Party's problems was the continued poor showing of its coalition partner United, which scored only 0.5 percent support, and the &quot;wasted vote&quot; going to its potential coalition partners, free-market Act and the Christian Coalition.  </p>
<p>Act registered 3.4 percent support, its best performance in the history of the poll, while the Christians scored 3.6 percent. Parties which do not win one of the 65 constituency seats must score five percent support to qualify for seats from the party list. The list is used to rebalance the number of seats to reflect a party's level of support.</p>
<p>If the poll was echoed on election night it would mean some eight percent of the vote that was likely to shore up a National-led government would be dismissed from the analysis.  </p>
<p>But UMR-Insight director Stephen Mills says the momentum is towards Act and the Christians and it is too soon to dismiss the possibility they will make the five percent threshold.</p>
<p>&quot;But the evidence is that a Labour-New Zealand First-Alliance arrangement will have more than enough support to govern. It is really how the dice fall between them and whether they can organise a coherent government&quot;.</p>
<p>He said the most interesting dynamic was whether National's support was now eroding to niche parties such as Act and Christians in the way Labour's did to the Alliance and New Zealand First.  </p>
<p>On the basis of Friday's numbers, National would qualify for 45 seats, New Zealand First 28, Labour 26 and the Alliance 21 in a 120 seat parliament.</p>
<p>Boosting the opposition's prospects was the poor showing of National in the poll of support in the constituencies.</p>
<p>National was down eight percentage points at 29 percent while Labour shed only one point to 30 percent.</p>
<p>Mills said the constituency vote should be viewed with caution because it contained a high &quot;don't know&quot; vote and was &quot;highly indicative&quot;.  </p>
<p>But the big disparity between Labour's constituency support and its level of support in the party vote suggests it will win more constituency seats than the number of overall seats its 20 percent support would qualify it for.</p>
<p>In that case, Labour keeps the &quot;overhang&quot; and the 120 seat parliament is increased in size by that number.</p>
<p>It is widely expected NZ First and Labour will strike a deal after the election, with a NZ First-National deal less likely given its stipulation that Prime Minister Jim Bolger and Finance Minister Bill Birch would have to lose their jobs first.  </p>
<p>Financial markets took little note of the poll. Indeed, the New Zealand share market powered to 2-1/2 year high while the New Zealand dollar and bond market were virtually unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;Did I miss the election? Has it gone?&quot; quipped SBC Warburg share broker John Rowley. &quot;There seems to be no interest at all in the election, it seems to be regarded as a non-event which is strange.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746  </p>
<p>It is widely expected New Zealand First and Labour will be able to strike a deal after the election, with a New Zealand First-National deal less likely given Peters' stipulation that Prime Minister Jim Bolger and Finance Minister Bill Birch would have to lose their jobs first.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
