<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9329" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australis says report of concern wrong.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australis says report of concern wrong.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pay television operator Australis Media Ltd said on Friday it believed that newspaper reports saying its largest U.S. bondholder was concerned about the recently announced rescue financing package were wrong.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that to be wrong,&quot; an Australis spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Sydney Morning Herald and The Australian Financial Review newspapers reported earlier on Friday that Merrill Lynch, Australis' largest U.S. bond-holder, was concerned about the cheap sale of Australis assets to rival operator Optus Vision as part of the US$105 million rescue package.  </p>
<p>The Financial Review said The Seven Network Ltd, which has a two percent stake in Optus Vision, was also concerned the package gives too much of Optus to Kerry Packer.</p>
<p>The Australis spokesman said he could not comment immediately on this aspect of the reports or elaborate on the attitude of the U.S. bondholders to the deal.</p>
<p>Packer's Publishing and Broadcasting Ltd, Lenfest Communications Inc of the United States, Ron Brierley's Guinness Peat Group, UIH International Holdings and Television and Radio Services Pty Ltd agreed to inject a further US$105 million into Australis in conjunction with a joint venture agreement with Optus Vision.</p>
<p>The newspapers said Merrill Lynch was concerned that Australis had sold its assets to Optus Vision too cheaply.</p>
<p>&quot;At this stage, however, it is unclear whether Merrill Lynch will withold its consent with talks between the parties set down for next week,&quot; The Sydney Morning Herald said.</p>
<p>Australis needs the approval of the bond holders to proceed with a further issue of US$225 million of bonds.</p>
<p>The US$105 million rescue package came after the bondholders demanded that at least US$100 million was injected before they granted approval.  </p>
<p>Australis shares rose one cent to 26 cents on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
