<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9335" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia minor parties differ on budget-Oppn.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia minor parties differ on budget-Oppn.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Labor opposition leader Kim Beazley said on Thursday opinions differed among the minor parties on the merits of measures in the conservative coalition government's budget.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got to be realistic about two things, firstly the minor parties don't agree with us on everything, and secondly on top of that an awful lot of what is done here is being done in what are so-called appropriations measures,&quot; Beazley said on ABC TV.</p>
<p>He had been asked how many measures he was confident of defeating in the Senate with the help of minor parties.</p>
<p>In Tuesday night's 1996/97 (July/June) budget, Treasurer Peter Costello announced a budget that cuts the underlying deficit from A$10.3 billion at June 1996 to A$5.6 billion in 1996/97, and will see a A$1.0 billion surplus by the fiscal year to June 1999.</p>
<p>The conservative Liberal National coalition government is two votes short of a majority in the Senate. Those two votes could come from the seven Democrats, two Greens, a pair of Independents or the Labor opposition.</p>
<p>No party is expected to vote against the Appropriation Bills -- that is those authorising expenditure -- since obstruction would spark a constitutional crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;The capacity to knock off appropriation measures is very very limited indeed, unless you want to create an absolute crisis and that's not on as far as we're concerned,&quot; Beazley said.</p>
<p>However, there were discrete areas where entitlements would continue in place if they were not amended, Beazley said.</p>
<p>&quot;I've indentified a few...most notably the one relating to HECS (higher education contribution scheme),&quot; Beazley said. The Democrats have also said they oppose this measure.</p>
<p>HECS is a levy on tertiary education paid through the tax system. In the budget the costs of courses were raised, the income threshold at which the levy is payable from was lowered and the rate at which it is repaid was quickened.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273 2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
