<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9336" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-WMC petroleum sale has mix of assets.</title>
<headline>RTRS-WMC petroleum sale has mix of assets.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>WMC Ltd said on Thursday that its petroleum unit, which is up for sale, includes a mix of producing and prospective assets.</p>
<p>WMC earlier on Thursday said it was selling off its petroleum division, except for a 1,380-km gas transmission pipeline leading to the goldfields region of Western Australia, located in Australia, the United States and New Zealand.</p>
<p>These include the WMC's wholly-owned Greenhill Petroleum Corp, a producer of oil in the United States, and the Kupe South prospective gasfield in New Zealand, a WMC spokesman told Reuters.  </p>
<p>The spokesman declined to place a total value on the assets up for sale, but said the company did not expect to record any significant gain or loss from the sale.</p>
<p>Analysts estimate the assets are worth a total of about A$290 million.</p>
<p>WMC expects to complete the transactions by second quarter of 1997, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Other assets to be sold include interests in offshore gas fields in Western Australia, which are scheduled to feed the goldfields pipeline.  </p>
<p>The A$450 million pipeline, 62.6 percent owned by WMC, is designed to carry natural gas from the northwest coast of Australia through the middle of Western Australia to supply mining operations, including WMC's Mt Keith and Leinster nickel mines.</p>
<p>Australasian petroleum output in the fourth quarter was 399,056 barrels for a full-year result of 1.97 million barrels, down from 2.67 million barrels in 1994/95, the company said in its most recent production report.  </p>
<p>WMC largely blamed the drop in full-year petroleum output on a continuing decline in production from its mature Western Australian fields.</p>
<p>The company said it expects most staff would transfer to the new owners and that the decision to sell off the division would not result in immediate job losses.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
