<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9337" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Budget ignores jobless - Democrats.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Budget ignores jobless - Democrats.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian Democrats will not block supply in the Senate, but they would still request amendments to Appropriations Bills, Democrats leader Cheryl Kernot said in her official response to the Government's Budget.</p>
<p>Kernot criticised the budget as being &quot;built on the backs of the unemployed,&quot; and heralding a significant shift from the public to private sector.</p>
<p>The Democrats would oppose several measures in the budget, but would not block supply as they do not believe in denying the government the money it needs to run the country, she said.  </p>
<p>In Tuesday night's 1996/97 (July/June) budget, Treasurer Peter Costello announced a budget that cuts the underlying deficit from A$10.3 billion at June 1996 to A$5.6 billion in 1996/97, and will see a A$1.0 billion surplus by June 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;But our pledge not to block supply doesn't stop us from requesting amendments to the Appropriations Bills,&quot; Kernot said, saying it was a tactic the Democrats intended to use.</p>
<p>Kernot said the Democrats would support the family tax package, but were unhappy with the loose targetting of the rebate.</p>
<p>The Democrats were also &quot;favourably disposed towards an increase in the Medicare levy for higher income earners.&quot; However, they were not &quot;favourably disposed&quot; to the lift in the threshold for the medical expenses tax rebate, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will announce our position on these changes in the next fortnight,&quot; Kernot said.</p>
<p>&quot;However we will vote against increases in payments for prescriptions under the Pharmaceutical Benefits scheme,&quot; she said, adding they had done so under the previous Labor government as well.</p>
<p>The Democrats are also opposed to user-pays education, and &quot;will oppose the cuts in operating subsidies to universities and we will vote against the changes to HECS and AUSTUDY,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Kernot also said the Democrats were opposed to funding cuts of the ABC and ATSIC. &quot;However, we know these cuts will form part of the roughly A$3 billion worth of measures whcih are not reviewable by the Senate,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The conservative Liberal National coalition government is two votes short of a majority. Those two votes could come from the seven Democrats, two Greens, a pair of Independents or the Labor opposition.</p>
<p>Kernot said the Democrats supported the need for deficit reduction, but believed the Government should focus on the two medium term goals of halving unemployment and achieving a structural surplus within the next two to three years.</p>
<p>A &quot;reduction of about A$4 to A$5 billion over the next three years represents a credible and responsible strategy in economic, fiscal and social terms,&quot; Kernot said.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273 2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
