<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9340" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia budget a betrayal and divisive - Opposition.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia budget a betrayal and divisive - Opposition.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Opposition leader Kim Beazley on Thursday called the conservative coalition government's budget bought down earlier this week a betrayal and divisive in his official reply to the budget.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a budget of betrayal,&quot; Beazley said, saying it was not only a betrayal of election promises, but also a betrayal of the Australian promise -- &quot;the promise of Australia working always towards a more fair, a more just, a more inclusive and united society.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Above all this budget also betrays the jobless,&quot; Beazley told Parliament.  </p>
<p>In Tuesday night's 1996/97 (July/June) budget, Treasurer Peter Costello announced a budget that cuts the underlying deficit from A$10.3 billion at June 1996 to A$5.6 billion in 1996/97, and will see a A$1.0 billion surplus by June 1999.</p>
<p>Beazley said the government, which won power from the Labor Party at the election in March, had placed a dead hand on the economy when they took office, and the cuts would further dampen growth.</p>
<p>&quot;It suits the government to have low growth because lowe growth makes it appear as if the bigger cuts are needed to restore the Budget to balance,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Greater growth, like the four percent growth Labor averaged over the last four years it was in office, could restore the budget to balance without the need for large cuts, as well as reducing unemployment, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;And unemployment, not the budget, is the number one problem facing Australia,&quot; Beazley said.</p>
<p>Beazley said Labor had no argument that Australia's longer term economic interests were best served by returning the Budget to surplus.  </p>
<p>The best way to achieve balance was through a moderate program of cuts over the government's term &quot;which do not harm valuable public programs, and which do not harm growth -- and which provide hope rather than despair for the jobless.&quot;</p>
<p>Beazley said Australians expected the Prime Minister to &quot;stand above Treasurers and a desire to please financial markets, when necessity dictates&quot;, but said Prime Minister John Howard had stood aside.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273 2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
