<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9342" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China offers talks to end hostility with Taiwan.</title>
<headline>China offers talks to end hostility with Taiwan.</headline>
<byline>Benjamin Kang Lim</byline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>China has offered to hold negotiations to end almost five decades of hostility with Taiwan but said on Thursday Taipei had spoiled the atmosphere for talks.</p>
<p>China's top negotiator with Taipei, Tang Shubei, told a visiting group from Taiwan on Wednesday that it was time for the rivals to hold political talks to pave the way for reunification, Chinese newspapers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Now is the time for the two sides to engage in political talks...to end the state of hostility,&quot; the overseas edition of the People's Daily quoted Tang as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;China wants peaceful reunification... Political disputes should be resolved through political talks,&quot; Tang said.</p>
<p>In Taipei, Kao Koong-lian, spokesman for the cabinet's Mainland Affairs Council, said: &quot;It is fine with us.&quot;</p>
<p>On Thursday, Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Shen Guofang urged Taiwan authorities to abandon their drive to break out of diplomatic isolation for the talks to push through.</p>
<p>&quot;The necessary atmosphere for the opening of the talks has (all along) been disrupted by the Taiwan authorities,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;The Taiwan authorities should in the first place put an end to their activities of trying to create 'Two Chinas' or 'One China, One Taiwan,'&quot; Shen told Reuters.</p>
<p>Taiwan, regarded by China as a renegade province, says it is committed to reunification but stresses this cannot be achieved overnight.</p>
<p>Taipei has banned official contact with Beijing since Chiang Kai-shek's Nationalist troops lost the Chinese civil war and fled to the island in 1949.</p>
<p>The two sides have skirted the ban by setting up unofficial bodies to handle bilateral affairs after tensions began easing in the late 1980s.</p>
<p>China suspended unofficial talks with the island last year shortly before Taiwan's President Lee Teng-hui made a landmark visit to the United States.</p>
<p>China's offer to hold reunification talks came after a series of regulations were introduced to pave the way for direct shipping links, which Taiwan still bans.</p>
<p>Taiwan has indirect shipping and air links with China through a third territory, mostly Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Chinese Vice-Minister of Foreign Trade Liu Xiangdong urged Taiwanese authorities to &quot;eliminate human barriers (to direct shipping links) as soon as possible&quot;, said the Communist Party mouthpiece People's Daily.</p>
<p>China's Foreign Ministry on Wednesday summoned Ukraine's ambassador in Beijing, Anatoly Plyushko, to protest against a visit to Kiev by Taiwanese Vice-President Lien Chan, an embassy spokesman said.</p>
<p>The former Soviet republic of Ukraine recognises China but not Taiwan.</p>
<p>In apparent retaliation against Lien's visit, Chinese State Councillor Li Tieying, a member of the powerful Politburo of the ruling Communist Party, has postponed a visit to Ukraine.</p>
<p>Taiwan's state radio reported that Ukrainian President Leonid Kuchma met Lien on Wednesday, but a spokesman for Kuchma denied this.</p>
<p>Lien surfaced in Kiev on Tuesday, two days after vanishing on a mysterious European mission. He made a secret detour to Ukraine to receive an honorary degree after making a state visit to the Dominican Republic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
