<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9344" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Aug 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Aug 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>NIHON KEIZAI SHIMBUN</p>
<p>Five leading Japanese steel manufacturers and trading firms are to radically review their contracts for steel exports, aiming to reduce commissions to trading firms.</p>
<p>Three steelmakers -- Nippon Steel Corp, Sumitomo Metal Industries Ltd and Kawasaki Steel Corp, plan to reduce foreign exchange commissions they pay to trading firms from the current one yen per dollar to 0.1 yen from October. Two other steelmakers will also follow suit next spring.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Nippon Steel Corp is expected to post parent current profit of 25 billion yen in the half-year to September 30, down 15 percent from the same period a year ago, against a previously forecast 19 percent rise to 35 billion yen.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>International telecommunications carrier Kokusai Denshin Denwa Co Ltd (KDD) and Thailand's state-run telephone firm have agreed to set up a joint company in Bangkok to start business in the personal handyphone system (PHS). They hope to receive permission from the Thai government by next spring.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>IBM Japan Ltd has set up a marketing plan targeting Japan's smaller cities. It plans to tie up with eight big retailers, including Best Denki Co Ltd and Joshin Denki Co Ltd, in its marketing. It hopes to raise its sales outside the Tokyo area to 45 percent of its total by the end of this year.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Alpha Therapeutic Corp, a U.S. unit of Green Cross Corp, is expected to pay around $90 million worth of compensation for patients who were infected with the HIV virus in the United States through contaminated blood products.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Leading car parts manufacturers affiliated with Nissan Motor Co Ltd plan to expand their business in Mexico.</p>
<p>Calsonic Corp is to build a five billion yen plant there to manufacture air conditioners, mufflers and other parts. Tachi-S Co Ltd, a leading car seat maker, will also double its production capacity.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Mitsubishi Corp plans to set up a joint investment fund with major South African conglomerate Anglo-American Corp to invest in small and medium-sized manufacturers in South Africa.  </p>
<p>Mitsubishi Materials Corp plans to spend 10 billion yen to set up a silicon wafer production plant in Indonesia, and aims to start output at the factory from the beginning of 1998.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Major Japanese dyestuff company Nippon Kayaku Co Ltd and Tomen Corp plan to build a joint textile dyestuff company with a Chinese company in China in September.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
