<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9345" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan VP coy on Ukraine meeting, office swap.</title>
<headline>Taiwan VP coy on Ukraine meeting, office swap.</headline>
<byline>Alice Hung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's Vice-President Lien Chan said on Thursday he spoke with people &quot;of all levels&quot; during a secretive Kiev mission that enfuriated China but declined to say if he met Ukraine's president.</p>
<p>&quot;I met the people I wanted to meet and discussed the things I wanted to discuss,&quot; Lien told reporters at Taipei's international airport when asked to confirm reports that he met President Leonid Kuchma.</p>
<p>&quot;In Ukraine, I met people from all levels, specific people, and had a full exchange of views. But I cannot identify who I met by name. That would not live up to the agreement I made before visiting.&quot;</p>
<p>Lien used similarly coy language when asked to confirm reports in the Taiwanese media, including one in the ruling Nationalist Party's Central Daily News, that Taiwan and Ukraine had agreed to exchange unofficial representative offices.</p>
<p>&quot;We both think we should promote relations on the basis of organisations. That was the consensus,&quot; Lien said, choosing his words carefully.</p>
<p>&quot;As for a setting up a representative office, Ukraine understands that we have such offices in Russia, Belarus and elsewhere and they understand the importance. There should be some subsequent development in this matter.&quot;</p>
<p>Ukraine, bearing the brunt of China's anger, flatly denied that Lien and Kuchma met, although Foreign Minister Hennady Udovenko told Reuters he found Beijing's furious reaction to Lien's visit to be &quot;out of proportion&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It wasn't even a visit but a trip, a private journey,&quot; Udovenko said of Lien's three-day stay.</p>
<p>China, which regards Taiwan as a renegade province, delivered a note of protest to Ukraine's ambassador in Beijing and cancelled a visit by a high-level delegation.</p>
<p>Udovenko confirmed that Ukraine, which recognises Beijing, was interested in developing trade with Taiwan and wanted to open a trade mission in Taipei.</p>
<p>Beijing says Taiwan, as a Chinese province, is not entitled to foreign ties and has rebuked even allies whom it sees as giving political or diplomatic quarter to the island's leaders.</p>
<p>Lien denied Beijing's allegation that his government sought to create &quot;two Chinas&quot; or &quot;one China, one Taiwan&quot;, saying Beijing was determined to destroy it.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone knows the Republic of China's diplomacy faces communist China's overall blockade. It wants the Republic of China to disappear from the world map,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lien said Taiwan would continue to press for international recognition, including a seat in the United Nations. &quot;It is necessary for the Republic of China to develop foreign relations for the sake of our survival and development,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lien surfaced in Kiev on Tuesday, two days after vanishing in New York following a state visit to the Dominican Republic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
