<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9347" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam dissidents get lighter than expected terms.</title>
<headline>Vietnam dissidents get lighter than expected terms.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam jailed a prominent dissident on Thursday and imposed suspended sentences on two others for violations of national secrecy laws, court sources said.</p>
<p>Le Hong Ha, a former Interior Ministry official and senior communist party member, was sentenced to two years' jail.</p>
<p>Ha Si Phu, a prominent academic, and Nguyen Kien Giang, a lesser known but outspoken communist critic, were given suspended prison sentences of 12 and 15 months respectively.</p>
<p>Thursday's trial was closed to foreign journalists for reasons which were not clear, and court officials refused to give any details of the daylong event.</p>
<p>Formal confirmation of the sentences was also not available on Thursday evening, but the terms -- relating to charges under article 92 of Vietnam's Penal code -- appeared lighter than anticipated.</p>
<p>Vietnam's sweeping national secrecy laws allow for jail sentences of between two and seven years with a maximum punishment of 15 years for more serious violations.</p>
<p>However, Hanoi-based analysts were hesitant to read too much into the apparent outcome.</p>
<p>&quot;It's difficult to make a judgment based on just one trial (since June's Communist Party Congress)... But, it would be good if this is a sign that things are improving,&quot; said a senior Western observer.</p>
<p>Le Hong Ha and Ha Si Phu were arrested late last year during a broader crackdown on dissent as preparations for the congress got into full swing.</p>
<p>Party congresses are major political events in Vietnam involving months of preparations and official meetings are usually held under a veil of secrecy. June's congress was seen as the most important Communist Party meeting since the end of the Cold War.</p>
<p>Le Hong Ha had been expelled from the party earlier in 1995 after calling for the rehabilitation of prominent intellectuals Hoang Minh Chinh and Do Trung Hieu.</p>
<p>Ha Si Phu is known to have published a number of articles advocating political reform and had given interviews to a number of foreign radio stations in which he openly criticised the Hanoi government.</p>
<p>Nguyen Kien Giang, a veteran communist was investigated for possessing state secrets in early January this year, but had not been taken into custody.</p>
<p>It had not been clear in advance of Thursday's trial whether he would be sentenced alongside Ha and Phu.</p>
<p>The event had been condemned earlier in the day by human rights group Amnesty International, which said Le Hong Ha and Ha Si Phu were being punished &quot;only for questioning the political views of the Vietnamese government&quot;.</p>
<p>Their arrests last year were also criticised at the time by the U.S.-based group Human Rights Watch/Asia which accused Hanoi in a strongly worded statement of violating international laws.</p>
<p>Vietnam has been a signatory to the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights since 1982.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
