<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9350" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Asian port conditions - Lloyds.</title>
<headline>Asian port conditions - Lloyds.</headline>
<text>
<p>Port conditions from Lloyds Shipping Intelligence Service.</p>
<p>CHINA, Aug 17 - Taichung - six vessels anchored, delays grain 2 days, iron ore 1 day, coal, scrap, steel and others 1-2 days. Aug 19 - Keelung - vessels in port 11 containers, 1 tanker, 9 other bulkers, 4 general cargo. Waiting at outer anchorage - 8 containers, 2 bulkers. Berthing delays 1 day for containers, 1 day bulkers. Kaohsiung - vessels in port 13 containers, 2 tankers, 3 grain, 3 other bulkers, 13 buoys.</p>
<p>INDIA, Aug 20 - Bombay delays container vessels 4-5 days, bulk 12-15 days, general cargo 20-21 days. 1 vessel loading at berth, 26 discharging at berth, 4 discharging at anchorage, 4 waiting at anchorage to load, 49 to discharge. 1 bunkering, 5 under repairs, 2 awaiting orders. Occasional rain hampered operations. Floating crane out of action from 5/8 indefinitely.</p>
<p>Calcutta - Vessels due 10 products, 1 crude tanker, 1 coal, 1 demolishing, 10-12 days delay. 10 vessels discharging at berth, 2 bunkering. Cochin - loading 3 containers, 1 breakbulk. Delays fertiliser, general cargo, scrap, tankers up to 1 day. 1 tanker waiting at anchorage to load, 2 vessels under repair/drydock.</p>
<p>Mormugao - Vessels due 1 container, 1 days delay, 1 coke, 1 molasses, 1 petcoke, 1 petroleum, 1-2 days delay, 2 loading at berth, 1 loading at anchorage, 3 discharging at berth, 1 discharging at anchorage, 1 waiting at anchorage to discharge 4 under repairs/drydock. 1 awaiting orders.</p>
<p>Jawaharlal Nehru - Vessels due 4 fertiliser/raw material, 8-10 days delay, 4 tankers/iron ore, 4-5 days delay, 2 vessels discharging at berth, 2 waiting at anchorage to load, 2 to discharge. Harbour tug officers on strike, all ships' movements stopped from 18/8 0800 hours.</p>
<p>Kandla - vessels due 1 sulphur, 10-12 days delay. 3 Scrap, 15-16 days delay, 2 rice, 20-25 days delay, 1 rock phosphate 9-10 days delay, 1 steel coils 7-8 days delay, 1 coke 7-8 days delay, 1 TEUS 2-3 days delay, 1 sugar 10-12 days delay. 5 vessels loading at berth, 2 loading at anchorage, 3 discharging at berth, 9 waiting at anchorage to load, 2 to discharge. 3 tankers berthed. M</p>
<p>Mangalore - 11 vessels due 2-3 days delay expected, 1 vessel loading at berth, 2 discharging. Madras 35 due, delays coal/coke 4-5 days, fertiliser 3-4 days, scrap 5-6 days, others 3-4 days. 4 vessels loading at berth, 11 discharging. 2 waiting at anchorage to load, 3 to discharge. 2 under repair/drydock, 1 awaiting orders. Tuticorin - four vessels due, 1-2 days delay. 2 vessels loading at berth, 5 discharging, 1 discharging at anchorage, 1 waiting to discharge, 1 awaiting orders.</p>
<p>Paradip - Eight vessels due. Delays 4 days for chrome, 15 days fertiliser, 1 day oil, 15 days scrap. 4 vessels loading at berth, 2 discharging.</p>
<p>Visakhapatnam - Vessels due/delays - 4 export iron ore, up to 1 day, 1 export alumina, up to 1 day, 1 export sugar, 7-8 days, 1 export rice 3-4 days, 1 export steel bars, up to 1 day, 1 import mop, 4-5 days, 7 import coking coal, 10-12 days, 3 import palm olein, 2-3 days, 1 import/export container, up to 1 day, 1 general cargo, 2-3 days, 1 export blocks, up to 1 day, 1 import steel rails, 3-4 days, 1 export sulphur and 1 general cargo, up to 1 day, 1 import rock phosphate, 4-5 days, 1 import ammonia, 1 import timber logs, 1 day, 1 import magnesite in bags, 2-3 days, 1 import oil, up to 1 day, 5 loading at berth, 6 discharging at berth.</p>
<p>S.KOREA, 20 Aug - Inchon - 91 vessels in port (53 berthed, 38 anchored) 13 logs, 8 general cargo, 4 containers, 3 each wheat, pulp, corn, scrap, 2 each sugar, cars, steel, plywood, 1 each alfalfa, silicone, wheat pellets, rapemeal, tapioca, coils, copper, copra. 5 cars, 4 each scrap, logs, general cargo, 3 each containers, coils, 2 each rapemeal, cotton seed meal, pulp, pig iron, 1 each wheat pellets, tapioca, soybean, copra, wheat, bananas, corn anchored. Approx 2-3 days delay. Busan - 181 in port (54 berthed, 127 anchored incl 63 laid up) of which 35 general cargo, 8 container, 6 scrap, 5 coal. 64 vessels awaiting berth, 3 days delay expected. Pohang - 22 in port (18 berthed, 4 anchored) 2 steel plates, 2 pipes, 2 billets, 1 each coal, on ore, bauxite, coils, coke discharging, 7 vessels loading steel, 4 awaiting berth, 1-2 Days delay. Ulsan - 29 vessels in port (24 berthed, 5 anchored) 2 each feed meal, woodchips, mono ethyl glycol, 1 each coal, coke, rock phosphate, cement, propylene, sugar, logs, zinc concentrate, copper concentrate, mtbe, acetic acid, rye, propane discharging, 1 each ammonium sulphate, fertiliser, general cargo, base oil, chemicals loading. 5 vessels awaiting berth, 10 days delay. Masan - five vessels berthed, 2 steel scrap, 1 logs discharging, 1 steel pipes, 1 container vessel loading, no waiting time expected.</p>
<p>MALAYSIA, Aug 21 - Port Kelang - North port container berths 3 vessels alongside, none waiting. Deep draft conventional wharf 4 vessels alongside, 2 berthed. 1 waiting. Dry bulk terminal 2 vessels alongside, 1 berthed, 2 waiting,  approx 4 days waiting time. West port 3 conventional vessels alongside. 2 cement carriers discharging alongside. 1 Wharf vacant.</p>
<p>PAKISTAN, Aug 19 - Karachi six vessels due, 24 hours delay containers, 48 hours general cargo. 5 vessels loading at berth (rice, wheat bran, chrome and general meal) 3 container vessels loading and discharging at berth, 8 vessels discharging at berth (general cargo, dap, urea and mogas), 1 rice vessel waiting to load, 9 vessels waiting to discharge (general cargo, containers, fertiliser, oil tankers, sugar, scrap), 1 awaiting orders.</p>
<p>SINGAPORE, Aug 20 - Tanjong pagar container terminal 7 container vessels berthed. Keppel terminal 15 container/general cargo vessels berthed. Pasir panjang terminal 5 container/ general cargo vessels berthed. Sembawang terminal 3 general cargo vessels berthed. Jurong Port 10 bulk cargo/steel/general cargo vessels berthed, oil terminal/sbm buoys 16 tankers berthed. Minimal delays at all ports/terminals.</p>
<p>SRI LANKA Aug 20 - Colombo - 11 vessels due, 3-4 Days delay expected.5 breakbulk loading at berth, 4 discharging at berth, Waiting at anchorage to load 2 breakbulk, 1 bagged rice, 1 outside harbour. 6 Vessels under repairs/drydock. 3 Vessels awaiting orders. Galle - one vessel discharging at berth. 2 loading at berth. Trincomalee - two discharging at berth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
