<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9352" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine peso hammered by assassination rumour.</title>
<headline>Philippine peso hammered by assassination rumour.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippine peso closed at 26.225 to the dollar on Thursday after being battered down to 26.235 on false rumours that defence secretary Renato de Villa had been killed in an ambush.</p>
<p>The Central Bank stepped in to sell $20 million in the last minutes of trade to calm the market and said it was ready to intervene again on Friday if the jitters continued.  </p>
<p>The day's average was at 26.209 pesos versus 26.194. Volume swelled to $180 million from $97 million.</p>
<p>A foreign bank dealer said he heard the rumour from overseas counterparts. &quot;They started lifting our offers&quot; before the dollar got very expensive. &quot;We didn't know who spread the rumour and who started it&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>The rumour sent banks into a panic, but the Central Bank stepped in at 26.235 pesos to halt the peso's slide, traders said.  </p>
<p>Central Bank Treasurer Sergio Edeza told Reuters &quot;we'll use it (the interest rate) if necessary (to stabilize the market). We'll just have to wait. I believe it has calmed down actually.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders share the view the peso would stabilize on Friday.</p>
<p>Another foreign bank dealer said some banks took advantage of the peso's slide to sell dollars, knowing that the stock market has turned bullish again and more foreign funds will be pouring in.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a heaven-sent rumour,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- LILIAN KARUNUNGAN (632) 841 8937</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
