<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9353" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta shares end up as political tension eases.</title>
<headline>Jakarta shares end up as political tension eases.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta share prices closed firmer on Thursday on the back of foreign buying and active secondaries as the country's political tensions appeared to ease somewhat, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Jakarta composite index rose 2.08 points, or 0.38 percent, to close at 544.28 points. Gainers led losers by 49 to 47, with 37 counters unchanged.</p>
<p>Brokers said market sentiment was firmer in late trading after news that opposition figure Megawati Sukarnoputri may come to a deal with the government to end the row over her ejection as leader of the Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI).  </p>
<p>&quot;I believe the goverment will push Megawati to come to an agreement,&quot; one local broker said.</p>
<p>Another broker said he believed there would be no fruther disturbances in connection with the PDI. &quot;It will help the market regain confidence,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Sentiment has been poor on the Jakarta bourse since riots erupted in the city on July 27 after police evicted supporters of Megawati from the PDI headquarters.</p>
<p>Brokers said foreign buying had boosted market sentiment and local players continued buying speculatively on second and thirdliners.  </p>
<p>Big and medium-size stocks Telkom Indonesia, Semen Gresik, Bimantara Citra and Citra Marga Nusaphala were among the targets of foreigners as they said the prices were at bargain levels.</p>
<p>Small stock Jembo Cable topped the active list with 12.0 million shares traded, rising 100 rupiah to 975. Brokers said the rise was due to speculative interest following firmer market sentiment.</p>
<p>Semen Gresik rose 325 rupiah to 6,150 on a volume of 1.7 million shares. --- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
