<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9360" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: U.S. customs permitted to visit HK factories.</title>
<headline>U.S. customs permitted to visit HK factories.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong sought to resolve a textiles dispute with the United States by announcing on Thursday it would permit U.S. customs officials to inspect Hong Kong factories.</p>
<p>The United States angered the territory's textile producers by imposing stringent country-of-origin certification requirements on June 17.</p>
<p>Washington said the aim was to stamp out efforts by Chinese textile producers to dodge quota limits with false &quot;made in Hong Kong&quot; labels.</p>
<p>Hong Kong had earlier refused U.S. demands for access to factories but has changed its mind in the hope of persuading the United States that its export controls were stringent enough to prevent false labelling.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope that the 30-day visit programme will prove a constructive way of getting round the two sides' differences over the matter of joint verification,&quot; a government spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;If not, we will consider other options, including referring the matter to the World Trade Organisation (WTO),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The visits by the eight U.S. customs officers will be subject to the consent of the factory owners, he said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong objected to the unilateral imposition of the new measures on 10 clothing categories.</p>
<p>Hong Kong argued the requirements applied only to products from the British colony and were therefore discriminatory.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
