<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9366" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China rate cut to impact in longer term - analysts.</title>
<headline>China rate cut to impact in longer term - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Alison Leung</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's intention to cut bank lending rates by 1.2 percentage points from Friday was well received but it would not impact immediately on state-owned companies nor the economy, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;There has always been a time lag and the effect from China's first interest rate cut in May has not surfaced yet,&quot; said Joanne Yim, economic research manager with Hang Seng Bank.</p>
<p>But expectations of the imminent rate cut have already boosted shares of Hong Kong-listed China companies on Thursday, with the H-share index closing at a 12-week high on hopes of improved business conditions.</p>
<p>China would cut bank deposit rates by 1.5 percent and lending rates by 1.2 percentage points from Friday.</p>
<p>An official China newspaper which reported on Thursday that conditions were ripe for a further interest rate cut pushed the H-share index to close at 841.17, up 21.95 points or nearly three percent, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very good news for the (H-share) companies and I'm turning more positive though I have been positive since April,&quot; Ching Ju Yeh, a senior investment manager with HSBC Asset Management Asia-Pacific Ltd, said.</p>
<p>HSBC Asset manages five China funds with a total size of US$50 million.</p>
<p>But Yeh said she would not rush to push up the H-share rating in HSBC funds, which account for between eight to 10 percent of the company's China fund portfolio.</p>
<p>&quot;It helps sentiment but I wouldn't say that's the only factor for me to consider to put more money in the sector,&quot; she said, adding that some H-share companies were still burdened with structural problems which need time to resolve.</p>
<p>Economists and analysts said lower interest rates would help ease interest payment burdens of many state-owned industrial companies in China.</p>
<p>But an analyst at a European house said long-term bank loans allocated to state-owned companies would normally have their rates fixed at the drawdown and for usual periods of five years.</p>
<p>&quot;Those companies that borrowed short-term working capital might benefit,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Analysts said an interest rate cut would not necessarily mean easier and cheaper credit for companies.</p>
<p>But Hang Seng's Yim said the Chinese economy would benefit as a whole from the rate cut since this would be a sign for further easing of monetary policy.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of the state-owned enterprises are facing operational problems due to the lack of working capital and heavy financial burden under higher interest rates,&quot; Yim said.</p>
<p>In the first quarter of 1996, China's state sector made a net loss of 3.0 billion yuan, the first deficit since paramount leader Deng Xiaopeng launched market reforms 17 years ago.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom  (852) 2843 6369</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
