<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9379" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK insurance authority to check on reserves.</title>
<headline>HK insurance authority to check on reserves.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's insurance authority said on Thursday that it was launching an investigation into the reserve funds of insurance companies after recent allegations that the industry was underprovided.</p>
<p>Calculations would be made to decide how much reserves insurance companies needed to keep and the body would then try to come to a consensus with companies involved, a top official with the Office of Commissioner of Insurance said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are allegations that the industry as a whole is underprovided for workmen's compensation and motor insurance, so we are carrying out an industry-wide investigation,&quot; assistant commissioner Joseph Mok said by telephone.</p>
<p>Ratings agency Standard &amp; Poor's recently said the local insurance industry could be under-reserved for motor vehicle insurance and workmen's compensation by HK$2 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The Standard and Poor's report has some foundation but to what extent we have to check,&quot; Mok said.</p>
<p>Mok said the investigation, slated to be completed by year end, would be carried out on 105 of Hong Kong's 223 insurance companies, which offer motor vehicle insurance and workmen's compensation coverage.</p>
<p>--Hong Kong newsroom (852) 28436441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
