<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9380" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK forwarders understand new air cargo rate rise.</title>
<headline>HK forwarders understand new air cargo rate rise.</headline>
<byline>Jim Gilchrist</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Freight forwarders in Hong Kong say they understand airlines increasing air cargo rates to Europe for the second time in two months.</p>
<p>The HK$2 a kg rise from October 1 was informally agreed at a meeting of Hong Kong's main air cargo carriers to Europe and follows a similarly imposed HK$3 a kg rise from August 1.</p>
<p>Sam Chung, chairman of the 260 member Hong Kong Association of Freight Forwarding Agents Ltd said market forces would prevail.</p>
<p>&quot;If the market stands for it then we are not against a rate don't mind because we know most airlines are suffering from limited profit and they need revenue. The trouble is if the market can't stand it the forwarders will be squeezed and put in trouble. There is always the possibility of that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chung, who is also director and general manager of Fritz Air Freight (HK) Ltd, said he doubted whether August's HK$3 increase has been fully passed on to all freight forwarders.</p>
<p>Some airlines are still charging the previous rates depending on whether they have space on aircraft and Asian airlines were more likely to offer deals and not pass on the full rate rise, he added.</p>
<p>On transpacific rates to the U.S. east coast, Chung said there is now a slow and peak season rate with a difference of around US20 cents per pound. Chung expects the peak season to start in October when rates will rise.</p>
<p>For the U.S. west coast, the peak season starts a month earlier in September with some airlines gradually increasing their rates towards Christmas, he added</p>
<p>&quot;It is more complicated for cargo rates to the U.S. and Canada and very difficult to tell what sort of rate the airlines will be charging this year,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The association's vice chairman, Anthony Lau, said it was up to individual forwarders whether the rate rise would be passed on to their customers.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very sympathetic to the airlines' position. In the last couple of years rates have been very soft and lower than what they were 10 years ago and they're trying to get back to a more reasonable level But whether or not the market can support the rise we will have to see. If the market is firm, I'm sure customers will accept that, but if it soft then we will have to tell the airlines and try and reach a compromise.&quot; Lau said.</p>
<p>Lau, chairman of the Hong Kong forwarding company Baltrans Ltd, which is a member of Baltrans Holdings Ltd said when airlines increased rates in the past his customers had been very reluctant to pay.</p>
<p>Freight forwarders will probably absorb this new rate for a maximum of three weeks, he added.</p>
<p>The westbound rate increase was agreed by a meeting of leading cargo carriers to Europe from Hong Kong on August 14. Among the airlines represented were Alitalia British Airways World Cargo, Cargolux Airlines International, China Airlines, Cathay Pacific Airways Ltd, Emirates, AHK Air Hong Kong Ltd, Malaysia Airline System Bhd, Martinair NV, Sinagpore Airlines Ltd, Swissair, Thai Airways International, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Jacky Lau, Hong Kong cargo manager for Dubai-based Emirates, said the rate increase was due to low yields and increased operating costs .</p>
<p>Swissair Hong Kong cargo manager, Edwin Cheung, which operates five flights a week to Zurich, said the second rate rise is necessary because August's HK$3 a kilo rate rise has not been implemented by all airlines.</p>
<p>&quot;Since May last year there has been a HK$6 a kilo drop and we are trying to get back that loss. Operating costs are higher and higher and we are trying to get back to the old level,&quot; Cheung added. --Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44-171-542-7706 Fax+44-171-542-5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
