<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9385" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan VP coy on reported Kuchma meeting.</title>
<headline>Taiwan VP coy on reported Kuchma meeting.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan Vice-President Lien Chan said on Thursday he had talked to people &quot;of all levels&quot; during a secretive Kiev visit that angered China but declined to confirm reports he had met the Ukrainian president.</p>
<p>&quot;I met the people I wanted to meet and discussed the things I wanted to discuss,&quot; Lien said on his return to Taiwan when asked to confirm whether he had met President Leonid Kuchma. &quot;But I cannot identify who I met by name. That would not live up to the agreement I made before visiting.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;In Ukraine, I met people from all levels, specific people, and had a full exchange of views,&quot; Lien told reporters at Taipei's international airport.</p>
<p>Lien used similarly coy language when asked to confirm Taiwan media reports, including one in the ruling Nationalist Party's Central Daily News, that Taiwan and Ukraine had agreed to exchange unofficial representative offices.</p>
<p>&quot;We both think that we should promote relations on the basis of organisations. That was the consensus,&quot; Lien said, choosing his words carefully.</p>
<p>&quot;As for a setting up a representative office, Ukraine understands that we have such offices in Russia, Belarus and elsewhere and they understand the importance,&quot; he said. &quot;There should be some subsequent development in this matter.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
