<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9388" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Fighting the summer slowdown.</title>
<headline>ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Fighting the summer slowdown.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian debt markets were quiet again on Thursday, but bankers said some borrowers are fighting off the summer torpor and seeking new funding opportunities.</p>
<p>Korea Exchange Bank Hong Kong mandated a 364-day HK$500 million floating rate certificate of deposit issue to Chase Manhattan Asia and Jardine Fleming Bank.</p>
<p>Some Hong Kong companies also are looking for dollars, both of the Hong Kong and U.S. variety, bankers said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong Chinese Bank is in the market now for US$50 million, and Guoco Group is expected to launch its US$180 million deal in the next couple of weeks.</p>
<p>Union Bank of Hong Kong also has mandated a group of banks to arrange a U.S. dollar deal.</p>
<p>Manhattan Card is canvassing the market, as are a number of Hong Kong banks eager to lock in funding before year-end, bankers said.</p>
<p>Ka Wah Bank today set a HK$43 million FRCD to be privately placed by HSBC Markets.</p>
<p>In other news from Hong Kong, Sino Land said it plans to securitise the rental income of one of its investment properties to raise HK$1.0 billion as a cheaper alternative to loan financing.</p>
<p>Securitisation in Hong Kong has a checkered history, with the few transactions structured in 1994 and 1995 failing to attract much investor demand.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, bankers expect to hear news of a new mandates from Korean issuers, including at least one more &quot;Kangaroo&quot; bond.</p>
<p>Korea Development Bank earlier this month became the first Asian borrower to tap domestic Australian bond markets with its so-called Kangaroo issue.</p>
<p>A few deals finished up on Thursday.</p>
<p>AsiaSat closed its US$250 million loan, with 12 banks signing on.</p>
<p>Samsung Hong Kong raised its transferable loan certificates deal to US$100 million from US$50 million after it was ovesubscribed in syndication, arranger DKB Asia said.</p>
<p>-- Andrea Ricci (852) 2843-6371 fax (852) 2845-0636</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
