<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9396" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan CPC to meet partners over Ecuador dispute.</title>
<headline>Taiwan CPC to meet partners over Ecuador dispute.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's Chinese Petroleum Corp said it and four partners would meet on Friday to discuss ways to continue exploring for oil in Ecuador, which has threatened to halt their operations.</p>
<p>&quot;Our representative in Ecuador will meet our partners on Friday to discuss the Ecuador government's plan to revise contracts,&quot; Chinese Petroleum vice president Pan Wen-yen told Reuters on Thursday.</p>
<p>The head of Ecuador state oil company Petroecuador, Paticio Lopez, said this week the government would revise all contracts with foreign companies extracting crude from Ecuadoran soil &quot;so that each one becomes a benefit for the state.&quot;</p>
<p>Pan said Chinese Petroleum learned of Ecuador's requests from its partner, Marxus Ecuador Inc, also known as Maxus.</p>
<p>Another Chinese Petroleum official said it appeared that Ecuador's government was demanding a stake in their joint venture.</p>
<p>Chinese Petroleum officials said the company hoped to continue oil exploration in Ecuador despite Quito's bid to revise foreign firms' contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;Chinese Petroleum will try to stay there to continue its oil exploration projects,&quot; oil exploration director Yeh Tien-shun said.</p>
<p>Yeh said Taiwan's oil monopoly would study any regulatory changes proposed or made by the Ecuador government.</p>
<p>Chinese Petroleum has a joint oil drilling operation in Ecuador's Block 16 with daily oil production of 30,000 barrels and in Block 17, which has yet to produce, Yeh said.</p>
<p>Maxus holds 35 percent of the joint venture while Chinese Petroleum's subsidiary Overseas Petroleum and Investment Corp holds 31 percent, a Chinese Petroleum document showed.</p>
<p>Nomeco Ecuador Oil Company has 14 percent and Canam Offshore Ltd and Murphy Ecuador Oil Co each hold 10 percent, it said.</p>
<p>Chinese Petroleum officials would not comment on how talks with Ecuador might proceed, but said they agreed in principle that foreign investment must bring benefits to the local economy.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign investors like Chinese Petroleum should include plans to benefit the local people,&quot; Yeh said.</p>
<p>Another Chinese Petroleum official said it was unlikely the Ecuadoran army would occupy Block 16, despite news reports that it might.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no need for Ecuador's government to use the army to occupy any block,&quot; Chinese Petroleum official Liao Pai-fon said. &quot;We will wait and see what deals the Ecuador government wants to reach.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (2-5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
