<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9399" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Eurodollar, Euroyen in limbo on stable rates.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Eurodollar, Euroyen in limbo on stable rates.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Eurodollars and Euroyen futures were trapped in limbo on Thursday after the Federal Reserve left U.S. rates unchanged, dealers said.</p>
<p>Dealers said a lack of fresh news after Tuesday's Federal Open Market Committee meeting kept most players sidelined, resulting in a dismal Eurodollars futures.</p>
<p>However, they said they hoped U.S. jobless claims data, due later on Thursday, could provide some fresh trading incentive.</p>
<p>December Eurodollars ended up two ticks from their IMM close at 94.23 while March was up a tick, at 94.10.</p>
<p>Total turnover for the two contracts was at 10,100 lots.  </p>
<p>Euroyen faired better than Eurodollars in terms of activity, dealers said.</p>
<p>After trading in a narrow band, December Euroyen ended at 99.16, up four ticks from its CME close. March was at 98.93, up a tick from its CME close.</p>
<p>Turnover for December and March Euroyen was at 8,700 and 6,800 lots respectively.</p>
<p>A dealer said a Japanese newspaper report suggesting that the Bank of Japan might hike rates was quickly dismissed as unfounded. The market focus was now on the August 28 Tankan.  </p>
<p>The market expectation was for the Japanese economy to continue to show a gradual improvement. Expectations were for the Bank of Japan to maintain short-term rates or at worse, increase them by a quarter percentage point.</p>
<p>The Japanese government bond (JGB) futures made another feeble attempt to break 121.00 resistance but failed.</p>
<p>After inching to a high at 120.94, September JGB ended at 120.74, down 19 ticks from previous. Turnover was light at 378 lots.</p>
<p>-- Angela Tan, Singapore newsroom (65 8703083)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
