<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9404" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia conglomerates eye Singapore-listed firms.</title>
<headline>Indonesia conglomerates eye Singapore-listed firms.</headline>
<byline>Helen Lumban Gaol</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian conglomerates are moving to take over Singapore-listed firms as part of a strategy to become regional players and for a safe haven in case the domestic political situation worsens, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Singapore stock exchange was rocked last week by takeover proposals for two listed companies by Indonesia's Sinar Mas Group and tobacco tycoon Putera Sampoerna.</p>
<p>On August 16, Price Waterhouse, interim judicial managers for the besieged Amcol Holdings Ltd, said PT Sinar Mas Tunggal, part of Indonesia's diversified Sinar Mas group, would buy Amcol, revamp it and inject US$2.0 billion in assets.</p>
<p>The next day, a company owned by Indonesian tobacco tycoon Putera Sampoerna, who controls cigarette producer PT Hanjaya Mandala Sampoerna, said it was making a conditional takeover offer for the Singapore-based trading and telecommunications company Transmarco Holdings.</p>
<p>Some Indonesian analysts said the moves were part of business strategies to expand but others linked it to recent political unrest in Indonesia.</p>
<p>Laksono Widodo, an analyst with ING Barings Securities in Jakarta, said a takeover was the easiest and the cheapest way to be listed in Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;By buying troubled listed firms at discounted prices, they suddenly become a listed company in an overseas bourse without going through regulation obstacles,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An analyst from a Hong Kong brokerage firm, who asked not to be identified, said the moves could have been triggered by fears of a worsening political situation in Indonesia.</p>
<p>&quot;Amid uncertainity in the domestic political situation, troubled firms listed overseas give new alternatives for them. So I think the moves are being made for a combination of business and political reasons,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Indonesia has witnessed political unrest since June when the government successfully backed efforts by a faction of the Indonesian Democratic Party to oust popular party chief Megawati Sukarnoputroi.</p>
<p>Riots erupted in Jakarta last month after police evicted Megawati's supporters from the PDI headquarters. A forced calm has prevailed since then but political analysts say dissent against the government is still widespread.</p>
<p>Economist Christianto Wibisono said the moves to acquire listed companies overseas were not a new trend.</p>
<p>&quot;Indonesian companies started to establish or acquire companies overseas a few years ago but recently the moves have gained pace. I think it is a part of their global strategy not to depend only on one country or place,&quot; said Wibisono, director of the Indonesia Business Data Centre.</p>
<p>He also said Indonesian conglomerates would continue eyeing troubled listed firm overseas which could be used as vehicles to mobilise fresh funds from international sources.</p>
<p>&quot;In the case of Amcol and Sinar Mas Tunggal, I believe their main concern is Amcol's status as a listed company, not other factors. By having a listed firm, they can easily raise money from overseas,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wibisono said political factors could play a role but added he believed Indonesian conglomerates still prefered doing business in Indonesia.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of assets, their biggest assets are here and they enjoy a lot of facilities here,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
