<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9405" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore oil products recover with crude.</title>
<headline>Singapore oil products recover with crude.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore oil product prices firmed on Thursday crude's recovery and bullish sentiment on Singapore refinery cuts in througputs.</p>
<p>Light distillate stocks fell to 4.879 million barrels, their lowest level since April 3 when levels were at 4.816 million barrels. Traders said refinery runs contributed to the fall which should prop up gasoline prices. But regional supplies were still ample with a Thai refiner heard sold 250,000 barrels of 92 octane unleaded at a 30 cent discount to Singapore prices fob mid-September. An Australian refiner confirmed selling a cargo to a U.S. refiner, with the cargo heard heading to the U.S.  </p>
<p>Gas oil and jet fuel prices rose but traders said the two products have been overpriced and expect some correction in September. They said the build in middle-distillates stocks for the week ended August 21 to 7.623 million barrels showed that there was some length on both products. At least two MidEast jet fuel cargoes were said heading east, with one Yanbu cargo being offered. Traders were monitoring Indonesia's September demand to see how it could support the market. Indonesia was said to have bought two to three cargoes for September out of an estimated demand of over one million barrels. 100,000 barrels of jet fuel was heard traded at $28.50 for mid-September lifting.  </p>
<p>Gas oil was actively bid with three buyers seen for mid September lifting at $24.45 to $24.50 a barrel fob. Projections into India's gas oil tender for October arrival ranged between 500,000-700,000 tonnes to 800,000-1.0 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Fuel oil prices rose by 50 cents with a bid heard for 180 cst at $103.50, up from Wednesday's bid/offer at $103/$105. Traders said regional demand from Thailand, Indonesia remained uncovered and reduced supplies due to refinery cuts and fewer Mideast supplies in August have supported prices. But in September, Chinese demand remained lacklustre while Mideast supplies were expected to be higher.--Singapore Newsroom</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
