<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9407" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Chinese soymeal imports hit one million tonnes.</title>
<headline>Chinese soymeal imports hit one million tonnes.</headline>
<byline>Mishi Saran</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>China has bought around a million tonnes of soymeal, mainly South American, since the start of the year and now only needs to cover for the fourth quarter, when it will probably turn to India, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically from July onwards people are waiting for their ordered meal to arrive so they can assess whether they overbought or not,&quot; said a Hong Kong-based grain source.  </p>
<p>&quot;After October and November, people will reassess the market and then perhaps start buying again if it looks good,&quot; another source said.</p>
<p>He said fourth quarter demand was likely to be covered from India because soymeal prices there should fall as the new soybean harvest comes onto the market by the end of November.</p>
<p>The trader added that Indian shipments were also more flexible because the soymeal was transported by smaller vessels which can be accomodated by smaller Chinese ports more easily than the large Panamax ships from South America.  </p>
<p>Soymeal deliveries reached a peak of about 100,000 tonnes a week in the second quarter and the steady pattern of imports has kept domestic prices stable and surprised some traders.</p>
<p>&quot;The price of meal in China is about 2,800 yuan ($337) a tonne and has been very stable over the past few months,&quot; a Dalian-based Chinese grain trader.</p>
<p>&quot;We made a mistake in May,&quot; another Chinese source said, &quot;We thought arrivals would be big in June and July, but this did not materialise, so the market did not drop as we thought it would.&quot; He said his company had expected a 100-yuan ($12) a tonne drop in domestic soymeal prices by early August.  </p>
<p>&quot;They (Chinese traders) were buying spreading out from June all the way to October and November,&quot; the source said. He said China now only needs to cover positions for the last quarter.</p>
<p>By January, imports will slow to a trickle in the slow season for soymeal consumption, another trader said.</p>
<p>Demand for soymeal -- a component of animal feed -- has burgeoned as China's livestock industry grows on the back of increasing meat consumption driven by higher living standards. ($1=8.3 yuan)</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
