<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9419" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Scores of relocated villagers said dying in Burma.</title>
<headline>Scores of relocated villagers said dying in Burma.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Scores of villagers die every month in a Burmese government relocation camp where thousands of people have been herded under the military's counter-insurgency plans, Burmese dissidents have said.</p>
<p>Most of the dead were women and old people, victims of malaria and diarrhoea, the All Burma Students' Democratic Front (ABSDF) said in a statement received on Thursday.</p>
<p>The villagers are mostly from the Karenni ethnic minority and were ordered out of their homes in the hills of eastern Burma's Kayah state earlier this year as the Burmese army battled Karenni guerrillas in the area.</p>
<p>&quot;At least 150 newly relocated Karenni refugees died within the month of July at the new relocation site in Shadaw town,&quot; the ABSDF said.</p>
<p>The dissidents, citing villagers who fled from the relocation site to the Thai-Burmese border, said people were living in overcrowded conditions without medical assistance.</p>
<p>There was no independent confirmation of the deaths but the forced relocation of civilians from areas in which rebels operate is a standard Burmese army counter-insurgency tactic.</p>
<p>The Burmese army has forced more than 10,000 people from their homes in Kayah state in an attempt to isolate the guerrillas in the area, Burmese opposition sources say.</p>
<p>The relocation sites are on the edges of government garrison towns.</p>
<p>Anyone remaining in the hills is liable to be regarded as an insurgent and risked being shot, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Many Karenni villagers were killed by the SLORC troops for failing to obey the order,&quot; the ABSDF said, referring to the ruling military body, the State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC).</p>
<p>Several thousand Karenni refugees have trekked from their hills to camps just inside Thailand in recent months to escape the forced relocations, refugee workers in Thailand said.</p>
<p>Karenni guerrillas signed a ceasefire with the SLORC in March last year but the truce collapsed several months later and intermittent fighting has continued in several parts of Kayah state since then.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
