<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9420" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea's Kim warns of military threats by North.</title>
<headline>S.Korea's Kim warns of military threats by North.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean President Kim Young-sam said on Thursday that famine and a faltering economy in North Korea could trigger &quot;reckless&quot; military provocation by the rival communist neighbour.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a high possibility that the North could trigger reckless military provocations to overcome its three difficulties -- economy, international isoalation and risk of a collapse of its system,&quot; Kim said in a statement.</p>
<p>Experts on North Korea have warned of a possible collapse of the communist state after floods last year devastated the country and left it on the brink of famine. The floods ruined crops and left about 100,000 people homeless.</p>
<p>Pyongyang said it was hit again last month by torrential rains that killed at least 116 people and caused about $1.7 billion in damage.</p>
<p>Kim visited the U.S.-South Korea command post in Songnam, south of Seoul, to inspect the annual military wargames codenamed &quot;Ulchi Focus Lens&quot;. He was briefed by General John Tilelli, commander-in-chief of the Korean and American combined forces.</p>
<p>The wargames are designed to evaluate and improve coordination between the troops in contingency operations.</p>
<p>&quot;I ask you to contribute to stability in the Korean Peninsula and East Asia as well as to world peace by reinforcing war preparations between South Korea and the United States,&quot; Kim told the troops.</p>
<p>South Korea launched the joint military and civil exercises on Monday. They are expected to last until August 30.</p>
<p>About 300,000 people will take part in the exercise, which will include the staging of mock air raids, acts of arson and terrorist attacks.</p>
<p>The government also conducted nationwide civil defence drills on Wednesday as part of the exercise.</p>
<p>About 37,000 American servicemen, backed by 655,000 South Korean military personnel, confront communist North Korea's 1.1 million-strong army across the world's last Cold War frontier.</p>
<p>The Stalinist North has accused Seoul and Washington of holding the Ulchi exercise as &quot;a rehearsal for invasion&quot; of the North. Pyongyang has demanded the military exercise be cancelled, saying it would drive the Korean peninsula to the brink of crisis.</p>
<p>Seoul and Washington cancelled their full-scale annual &quot;Team Spirit&quot; military drill this year, an exercise far larger than Ulchi Focus Lens, hoping to ease tension between the Koreas. The two nations technically remain at war since their 1950-53 conflict.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
