<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9422" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian crudes weaker, more Minas deals said done.</title>
<headline>Asian crudes weaker, more Minas deals said done.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crude oil prices were moderately weaker on Thursday with talk of more Minas deals while the Brent/Dubai spread narrowed slightly following Brent's overnight losses.</p>
<p>Traders said players were easing into the October MidEast market and the September regional market but with little urgency.</p>
<p>Brent/Dubai narrowed following the second-day Wednesday of a market correction in Brent. Brent/Dubai for October to $1.85/$1.95 per barrel, in from $1.85/$2.05 on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Dubai intermonth spreads were steady around 30 cents for October/November and November/December.</p>
<p>Paper Tapis fell, tracking the overnight fall on Brent and NYMEX. September paper Tapis was assessed $20.95/$21.05, down 15 cents from a day-earlier.</p>
<p>General talk on regional grades was quiet but another Minas deal was heard done -- 200,000 barrels at ICP  minus 25 cents per barrel to a U.S. major.</p>
<p>In addition, 100,000 barrels were heard done to a Japanese refinery at ICP  minus 30 cents. Both deals could not be immediately confirmed.  </p>
<p>The deals added to a Tuesday deal when a major sold 200,000 barrels of Minas to Korean refinery at ICP less 25 cents.</p>
<p>A major was said to have sold an October Murban cargo at ADNOC +15 cents, but some traders suggested the talk was speculative.</p>
<p>Workers at Shell's 115,000 barrels-per-day refinery in Australia voted to return to work Friday after walking out over a pay dispute August 13.</p>
<p>--Singapore, N. Fullick (+65 870 3081), J. Oshima, Tokyo (+813 5473-3708)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
