<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9427" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia gas oil, jet fuel overpriced, correction seen.</title>
<headline>Asia gas oil, jet fuel overpriced, correction seen.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>High Asian gas oil and jet fuel prices were causing concerns among sellers in Singapore who were facing difficulties in finding outlets for their rising stocks, traders said on Thursday.</p>
<p>High stocks in Singapore and South Korea and few outlets, were expected to force a downward price correction in September, they said. &quot;Prices are way out of control,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;They are being priced on paper (swaps) market rather than on demand and supply fundamentals and are out of touch with reality. We are having a tough time moving barrels because of the high prices,&quot; the trader added.  </p>
<p>Gas oil prices have been climbing since July 10 when it touched a low of $23.75 a barrel to the current $25.50. Jet fuel prices have been even stronger, climbing from $23.65 on June 27 to current levels of above $28.50.</p>
<p>Traders said they were finding it hard to sell jet fuel at 30-40 cents a barrel above Singapore spot quotes, free-on-board basis (fob) and gas oil at 40-50 cents premiums.</p>
<p>They said there were &quot;some length&quot; in gas oil supplies in Singapore, rather than a full storage situation, while the MidEast market was quite tight. But one trader said he was not surprised if jet fuel stocks here were at &quot;tank-top.&quot;  </p>
<p>Traders therefore had expected Singapore's weekly middle-distillates stocks to rise. The Trade Development Board announced on Thursday stocks level for the week ended August 21, rose by 335,000 barrels to 7.623 million barrels, the highest since early April.</p>
<p>Traders said Singapore refiners were feeling some anxieties as there were excess South Korean cargoes--estimated between seven and 10--while China was not buying large volumes. They said high gas oil prices have spooked away Chinese buyers who continued to hold on to bids of $190 a tonne, cost-and-freight basis, while sellers were seeking around $200.  </p>
<p>China was estimated to have bought only 250,000 tonnes of gas oil in August and were not expected to buy more than that for September at current prices. China's purchases have been limited to small lots rather than the normal 25,000-tonne cargoes, traders said.</p>
<p>They also said India's purchase of only 255,000 tonnes for September added a bearish undertone for the month.</p>
<p>While Indonesia was expected to give some boost, its additional gas oil and jet fuel demand due to the shutdown of two refineries in September and October might not be enough to offset the softer demand from China and India, they said.  </p>
<p>Some traders expect Indonesia to buy around 3.0 million barrels of gas oil and over 1.0 million barrels of jet fuel for September.</p>
<p>Japan's winter kerosene stockpiling has also not stirred spot market activities and traders said the current high prices might slip in September. South Korean winter jet fuel imports were expected to drop 20 percent from last year as endusers buy more term barrels and as Korean refiners become self-sufficient with the startup of new units.</p>
<p>At least two MidEast jet fuel cargoes were also seen heading east in September, adding to regional supplies, traders said.  </p>
<p>But traders painted a different picture for the middle-distillate market in October. India was expected to give some boost to gas oil with estimates for its October tender ranging from 500,000-700,000 tonnes to as high as 800,000-1.0 million tonnes. Traders also expect to see serious purchases from Japan from October to stock for the winter.</p>
<p>--Singapore newsroom (+65-8703084)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
