<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9428" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: China, Taiwan exchange calls for resuming talks.</title>
<headline>China, Taiwan exchange calls for resuming talks.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Parker</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan and China restated their willingness on Thursday to resume talks stalled a year ago over the Nationalist island's drive to wriggle free of political isolation enforced by its huge communist neighbour.</p>
<p>&quot;Now is the time for the two sides to engage in political talks...to end the state of hostility,&quot; China's top negotiator, Tang Shubei, was quoted by mainland state media as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;China wants peaceful reunification. ... Political disputes should be resolved through political talks,&quot; Tang said.</p>
<p>Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Shen Guofang, in a subsequent interview in Beijing, was less enthusiastic, repeating Beijing's line that Taipei was holding up talks.</p>
<p>&quot;The necessary atmosphere for the opening of the talks has been disrupted by the Taiwan authorities,&quot; Shen told Reuters.</p>
<p>Taiwan issued a positive, though noncommittal, response.</p>
<p>&quot;We have never ruled out talks on political issues with the mainland,&quot; said Kao Koong-lian of Taiwan's policymaking Mainland Affairs Council. &quot;The most urgent thing right now is to resume negotiations.&quot;</p>
<p>Kao indicated the top agenda item should be Taiwan's ties with Hong Kong during the British colony's return to Chinese sovereignty in mid-1997.</p>
<p>Analysts were quick to note that previous calls for talks had come to naught, although they pointed out that China's earlier expressions had called for a &quot;timetable for talks&quot; while Tang's latest comment said the time for talks had come.</p>
<p>The mutual calls coincided with Beijing's furious censure of the former Soviet republic Ukraine, which offended China by allowing a private visit by Taiwan Vice President Lien Chan.</p>
<p>Taiwan media said Lien won agreement to swap unofficial representative offices with Ukraine during an &quot;unofficial&quot; meeting with President Leonid Kuchma.</p>
<p>Kuchma aides in Kiev -- acknowledging China's fury -- denied that any such meeting took place.</p>
<p>Taiwan's government said there would be no comment before Lien returned to Taipei late on Thursday.</p>
<p>Beijing has viewed Taiwan as a rebel province since a civil war split them in 1949, pushing it into isolation and reserving the right to use force to bring it under China's red flag.</p>
<p>China on Monday won the latest round in its diplomatic tug-of-war with Taiwan, restoring ties with Niger four years after it switched recognition to Taipei. Only 30 states now recognise Taiwan's exiled Republic of China.</p>
<p>China on Tuesday launched a separate effort to woo Taiwan back to the fold, publishing rules governing direct shipping links across the Taiwan Strait despite Taiwan's 47-year-old ban on direct investment, transport and communications.</p>
<p>The rules fuelled new hopes among many Taiwan investors, who have poured at least $20 billion into China and clamour for the huge cost savings that direct links would provide.</p>
<p>It remained to be seen whether Taipei or Beijing would allow vessels flying third-country flags to pioneer direct routes.</p>
<p>After decades of cross-straits enmity, an economic thaw began in the late 1980s and heralded historic quasi-official talks in Singapore in 1993, which evolved in turn into increasingly productive contacts.</p>
<p>But relations crashed in mid-1995 after Washington allowed Taiwan President Lee Teng-hui to make a private U.S. visit.</p>
<p>Beijing assailed Lee's journey as a breach of Washington's &quot;one China&quot; policy, the cornerstone of U.S.-China ties.</p>
<p>It also punished Taiwan by freezing the talks and mounting a campaign of intimidating war games and missile tests in waters near the island that peaked just before Taiwan's unprecedented popular presidential election on March 23.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
