<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9430" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai interbank rate down again, baht firmer late.</title>
<headline>Thai interbank rate down again, baht firmer late.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Thai overnight interbank rate eased to a three-month low of 4.50-5.00 percent in late trade on Thursday from 5.75 percent earlier and 6.00-7.00 percent late on Wednesday on an extremely high money supply, dealers said.</p>
<p>Dealers said liquidity was high because banks were trying to lend out reduce surplus funds after the passing of central bank reserve requirements on thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The interbank rate is likelty to rebound tomorrow as banks will take advantage of the low rate to accumulate funds for the next reserve requirements,&quot; said a dealer at a foreign bank.  </p>
<p>All commercial banks have to meet the Bank of Thailand reserve requirements on the seventh and 22nd of every month.</p>
<p>The baht edged up to 25.296-25.299 to the dollar in late trade from 25.297-25.302 earlier on local dollar selling, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;I heard some offshore banks were selling dollars in order to reduce long dollar position,&quot; said a currency dealer. &quot;But there was little interest for dollars today as most players have already squared their positions.&quot;  </p>
<p>The one-month swap premium was at 6.75/7.50 satangs per dollar late compared with 7.00 earlier.</p>
<p>The mid-rate was fixed unchanged at 25.30 baht to the dollar.</p>
<p>-- Tang Nguyen (662) 252-9950</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
