<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9443" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL shares end lower on profit-taking.</title>
<headline>KL shares end lower on profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue chips closed lower on profit-taking after Wednesday's sharp run-up, as interest reverted back to second line stocks, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Focus was back on second liners although most counters lost their morning gains at the close,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>He said Wednesday's gains among blue chips were sharp and had to be digested.</p>
<p>The benchmark Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange Composite Index ended at 1,120.76, down 2.06 points, after rising 17.38 points on Wednesday. The Second Board index ended down 1.43 points at 505.00 after hitting a day's high of 512.55.  </p>
<p>Market volume was 190.9 million shares, with losers leading gainers 373 to 190.</p>
<p>Malayan Banking, which led the market's surge on Wednesday, backtracked down 10 cents to 23.80 ringgit.</p>
<p>Newly-listed Second Board stock, SHH Resources, closed at 10.30 ringgit against an offer price of 4.40 ringgit. It traded as high as 11.50 ringgit.</p>
<p>Golden Hope Plantations rose six cents to 3.94 ringgit. Its full-year net profit of 209.3 million ringgit or 20.9 cents a share was above market expectations.</p>
<p>-- Syed Azman (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
