<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9444" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia rubber ends steady on Thai flood signals.</title>
<headline>Malaysia rubber ends steady on Thai flood signals.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian rubber prices closed steady on optimism that impending floods in Thailand will boost regional prices, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Heavy rain has been reported in northern and central Thailand by our dealers and this is in an indication that the monsoon season is going to hit Thailand soon,&quot; said David Khoo, a trader with Safic-Alcan in Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>The rains will mean reduced production and higher prices, Khoo said, adding: &quot;If Thailand raises its rubber prices, so will Malaysia and Indonesia.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said the market was quiet through the day.  </p>
<p>At the close, the Malaysian Rubber Exchange and Licensing Board set market indicator price for September RSS1 buyer at 321 cents ($1.29) a kg, unchanged from Tuesday. September SMR20 buyer was 1.5 cents higher at 304.</p>
<p>Traders retained Wednesday's offer rates. The SMR20 was offered at 303 cents, SMR10 at 304, SMR5 at 315-316, SMR CV at 370-372, SMR L at 353-355 and drum latex FOB at 247-248.</p>
<p>The INRO five-day average fell to 245.76 Malaysian/Singapore cents per kg on August 21 from 246.21 on August 20. The daily indicator dipped to 245.36 from 244.81.</p>
<p>-- Barani Krishnaan (603-230-7510) ($1=2.4950 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
