<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9452" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Amnesty International condemns Vietnam trial.</title>
<headline>Amnesty International condemns Vietnam trial.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Human rights group Amnesty International has condemned Vietnam's decision to place two prominent dissidents on trial on Thursday.</p>
<p>The London-based organisation said in a facsimiled statement that Le Hong Ha and Ha Si Phu faced jail terms of up to 15 years &quot;only for questioning the political views of the Vietnamese government.&quot;</p>
<p>Le Hong Ha, a former high-ranking member of the Communist Party, and Ha Si Phu, a leading academic, were arrested last year amid a broader crackdown on dissent during the run-up to Vietnam's Eighth Communist Party Congress.</p>
<p>The pair have been accused of divulging state secrets. Ha Si Phu is said to have openly criticised Hanoi during an interview with a foreign radio station.</p>
<p>Le Hong Ha had been expelled from the Communist Party after voicing support for another dissident, Hoang Minh Chinh.</p>
<p>Their trial was due to begin later on Thursday, with sentencing likely to be announced the same day. A foreign ministry spokesman said the trial was closed to foreign reporters.</p>
<p>The U.S.-based group Human Rights Watch/Asia earlier accused Hanoi of violating international laws at the time of their arrest last year. Vietnam is a signatory to the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
