<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9453" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Arafat, Peres meet as Israel-PLO ties strained.</title>
<headline>Arafat, Peres meet as Israel-PLO ties strained.</headline>
<byline>Taher Shriteh</byline>
<dateline>BEIT HANOUN, Gaza Strip 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli-PLO ties reached crisis point on Thursday, rocked by a flap over a West Bank flight by Yasser Arafat and a meeting between the Palestinian President and former Israeli leader Shimon Peres.</p>
<p>Israel angered Arafat by holding up for three hours permission to fly over its territory by helicopter to the West Bank town of Ramallah for a scheduled meeting with Peres.</p>
<p>Palestinians said Arafat cancelled an Israeli-PLO meeting on civilian affairs in protest. The Palestinian leader met Peres in the evening in the self-ruled Gaza Strip. It was their first meeting since Peres lost Israel's May 29 elections.</p>
<p>Arafat and Peres, main architects of the 1993 PLO-Israel peace deal along with Israel's Yitzhak Rabin who was killed by a right-wing Jew last year, met for about an hour at the Palestinian military coordination headquarters.</p>
<p>They told reporters afterwards they were committed to protecting the peace deal.</p>
<p>&quot;In this meeting we had a very important discussion on how to protect and to push forward the peace process,&quot; Arafat said.</p>
<p>Peres said: &quot;You may have heard, I'm no longer in the government...neither did I come here to attack the government.&quot;</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;We made an agreement with the Palestinians... and I feel deeply obliged that every promise we made on behalf of the (previous) government, on behalf of the Israeli people should be respected.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If you replace rifles with words, words must be respected,&quot; Peres said. Israel Channel One television said Peres pledged to also aid the Palestinians to solve economic problems.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's election last May dismayed Palestinians, who in the 1993 deal won limited self-rule on the West Bank and Gaza and a commitment from Israel to negotiate a final peace.</p>
<p>Netanyahu opposes trading occupied land for peace and has so far refused to meet Arafat. The right-wing leader has yet to carry out a redeployment of Israeli troops in the West Bank town of Hebron, part of a deal signed last September.</p>
<p>Final peace talks, begun before the May election, have yet to resume.</p>
<p>Israel's army radio said Arafat told Peres that joint committees running security and civilian matters were no longer working as they should under the new Israeli administration.</p>
<p>Palestinian peace negotiator Hassan Asfour charged Netanyahu, who has accused Peres of trying to undermine his government's authority, of personally barring Arafat's flight.</p>
<p>David Bar-Illan, Netanyahu's communications director, dismissed the accusation, saying technical problems rather than political ones had kept Arafat grounded in Gaza.</p>
<p>Bar-Illan blasted Peres, 73, over the Arafat meeting and suggested he retire from politics and accept an &quot;elder statesman's&quot; role if he wanted to continue his peace efforts.</p>
<p>Netanyahu has accused Nobel peace laureate Peres of &quot;sticking spokes in the wheels of peace&quot; by meeting Arab leaders while in opposition.</p>
<p>After the two met, Israel's Itim news agency quoted Netanyahu as telling his Likud party: &quot;I understand Mr Peres has lots of time on his hands these days. We wish him lots and lots of free time.&quot;</p>
<p>Yossi Beilin, a former minister in Peres's cabinet, said the Labour party chief had every right to meet Arafat.</p>
<p>&quot;How can someone think he can stop the head of the opposition (Peres) from meeting Mr. Yasser Arafat? These are two people who brought about such great changes in the history of the region,&quot; Beilin told Israel Radio.</p>
<p>Ahmed Korei, speaker of the Palestinian Legislative Council, said the council dedicated its morning session to discussion of &quot;Israel's flagrant violation of the accords by restricting President Arafat's movement.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This is an attempt by the Israeli government to impose a whole mentality of domination and humiliation on the Palestinian leadership, and has serious political implications,&quot; Minister of Higher Education Hanan Ashrawi told Reuters.</p>
<p>She added: &quot;If Netanyahu wants to renege on agreements, this is clearly one way he's doing it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIT HANOUN, Gaza Strip"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
