<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9455" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: King tells MPs bread riots harmed Jordan's image.</title>
<headline>King tells MPs bread riots harmed Jordan's image.</headline>
<byline>Rana Sabbagh</byline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>King Hussein defended the decision to raise bread prices, telling members of parliament on Thursday that the ensuing riots had harmed Jordan's stable image and allowed its enemies to gloat.</p>
<p>But he also struck a conciliatory note with the deputies -- most of them opposed to the price increase -- saying he remained committed to democracy, public freedoms and fighting corruption and abuses of power.</p>
<p>The meeting at his palace was part of efforts to rebuild links with society and stage displays of unity after containing the country's worst unrest since 1989.</p>
<p>The king's response to the riots had angered many Jordanians. After the first riots on Friday he suspended the summer session of the lower house of parliament and vowed an &quot;iron fist&quot; against unrest.</p>
<p>The king's action had increased anger at Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti, who ignored parliament's views and pushed ahead with the price rise last Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The recent events allowed our enemies to gloat and allowed them to get at what they wanted,&quot; King Hussein told deputies, including 23 opposition lawmakers who had threatened to boycott parliament until the government reversed the price rise.</p>
<p>&quot;What happened had a negative impact on years of what we tried to build to tell the world, that Jordan is an oasis of stability,&quot; he said in a speech shown on state television soon after it was delivered.</p>
<p>The king defended the decision to double bread prices as necessary to build a modern nation, but promised to review the economic and political situation to avoid future problems.</p>
<p>The king again blamed &quot;outside parties&quot; for the unrest, which flared in the southern city of Karak, spread to nearby centres and by Saturday night to Amman.</p>
<p>&quot;There are many confessions with us that prove that a large part of this dissension had its origins outside the country with government decisions, commitment, support and incitement,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The king did not explicitly repeat his charges that Iraq and the pro-Baghdad Jordanian Arab Socialist Baath Party (JASBP) caused the trouble. Critics and protesters blame the unrest on economic hardship.</p>
<p>The king, who has met popular representatives and dignitaries since Sunday, said government and parliament had to face duties or &quot;the future will remain hostage to uncertainty&quot;.</p>
<p>Bread is a staple for the poor majority of Jordan's 4.2 million population, facing falling standards of living, unemployment and still awaiting promised economic dividends from the controversial 1994 peace treaty with Israel.</p>
<p>Kabariti said he had to raise bread prices to close a gaping budget deficit that threatened to undermine the next stage of an IMF economic reform plan and the vital loans it would bring.</p>
<p>At the palace lunch, the opposition group, led by the Islamic Action Front Party (IAF), presented a petition demanding the release of detainees, an end to the military presence in Karak and a reversal of the bread price increases.</p>
<p>The army has eased the curfew on Karak as normality returns, but over 200 activists and suspects remain in jail, officials said. The JASBP said in a statement on Thursday four more senior leaders were arrested.</p>
<p>However, officials announced a one-week delay in the start of the academic year for thousands of children across the kingdom because of the riots.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
