<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9460" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Moroccan envoy to visit Western Sahara for talks.</title>
<headline>Moroccan envoy to visit Western Sahara for talks.</headline>
<dateline>RABAT 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Moroccan government delegation led by Interior Minister Driss Basri, will visit the disputed Western Sahara next week to talk to hundreds of young unemployed Saharans, the official MAP news agency said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The young Saharans staged a six-day peaceful demonstration in Rabat earlier this month to press for jobs and social benefits. They ended their protest after a meeting with Basri, who promised to meet them later in Western Sahara.</p>
<p>The visit will coincide with the preparations throughout the country for the referendum on the constitution reforms set for September 13, an official said. The referendum will also take place the Western Sahara provinces, he said.</p>
<p>Morocco, which controls four-fifths of the territory, claims Western Sahara as an integral part of the kingdom but its claims have been contested since 1976 by the Algeria-backed Polisario Front which fought for independence of the area.</p>
<p>A long-delayed referendum, under the U.N. supervision, is supposed to enable those living in the former Spanish colony to decide between independence, as sought by Polisario, or integration with Morocco.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPSAH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RABAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
