<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9461" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Rights groups urge PA to honour high court ruling.</title>
<headline>Rights groups urge PA to honour high court ruling.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian watchdog groups in the West Bank and Gaza Strip on Thursday urged the Palestinian Authority to honour a High Court decision to free 10 university students held without charge for nearly six months.</p>
<p>Eight human rights organisations said in a joint press release faxed to Reuters that the 10, all univeristy students at the West Bank University of Bir Zeit, were still in jail despite a court order issued on August 18 for their release.</p>
<p>&quot;We have come together, as concerned local human rights organisations, at this crucial moment to urge all officials of the Palestinian National Authority to respect the structures that have been put in place to organise our society,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>It said that lawyers for the 10 delivered a release order from the High Court to the Ramallah Central Prison immediately after the decision was issued.</p>
<p>&quot;As of today, Thursday, August 22, the students have not been released by the prison,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;According to the applicable law, the government is obliged to implement the decisions of the High Court and no authority is permitted to influence the functioning of the courts,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The statement said that prison officials had initially assured them they would be freed on Sunday. But later they said that they were awaiting orders from Gaza, where the Palestinian Authority is based.</p>
<p>No officials from the Palestinian Justice Ministry were immediately available to comment on the report.</p>
<p>The 10 students were among hundreds of people rounded up by the Palestinian Authority in a crackdown on Islamists after Hamas and Islamic Jihad suicide bombers killed 59 people in Israel in four attacks in February and March.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
