<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9468" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Milling firms boost trading on Cairo bourse.</title>
<headline>Milling firms boost trading on Cairo bourse.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Popular milling shares led Egyptian share upwards on Thursday while a handful of deals in the financial sector helped boost volume.</p>
<p>Blue-chip North Cairo Flour Mills, the day's most active stock, rose another 2.50 pounds to 94.50, capping its gains throughout the week.</p>
<p>Central Egypt Flour Mills was a close second, but only gained 0.30 pounds to 24.55.</p>
<p>&quot;We're very bullish about the mills, there's plenty of room for expansion and they will go far,&quot; said Ramzi Zaki of Financial Brokerage Group.</p>
<p>Brokers said the market had closed higher after a bullish day but the Capital Market Authority's overall index fell 0.30 points to 233.48. The independant Prime IPO Index rose 0.77 percent to 2311.6 points.</p>
<p>The CMA did not give a figure for total turnover but brokers said both Misr Exterior Bank and blue chip Commerical International Bank (CIB) were among the day's most heavily traded shares.</p>
<p>Misr Exterior leaped 80.00 pounds to 600.00 in two high-volume closed deals while CIB gained 3.00 to 450.00 in a few deals.</p>
<p>Newly privatised Kafr el-Zayat Pesticides and Chemicals continued to rally amid rumours of a takeover bid which brokers said may have been launched by a rival firm. Shares rose 8.00 pounds to 55.00 pounds in heavy trade.</p>
<p>The CMA index for openly traded firms rose to 335.17 points from 334.98 points on Wednesday. The index for the rarely traded &quot;closed&quot; firms fell to 160.49 points from 160.97.</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +202 578 3290/91</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
