<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9473" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey sees increased drugs trade, usage.</title>
<headline>Turkey sees increased drugs trade, usage.</headline>
<byline>Suna Erdem</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey, on the &quot;Balkan route&quot; of the billion-dollar drugs trade, has seen a marked increase in narcotics traffic and in demand at home, drug squad chief Onder Karaman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Turkey has traditionally been on the route between the producer and consumer countries. Lately we have seen that there is also a demand at home,&quot; Karaman told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has not yet been fully formed, but we are seeing the warning signs. This market has to be destroyed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Turkish police said they captured 1.509 tonnes of drugs, mostly heroin and hashish, between January 1 and August 15 this year, compared with 1.05 tonnes for the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>Among this year's haul was 714 kg of heroin and 782 kg of hashish.</p>
<p>Eighteen people, mostly in their teens and early twenties, have died in Turkey as a result of drug-taking so far in 1996. One was the daughter of a leading Islamist figure. Twenty-four died in 1995.</p>
<p>The so-called Balkan drug route is used to transport narcotics produced in Afghanistan, Pakistan, Iran and northern Iraq to Europe, either by land through Istanbul and Thrace or by sea from the western port town of Izmir.</p>
<p>Kurdish separatists fighting for 12 years in southeast Turkey also deal in drugs for money, food and arms, he said.</p>
<p>Lorry-loads of drugs are often seized during attempts to smuggle them from northwestern Turkey to Bulgaria or Greece.</p>
<p>&quot;They are concealed in compartments you would never imagine existed, that you never could find,&quot; said Karaman. &quot;It takes us days, weeks, months tracking them to catch them.</p>
<p>&quot;Just recently we caught 87 kilos of heroin in a lorry. Just one kilo of that is worth up to DM 15,000 ($10,000) in Turkey, about DM 35,000 ($23,500) in Holland,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Karaman said the rise in the amount of drugs captured in Turkey was a reflection in part of extra effort by police, but also showed a trend of increased drugs usage at home.</p>
<p>&quot;The recent deaths were very sad, but they are making us notice the trend at home,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Karaman said Turkish youth, not traditionally into drugs, were being affected by the increasingly frequent portrayal of drug-taking on television and in foreign films, as well by a growing tendency to copy western habits.</p>
<p>A number of singers popular among Turkish teenagers have been caught with or are reported to be taking drugs. Even school children are now occasionally caught with drugs.</p>
<p>Karaman said police had begun an education programme in schools. They also patrol certain schools more susceptible to drugs trade in an effort to nip the trend in the bud.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
