<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9484" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dlr ends softer in US, Buba rate cut gains crumble.</title>
<headline>Dlr ends softer in US, Buba rate cut gains crumble.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar closed moderately weaker against the mark after an early rally fueled by a surprisingly generous German repo rate cut fizzled, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank, back from summer break, slashed the repo rate 30 basis points to 3.00 percent. The move jolted many market players who had expected a more modest reduction.</p>
<p>&quot;The market had really reined in its expectations to something in the range of a five to 10 basis point adjustment by the Bundesbank,&quot; said Dennis Pettit, foreign exchange manager at Long Term Credit Bank of Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;To get 30 basis points on the repo was I guess a pleasant surprise for people that were (positioned) the right way,&quot; Pettit added.</p>
<p>After the Bundesbank announced the rate cut, the dollar jumped sharply and continued climbing to 1.4964 marks, its highest level in five weeks. However, the rally ran out of steam as some investors took advantage of the move higher by selling the U.S. currency and booking profits.</p>
<p>&quot;It moved a good strong pfennig,&quot; said Diego Giurleo, vice president of the Treasury at Royal Bank of Canada. &quot;They bought the dollar, (but it) lost momentum above 1.4950.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders noted that there was talk of good dollar offers just above 1.4950 marks, while they saw solid support amid rumors of buying interest just below 1.4900.</p>
<p>The dollar closed at 1.4919/26 marks, down from 1.4940/45 at the open. It fell to 108.24/34 yen from 108.70/73.</p>
<p>Buba President Hans Tietmeyer said a slowdown in German money supply growth and low inflation had allowed the central bank to cut its main money market rate.</p>
<p>Other European central banks also slashed rates on the heels of the German rate cut including banks in France, Austria, Belgium and the Netherlands.</p>
<p>The Swiss National Bank left its discount rate unchanged but pumped liquidity into the Swiss money market to relieve upward pressure on money market rates.</p>
<p>While currency traders applauded the repo rate cut on Thursday, concern about where German interest rates are headed from here may have limited early dollar gains against the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm just surprised that it didn't move over 1.50 (marks) because that's a very strong move by the Bundesbank,&quot; said Tom Benfer, director, foreign exchange at Bank of Montreal.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market is now trying to grapple with the notion -- is this the last move of the Bundesbank or could there be further cuts in the future,&quot; Benfer asked.</p>
<p>In other trade, the dollar finished at 1.2074/81 Swiss francs, down slightly from 1.2080/90 at the open.</p>
<p>Sterling rose to US$1.5509/17 from US$1.5470/80.</p>
<p>The dollar closed at Canadian $1.3690/95, off from C$1.3754/59.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar closed at $0.7910/15.</p>
<p>-- Donna Sells 212-859-1668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
