<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9485" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries end narrowly mixed in nervous trade.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries end narrowly mixed in nervous trade.</headline>
<text>
<p>*US Treasuries end narrowly mixed in nervous trade.</p>
<p>*Surprise Buba rate cut gave dollar, Treasuries early boost.</p>
<p>*Hedge fund selling in evidence, but not aggressive. Hedging of $1.0 bln U.S.A.I.D. Israel deal said to pressure prices.</p>
<p>*Market eyes Fri orders data, seeking sign of slower economy.  </p>
<p>In the cash market, prices softened in securities maturing between 2014 and 2016, he said.</p>
<p>Kevin Flanagan, first vice president and money market economist at Dean Witter Reynolds, said the market recovered some ground in afternoon trade as a few investors bought on dips. Volume looked thin, he noted.</p>
<p>Flanagan said the market's meager performance on Thursday after the German rate cut was disappointing.  </p>
<p>&quot;What's occurring is that people are expecting that the next economic reports won't support the view of an economy that is slowing that much,&quot; said Flanagan.</p>
<p>&quot;The anecdotal evidence is suggesting that maybe some of these reports will be a little more robust than what the market has priced in,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Samuel Kahan, president of A.S.K. Financial Research, agreed that the inflation-conscious credit market is concerned about whether the slowdown in the economy that apparently occurred in July will continue.  </p>
<p>&quot;We've seen some signs of deceleration -- but only some,&quot; said Kahan. &quot;The major fly in the ointment has been the decline in initial claims for unemployment. The current level is still well below the the range we've been at for the last two years. The question is whether that is just a statistical aberration or a sign that the labor market is heating up.&quot;</p>
<p>On Friday, the market will get data on July durable goods orders. Economists polled by Reuters last week offered an average forecast of a 0.3 percent increase in July orders after a 0.6 percent decline in June.  </p>
<p>Flanagan said some analysts revised their July durable goods orders forecasts up rather strongly early this week.</p>
<p>&quot;Most everyone is looking for a rebound,&quot; said Flanagan, noting expected strength in aircraft orders.</p>
<p>Kahan said an orders decline &quot;would go a long way&quot; toward reassuring people that the deceleration process is continuing.</p>
<p>The bellwether 30-year Treasury bond closed at 98-27/32, down 2/32, to yield 6.84 percent.</p>
<p>The 10-year note ended at 102-23/32, down 1/32, to yield 6.62 percent.</p>
<p>At the short end of the maturity range, three- and six-month bill rates each fell one basis point to 5.00 percent and 5.07 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>The 6-1/4 percent two-year note ended unchanged at 100-15/32, yielding 5.99 percent.</p>
<p>In the intermediate sector, the five-year note closed at 101-1/32, down 2/32, yielding 6.62 percent.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1679</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
