<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9496" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Miss Universe hides behind veil of silence.</title>
<headline>Miss Universe hides behind veil of silence.</headline>
<byline>Kieran Murray</byline>
<dateline>LAS CRUCES, N.M. 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Miss Universe, Venezuela's Alicia Machado, left New Mexico  on Thursday, refusing to answer questions about her weight or claims she was told to either go on a crash diet or give up her title.</p>
<p>Machado, 19, flew to Los Angeles after slipping away from the New Mexico desert town of Las Cruces, where she attended the 1996 Miss Teen USA pageant on Wednesday.</p>
<p>While Machado was not a contestant here, she came under intense scrutiny following reports she was given an ultimatum by Los Angeles-based Miss Universe Inc. to drop 27 pounds (12 kg) in two weeks or risk losing her crown.</p>
<p>In Venezuela, her mother told Reuters that Machado had a swollen face when she left home two weeks ago because she had her wisdom teeth extracted.</p>
<p>Marta Fajardo insisted her daughter, who weighed 112 pounds (51 kg) when she won the Miss Universe title in Las Vegas in May, had perfectly normal eating habits.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody has their own addiction to something or other but it's not as if she eats cakes like crazy,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Organisers flatly denied ever threatening Machado but immediately put her under wraps and blocked access to her.</p>
<p>Dressed in a black strapless evening gown at Wednesday's pageant, Machado was clearly heavier than the contestants but still won rave reviews after her brief appearance on stage.</p>
<p>&quot;Are you kidding? She's fantastic,&quot; said Nikki Campbell, 28, who went to the pageant. &quot;She looked great. Very sexy.&quot;</p>
<p>Machado's publicists said on Thursday she was scheduled to stay in Los Angeles for promotional work with sponsors before returning to Venezuela on Sept. 5.</p>
<p>Beauty queens are high-profile personalities in Venezuela and Machado's alleged weight problem made front page news this week.</p>
<p>It was an official of the Miss Venezuela Organisation who first said Machado had been told to lose weight fast.</p>
<p>People close to her said she then eased up on her diet and indulged her passion for pasta and cake, but it was not clear how many pounds she gained and most people who saw her said she was still a long way from being fat.</p>
<p>Martin Brooks, president of Miss Universe Inc, said he spoke with Machado to assure her that organisers were not putting pressure on her.</p>
<p>&quot;She's fine with it. She wished, as we all did, that it hadn't happened but she's spiritually and mentally terrific. There's no problem whatsoever,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the lifestyle associated with being Miss Universe could make routine exercise difficult.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem is they travel so much and are so busy that the ability to have any type of regimented routine workout doesn't exist. I dont know if Alicia is working out. We haven't talked about it because it hasn't been an issue,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS CRUCES, N.M."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
