<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9500" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russians, Chechen rebels agree truce from Friday.</title>
<headline>Russians, Chechen rebels agree truce from Friday.</headline>
<byline>Dmitry Kuznets</byline>
<dateline>NOVYE ATAGI, Russia 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian security chief Alexander Lebed struck a deal with Chechen rebels on Thursday to stop fighting on Friday and promised to withdraw troops from all of Chechnya as well as the capital Grozny.</p>
<p>&quot;Troops will be withdrawn from Grozny because constitutional order cannot be introduced using air and artillery strikes,&quot; a triumphant Lebed told reporters in this village about 20 km (12 miles) south of Grozny.</p>
<p>&quot;They will be withdrawn from the whole of Chechnya,&quot; he said after a signing ceremony on a second days of talks.</p>
<p>Moscow's forces have been attacking Grozny to try to oust rebels who seized it in a raid on August 6 that humiliated the Russian military. The separatists said the attack was in retaliation for Russian bombardments of Chechen villages.</p>
<p>Russian news agencies said Lebed and Maskhadov agreed to cease fire from midday (0800 GMT) on Friday. Itar-Tass news agency said they had also agreed to an unconditional exchange of all dead and prisoners.</p>
<p>The latest bout of fighting followed a deal which foresaw rebel disarmament in return for step-by-step troop withdrawals from the mainly Moslem region to be completed by September 1.</p>
<p>Truces have come and gone in 20 months of the Chechen conflict, and it was too soon to say whether the new deal would bring respite for civilians who have been fleeing Grozny in tens of thousands since the raid began.</p>
<p>It was also unclear how much power Lebed actually wields. Though President Boris Yeltsin appointed him his special envoy to Chechnya, Security Council secretary and security adviser, he criticised him in an interview earlier on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not completely satisfied with Lebed's performance in Chechnya,&quot; Yeltsin told RIA news agency in an interview shown in a television feed.</p>
<p>Lebed predicted further criticism from his many opponents in Moscow -- democrats and hardliners alike. But he seemed not to care, saying: &quot;Anyone who is unhappy is welcome to complain.&quot;</p>
<p>The exact text of the deal, signed by two of the more compromising figures on the two sides, was not available.</p>
<p>&quot;Joint military administrations will be set up in Grozny to protect the city from looters and bandits,&quot; Lebed said.</p>
<p>&quot;I will come back with a draft political agreement in two days. We will discuss it and sign it,&quot; he added. That deal would also address the root of the fighting -- Chechnya's status.</p>
<p>Lebed said forces would start withdrawing from southern Chechnya on Friday and joint military administrations would be set up at the same time.</p>
<p>Before signing the deal, Lebed dumped plans by the Russian command in Chechnya to launch an all-out attack on Grozny if the rebels did not withdraw from the city.</p>
<p>News of the truce had apparently failed to reach Grozny fast enough. Interfax news agency said at least 50 Russian servicemen have been killed in a battle which erupted at Grozny's Minutka square on Thursday and continued after the truce deal was signed. The report could not be independently confirmed.</p>
<p>Interfax quoted Russia's military command in Chechnya as saying that about 200 interior ministry troops sent on a reconnaisance mission had been outnumbered by attacking rebels.</p>
<p>Interfax made clear that the interior ministry detachment had been sent on the mission before the truce deal had been signed at the local equivalent of 1500 GMT. But fierce fighting still raged at 1600 GMT, Interfax said.</p>
<p>Yeltsin appointed Lebed his security chief after the former paratrooper captured around 15 percent of the votes in the first round of Russia's presidential election this year.</p>
<p>But he criticised him after talks began before the deal, saying: &quot;We must remember, when he met voters he always promised to solve the Chechen problem if he had power. Now he has power. But unfortunately the results of his work are not yet obvious.</p>
<p>&quot;But we must not despair, we will take this issue to the end,&quot; Yeltsin added.</p>
<p>More than 30,000 people have been killed in the breakaway North Caucasus region since Yeltsin sent in his forces in December 1994 to end an independence drive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NOVYE ATAGI, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
