<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9532" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mississippi governor bans gay marriage.</title>
<headline>Mississippi governor bans gay marriage.</headline>
<dateline>JACKSON, Miss 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mississippi Gov. Kirk Fordice issued an executive order Thursday banning same-sex marriages, saying he feared gay couples someday may be able to wed in Hawaii and later demand legal recognition back home.</p>
<p>Calling the idea of a gay marriage &quot;an absurdity,&quot; the Republican governor told a news conference that his action would defend the sanctity of traditional matrimony.</p>
<p>&quot;It can't be a marriage with people of the same sex,&quot; Fordice said at the state capitol, where he appeared alongside members of the conservative Mississippi Family Council, the American Family Association and other like-minded groups.</p>
<p>&quot;The state has an interest in preserving and protecting the special status of marriage as the foundation of a healthy society,&quot; he continued. &quot;Traditional families are the foundation for a better and more productive life.&quot;</p>
<p>Fordice's move was prompted by an ongoing legal battle in Hawaii, where a gay couple has been trying to force the state to grant them a marriage license. Arguments were expected before the state Supreme Court next month and Mississippi officials believed the case could go to the gay couple.</p>
<p>Forest Thigpen, spokesman for the Jackson-based Mississippi Family Council, said the governor's action made the state the 24rd to take steps to ban same-sex marriages.</p>
<p>But Brenda Henson, a gay rights activist with the community-service group Camp Sister Spirit in Ovett, Mississippi, said she was outraged by the executive order.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a myth out there that gay and lesbian people are very promiscuous. If people truly believed that and wanted to change it, they shouldn't be denying us the right to legalise our unions and stabilise our commitments,&quot; said the woman, who has had the same partner for 13 years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JACKSON, Miss"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
