<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9540" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: The obscure fight to be heard in U.S. politics.</title>
<headline>The obscure fight to be heard in U.S. politics.</headline>
<byline>Leslie Gevirtz</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>She is not a millionaire or a moderate, a Republican or a Democrat. She has no advertising budget, no paid campaign staff and no solid chance of winning.</p>
<p>But she is a third party candidate.</p>
<p>Susan Gallagher, like scores of others eager for political office, will be on November's ballot seeking a senate seat but faces the prospect that no one will know who she is or what she stands for.</p>
<p>Compared to the well-publicised presidential bid of Reform Party candidate Ross Perot, the Libertarian Party, the Natural Law Party and the Green Party will have candidates on ballots in many states but probably not on CNN's Larry King Live.</p>
<p>With typically small followings, they advocate everything from meditating for peace to more controls on big business and less restrictive government. While they get little publicity, Americans say they want to hear more about them.</p>
<p>Some 2,007 voters surveyed by the Freedom Forum at Columbia University's Centre for Media Studies said they would like more information about the whole field of candidates and thought &quot;the media gives undue advantage to the frontrunners,&quot; said Dr. Andros Szanto, who conducted the study.</p>
<p>Nancy Woodhull, executive director of the Freedom Forum, said those polled think &quot;that by not covering the other candidates, the press is trying to control things.&quot;</p>
<p>Gallagher, a 37-year-old realtor, will be on the ballot in Massachusetts running against Republican Gov. William Weld and Democratic incumbent Sen. John Kerry, both millionaires who have well-financed campaigns and the public exposure that comes from televised debates.</p>
<p>Gallagher, a mother of four who rails against abortion, homosexuals, and free-trade agreements, has never earned more than $50,000 annually. She said both Weld and Kerry &quot;are too liberal and too out of touch with real people&quot; and has sought to be included in the debates. The media consortium that has arranged them has so far declined.</p>
<p>Walter Robinson, metropolitan editor of The Boston Globe, said he told Gallagher that she would have to get enough signatures to get on the ballot, which she did.</p>
<p>He also told her that she needed to present &quot;some other indication of viability ... evidence of popular support, the ability to raise money, the mere existence of position papers, a campaign staff or separate office.&quot; She now runs her campaign out of her realty office with volunteers.</p>
<p>The Libertarians and their senate candidate, George Phillies, a physicist who teaches at Worcester Polytechnic Institute, has also asked to be included in the debates.</p>
<p>&quot;Last time around, the media told us that to be in the debates we had to be a major party. We got that designation after securing 3 percent of the vote in the last election,&quot; said Phillies. &quot;Now, they want us to submit signatures to get on the ballot, but we're automatically on the ballot. They just keep changing the rules.&quot;</p>
<p>There is no federal requirement for televised debates to include all qualified candidates but some think the potential candidates deserve a higher profile.</p>
<p>&quot;Newspapers and TV provide a forum for the country to talk to itself. And it gets itself in trouble by leaving out of the conversation a number of viewpoints,&quot; said Woodhull of the Freedom Forum.</p>
<p>The Natural Law Party, which says it can meditate away crime and even wars, has put up Robert Stowe as a senate candidate. &quot;The media always controls political races to a large extent,&quot; said Stowe. &quot;They will decide who they want to cover.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
