<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9541" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Utica must pay state on time or face oversight - NYS.</title>
<headline>Utica must pay state on time or face oversight - NYS.</headline>
<byline>Joan Gralla</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York State, which was forced to rescue Utica from a potential default by buying some of its debt, on Thursday said it had wrung a promise from the troubled city to accept its oversight if its fails to repay the state.</p>
<p>In the past, the cities of New York City, Troy and Yonkers have had to cede control of their finances or bonding to state-imposed control boards, a step Utica, which has a population of 68,000, has fought although it was teteering on the brink of a default.</p>
<p>Saying cities throughout the state also faced problems as their tax bases were declining, state Comptroller H. Carl McCall also raised the possiblity of a state bond bank that would help cities when private buyers turn away.</p>
<p>Utica had to sell new debt to repay about $25 million of bonds that mature on Friday. Had buyers failed to buy all of the $24.5 million of new debt it was issuing to pay off those bonds, the entire transaction would have fallen through.</p>
<p>Once the state comptroller stepped in and bought $2.145 million of approximately $11.5 million of new notes, buyers who were interested in the rest of the issue but concerned about the city's shaky finances agreed to buy the rest.</p>
<p>And McCall, who travelled to Utica, which is located about 95 miles away from Albany to announce that the city's debt sale had closed, did not paint over Utica's difficulties.</p>
<p>&quot;Today is not a day for celebration. We've helped Utica avert default and bankruptcy, but we can't pat ourselves on the back for a job well-done, because the job isn't done yet,&quot; McCall said, in prepared remarks.</p>
<p>In return for his assistance, the comptroller won several major concessions from the city, which restrict its ability to sell its waterworks. The concessions also protect holders of the new notes, as well as the state's Environmental Facillities Corp, which owns some of Utica's bonds.</p>
<p>Utica, which sold $12.5 million of bonds in addition to the new notes, has about $53.5 million of debt outstanding. Its 1997 fiscal budget is about $37.5 million, and rating agencies say it faces a potential gap of about $2 million.</p>
<p>To improve the security of the $11.5 million of new bonds it issued, Utica promised that it will not use its water revenues, which typically run at least $5 million a year, to back any more bonds until the state's notes are repaid.</p>
<p>The $11.5 million issue comes due on May 22, and Utica was forced to pay a high yield of 8.25 percent on the short-term notes. Dennis Tompkins, a spokesman for the comptroller said only, &quot;We think it's a very good rate of return.&quot;</p>
<p>The notes were bought by the state's investment pool.</p>
<p>As part of the legal agreement for the notes, Utica also promised it would not sell, lease or encumber the water system until it has repaid the notes. It can, however, sign a contract to sell the system, and the comptroller noted that the city expects to sell its waterworks to the Upper Mohawk Regional Water Finance Authority.</p>
<p>The Authority plans to issue bonds to finance this purchase, some of which will repay Utica's new notes.</p>
<p>Utica agreed to pay one-ninth of the notes's interest each month, and not use the water revenues, which run at least $5 million a year, for any purpose other than to repay the notes or the bonds held by the Enviromental Facilities Corp. The Enviromental Facilities Corp manages the state revolving loan fund program.</p>
<p>McCall made it plain that Utica would have to accept a Municipal Assistance Corporation, as New York City had to during its fiscal crisis during the mid-1970s, if the city has &quot;further market access problems&quot; when the new notes come due.</p>
<p>Finally, Utica also must document that its waterworks meets environmental regulations.</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
