<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9542" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</title>
<headline>Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain and oilseed exports reported by USDA and private export sources.</p>
<p>BARLEY SALE - Saudi Arabia is said to have purchased 800,000 tonnes of optional-origin feed barley at between $160 and $162 per tonne including freight, but the deal has yet to be confirmed, European grain traders said. Saudi Arabia seeks 250,000 tonnes for September 25 arrival and 550,000 tonnes for delivery by October 15. Traders said that, if confirmed, the selling price was &quot;in line with expectations.&quot;  </p>
<p>WHEAT AND BARLEY SALE - The Japanese Food Agency said on Thursday it bought 60,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat, 60,000 of Canadian wheat, and 20,000 of Australian wheat at a weekly tender. It bought 20,000 tonnes of Canadian barley and 20,000 of Australian barley. All are for October shipment.</p>
<p>PALM OIL SALE - India's STC bought 6,000 tonnes of RBD palm olein on Wednesday at $589 a tonne for last half September shipment. It purchased the oil from FELDA.</p>
<p>SOYBEAN TENDER - Taiwan's Breakfast Soybean Procurement Association plans to tender on Friday for two shipments of U.S. soybeans totalling 108,000 tonnes, traders said.  </p>
<p>SOYBEAN TENDER cont'd - The first shipment would be slated for delivery from the U.S. Gulf of Mexico November 10-24 or from the Pacific Northwest November 25-December 9. The second would be slated for delivery from the U.S. Gulf December 5-19 or from the Pacific Northwest December 20-January 3.</p>
<p>SOYBEAN TENDER - Pakistan is seeking 30,000 to 34,000 tonnes U.S. no. 2 or better yellow soybeans under PL 480, Title I. Delivery is slated for October 15-30. Bids must be submitted by August 28 and remain valid until August 29.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDER - Taiwan's Provincial Food Bureau will tender on August 28 for a 15,470-tonne shipment of U.S. No.1 wheat, grain traders said. The shipment would be slated for delivery from the Pacific Northwest between October 1 to 20.</p>
<p>- Moldova will tender on August 27 for 35,000 tonnes of U.S. hard red winter wheat to be financed by Title I PL-480 funding for shipment September 5 and 25.</p>
<p>- The CCC is seeking up to 33,000 tonnes of U.S. No.2 soft white wheat under the donation program to Bangladesh for Sept 10-Oct 5 delivery. Offers are due on August 27.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDER - The CCC seeks up to 17,000 tonnes of U.S. No.2 Northern Spring/Dark Northern Spring wheat under export donation program to Nicaragua for Nov 15-Dec 10 shipment.</p>
<p>- Sri Lanka will tender on August 30 for 100,000 tonnes of U.S., Canadian or Argentinian wheat. It includes 50,000 tonnes of soft wheat for September shipment and 50,000 tonnes of hard wheat for October shipment.</p>
<p>- Syria's General Establishment for Cereal Processing and Trade was offering 100,000 tonnes of hard amber durum wheat for sale. The date to receive offers was Sept 3.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDER - The CCC seeks up to 16,000 tonnes of U.S. No. 2 hard red winter or SRW or soft white wheat under the donation program to Tajikistan for Sept 15-Oct 10 shipment.</p>
<p>- Jordan will tender August 28 for 90,000 tonnes of U.S. HRW or spring wheat and 10,000 tonnes of soft white or SRW wheat for first and second half October shipment, No. 2 or better wheat with option for equivalent origins in two 50,000-tonne lots.</p>
<p>BARLEY AND RYE TENDER - German grain traders placed bids to export 800,000 tonnes of intervention barley and 190,000 tonnes of intervention rye to third countries, the intervention board BLE said. The EU cereals management committee will decide on the bids at a meeting later today.</p>
<p>MARKET TALK - The outlook for U.S. wheat sales to China, which until a few months ago was one of the brightest spots in the U.S. grain export picture, has lost its rosy glow.</p>
<p>A record-large wheat harvest in China, stiff competition from non-U.S. grain suppliers and a lingering dispute between Washington and Beijing over the quality of recent U.S. wheat shipments have sharply dimmed the chances for sales of American wheat to China for at least the next several months, grain industry officials and agricultural experts said.</p>
<p>--Doris Frankel 312-983-7305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
