<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9543" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lloyd's insures more than just celebrities.</title>
<headline>Lloyd's insures more than just celebrities.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Vowinkel</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>To many Americans, Lloyd's of London is some obscure British entity that insures things like Betty Grable's legs and Bruce Springsteen's voice.</p>
<p>But Lloyd's, which is an insurance market and not an insurance company as many people mistakenly believe, also touches the lives of countless ordinary Americans in the course of their every day lives.</p>
<p>It insures such mundane organisations as the (San Francisco) Bay Area Rapid Transit system, the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, major airlines, hospitals and Fortune 500 companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Every time you get on a Western-based jet plane, there's Lloyd's at the back of it somewhere,&quot; a Lloyd's spokesman said.</p>
<p>Lately, however, Lloyd's has been getting more attention in the United States for its financial and legal problems than for the exotic insurance that it writes.</p>
<p>The 300-year-old insurance market, beset by massive losses from natural disasters as well as asbestos and environmental claims on policies written decades ago, is seeking to avert insolvency by implementing a recovery plan.</p>
<p>Under its recovery  plan, Lloyd's plans to reinsure billions of dollars of liabilities into a new company, Equitas. It is asking investors in Lloyd's, known as Names, to help pay for Equitas, but has offered them 3.2 billion British pounds ($4.8 billion) to offset this cost and end litigation.</p>
<p>But the heavy losses at Lloyd's also spelled trouble for the Names, who had agreed to financially back Lloyd's with all their personal assets in return for a share of the premiums.</p>
<p>Instead of reaping rich returns, some of the Names, especially in the United States, are facing financial ruin from their Lloyd's commitments.</p>
<p>A group of 93 Names has sued Lloyd's in a federal court in Richmond, Va., in an effort to block Lloyd's recovery plan.</p>
<p>A decision in the case is expected Friday afternoon, just five days before Names worldwide must decide to accept or reject Lloyd's recovery plan. A federal judge on Thursday delayed for one day a decision on whether to allow the reorganization to go forward.</p>
<p>In an interview in London, Lloyd's Chairman David Rowland said any injunction served against the insurance market by the judge in the Virginia case would be quickly appealed.</p>
<p>There are about 33,000 Names worldwide, but only about 13,000 still actively participate in Lloyd's. In the United States, about 750 of 2,600 Names are still active.</p>
<p>A sudden failure of Lloyd's could have widespread implications for many Americans, said Brian Atchinson, president of the National Association of Insurance Commissioners.</p>
<p>&quot;The impact would be on many, many insurance policies held by people who would never imagine they would be affected by that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Despite its recent woes, U.S. risk managers depend on Lloyd's for the breadth of its market and its ability to provide coverage for unusual and hard-to-place risks.</p>
<p>&quot;I think when you have maybe unusual situations or large amounts of coverage you're looking for, I think Lloyd's has filled a particular niche in the insurance world that it would be difficult to match,&quot; said Keith Grand, risk manager for the city and county of San Francisco.</p>
<p>In purchasing liability coverage for the San Francisco airport, Grand said, Lloyd's consistently provides the best coverage at the best price.</p>
<p>&quot;In that particular part of the marketplace there aren't a whole lot of companies that are even in the business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In addition to aviation, Lloyd's specialises in other difficult markets, including medical malpractice insurance, insurance for directors and officers at major corporations, and kidnap and ransom insurance.</p>
<p>One-third of Lloyd's business comes from the United States, which is its second-largest market next to Britain.</p>
<p>Excluding private passenger automobile insurance, which is sold only in Britain, the United States is its largest market.</p>
<p>Lloyd's entered the U.S. market as a marine insurer in the mid-1800s, but business took off after the 1906 San Francisco earthquake, when Lloyd's agreed to pay claims and other insurers stalled.</p>
<p>&quot;That made our reputation for paying up,&quot; the Lloyd's spokesman said. Lloyd's still has not failed to pay a valid claim in the last 70 years or so it has operated under its current structure, he said.</p>
<p>San Francisco's Grand said recent changes allowing corporate capital to be invested at Lloyd's with limited liability could further strengthen the market.</p>
<p>&quot;When you look at the number of corporations and insurance companies that have put a lot of money into Lloyd's to make it available for underwriting, that's sort of a testament by the folks who understand best what's going on that this is a good place to put their money,&quot; Grand said.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result, the capacity (to write insurance) is almost as much as it's ever been despite the publicity being worse than its ever been,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
