<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9552" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natgas futures end mixed, fronts down sharply.</title>
<headline>Natgas futures end mixed, fronts down sharply.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures ended mixed Thursday in an active session, with front months cratering on softer cash prices and bearish technicals, industry sources said.</p>
<p>September tumbled 10.9 cents to close at $1.921 per million British thermal units. October settled 9.4 cents lower at $1.999. Others ended mixed.</p>
<p>&quot;We made a new low and settled near the lows, so it doesn't look too good technically,&quot; said one Houston-based trader, noting bearish measurement objectives could take September into the $1.70s.  </p>
<p>Traders said bearish AGA data, negative technicals and mild weather that softened the cash all combined this week to undermine the complex.</p>
<p>And with more below-normal weather ahead, few expected much upside in the cash as September bidweek gets underway later this week and next.</p>
<p>Technically, traders said Tuesday's downside reversal and subsequent break of a bear flag likely meant more downside ahead, possibly to the mid-$1.80s in September before it expires on Monday.</p>
<p>Cash prices at the U.S. Gulf Coast lost about five cents Thursday to the $1.95-2.00 area. Midcon pipes fell a similar amount to about $1.80.</p>
<p>The 12-month strip slipped 4.4 cents to $2.075. NYMEX said 59,608 Henry Hub contracts traded, almost double Wednesday's revised tally of 30,023.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Permian natgas closed eight cents lower at $1.67, while deferreds settled down by five to eight cents but again were untraded. NYMEX said 64 Permian contracts traded, down from Wednesday's total of 63.</p>
<p>NYMEX September Permian natgas futures expire Wednesday August 28.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, September finished down by seven cents at $1.77, while deferreds ended two to 6.1 cents lower. The East/West spread narrowed by 3.9 cents to 15.1 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>KCBT September natgas futures expire Tuesday, August 27.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
