<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9558" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX oil complex closes up, heat leading rebound.</title>
<headline>NYMEX oil complex closes up, heat leading rebound.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The NYMEX oil complex closed up sharply after early news of a refinery fire and a pipeline shutdown sparked short covering following two days of profit-taking, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There were several news items like the early Tosco refinery fire and the Sumed pipeline shut down that made this go up,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>October crude settled up 58 cts to $22.30 a barrel.</p>
<p>A fire broke out late Wednesday night at the Bayway refinery in New Jersey though its operator Tosco Corp reported little damage.  </p>
<p>Near term resistance in September heating oil was pegged at 62.85 cts a gallon and for October crude at $22.50 a barrel. Some sources said crude's short-term gains were limited on a lack of news.</p>
<p>&quot;With no bullish news, crude is going to have a hard time getting through $22.50,&quot; said Rita Beale, an analyst with Fimat USA Futures.</p>
<p>Traders are waiting to see what impact Tropical Storm Dolly will have on Mexico's oil operations as well as those of others in the Gulf of Mexico on Friday.</p>
<p>Dolly is expected to reach hurricane strength before making landfall and has since shut down Mexico's three crucial crude export ports.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, normal operations resumed at the Sumed pipeline in the Mediterranean after the 2.4 million barrel-a-day pipeline reported a brief shutdown.</p>
<p>Crude's rise also reflected a rally in September heating oil which settled up 1.50 cts to 62.48 cts a gallon on views of tight stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;There was only a very slight build,&quot; said one trader of the most recent inventory data on heating oil.</p>
<p>September gasoline's gains lagged, closing 0.76 ct at 63.88 cts a gallon amid talk of a large amount of gasoline imports from Europe seen arriving in two weeks.  </p>
<p>-- Harry Milling, NY Energy Desk, +1 212-859-1761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
