<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9565" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soybeans close higher on crop tour report.</title>
<headline>CBOT soybeans close higher on crop tour report.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT soybean futures closed higher in late dealings on a report from the Midwest crop tour of low soybean and corn yield potential in eastern Iowa and Minnesota, traders said.</p>
<p>Traders said there was a report from the Professional Farmers of America tour that eastern Iowa corn yields and soy pod counts were below average.</p>
<p>&quot;There has really been no news from the tour until now and that's what popped it,&quot; said Vic Lespinasse of Dean Witter Reynolds referring to the late jump in soybean futures.</p>
<p>The various tour groups were in agreement about yields.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't seen any bean fields without pods but the pod counts are low and they are basically finished flowering,&quot; said John Turner, crop analyst with the U.S. Department of Agriculture.</p>
<p>ADM Investor Services bought three million bushels of November and bought one million September, traders said. Tenco Inc bought 1.5 million bushels of September. Cargill Inc sold 4.5 million bushels of November, sources said.</p>
<p>Soybeans closed three to 8-1/2 cents per bushel higher, with September up 8-1/2 at $8.08-3/4. November was up 6-1/4 at $7.85-1/4.</p>
<p>Soybean futures volume was estimated at 46,000 contracts, about the same as the 46,286 contracts traded Wednesday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>In the soybean options pit, ADM Investor Services bought 700 September $7.75 calls and sold 700 September $7.50 calls, pit sources said.</p>
<p>Soybean options volume was estimated at 24,000 contracts, up from 19,296 Wednesday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
