<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9568" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME live cattle close mixed on profit taking.</title>
<headline>CME live cattle close mixed on profit taking.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME live cattle futures slipped late on profit taking and closed mixed after posting an new contract high in August early. Feeders also slipped late as corn futures firmed, traders said.</p>
<p>August set a new high of 70.350 cents a lb before falling late to end at 69.775 cents, down 0.100 cent. Other months finished 0.050 higher to 0.250 lower with October up 0.025 at 71.175 cent and December off most on spread action.</p>
<p>Live cattle showed early gains following strength in cash markets. Added support in nearbys came from bull spreading ahead of USDA's Cattle-on-Feed report Friday, traders said.</p>
<p>Spreaders bought August and sold October and especially December. Light fed cattle supplies were expected into the fall, before rising on recent larger placements.</p>
<p>Analysts' estimates for the number of cattle on feed in the seven key feeding states for Friday's report averaged 86.2 percent of a year ago in a range of 84 to 88 percent. July placement estimates averaged 110.5 percent of a year ago in a range of 100 to 116 and July marketings averaged 102.4 percent in a range of 100.5 to 106 percent.  </p>
<p>In live cattle options, commission houses sold February 64 amd 66 straddles and commercials sold October 70 calls early. Commercials later sold December 68 and 70 pits. Selling up the premium weakened volatility, pit sources said.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle futures also retreated from early highs as corn futures reversed direction and moved up for gains late, traders said. Persistant selling by ADM Investor Services also offset active early demand from Lind-Waldock in October and November, sources said.</p>
<p>Back months were mostly higher, pit sources added.</p>
<p>The latest CME feeder cattle index was up $0.03 at $62.95 per cwt.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle futures closed 0.375 cent lower to 0.200 higher with October off 0.075 at 63.375 cents.</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
