<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9571" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Six U.S. wildfires contained, more erupt.</title>
<headline>Six U.S. wildfires contained, more erupt.</headline>
<byline>Adam Entous</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Weary crews contained six major wildfires across the Western United States on Thursday, but a new blaze was reported in Wyoming and fires burned in seven states, officials said.</p>
<p>An army of 14,750 firefighters were battling 24 large fires that had burned 410,334 acres (166,000 hectares) by Thursday. By contrast, more than 20,000 personnel were assigned to 29 major fires on Wednesday, the National Interagency Fire Centre said.</p>
<p>Thousands of firefighters pulled from fire lines were being moved to other hot spots, authorities said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some (firefighters) are having a chance to rest,&quot; Ron DeHart, an information officer with the fire centre, said. &quot;But we're bracing for another tough weekend and tough week because we expect some dry lightning. This continues to be a very dangerous and explosive fire season.&quot;</p>
<p>Fire crews contained six major blazes in California, Colorado, Arizona, Montana and Utah, authorities reported.</p>
<p>In northern California, thousands of firefighters and more than 600 soldiers gained ground on the so-called Fork fire about 100 miles (160 km) north of San Francisco, which had expanded slightly overnight to 77,490 acres (31,360 hectares), up from 73,600 acres (29,790 hectares) on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Fork fire was 50 percent contained and residents evacuated from the Long and Spring valley areas returned to their homes, but about 40 homes near the fire lines remained off limits.</p>
<p>&quot;The weather is holding,&quot; said Alleah Haley of the state Department of Forestry. &quot;We're getting a jump on this fire.&quot;</p>
<p>In San Luis Obispo County, midway between San Francisco and Los Angeles, a wildfire had consumed 104,000 acres (42,090 hectares), up from 69,000 acres (27,600 hectares) on Monday. The fire increased in size because firefighters ignited unburned vegetation inside the control lines, but it was 75 percent contained and officials expected to have it under control by Thursday night.</p>
<p>Thus far, the San Luis Obispo County fire has cost $6 million to fight. The fire swept through a condor habitat but none of the birds was harmed. &quot;We believe that there was no danger posed to them,&quot; Helen Tarbet, a spokeswoman, said.</p>
<p>Also in California, the so-called Ackerson Complex fires had burned 19,865 acres (8,037 hectares), threatening more than 20 historic homesteader cabins and other structures in Yosemite National Park. The fire was 15 percent contained.</p>
<p>In southwest Utah, near Cedar City, a wildfire expanded to 10,100 acres (4,087 hectares) from 9,300 (3,764 hectares) on Wednesday, threatening some properties near the blaze. Firefighters asked local ranchers to move 500 to 800 range cattle from the area.</p>
<p>The latest fire reported in Wyoming was the Logan Creek fire that had burned an estimated 1,500 acres (607.1 hectares) of Ponderosa Pine, Pinyon Juniper, grass and sage.</p>
<p>In Oregon, firefighters continued to make progress battling several wildfires that have threatened powerlines and vast wilderness areas.</p>
<p>In Colorado, nearly 650 firefighters were battling a 4,700 acre (1,880 hectare) blaze in the Mesa Verde National Park in the southwestern part of the state. Fire information officer Bob Irvine said the fire was 60 percent contained. Full containment was expected on Friday night.</p>
<p>Tourists anxious to see the treasured cliff dwellings of the Anasazi people were still not allowed to visit the park, Irvine said. Park officials said they believed the cliff dwellings were safe because they were not surrounded by trees.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
