<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9574" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. West spot power up amid hot weather, BPA hike.</title>
<headline>U.S. West spot power up amid hot weather, BPA hike.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West spot electricity prices rose Thursday amid outlook hot weather in the region and Bonneville Power Administration's (BPA) hike of its next-day power prices, brokers and marketers said.</p>
<p>Temperatures in western U.S. are forecasted to be above normal to much-above normal in the next six to 10 days.</p>
<p>BPA reportedly increased the value of electricity in 18 hour blocks for Friday delivery to $23.00 per megawatt hour (MWh), up from Thursday's price of $17.90 for 16 hour deals.</p>
<p>Today's prices were also buoyant by growing sentiments that hydroelectric output would slow in Septmember.  </p>
<p>Further north at the Mid-Columbia (Mid-C) delivery point in Washington, firm, peak electricity prices for next-day delivery were quoted at $20.50-$23.00 per MWh, up from $15.50-$16.50 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>September Mid-C electricity was pegged at $18.00-18.40, up from Wednesday's $17.25-$17.75. December Mid-C was offered in the $18.25 area.</p>
<p>Down at the Palo Verde (PV) switchyard close to Phoenix, Ariz., next-day electricity for peak, firm delivery was valued at $23.00-$25.00, up from Wednesday's $22.00-$22.50 range.  </p>
<p>Next-day PV power for firm, off-peak delivery was quoted at $10.00-$12.00.</p>
<p>September firm, peak PV were quoted at $20.30-$21.00, down from $20.70-$21.25 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Some market sources attributed the weakness in September PV to the ongoing decline in September natural gas prices.</p>
<p>October PV electricity, with similar delivery terms, was assessed at $16.65-$17.10, up from Wednesday's range of $15.75-$16.50.</p>
<p>Fourth-quarter 1996 PV were quoted at $14.75-$15.30, down from Wednesday's $16.20-$16.50 range.  </p>
<p>Arizona Public Service Co said today it shut a 745 MW coal-fired power unit at the Four Corners generating station near Farmington, N.M., to repair a boiler tube leak. The unit is expected to return to service in a few days, the company said.</p>
<p>--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
