<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9577" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT corn closes higher on Iowa crop tour results.</title>
<headline>CBOT corn closes higher on Iowa crop tour results.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT corn futures closed higher on late local short covering and commission house buying tied to bullish input from a crop tour of eastern Iowa, traders said.</p>
<p>Crop scouts said northeastern Iowa corn ears were small and soybean pod counts were low.</p>
<p>&quot;Once that came out we took off,&quot; said Vic Lespinasse of Dean Witter Reynolds.</p>
<p>The scouts said Iowa corn and soybean fields sampled in one northeastern route of the Professional Farmers of America tour were better than fields seen in Illinois and Indiana.</p>
<p>But corn ears were small and soy pod counts were low, they said. Tour groups on other routes in eastern Iowa and Minnesota painted a similar scenario, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year was also a late year but by this time it was starting to catch up,&quot; said Weather Services Corp  president Peter Leavitt, a 20-year tour veteran. &quot;This is the latest I've seen it in Illinois and Iowa.&quot;</p>
<p>Corn ended steady to up 1-1/4 cents a bushel, with September up 1-1/4 at $3.67-1/2. December rose 3/4 to $3.38-1/2.</p>
<p>SAK Futures bought two million bushels of December, LIT america sold three million December and Cargill Inc sold two million September, they said.</p>
<p>Corn futures volume was estimated at 42,000 contracts, down from 42,701 Wednesday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>In the corn options pit Smith Barney was a key buyer of 500 December 290 Puts at 2-1/4 cents.</p>
<p>Corn options volume was estimated at 12,000 contracts, down from 19,296 Wednesday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
