<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9580" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US debt futures finish mixed in range-bound trade.</title>
<headline>US debt futures finish mixed in range-bound trade.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. debt futures finished narrowly mixed, as another day passed with little interest or event to push bonds or Eurodollars out of their consolidative ranges, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>Once again, bond futures ended slightly lower, while Eurodollars were steady to marginally higher.</p>
<p>&quot;This type of action makes me bullish,&quot; said Robert Elisha, an analyst at E.D.&amp; F. Man. &quot;September (bonds) had a quick run from 108-00 to the 112-00 area and it is not giving back those gains in light volume.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If anything, Eurodollars are more bullish,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Front-month Eurodollars closed with slim gains, with December Eurodollars drifting around their 14-day range of 94.16 to 94.28.</p>
<p>One floor trader noted that locals are heavily short September Eurodollars, while the retail sector of the market continues to hold long positions that were placed well below the 94.50 level.</p>
<p>&quot;If locals start covering their positions through 94.50, look out, because retail has been waiting to get out of their longs,&quot; he said, adding that long liquidation would probably occur at 94.50 and push the contract back to 94.45.  </p>
<p>Traders dismissed the 6,000 increase in U.S. weekly jobless claims and the 1.3 percent decline in U.S. mortgage applications as factors.</p>
<p>They were more interested in Friday's U.S. July durable goods data, which will be released at 0830 EDT/1230 GMT. Goods orders are seen rising 0.3 percent, versus down 0.8 percent in June, while orders excluding defense are seen increasing 0.8 percent, from down 2.0 percent in June.</p>
<p>Most traders also said the 30 basis point cut in the German repo rate on Wednesday night was not expected to continue to affect bonds.  </p>
<p>While U.S. bond futures opened with a bid due to the surprisingly large German rate cut by the Bundesbank, dealers and funds used the opening as a chance to liquidate long positions in the U.S. bond market.</p>
<p>At the end of pit trade, September bonds were down 02/32 at 110-18/32, December Eurodollars were up one basis point at 94.22, March Eurodollars were steady at 94.10, December T-bills were up two bps at 94.82, September 10-year notes were down 03/32 at 108-11/32 and munibonds were up 09/32 at 115-16/32. Derivatives Desk 312-408-8750;E-mail derivatives@reuter.com.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
