<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9596" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Albert Bertino, Disney animator, dies at 84.</title>
<headline>Albert Bertino, Disney animator, dies at 84.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albert Bertino, a Walt Disney animator who helped create such characters as Bambi, Goofy and Donald Duck, has died, a Disney spokesman said on Thursday. He was 84.</p>
<p>Bertino, who joined Disney in 1939 after working as a cartoonist and illustrator, died in Los Angeles on Sunday.</p>
<p>He also had a hand in the animated movies &quot;Fantasia&quot; and &quot;Pinocchio&quot; and was credited with perfecting the art of &quot;Imagineering,&quot; a combination of imagination and innovative engineering with which he created some of the most popular rides at the Disneyland amusement park in Anaheim, California, south of Los Angeles.</p>
<p>Bertino was responsible for &quot;Pirates of the Caribbean,&quot; &quot;Mr. Toad's Wild Ride,&quot; the &quot;Haunted Mansion&quot; and &quot;Country Bear Jamboree,&quot; a stage show featuring an animatronic bear named &quot;Big Al,&quot; which Bertino said was modelled on himself.</p>
<p>In addition to being an animator, he wrote many of the episodes for the &quot;Walt Disney's Wonderful World of Colour&quot; television series.</p>
<p>Bertino is survived by his wife, a son and daughter and four grandchildren.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
