<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9597" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY precious metals end higher after Euro rate cuts.</title>
<headline>NY precious metals end higher after Euro rate cuts.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York precious metals futures recovered from early lows to end higher Thursday, on buying by both funds and locals, against the backdrop of an easier global monetary policy setting, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold and silver were bought by funds and locals, trade met by only light trade selling, while the trade was also seen buying $400 and $410 calls in the options pit,&quot; one floor trader said.</p>
<p>COMEX December gold ended up $0.70 an ounce at $392.50, after seeing a seven day high at $393.40. Total estimated volume was 18,000 lots.  </p>
<p>A more accommodating monetary policy stance may lower real interest rates and boost demand for precious metals by both investors and fabricators, analysts said.</p>
<p>In New York bullion trade, spot gold was quoted $387.20/387.70 at the close, from a London afternoon fix of $387.00 and a New York close Wednesday at $386.60/387.10.</p>
<p>The Philadelphia Stock Exchange's gold stocks index ended up 1.80 points, or 1.43 percent, at 127.60 also.</p>
<p>COMEX September silver ended up 5.0 cents at $5.220 an ounce, after edging up to a new two month high at $5.245 intraday. Total silver futures volume was pegged at 22,000.</p>
<p>&quot;But I think we're closer to the top of the likely range than the bottom for the next few months,&quot; Imperial Bank's Los Angeles based chief trader Jeff Singer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Silver mostly rose on shortcovering earlier this week, but producers are ready to hedge again to ensure cash flow not far from current levels.&quot;</p>
<p>NYMEX October platinum ended up $1.00 an ounce at $403.00, with support seen around $400 and resistance at $405.00.</p>
<p>Open interest in the NYMEX October contract stood at 964,000 ounces as of August 19, far in excess of the 71,500 ounces of physical platinum registered against NYMEX positions, analysts noted.</p>
<p>NYMEX September palladium ended down $0.60 an ounce though at $125.00.</p>
<p>The September palladium contract, which is only 10 days from becoming deliverable, has open interest of 415,000 ounces, while warehouse stocks are only 12,000 ounces.</p>
<p>--Clive McKeef, New York Commodities Desk, +212-859-1641.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
