<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9599" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rosy outlook for U.S. wheat sales to China fades.</title>
<headline>Rosy outlook for U.S. wheat sales to China fades.</headline>
<byline>Maggie McNeil</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The outlook for U.S. wheat sales to China -- which until a few months ago was one of the brightest spots in the U.S. grain export picture -- has lost its rosy glow.</p>
<p>A record-large wheat harvest in China, stiff competition from non-U.S. grain suppliers and a lingering dispute between Washington and Beijing over the quality of recent U.S. wheat shipments have sharply dimmed the chances for sales of American wheat to China for at least the next several months, grain industry officials and agricultural experts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There may not be that much demand in China for additional U.S. wheat purchases,&quot; said an international trade specialist at the Agriculture Department.</p>
<p>&quot;It doesn't take a rocket scientist to see that there's going to be a lot of competition,&quot; said a grain industry official, referring to good wheat harvests and abundant export supplies currently being reported in major non-U.S. wheat exporting nations such as Canada, Australia and Argentina.</p>
<p>China produces and consumes more wheat than any other nation in the world. This year it is estimated that Chinese farmers grew an astoundingly large wheat crop of 107 million metric tons -- almost twice what American farmers harvested -- and that Chinese consumers will eat 114 million tons of wheat -- about four times the U.S. consumption.</p>
<p>Sparked by sky-rocketing economic growth in China's urban areas, higher incomes and a huge population of 1.2 billion people, Chinese demand for imported farm goods has surged.</p>
<p>China is now the world's largest importer of wheat and has become one of the biggest buyers of U.S.-grown wheat. Like the former Soviet Union in the 1970s, big grain purchases by China, or even signs that the Chinese are interested in making some deals, can roil grain markets around the globe.</p>
<p>Substantial purchases of U.S. wheat by China in the last few years has buttressed prices. Total Chinese wheat imports in 1994 soared to over 10 million tons, then jumped to 12 million the next year. The United States provided about a third of those imports.</p>
<p>This year, however, the U.S. Agriculture Department has estimated that Chinese wheat imports will drop to 8 million tons, and experts say that number could go even lower, depending on the final size of the big Chinese wheat harvest.</p>
<p>Exporters have already shipped over 800,000 tons of U.S. wheat to China, and had booked over another million tons for delivery this summer.</p>
<p>But Chinese concerns about a fungus in U.S. wheat popped up in July, causing Beijing to reject several cargoes of U.S. wheat and resulting in the eventual cancellation of hundreds of millions of dollars worth of U.S. wheat sales to China.</p>
<p>Officials from Washington and Beijing have been meeting on the issue for several weeks, and U.S. officials have publicly remained cautiously optimistic that the problem can be resolved and that China will be back in the U.S. market.</p>
<p>An increasing number of experts, however, say that at least for this marketing year, which ends next May, China will probably not be a major presence in the U.S. wheat market.</p>
<p>&quot;China probably won't be back in the U.S. market until the end of this year or early next year at the earliest,&quot; said an official with a major exporter. &quot;And it wouldn't surprise me if China stays out of the market all this marketing year.&quot;</p>
<p>One trade specialist said that instead of turning to the United States, China will likely buy about 5 million tons of wheat from Canada, another 2 million tons from Australia, and maybe even purchase some wheat from Argentina.</p>
<p>But China expert Hunter Colby at the Agriculture Department said that long-term, the trend for China's agricultural demand is still rosy.</p>
<p>&quot;In one year you can have a sharp swing in trade, but the trend is up,&quot; said Colby. &quot;China's economic growth is strong, and their consumption will grow. There's significant room for growth in imports in the future.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
