<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9601" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee ends up sharply, Dec at 3-month high.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee ends up sharply, Dec at 3-month high.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures charged higher Thursday, as fund buying lifted most-active December to its highest settlement in three months, traders said.</p>
<p>Industry sources said today's rally was led by the spot September contract, as dealers scrambled to cover short positions on September's first notice day Thursday.</p>
<p>September's open interest declined 588 lots as of August 21, to 2,768 lots, the equivalent of 692,000 bags of coffee. However, only 34,516 bags remained in the Exchange's cache as of August 16.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the number of open positions, it looks like there is a squeeze going on with September delivery,&quot; said Refco analyst Ann Prendergast.</p>
<p>Additionally, no delivery notices issued against September issued today, she noted.</p>
<p>Spot September settled up 6.05 cents a lb, at 131.10. The benchmark December closing 3.80 cents higher, at 120.80 cents, its highest level since May 21, after ranging between 121.00 and 116.50. The remaining months finished up 1.20 to 2.70.</p>
<p>Concerns about the scarcity of available coffee for delivery against the September contract have bolstered the market for six consecutive sessions, traders said.  </p>
<p>Reflecting nearby supply worries, the September/December switch swelled to a hefty 10.30 cents on Thursday, compared to 8.05 cents at Wednesday's close.</p>
<p>However, some traders said the market appeared overbought after rising 9.25 cents -- or more than eight percent -- since last Friday.</p>
<p>Volume was heavy, at an estimated 15,440 lots.</p>
<p>-Patricia Avidan, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
