<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9602" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Perot predicts Democrats will also back tax cuts.</title>
<headline>Perot predicts Democrats will also back tax cuts.</headline>
<byline>Michael Lindenberger</byline>
<dateline>LOUISVILLE, Ky. 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reform party presidential candidate Ross Perot predicted Thursday that Democrats will join Republicans in calling for a tax cut, a device he said was little more than a promise of free candy.</p>
<p>&quot;Our country has severe financial problems,&quot; he told a Veterans of Foreign Wars convention. &quot;We've got to deal with them now. If we don't we're going to have a financial meltdown.&quot;</p>
<p>He said neither of the two major parties will take responsibility for the massive government debt or for Social Security and pension systems that are operated hand-to-mouth, month-by-month.</p>
<p>&quot;My position is they were both there when it happened. Nobody else was there so somebody has to take responsbility,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But now they're going to present you with massive and exciting plans to solve these problems. And they're going to to present you, both parties, with the mother of all tax cuts to fix this,&quot; Perot said.</p>
<p>&quot;Let me give you an analogy. You come out and see me and say 'Ross, I'm hopelessly in debt. I can't pay my bills. You're a businessman, could you give me some advice?'</p>
<p>&quot;And I'd say 'Sure...get your boss to cut your salary.' You'd say 'Ross but I can't pay my bills now.' I'd say 'Let's change the subject.' That's what they're telling you right now and boy do we love it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Ask yourself, are they giving you hard facts or are they spending their time promising you free candy.&quot;</p>
<p>Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole, who spoke to the same group earlier this week, has proposed a 15 percent income tax cut which he said should put money in the pockets of middle-class American wage earners and encourage growth and investment.</p>
<p>President Clinton has been critical of Dole's plan.</p>
<p>Perot got 19 percent of the votes cast in the 1992 presidential election against Republican George Bush and Clinton. He has accepted $29.2 million in taxpayers money to fund this year's campaign.</p>
<p>He told the veterans that 62 percent of voters want a new party and &quot;there's not a penny of special interest money&quot; in his organisation.</p>
<p>He said the country's 27 million veterans represent more than enough votes to swing the election and he urged them to study the issues and not be manipulated by propaganda &quot;just like Tokyo Rose and people like that dumped on you during World War II.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOUISVILLE, Ky."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
