<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9604" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME pork belly futures close mostly limit up.</title>
<headline>CME pork belly futures close mostly limit up.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME pork belly futures remained strong on a reversal in August and technical demand in next year contracts and closed mostly up the 2.000-cent-a-lb limit. Hog futures also closed up on technical support, traders said.</p>
<p>August through March bellies finished limit up with August at 91.375 cents a lb and February at 84.150 cents. Other months finished 1.900 to 1.600 cents.</p>
<p>Recent selling pressure in August after three limit losses in a row, subsided as that month stopped following the fresh cash market and started looking at tight deliverable supplies.</p>
<p>&quot;There are continued tight supplies and continued strong demand&quot; for bacon, said Julia Bussie, analyst for AG Edwards.</p>
<p>Belly futures had fallen sharply recently when the fresh market broke from $106 per cwt to $81. Next year contracts started to show support Wednesday on an oversold condition and August turned Thursday morning after posting an early loss of 1.575 cents.</p>
<p>Bussie noted the strong technical signals continued in back months and a rally in August helped take those months up the daily limit. Deferreds held support Wednesday and appeared set to move higher, she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
