<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9605" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: COMEX copper settles barely lower, awaits LME data.</title>
<headline>COMEX copper settles barely lower, awaits LME data.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX copper settled lower in light volume with the most-active December contract trading within less than a cent range.</p>
<p>There was no fresh fundamental news to shake the market from its trading range, leaving brokers to await Friday's LME stock report, the last report until next Friday, for much hoped for direction.</p>
<p>The LME will be closed Monday due to a U.K. public holiday so the regularly scheduled stock report set for Tuesday will not be released.</p>
<p>In the U.S. labor talks at Phelps Dodge's Chino mine continued, and BHP Copper said it restarted its San Manuel smelter late Wednesday following a nine-day shutdown.</p>
<p>December COMEX settled 0.25 cent weaker at 89.65 cents per lb, traded 90.20 to 89.40 cents. September went out 0.75 cent lower at 90.65 cent, with August ending 0.45 cent down at 91.15 cent.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at 6,000 lots, barely changed from Wednesday's official 6,191 lots.</p>
<p>Some traders expected no significant moves in the copper market until after Labor Day in the U.S. on September 2.</p>
<p>-- New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
