<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9611" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sun International confident on casino plan.</title>
<headline>Sun International confident on casino plan.</headline>
<byline>Robin Sidel</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sun International Hotels Ltd expressed confidence Thursday that it will win approval to enter Atlantic City's booming casino market despite nagging questions about prior business practices.</p>
<p>The latest project, combined with its resorts in the Bahamas and Connecticut, will likely keep Sun International from entering the Las Vegas market anytime soon, said South African gambling magnate and company chairman Sol Kerzner.</p>
<p>&quot;I would be very surprised to see us in Las Vegas in the next year or two,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Kerzner made his comments in an hour-long conference call hosted by Bear Stearns &amp; Co, which is representing Sun in its proposed $210 million purchase of Griffin Gaming &amp; Entertainment Inc. Griffin owns the Resorts facility in Atlantic City.</p>
<p>Kerzner said he hopes to secure a license from the New Jersey Casino Control Commission within the typical four to six months.</p>
<p>&quot;If anything, we think our licensing process could be on the short end&quot; of that timeframe, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I want to make it very clear obviously that (we) as a company - Sun International - would not have filed a gaming license (application) one month ago unless we had done a lot of homework. We do not file a gaming license in Atlantic City in a vacuum,&quot; Kerzner said.</p>
<p>Sun International owns hotels and casino resorts around the world, including Paradise Island in the Bahamas and the soon-to-be-opened Mohegan Sun Casino and Resort in Connecticut.  </p>
<p>Kerzner acknowledged &quot;there will be rumors, there will be innuendoes and all that kind of stuff,&quot; referring to a investigation conducted by the state of Connecticut before it granted a casino license to Sun.</p>
<p>Kerzner has faced numerous questions about financial dealings in South Africa in the late 1980s. A comprehensive investigation into Kerzner's background found &quot;there was nothing that the state police came up with that gave us any pause whatsoever&quot; to grant him a license, said George Wandrak, deputy executive director of the Connecticut Division of Special Revenue Services.  </p>
<p>&quot;At the end of the day, the facts will count,&quot; Kerzner said in the conference call.</p>
<p>Kerzner said he was excited about prospects for the Resorts hotel, which is slated to undergo a major expansion, and for the gaming industry in Atlantic City.</p>
<p>&quot;We just came away convinced that this was far and away...superior entrance into Atlantic City than trying to put down $700 million or $800 million...&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Atlantic City is undergoing a major construction boom as casino and hotels bet big bucks on the famous seaside resort located on the U.S. East Coast.  </p>
<p>Over the past year, major Las Vegas operators Mirage Resorts Inc  Circus Circus Enterprises Inc and MGM Grand Inc have announced elaborate plans for Atlantic City casinos, the grandest being Mirage's plans to develop the Marina district.</p>
<p>Also, ITT Corp recently announced a major building plan for Atlantic City, and Hilton Hotels Corp announced plans to buy Bally Entertainment Corp in a $2 billion deal that gives it an Atlantic City presence.</p>
<p>Regarding other hotel and casino properties owned by Sun International, Kerzner said the Paradise Island hotel is operating at an occupancy rate of more than 90 percent.</p>
<p>The Connecticut casino, located near the hugely successful Foxwoods Casino, is slated to open in October.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
