<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9612" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. refiners' fortunes hang on 4Q heating oil.</title>
<headline>U.S. refiners' fortunes hang on 4Q heating oil.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. refiners, plagued by anemic margins this summer, are hanging their fortunes in the fourth quarter on a boom in heating oil, analysts say.</p>
<p>Light grades of crude oil like West Texas Intermediate and North Sea Brent are expected also to firm, benefitting from their high distillate yields, but overall gains should come from products outpacing the cost of crude oil during the winter.</p>
<p>&quot;Margins have not been doing well because crude has done a fabulous job of keeping up with products,&quot; said John Saucer, Houston-based oil analyst with Smith Barney.  </p>
<p>Robust distillate demand growth and disincentives to build inventory are raising prospects for tight products supply and better margins later this year, Saucer added.</p>
<p>This could turn the tables on the typically weak fourth quarter, when margins usually are more sluggish than other quarters.</p>
<p>Others cautioned that a scramble to supply heating oil, while hiking its price, could flood the market with other less desirable products and bear down on overall profitability as refiners cannot turn over their entire production from, say, gasoline to heating oil.  </p>
<p>&quot;The stocks may be a bullish factor, but making up one component, we risk oversupplying other components,&quot; analyst Paul Ting at Salomom Brothers said.</p>
<p>For the near-term, refiners are expected to keep output running at least around current levels, at 93 percent capacity.</p>
<p>NYMEX crack spreads -- one barometer of refinery profitability -- dropped drastically for gasoline/crude but is being offset by improved heating oil/crude cracks.</p>
<p>The gasoline/crude crack fell from over $8.00 a barrel in early May to an unseasonal $3.94, while heating oil/crude has jumped to $4.00 a barrel from $1.60 a month ago.  </p>
<p>Apart from the West Coast, refinery profits elsewhere have mostly been doused by less buoyant gasoline prices, where demand is down 0.9 percent from a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Midwest margins have fallen off quite precipitiously since the second quarter, down by more than $1.00,&quot; Salomon Brother's Paul Ting said.</p>
<p>Second quarter margins were $5.35 a barrel, compared with an estimated $4.33 a barrel average for the third quarter.</p>
<p>And margins could become more sickly depending on winter temperatures and the rate at which stocks are replenished.  </p>
<p>A study by Charles River Associates notes that heating oil deficits in the East Coast region could be fixed by increased supplies from the Gulf Coast this winter, leaving an excess of 50,000 to 100,000 barrels per day of supply.</p>
<p>Far East refinery capacities have bounced up sharply this year, mostly in South Korea, and this has already narrowed arbitrage opportunities from the U.S.</p>
<p>--New York Energy Desk, +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
