<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9613" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Judgmental forecasts dwarf economic models at Fed.</title>
<headline>Judgmental forecasts dwarf economic models at Fed.</headline>
<byline>Isabelle Clary</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Although the Federal Reserve has traditionally relied on macroeconomic models for its decisions, policy makers are turning increasingly to &quot;judgmental forecasts&quot;, sources at the Fed said.</p>
<p>The shift towards putting a higher degree of interpretation on data has occured because broad technological changes have thrown into question the ability of the models to gauge productivity gains accurately, they said.</p>
<p>This is mainly a problem in the latest sector to benefit from the computer revolution, the service sector, they added.  </p>
<p>&quot;The relationship has basically broken down,&quot; one Fed source told Reuters.</p>
<p>The source, refering to the relation between growth and inflation, said &quot;the question is whether a structural shift (in the economy) has actually occurred.&quot;</p>
<p>The source said central bankers are heavily relying on judgmental forecasts because it is difficult to gauge the impact on the huge economy of massive business investments in cost-saving new technologies.</p>
<p>&quot;Productivity gains in the service sector are particularly difficult to gauge,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The models are equations to estimate the behavior of key relationships for the economy, based on data going as far back as possible,&quot; the source said. &quot;The longer the period, the better the forecast is, provided there has not been a kind of structural shift during the period studied.&quot;</p>
<p>The source said pointed out that the U.S. economy may be more efficient today due to the many technological innovations that have reached a broad spectrum of business activity.</p>
<p>&quot;By the same token the Consumer Price Index may overstate inflation, productivity may be understated,&quot; the source said.  </p>
<p>Another Fed source said the Fed Board's models, which are based on economic series running back several decades, &quot;may have too much historic relationship embedded with them.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The Fed tends to put less weight on the models as opposed to a judgmental approach,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>According to the sources, the models were put to the test in early 1995 when data, based on historic performance, continued to signal the possibility of inflationary pressures coming from a year marked by strong growth.</p>
<p>Alan Blinder, an expert on inventories who was Fed Vice-Chairman at the time, was the first to point to the risk of a slowdown.  </p>
<p>The Fed, ending a rapid-fire preemptive tightening cycle, lowered the federal funds rate three times between July 1995 and January 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Macroeconomic models are useful tools, but the truth of the matter is that the ability to condense the behavior of 250 million into a set of 50 or 100 equations is still limited,&quot; the second source said.</p>
<p>He agreed the central issue in the U.S. economy today may be the understatement of productivity &quot;which would allow to place potential growth at a higher level.&quot;</p>
<p>A more efficient economy would also allow for a lower unemployment rate to prevail over an extended period without fueling inflationary pressures.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1666</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
