<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9617" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Republicans favored for U.S. Congress - Reuters poll.</title>
<headline>Republicans favored for U.S. Congress - Reuters poll.</headline>
<byline>Eddie Evans</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>American voters narrowly prefer Democratic President Bill Clinton over challenger Bob Dole, but they still want Republicans in control of Congress, a Reuters poll said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The apparent preference for divided government was a key finding of the survey conducted for Reuters by John Zogby Group International.</p>
<p>It found that 43.6 percent of voters want Republicans to control the Senate and 36.6 percent would prefer Democrats. For the House of Representatives, 40.8 percent wanted Republicans in control and 37.7 percent favoured Democrats.</p>
<p>The results were similar to the last Reuters-Zogby poll, released on August 6, which put Republicans ahead of Democrats 42.4 percent to 39.7 percent for the Senate and 42.2 percent to 40.2 percent for the House.</p>
<p>&quot;The voters like this mix. They like this divided government, as long as they get things done,&quot; pollster John Zogby said.</p>
<p>The latest poll, taken just after last week's Republican convention, put Dole five percentage points behind in the race against Clinton, a much narrower gap than the 12 points in the August 6 poll.</p>
<p>The new poll, of 1,007 likely voters, was taken from August 18-20, just as the signing of major legislation on the minimum wage, health care and welfare reform by President Clinton this week began to dominate the political news.</p>
<p>&quot;With a big week for major legislation ... voters may be responding to a feeling of getting the best of both worlds -- divided government without gridlock,&quot; Zogby said.</p>
<p>The poll suggested the crucial region in the November 5 election would be the central states and the Great Lakes, where Republicans led in overall Congressional preferences while Clinton was ahead in the presidential election.</p>
<p>In the central and Great Lakes states, 46 percent preferred that Republicans keep a majority in the Senate against 33 percent for Democrats, and 44 percent for Republicans to keep the House against 35 percent for Democrats.</p>
<p>In the South and West, voters preferred Republicans for both the presidency and Congress. But in the East, they preferred Democrats for both the presidency and Congress, the poll said.</p>
<p>Which party is your preference to win a majority in</p>
<p>	 the Senate and the House, respectively?</p>
<p>				  Fem    Demo- Repub Indep-   Aug 6</p>
<p>		  All   Male  -ale   crat  lican endent   Poll</p>
<p> Democrats    36.6   32.2  40.9   74.8   7.9  26.3     39.7</p>
<p>in the Senate</p>
<p> Republicans  43.6   49.9  37.5    9.3  81.7  39.5     42.4</p>
<p>in the Senate</p>
<p> Democrats    37.7   34.4  40.8   75.2   8.0  29.2     40.2</p>
<p>in the House</p>
<p> Republicans  40.8   47.9  34.1    8.3  80.1  33.6     42.2</p>
<p>in the House</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
