<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9622" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IRS need not specify why auditing muni bonds - Owens.</title>
<headline>IRS need not specify why auditing muni bonds - Owens.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Internal Revenue Service told municipal bond lawyers it does not have to disclose to states and localities the specific reasons why it has targeted a particular bond offering for audit.</p>
<p>Marcus Owens, director of IRS's exempt organizations division, made the statement in an Aug 8 letter to National Association of Bond Lawyers (NABL), which had urged IRS in a May 7 letter to inform issuers &quot;as fully as possible&quot; about the nature of pending audits.</p>
<p>NABL released a copy of the Aug 8 letter from IRS today.  </p>
<p>Owens said it already is IRS' policy to tell an issuer &quot;generally&quot; why it is auditing a particular bond offering, such as whether it is for a general audit, a review of a particular market sector or a statistical sampling.</p>
<p>&quot;We have and will continue to do this in the bond area,&quot; Owens said. &quot;We are initiating our first statistical sampling program in the tax-exempt bond area early next fiscal year,&quot; he noted.</p>
<p>But issuers that want specifics about an audit, such as what rules the IRS thinks may have been abridged and how, will not have much luck, Owens said.  </p>
<p>&quot;In our view, to provide a description of the issues classified or targeted in a specific examination could adversely impact the success of the Service's bond examination program,&quot; Owens said in the two-page letter addressed to John Cross, chairman of NABL's general tax committee.</p>
<p>It could give issuers and the public the wrong idea about the &quot;breadth and scope of an examination, Owens said.</p>
<p>And it could &quot;shape&quot; the amount and type of information IRS gets from a targeted issuer in the future, Owens said.  </p>
<p>Cross had told IRS in May that issuers want as much information as possible about an audit so they can comply with the disclosure requirements of the federal securities laws.</p>
<p>Regulations approved by the Securities and Exchange Commission in November 1994 bar dealers from underwriting bonds unless the issuer has pledged to provide ongoing financial information, such as newsbreaking events, to the market.</p>
<p>Cross also said clearer information from IRS means that financially strapped localities can spend less on duplicating and other costs of responding to the Service's inquiry.  </p>
<p>Amy Dunbar, director of governmental affairs for NABL, said about Owens' letter, &quot;It's still not clear to me what they are going to be telling us&quot; about audits.</p>
<p>She said it sounds like IRS will send issuers a &quot;fairly generic letter&quot; about an audit, whether it is targeted or not. &quot;It will just say you are being audited, please send us your documents and here's who to call,&quot; Dunbar said.</p>
<p>&quot;The question is that when you call, what additional elaboration are you going to get? That is still not clear to me from this letter&quot; in light of other recents statements by IRS officials, Dunbar.</p>
<p>She referred to an earlier statement by Gerald Sack, special assistant in IRS' exempt organizations division, who said issuers can call the IRS agent assigned to the audit for more information.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
