<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9626" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton signs welfare bill that gets mixed reviews.</title>
<headline>Clinton signs welfare bill that gets mixed reviews.</headline>
<byline>Laurence McQuillan</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Amid high praise and angry rebukes, President Bill Clinton on Thursday signed an overhaul of the welfare system that gives states more power, limits eligibility and ends direct federal aid for poor children.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we are ending welfare as we know it,&quot; Clinton said, echoing his 1992 presidential campaign promise as he signed the bill delivered by the Republican-controlled Congress.</p>
<p>&quot;But I hope this day will be remembered not for what it ended but for what it began, a new day that offers hope, honours responsibility, rewards work and changes the terms of the debate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>With Republican and Democratic leaders of Congress conspicuously missing from the politically charged election-year ceremony, Clinton acknowledged the new law &quot;is far from perfect&quot; but vowed to work to correct its flaws.</p>
<p>&quot;What we are trying to do today is to overcome the flaws of the welfare system for the people who are trapped on it,&quot; he said. &quot;We all know that the typical family on welfare today is very different from the one that welfare was designed to deal with 60 years ago.&quot;</p>
<p>Under the new law, which has been condemned by many of the liberal allies Clinton deems essential to his bid for a second term, federal welfare spending will be cut by about $55 billion over six years, mainly by reducing funding for the Food Stamps programme and aid to legal immigrants.</p>
<p>It also imposes a five-year lifetime limit on receiving welfare and requires recipients to begin working within two years after receiving benefits.</p>
<p>One of the more controversial changes ends a 61-year guarantee of federal aid for poor children. Aid to Families with Dependent Children, the main federal cash welfare programme, and smaller programmes are folded into an annual block grant to states to run their own programmes instead.</p>
<p>The bill upset many Democrats and their traditional allies. &quot;This isn't welfare reform, it's welfare denial,&quot; Sen. Paul Simon of Illinois complained. Eleanor Smeal, head of the Feminist Majority, charged that &quot;tragically, President Clinton has caved in to this reactionary Congress' demands.&quot;</p>
<p>At the same time, Christina Martin, a spokeswoman for Republican presidential challenger Bob Dole, said that &quot;by selling out his own party, Bill Clinton has proven he is ideologically adrift.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton twice before vetoed welfare legislation crafted by the Republican Congress, but with election-year politics heating up, several of his political strategists recommended that he sign this version and try to amend it later.</p>
<p>Even before signing the bill into law, he granted waivers from the five-year limit for benefits to Hawaii, Minnesota and the District of Columbia. Representative Clay Shaw of Florida, a chief congressional sponsor of the bill and the only Republican lawmaker to attend the signing ceremony, made public a letter to Clinton objecting to the waivers and urging him &quot;to avoid any further efforts to undermine and weaken welfare reform.&quot;</p>
<p>White House officials privately admit the law has created a strain with the Democratic Party's liberal wing but believe most will return to the fold before the Nov. 5 election.</p>
<p>Campaign strategists hope to strike an inclusive tone at next week's Democratic National Convention in Chicago, with black civil rights activist Jesse Jackson -- an ardent critic of the welfare law -- the first major speaker to address the conclave on Tuesday night.</p>
<p>In Kansas City, Stephen Burger, executive director of the International Union of Gospel Missions, one of the nation's largest providers of services to the homeless, offered mixed reviews of the changes.</p>
<p>He said they offered &quot;tremendous opportunities&quot; for some social service organisations but noted &quot;the devil is in the details&quot; and said he was concerned that religious groups &quot;accepting government funds would either have to change their programmes fundamentally or risk being sued.&quot;</p>
<p>The American Civil Liberties Union expressed similar worry about litigation because the law's Charitable Choice Clause that allows &quot;states to contract with religious organisations to provide social services to the poor&quot; requires that none of the funds &quot;shall be expended for sectarian worship, instruction, or proselytisation.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
