<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9627" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lilly gets boost from Dura deal.</title>
<headline>Lilly gets boost from Dura deal.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eli Lilly &amp; Co gets a one-time boost from its fading Ceclor antibiotic franchise by agreeing to sell the U.S. marketing rights to a time-release formulation of the drug to Dura Pharmaceuticals Inc, industry analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Ceclor-CD is a dead product,&quot; said NatWest Securities pharmaceutical industry analyst Jack Lamberton.</p>
<p>Ceclor sales have fallen since it lost patent protection. Once Lilly's top product, Ceclor had sales of $281 million in 1996's first half, down from $421 million a year before.  </p>
<p>&quot;This would be a way for them to get a little more mileage out of it,&quot; said NatCity Investments analyst David Lebedeff.</p>
<p>For $100 million, Lilly also is selling to Dura marketing rights to Keftab, another antibiotic in a sales sunset. First half 1996 Keftab sales were $83 million, flat from a year ago.</p>
<p>For San Diego-based Dura, the $100-million transaction means a big boost in sales. The company said Thursday adding Keftab and Ceclor-CD to its product line could mean $100 million in additional sales in the year 2000.</p>
<p>Dura reported total sales of $18.8 million in the second quarter ended June 30, up from $13.1 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>Shares in Dura were up 5-1/4 to 32 at midday Thursday, while shares in Lilly were up 1/4 to 59-5/8.</p>
<p>&quot;This acquisition is the big one that investors had hoped for&quot; by Dura, said Vector Securities analyst Peter Ginsberg.</p>
<p>Ceclor is already being made generically by IVAX Corp, but the time-release formula sold to Dura will likely take market share from older versions, Ginsberg said.</p>
<p>--Kevin Drawbaugh 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
