<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9628" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Gulf oil output turns corner, to double by 2000.</title>
<headline>US Gulf oil output turns corner, to double by 2000.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Connole</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>After years of decline, oil production in the U.S. Gulf of Mexico is turning the corner thanks to deepwater technology and is charted to double to more than two million barrels a day, analysts predict.</p>
<p>Oil production will accelerate by a net 200,000 barrels-per-day by the end of next year, and be double last year's output by the turn of the century, according to industry estimates compiled by Reuters Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Led by the massive Mars and Ursa fields, the U.S. Gulf is charted to pump at 2.114 million barrels-per-day (bpd) by the year 2000, compared with 1995 output of 1.031 million bpd, according to the International Energy Agency in Paris.</p>
<p>&quot;The start up of the deep water Gulf Mars field this month represents the first 100,000 bpd field in the U.S. Gulf of Mexico and the effective inauguration of the U.S. Gulf as a major new world class production province,&quot; said the IEA's report in July.</p>
<p>Old fields already in production pump around 704,000 bpd of oil and will see their volumes decline by 124,000 bpd to 580,000 bpd by the year 2000.  </p>
<p>However, more than 20 sizable new fields will be brought onstream in the next four years to spike offshore output by some million barrels a day.</p>
<p>The reversal in Gulf production forecasts comes mainly from the advent of extreme deep-water drilling, as in the case of Mars and Ursa, which are located some 3,000-4,000 feet below water.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said the cost of digging for oil has been made less and less prohibitive with the use of new technologies, reflecting a pattern seen in other parts of the world, notably in the North Sea.  </p>
<p>&quot;Technology lowers costs, oil that was expensive a few years ago (to extract) is no longer,&quot; said Bill O'Grady, oil analyst with A.G. Edwards &amp; Sons in St. Louis.</p>
<p>Major producers British Petroleum and Shell are invested in the Mars and Ursa projects, two of the leading ventures bolstering the Gulf's prospects.</p>
<p>Mars is Shell's $1.2 billion deep-water entry, currently averaging 21,000 bpd of oil output and 25 million cubic feet of natural gas per day. Daily production is to plateau at 100,000 bpd of oil and 110 million cubic feet of gas per day in early 1997, according a Shell spokeswoman.  </p>
<p>Shell holds a 71.5 pct interest in Mars, with BP owning the remaining 28.5 pct.</p>
<p>Shell also is operator of the Ursa field, which is to come onstream mid-1999, and possess daily peak capacity at 150,000 bpd of oil and 400 million cubic feet of gas, surpassing Mars' maximum output by year 2000.</p>
<p>Shell runs Ursa with smaller investments provided by BP, Exxon and Conoco.  </p>
<p>For its part, BP said its Troika development, owned in three 33 percent slices with Shell and Marathon, will come onstream in the first half of 1998 and have peak capacity at 80,000 bpd.</p>
<p>Other large Gulf projects include Shell's Auger field, already pumping around 65,000 bpd, a figure expected to peak at 70,000 bpd from 1997 to 2000.</p>
<p>The Shell spokeswoman said the Ram-Powell field will arrive in 1997, and eventually peak at 60,000 bpd of oil and 200 million cubic feet of gas per day.  </p>
<p>Added output is also seen for the second phase of Tahoe development and from the Enchilada holding, which will have maximum output of 40,000 bpd of oil and 300 million cubic feet of gas per day, the Shell spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Other new fields due for major incremental production in coming years include the following:</p>
<p>--Mahogany, rising from 10,000 bpd to 45,000 bpd next year and thru 2000. Operator Phillips Petroleum..</p>
<p>--Neptune, starting at 20,000 bpd next year and rising to 25,000 bpd. Operator Oryx Energy.  </p>
<p>--Sunday Silence starting last year at 10,000 bpd, rising to 30,000 bpd this year and peaking at 50,000 bpd next year and through 2000. Operator Tatham Offshore.</p>
<p>--Wasatch is coming on at 20,000 bpd in 1998 and rising to 50,000 bpd the year after and to 75,000 bpd in 2000. Operator Marathon.</p>
<p>--Alleghany starts at 10,000 bpd in 1998, rises to 50,000 bpd the next year and 70,000 bpd in 2000. Operator Enserch.</p>
<p>--Baldpate arrives with 10,000 bpd in 1998 and climbs to 35,000 bpd in 2000. Operator Texaco.  </p>
<p>--Spend-a-Buck starts at 10,000 this year, rises to 35,000 bpd in 1997 and peaks at 45,000 bpd in 2000. Operator Tatham Offshore.</p>
<p>--Genesis comes on at 10,000 bpd in 1999 and rises to 40,000 bpd the year after. Operator Chevron Corp.</p>
<p>--Patrick Connole, New York Energy Desk, +1 212 859 1828</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
