<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9629" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton shows weakness among his own generation.</title>
<headline>Clinton shows weakness among his own generation.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, U.S. Political Correspondent</p>
<p>One in three Democrats thinks President Bill Clinton lacks a firm core of beliefs, while one in five Republicans believes Bob Dole is too old to be president, according to a new Reuters poll.</p>
<p>The poll, conducted for Reuters by the John Zogby Group, found both major candidates have potential weaknesses in the campaign for the Nov. 5 presidential election.</p>
<p>But Texan billionaire Ross Perot, running on the ticket of his own Reform Party, is unlikely to be able to capitalise. More than 60 percent of respondents believed his personality did not make him suitable to be president.</p>
<p>The poll of 1,007 likely voters carried a margin of error of plus or minus 3.2 percentage points. It showed Clinton leading Dole by a little more than five percentage points, 41.5 to 36.3 percent. Perot trailed with 7.4 percent.</p>
<p>Clinton led Dole by 23 points in the East, while Dole had a narrow three-point lead in the South and West and the Rocky Mountain states. In the central and Great Lakes states, where the election may be decided, Clinton had a four-point lead.</p>
<p>Not surprisingly, Clinton had twice as much support as Dole among voters under the age of 30 and held a 6.5-point lead among those in the 30-49 age-group. While the president and Dole were tied among voters of 65 or older, Clinton, who turned 50 this week, was weakest in the 50-64 age group, where Dole enjoyed a five-point advantage.</p>
<p>These figures might be a problem for Clinton since younger people are less likely to turn out to vote.</p>
<p>The president had a narrow lead among Catholic, who comprise a crucial swing group. But Dole led by almost 15 points among Protestants.</p>
<p>Clinton also led among groups earning less than $75,000 a year but richer Americans preferred Dole by a 25-point margin.</p>
<p>The gender gap remained a factor. Women preferred Clinton by 12 points. Men preferred Dole by 1.5 points.</p>
<p>Republicans fear Perot's entry into the race will hurt Dole. But 33 percent of Perot supporters said they would have voted for Clinton if their candidate had not run, while only 19 percent said they would have backed Dole. Among voters who supported Perot in 1992, the split was about even.</p>
<p>Some 12.5 percent of self-described Republican voters in the survey intend to vote for Clinton while eight percent of Democrats support Dole.</p>
<p>Turning to congressional elections, Democrats clearly have a major problem. Respondents preferred a Republican majority in the Senate by a historically wide margin of around 13 points in all regions except the East, where Democrats led by 10 points.</p>
<p>For the House of Representatives, the Republican lead was around nine points in all regions except the East, where Democrats led by 14 points. In 1994, when Republicans won control of both houses of Congress, they outpolled Democrats by 7.4 percentage points nationwide.</p>
<p>Dole's major challenge remains his need to overcome strong scepticism about his economic package, which includes a promise to cut income tax rates by 15 percent.</p>
<p>Some 36 percent of respondents strongly disagreed that Dole could succeed in both cutting taxes and balancing the budget, including 16 percent of Republicans and 35 percent of 1992 Perot voters. A further 16 percent of Republicans said they somewhat disagreed Dole could succeed.</p>
<p>Among voters who described themselves as conservative or very conservative, 53 percent disagreed that Dole could deliver the tax cuts and balance the budget.</p>
<p>Almost 60 percent of Republicans and 58 percent of Dole supporters said they would be willing to forgo the tax cut if they believed it would lead to an increase in the deficit.</p>
<p>Only 13.8 percent of Republicans listed taxes as the most important issue in the campaign, compared to 20 percent who cited education and 31.4 percent who rated the integrity and character of the candidate the most important issue.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
