<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9631" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NE Iowa corn ears small, soy pod count low - tour.</title>
<headline>NE Iowa corn ears small, soy pod count low - tour.</headline>
<dateline>BREMER COUNTY, Iowa 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iowa corn and soybean fields sampled on one northeastern route of the Pro Farmer crop tour were generally better than fields seen in Illinois and Indiana but corn ears were small and soy pod counts were low, crop scouts said.</p>
<p>Scouts attributed the slow maturity to late planting and cooler than normal July temperatures.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year was also a late year but by this time it was starting to catch up,&quot; said Weather Services Corp president Peter Leavitt, a 20-year tour veteran. &quot;This is the latest I've seen it in Illinois and Iowa.&quot;  </p>
<p>Scouts on one of 14 Iowa routes toured fields in the northeastern section and estimated potential corn yield at 130 to 140 bushels an acre.</p>
<p>That was mostly in line with the tour's five year average for the northeastern region of 131.1 bushels an acre.</p>
<p>Soybean pod counts ranged from 748 to 1,012 pods per three foot by three foot square. The five year tour average for the region was 979.2 pods but scouts noted this year's tour was held one week later than in previous years.  </p>
<p>&quot;We haven't seen any bean fields without pods but the pod counts are low and they are basically finished flowering,&quot; said John Turner, crop analyst with the U.S. Department of Agriculture.</p>
<p>Corn fields toured in Dubuque and Delaware counties were mostly in the milk stage while some Fayette county fields had just pollinated.</p>
<p>Ears sampled in one Fayette county field had a pink hue on the kernel. &quot;That could be fusarium (fungus),&quot; Turner said.</p>
<p>Soybeans were mostly in the pod fill stage, about on average pace for the region.</p>
<p>Scouts from all 14 routes will meet in Worthington, Minn., on Thursday night to compile statewide estimates.</p>
<p>The four-day tour, sponsored by the farm marketing and merchandising group Professional Farmers of America, will scout fields in Minnesota and Iowa on Thursday and conclude on Friday by computing overall corn and soybean projections.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk 312-408 8720</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BREMER COUNTY, Iowa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
