<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9634" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Taylor ex Larry Fortensky facing drug charge.</title>
<headline>Taylor ex Larry Fortensky facing drug charge.</headline>
<dateline>HEMET, Calif. 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Larry Fortensky, the estranged husband of Elizabeth Taylor, was arrested and charged with drug use after police found him in an illegally parked luxury motor home, authorities said on Thursday.</p>
<p>He was arrested on Wednesday at the motor home, which police said was in a parking lot in Hemet, about 70 miles (113 km) east of Los Angeles. The vehicle had no license plates, Hemet Police Sgt. Gil Kammerzell said.</p>
<p>Police said Fortensky, 44, was in the motor home with a woman identified as his live-in maid. A black BMW belonging to Fortensky was parked next to the vehicle.</p>
<p>Fortensky, a construction worker before his marriage to Taylor in 1991, &quot;appeared to be extremely agitated and refused to cooperate with the officer when he was asked for the motor home's registration papers,&quot; Kammerzell said.</p>
<p>He said Fortensky remained uncooperative and refused to answer most of the officer's questions. &quot;While speaking with Fortensky the officer noticed that he displayed symptoms of being under the influence of a controlled substance.&quot;</p>
<p>Fortensky was released on his own recognisance and arraignment was scheduled for Sept. 20. He faces up to a year in county jail if convicted.</p>
<p>Taylor and Fortensky met in 1990 at the Betty Ford clinic in Palm Springs, California, where she was being treated for dependency on prescription drugs and he was undergoing treatment for alcoholism.</p>
<p>In Taylor's eighth marriage, they were married in 1991 at pop star Michael Jackson's Neverland Ranch amid a blaze of publicity. At the time she was 59 and he was 39.</p>
<p>Taylor filed for divorce in February this year and the divorce proceedings are still going through the courts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HEMET, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
