<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9643" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Education heads list of voter concerns in poll.</title>
<headline>Education heads list of voter concerns in poll.</headline>
<byline>Susan Cornwell</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Education and jobs are issues of more concern to U.S. voters than taxes, a Reuters poll said on Thursday in a finding that could favour President Bill Clinton over his opponent Bob Dole.</p>
<p>The poll, conducted for Reuters by John Zogby Group International, showed education was uppermost in voters' minds. Some 85.9 percent of respondents said it was the most important issue or very important in determining how they would vote in the November 5 presidential election.</p>
<p>The issue of jobs and the economy was second with a ranking of 79.9 percent, followed by crime, the candidate's character, health care, the federal budget deficit and the environment.</p>
<p>The issue of taxes was in eighth place in the list of 10 issues, with only 55 percent saying it was most important or very important. Dole has made a 15 percent tax cut the centrepiece of his campaign.</p>
<p>Abortion, an issue which seemed to dominate the Republican party debate prior to their convention in San Diego, ranked last of the 10 issues, even behind foreign policy.</p>
<p>The poll found overall that 41.5 percent of voters supported Clinton against 36.3 percent for Dole and 7.4 percent for Texas billionaire Ross Perot. That was a marked improvement for Dole from the first Reuters-Zogby poll Aug. 6, which showed him 12 points behind Clinton.</p>
<p>But pollster John Zogby said the findings on issues suggested voter interest may have subsided in Dole's tax cut plan, which grabbed attention when it was announced earlier this month.</p>
<p>&quot;When Dole announced it, it captured peoples' imaginations.  ... But the luster has worn off,&quot; Zogby said.</p>
<p>Furthermore, three in five respondents to the latest Reuters-Zogby poll (60.4 percent) would be willing to forego a tax cut if that would increase the deficit. Dole says he can cut taxes and reduce the deficit at the same time.</p>
<p>Education was a paramount concern for Americans. This was true across the political spectrum, with conservatives valuing it just as much as liberals, Zogby said.</p>
<p>This finding could help Clinton, Zogby said. The Democratic president has said he will protect education programmes from Republican budget cuts, and has proposed targeted tax cuts to help Americans pay for college.</p>
<p>But Zogby added that education was a tough issue for presidential candidates since many people think educating children is the duty of the states, not the U.S. government.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue should play to Clinton, and yet, George Bush wanted to be the education president and listed a number of programmes that just seemed to stall,&quot; Zogby said, recalling Clinton's Republican predecessor at the White House.</p>
<p>Dole has also emphasised education, most notably in his speech accepting the Republican nomination for the presidency in San Diego last week.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not educating all of our children,&quot; he said. &quot;Not for nothing are we the biggest education spenders and among the lowest of education achievers of the leading industrial nations.&quot;</p>
<p>But Dole's solutions to the problem are the ideological opposite of Clinton. Dole charged that teachers unions, who generally support the Democratic president, are to blame for much of the problem.</p>
<p>&quot;If education were a war, you would be losing it,&quot; he said of unions. He also backed &quot;school choice,&quot; a proposal that would provide government-funded vouchers so that low-income children can attend private schools if they choose.</p>
<p>The Reuters-Zogby poll of 1,007 likely voters was carried out between Sunday and Tuesday this week, just after the Republican convention ended.</p>
<p>The finding that jobs and the economy are still important to voters may also play well for Clinton. He frequently mentions that 10 million jobs have been created during his presidency, a time of economic expansion.</p>
<p>&quot;Hitting jobs and the economy is going to be a tough sell for Dole. Clinton has the opportunity to go before the people with a real record of accomplishment,&quot; Zogby said.</p>
<p>Crime and character were also important to voters. The character issue could be a negative for Clinton, especially since independent voters were quite concerned about it, Zogby said. &quot;It is a possible hole for Dole to plug into,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Clinton has been plagued by a host of character issues ranging from his investment in the failed Whitewater real estate deal in Arkansas, to allegations of sexual harrassment. How important is each of the following issues in determining how you vote in this year's election?</p>
<p>	   Most	Very    Somewhat     Not    Not Sure/</p>
<p>	 Important Important Important Important No Opinion</p>
<p> Taxes     12.9	42.1	36.3	 6.9	 1.8</p>
<p>Budget</p>
<p> Deficit   14.8	49.5	29.3	 4.8	 1.6</p>
<p>Jobs and</p>
<p> Economy   22.3	57.6	17.5	 1.2	 1.4</p>
<p> Crime     19.3	56.7	19.8	 3.1	 1.1</p>
<p> Education 25.8	60.1	11.0	 1.9	 1.1</p>
<p>Health</p>
<p> Care	21.8	51.5	21.2	 4.2	 1.2</p>
<p>Envir-</p>
<p> onment    13.3	43.3	35.1	 7.3	 1.0</p>
<p> Abortion  11.8	32.7	23.5	27.1	 5.0</p>
<p>Foreign</p>
<p> Policy    10.5	38.1	38.4	 9.1	 4.0</p>
<p>Candidate</p>
<p> Character 23.6	50.1	18.0	 5.8	 2.6</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
