<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9657" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Reuters poll shows Dole narrowing gap on Clinton.</title>
<headline>Reuters poll shows Dole narrowing gap on Clinton.</headline>
<byline>Eddie Evans</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bob Dole has narrowed the gap to just five points behind President Bill Clinton since the announcement of his tax cut plan, the choice of Jack Kemp as running mate and the successful Republican convention, a Reuters poll said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The poll of 1,007 likely voters conducted by John Zogby Group International from August 18-20 showed 41.5 percent supported Clinton and 36.3 percent Dole -- a gap of just 5.2 percentage points. Texas billionaire Ross Perot got 7.4 percent, 0.6 percent chose other candidates and 14.2 percent were undecided. The survey margin of error was plus or minus 3.2 percent.</p>
<p>The last Reuters-Zogby poll, released on August 6, had Dole 12 points behind Clinton.</p>
<p>The gap narrowed even more when voters were asked about Dole's vice presidential running mate Jack Kemp. Asked in a separate question to choose between the candidates -- this time with vice presidential candidates Al Gore and Kemp included -- the margin narrowed to just 3.7 points.</p>
<p>The Clinton/Gore ticket had the support of 42.8 percent, against 39.1 percent for Dole/Kemp. Support for Perot, who has yet to name a running mate, slipped to 6.1 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Dole certainly got his bounce from the Republican convention. He had a very good week -- a popular and focused tax cut plan that appears to have brought his base home, the startling selection of Jack Kemp as running mate, and an above average performance defining himself at a no-glitches convention,&quot; pollster John Zogby said.</p>
<p>&quot;The race appears to be competitive, but it remains to be seen if the gap has closed enough, as the President has scheduled a big week with major bill signings as a segue to his convention in Chicago,&quot; he said, referring to the Democratic national convention next week.</p>
<p>But when likely voters were asked which issues were most important to them, the results appeared to tip in Clinton's favor, Zogby said.</p>
<p>Respondents named education, the integrity and character of the candidate, jobs and the economy, crime, and health care as the &quot;most important&quot; issues. Taxes, the issue on which Dole has staked his campaign, is well down the list of priorities.</p>
<p>&quot;If you add the issues up, I think the balance gets tilted in favor of Clinton,&quot; Zogby said. &quot;Dole doesn't emerge from this with a major vote grabber, except for the integrity question,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In a separate question, 60.4 percent of respondents said they would be willing to forego Dole's proposed 15 percent tax cut if such a cut meant an increase in the budget deficit.</p>
<p>Despite backing Clinton for President, voters appear to favor divided government in Washington. The poll shows they prefer Republicans to control both chambers of Congress. Survey respondents wanted Republicans in the Senate majority by 43.6 percent to 36.6 percent and in the House of Representatives by 40.8 percent to 37.7 percent.</p>
<p>Zogby said that support for Clinton was stronger towards the end of the three-day polling period, following publicity about Clinton signing major pieces of legislation including a minimum wage increase and health care and welfare reforms.</p>
<p>Zogby also said that Dole's post-convention bounce in the polls was vulnerable when viewed historically.</p>
<p>&quot;I do recall that polls showed (Democrat) Walter Mondale in a dead heat against (Republican) Ronald Reagan at the end of the 1984 Democratic convention,&quot; Zogby said. Reagan won that race in a landslide.</p>
<p>The results of the Reuter poll may differ slightly from some other recent surveys because of methodology, Zogby said. The Reuters poll excluded respondents if they were not registered to vote or said they were unlikely to vote.</p>
<p>&quot;Our universe has to be those who show up to vote on election day. A lot of adults don't vote,&quot; Zogby said. Some other polls survey voting-age adults or registered voters.</p>
<p>The poll was the second of three major surveys Zogby is conducting for Reuters. In the last month of the campaign Reuters will publish a daily tracking poll done by Zogby.</p>
<p>If the election for president were held today, for</p>
<p>	 whom would you vote, Clinton, Dole, or Perot?</p>
<p>				Fem    Demo- Repub Indep-     Aug 6</p>
<p>		All   Male  -ale   crat  lican endent     Poll</p>
<p> Clinton    41.5   38.7  44.2   77.4  10.3  36.4	 43.3</p>
<p> Dole	 36.3   40.2  32.5    7.8  72.2  28.4	 31.3</p>
<p> Perot	 7.4    7.7   7.1    4.5   4.3  13.7	  9.2</p>
<p> Other	 0.6    1.3   0.0    0.2   0.3   1.5	  2.7</p>
<p> Undecided  14.2   12.1  16.2   10.0  13.0  20.0	 13.4</p>
<p>Note: Columns may not add to 100 percent due to rounding</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
