<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9662" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. takes back seat in Mideast peace efforts.</title>
<headline>U.S. takes back seat in Mideast peace efforts.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Worsnip</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>With presidential elections looming, the United States has slumped back into a subsidiary role in Middle East peacemaking, willing to help but only if the parties themselves take the lead, U.S. analysts say.</p>
<p>The U.S. dream has faded of clinching a comprehensive Middle East peace during this administration, one that would give Israel treaties with Syria and Lebanon to add to those with Egypt, Jordan and the Palestinians.</p>
<p>Already looking shaky under the previous, pro-peace Labour government in Israel, that prospect virtually vanished when Benjamin Netanyahu, leader of the right-wing Likud Party, won Israeli elections in May.</p>
<p>&quot;For a moment it looked as though the United States might take the lead,&quot; Yahya Sadowski, Middle East analyst at the Brookings Institution in Washington, said. &quot;Now it appears they are going to remain loyal to the old maxim of 'never to be more forward than the principals themselves.'&quot;</p>
<p>Washington's role as the key intermediary was underlined again this week when Israel asked the U.S. ambassador in Tel Aviv to forward a message to Syria about Israel's willingness to engage in peace talks without preconditions.</p>
<p>But with the U.S. presidential vote less than 11 weeks away, no one in Washington has the political capital to invest in any role much greater than message-carrier, certainly not one that involves diplomatic sparring with Israel.</p>
<p>Secretary of State Warren Christopher, who has led the U.S. Middle East peace effort for the past three and a half years, has paid one brief visit -- in June -- to Israel since Netanyahu was elected.</p>
<p>Aides say he has no plans to return to the area before a regional economic summit in Cairo in November. Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak suggested on Thursday that even that could be in doubt because of what Arabs see as Israel's stalling on the peace process.</p>
<p>Christopher is widely expected to retire at the end of this administration, even if President Bill Clinton is reelected, and most analysts say any new push in the Middle East will have to await a successor.</p>
<p>Much of the U.S. activity in the Middle East since Netanyahu was elected -- an event that apparently took Washington by surprise -- has been devoted not to advancing the peace process but to keeping it from going backwards.</p>
<p>The United States has urged the Arabs not to give up on Israel and has sought to keep Palestinian self-rule going in the West Bank and Gaza by ensuring a continued flow of aid to the Palestinian Authority.</p>
<p>In private, U.S. officials make clear their considerable differences with Netanyahu's policies, especially his refusal to adhere to the principle of &quot;land for peace&quot; that his Labour rivals had espoused in negotiations with the Arabs.</p>
<p>The administration has given no sign that it thinks the recent Israeli proposal for a &quot;Lebanon-first&quot; deal with Syria, which would remove the guerrilla threat to Israel from south Lebanon before there is any talk of Israel returning the Golan Heights to Syria, is going to work.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the U.S. view that they will have to at some point discuss the disposition of the Golan Heights. I mean, I don't think there's any question about that,&quot; State Department spokesman Glyn Davies said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Syria has rejected the Lebanon-first idea. It also rejected on Thursday Israel's latest peace talks offer, saying the &quot;no-conditions&quot; proposal merely meant Israel's abandonment of the land-for-peace principle that underlay previous talks.</p>
<p>The weakness of Washington's position has been shown by the reluctance of U.S. leaders to insist publicly on land-for-peace, a phrase avoided by Christopher during his last visit to Israel.</p>
<p>Analysts say Washington is in a similarly weak situation on the question of Israeli settlements on occupied territory. The Netanyahu government has moved to unblock restrictions on settlements imposed by Labour.</p>
<p>Washington calls the settlements &quot;unhelpful&quot; and &quot;complicating&quot; but Sadowski asked what the United States would be prepared to do to stop Israel from expanding them. &quot;We can stand there and lecture about settlements being unhelpful but that will have about the same effect as lecturing the Bosnian Serbs,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SYRIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
