<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9668" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE world sugar ends narrowly mixed in thin trade.</title>
<headline>CSCE world sugar ends narrowly mixed in thin trade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE world sugar futures settled barely changed as the October contract failed to pierce key resistance pegged at 11.90, market sources said.</p>
<p>The contract made its high of 11.89 on early trade buying but a lack of followthrough, and producer selling at the highs, limited gains. The market challenged the day's highs again on late-session trade buying in the October/March spread. Producer selling capped the move and pressured the contract down towards unchanged.</p>
<p>Several dealers see firmer prices Friday, however. One trader said fresh speculative buying could emerge in October, as there is still five weeks before the contract expires.</p>
<p>The October contract closed up 0.03 at 11.85, having ranged from 11.89 to 11.75. March eased 0.01 on the day to 11.45, while the back months went out unchanged to 0.02 lower.</p>
<p>Workers at the Dominican Republic state sugar corporation have threatened to strike, but market sources said the news is not likely to move prices. &quot;For the time being it wouldn't have too much of an effect on the No 11 contract,&quot; one broker said.  </p>
<p>London white sugar futures settled weaker but off the lows in thin dealings. October ended off $1.80 at $351.60, while December finished 40 cents lower at $346.40.</p>
<p>-- Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities, 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
