<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9674" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. welfare is &quot;barely enough&quot; now, says mother. [Corrected 18:05 gmt]</title>
<headline>U.S. welfare is &quot;barely enough&quot; now, says mother. [Corrected 18:05 gmt]</headline>
<byline>Deborah Zabarenko</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ericka Lewis, a 20-year-old mother of two, has few worries about big cuts in welfare, even though she depends on it. Against all odds, she hopes to be off public assistance before the cuts start to pinch.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm hoping that by November I will have a job 'cause I don't like being on public assistance ... It's barely enough. When you have bills like rent and phone and kids that are growing every day it's really not enough,&quot; Lewis told Reuters.</p>
<p>She was aware of at least one key provision of a sweeping welfare reform bill President Bill Clinton signed on Thursday: the five-year lifetime limit on receiving public aid. She agrees with the concept. &quot;I think that public assistance is only assistance,&quot; she said on the eve of the signing.</p>
<p>The law ends a 61-year-old U.S. guarantee of federal aid to poor children, transferring the money and responsibility to the states -- in Lewis's case, the District of Columbia. It also cuts spending by $55 billion (corrects from $55 million) over six years, requires recipients to work after two years and reduces spending on Food Stamps.</p>
<p>Lewis lives in what sounds like a stereotypical welfare family: four generations in a three-storey row house in the Montana Terrace public housing project in Washington's northeast quadrant, a household with three women, five children and no adult males.</p>
<p>She gets by on $415 a month, which covers food and clothing for herself and sons Gerald, 5, and Earic, 2. She started receiving benefits after her children's father was killed two years ago. Before that, she received Social Security benefits after her mother died when she was 12.</p>
<p>Single motherhood cut into her school attendance; she graduated in June from an alternative public high school that gave her some clerical training. Lewis said she wanted to work as a secretary or receptionist and hoped her old high school would help her find work.</p>
<p>If that happens, her younger son would go into a daycare programme within walking distance of her home; her older son is set to begin school in September.</p>
<p>Lewis's career ambitions, her high school diploma and her determination not to have any more children set her apart from other young women she knows.</p>
<p>&quot;For other people that live in my neighbourhood, they have two and three kids and they steady having babies and they don't have a junior high school education,&quot; she said. &quot;For me, I'm trying to keep my life going so I won't be caught up.&quot;</p>
<p>But the general conditions of Lewis's life put her family at risk, said Bobbi Blok of the Washington Child Development Council, which refers children like Lewis's to various aid programmes. Cash-strapped cities like Washington are increasingly unable to offer real help to girls who become mothers in their teenage years and who are part of families where grandparents and great-grandparents care for young children, Blok said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's families at risk. Child care may be the one link keeping that family together ... and that's being threatened,&quot; Blok said. Her agency is already contending with a 12 percent cut in public assistance from the city. Cuts in federal welfare programmes may not be felt for up to a year.</p>
<p>Still, Blok heaves a big sigh when asked what impact the cuts will have. &quot;The frustration level becomes extremely high,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
