<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9678" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Some Texas roads going downhill - pavements chief.</title>
<headline>Some Texas roads going downhill - pavements chief.</headline>
<byline>Kathie O'Donnell</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some Texas roads have gone from bad to worse since 1993, and the longer the state waits to repair or replace them, the more it will cost, Texas Director of Pavements Kenneth Fults said.</p>
<p>A report called &quot;The Condition of Texas Pavements&quot; that covers fiscal years 1993 to 1995 said 14 percent of Texas highways were in &quot;fair to poor&quot; condition,  Fults said.</p>
<p>That compares with 12 to 13 percent in fiscal 1993, he said. Not surprisingly, the roads in the poorest shape in 1993 have worsened more than others, Fults said.</p>
<p>&quot;Over this time period we are in a declining mode as far as the conditions of the pavements in Texas,&quot; Fults said. &quot;The interstate highways (and) the main feeder roads are in pretty good shape, and seem to be holding their own, but what is happening to us is the ones down on the bottom end, the ones that are in bad shape, are getting worse...When roads get in that kind of condition, it costs a lot more to bring them back to an acceptable level.&quot;</p>
<p>Many roads are past the point where maintenance will suffice, and instead require heavy rehabilitation or complete reconstruction, he said.</p>
<p>Completed in April, the annual report was released last month. A new report containing 1996 data is expected out by late fall or early winter, Fults said.The reports allow the state to compare road conditions from year to year.</p>
<p>According to Fults, a program the state uses called the Pavement Management Information Systems shows that to maintain Texas pavements in their current condition into fiscal 1997, it will cost the state $600 million. That $600 million covers only rehab and preventive maintenance relating only to pavements. It does not cover extras such as bridges and and ditches.</p>
<p>If the state decided it wanted to upgrade road conditions, the price tag would be roughly $800 million.</p>
<p>&quot;If we were lucky enough that we could talk the administration into fixing all the problems, then we would need $1.55 billion, and that's up from $1.1 billion in 1993,&quot; Fults said. &quot;In other words, if we had $1.1 billion in 1993, we could have fixed all the problems.&quot;</p>
<p>--212-859-1655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020041">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
