<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9679" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole just 5.2 points behind Clinton - Reuter poll.</title>
<headline>Dole just 5.2 points behind Clinton - Reuter poll.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bob Dole has narrowed the gap to just five points behind President Bill Clinton since the announcement of his tax cut plan, the choice of Jack Kemp as running mate and the successful Republican convention, a Reuters poll said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The poll of 1,007 likely voters conducted by John Zogby Group International from August 18-20 showed 41.5 percent supported Clinton and 36.3 percent Dole -- a gap of just 5.2 percentage points. Texas billionaire Ross Perot got 7.4 percent, 0.6 percent chose other candidates and 14.2 percent were undecided. The survey margin of error was plus or minus 3.2 percent.  </p>
<p>The last Reuters-Zogby poll, released on August 6, had Dole 12 points behind Clinton.</p>
<p>The gap narrowed even more when voters were asked about Dole's vice presidential running mate Jack Kemp. Asked in a separate question to choose between the candidates -- this time with vice presidential candidates Al Gore and Kemp included -- the margin narrowed to just 3.7 points.</p>
<p>Respondents named education, the integrity and character of the candidate, jobs and the economy, crime, and health care as the &quot;most important&quot; issues in the campaign for the November 5 election. Taxes, the issue Dole has highlighted with his tax cut plan, was well down the list of priorities.</p>
<p>Despite backing Clinton for President, voters appear to favor divided government in Washington. The poll shows they prefer Republicans to control both chambers of Congress.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
