<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9680" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Plains feedlot cattle trade at standstill -private.</title>
<headline>Plains feedlot cattle trade at standstill -private.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Plains feedlot cattle markets just ahead of midday Thursday were quiet, with no sales of slaughter steers or heifers reported, feedlot sources said.</p>
<p>Most showlists were sold out during this week's active trading that broke week-to-date volume records in the Texas Panhandle/western Oklahoma and Kansas.</p>
<p>The majority of this week's sales took place Tuesday at $68.00 per cwt, up $2.00 from a week ago.</p>
<p>Owners were now pricing cattle at $69.00 to $70.00 for the handful of remaining cattle, but packer inquiry was generally light and cattle feeders were passing the bids.  </p>
<p>Feedlot cattle prices this week were boosted by a rebound in boxed beef prices which spurred buying by packers who were short of live inventories, the sources said.</p>
<p>Boxed beef prices at midday were quoted up $0.14 to $0.36 per cwt, with the choice heavyweight value up $0.26 at $104.92, USDA said. There were 193 fabricated loads sold.</p>
<p>Projections for increasingly tighter feedlot cattle supplies the next four weeks also fueled the competitive bidding that kicked prices higher, sources said.</p>
<p>--Bob Janis 312-983-7347--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
