<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9701" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Banisadr says Iran's Khameini ordered Kurd deaths.</title>
<headline>Banisadr says Iran's Khameini ordered Kurd deaths.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Iranian president Abolhassan Banisadr told a heavily guarded German court on Thursday that Iran's religious leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei ordered the 1992 killing of opposition Kurd leaders.</p>
<p>Nearly four years after the three Iranian Kurdish leaders and their translator were shot in a Berlin restaurant, Banisadr told the court that he had information from three independent sources linking Tehran to the murder.</p>
<p>Closely protected by a team of bodyguards, Banisadr said that a secret &quot;council for special operations&quot; supervised by Khamenei had drawn up the plans to kill the exiles.</p>
<p>&quot;According to the current (power) structures (in Iran) there can only be one person who ordered this and that is the ruler himself -- Ayatollah Ali Khamenei,&quot; Banisadr told the Berlin court.</p>
<p>Tehran has denied the allegations which he also made in an interview with prosecutors in June.</p>
<p>Speaking softly in Farsi, Banisadr said through translators that he based his assertions on information gathered about the power structures in Iran during his 15 years in exile from sources &quot;within and the regime and outside&quot;.</p>
<p>Banisadr said he also cross-checked his information with other sources. He said that he could not provide the court with the names of his sources but added: &quot;This information is reliable. I have no doubts about its reliability.&quot;</p>
<p>He alleged that the &quot;council for special operations&quot; in Tehran was outside official political structures and was responsible for determining who would be assassinated and how.</p>
<p>The former president said Khameini and four other men sat on the council, including Intelligence Minister Ali Fallahiyan. German authorities issued an arrest warrant for Fallahiyan in March in connection with the 1992 Kurd dissident killings.</p>
<p>Banisadr said that once a plan was approved by the council, it was up to Fallahiyan to carry it out.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no laws for these things in a state of absolute rule,&quot; Banisadr said.</p>
<p>&quot;There can be no political assassination without the approval of the leader,&quot; he said, referring to  Khameini.</p>
<p>Banisadr repeated his accusations at a news conference held in the courtroom after the first day of his two-day testimony.</p>
<p>He said he was worried that even if the defendants were convicted, the German government would soon release them.</p>
<p>&quot;I am concerned that one way or another they will be released after the trial ends and be given high positions in Iran,&quot; Banisadr said.</p>
<p>Banisadr is the star prosecution witness against an Iranian, Kazem Darabi, and four Lebanese who have been on trial for nearly three years on charges of murdering the dissidents.</p>
<p>Two masked men armed with machineguns burst into the Mykonos restaurant in Berlin on September 17, 1992, and fired at dozens of Iranian dissidents seated at a table.</p>
<p>Three leaders of the Iranian Democratic Party of Kurdistan (DPK-I) and the translator were killed in the hail of bullets.</p>
<p>Federal prosecutor Bruno Jost said that Banisadr's testimony had so far been useful but that he wanted more details on his knowledge of the assassination.</p>
<p>But another prosecuting attorney, Wolfgang Wieland, said Banisadr's testimony had convinced him of Tehran's involvement. &quot;There is no doubt that these murders were ordered by the state,&quot; Wieland told reporters outside the courtroom.</p>
<p>Security for the trial, which is expected to wind up in the early autumn, has been tight all along but reached unprecedent levels on Thursday with about 100 police officers on hand.</p>
<p>Outside the courthouse, police closed off a busy Berlin street to traffic. Scores of police in bullet-proof vests and carrying machineguns patrolled the area.</p>
<p>Banisadr was escorted into the courtroom from an underground entrance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
