<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9702" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Sweden expels North Korean diplomats for smuggling.</title>
<headline>Sweden expels North Korean diplomats for smuggling.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden said on Thursday it had expelled three North Korean diplomats from Stockholm, accusing them of smuggling cigarettes into Sweden.</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry spokesman Staffan Bjorck told Reuters the three men were ordered to leave the country on July 12 after they were caught smuggling in the Estonian capital of Tallinn.</p>
<p>Pyongyang's ambassador to Sweden had not been expelled, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We called the ambassador to the Foreign Ministry and told him that three of the dipolmats at the embassy in Stockholm were no longer welcome in Sweden,&quot; Bjorck said.</p>
<p>&quot;We did this because they were smuggling cigarettes from abroad to Sweden. They left the country within a week or so. This is not the way a diplomat should behave.&quot;</p>
<p>Bjorck said Swedish and Estonian police had been investigating the group for several months. They were arrested in a small van.</p>
<p>No-one from the police or customs office was available to comment further on the case.</p>
<p>Bjorck said that until July there were seven North Korean diplomats based in Stockholm. He said the vacant positions had not yet been filled.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
