<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9706" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Hochtief output up, orders surge.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Hochtief output up, orders surge.</headline>
<byline>Catherine O'Mahony</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German construction group Hochtief AG on Thursday predicted satisfactory 1996 profits after its first-half output rose 9.3 percent and order volumes boomed due to a major contract for the Athens airport.</p>
<p>The company reported construction output of 5.50 billion marks ($3.70 billion) for the first six months along with a surge in incoming orders to 8.48 billion marks, up 62 percent from the year-ago period.</p>
<p>&quot;Against a downward tendency in earnings from domestic business are set the continued good returns from foreign business,&quot; Hochtief said. &quot;Thus we expect a satisfactory result overall for the current year.&quot;</p>
<p>Investors welcomed the news and sent Hochtief's stock up 40 pfennigs to 66.90 marks in bourse trade. The group, owned by giant Germn utility group RWE, had reported net profit of 137 million marks in 1995.</p>
<p>Business was, and would continue to be, driven by foreign demand, Hochtief said. In the first half of 1996, foreign orders jumped 190.8 percent to 4.85 billion marks, of which 2.38 billion came from the Athens order alone.</p>
<p>Orders in hand rose nearly 33 percent to 14.05 billion marks after the airport order was booked in June -- higher than Hochtief's output of 11 billion marks for all of 1995.</p>
<p>Even excluding Athens airport -- of which Hochtief owns 36 percent and plans to operate as well as build it -- foreign orders rose by 48 percent and overall orders by 16.6 percent in the first six months, the group said.</p>
<p>Hochtief noted that solid economic growth in North America, South East Asia and Eastern Europe had boosted the international construction market. German builders were managing to hold their own through expansion, the group said.</p>
<p>Hochtief hoped to expand further in eastern Europe via its investment earlier in the year in the Polish firm KPIS-Cracovia S.A.</p>
<p>On the other hand, it cautioned that conditions on the German building market -- which has been damaged by weak economic growth and tighter government spending on public buildings -- remained poor.</p>
<p>Construction spending weakened throughout Germany in the first half of 1996, ending a phase of continued demand from the developing eastern states which sustained the market in 1995.</p>
<p>Domestic incoming orders rose by just 1.9 percent to 3.63 billion marks in the first six months while output rose two percent to 3.32 billion marks, compared with a 22.4 percent rise in output in foreign business.</p>
<p>&quot;The unsatisfactory development in domestic construction, particularly the sometimes ruinous price competition, influenced our earnings development,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Staff levels at the group rose 5.8 percent to 41,943, as foreign staffing increased 14.8 percent to 20,498 at end-June. Domestic employee levels dropped 1.7 percent to 21,445. ($1=1.4925 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
