<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9707" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Immigrants stand-off heats up in France.</title>
<headline>Immigrants stand-off heats up in France.</headline>
<byline>John Follain</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tension rose in a 49-day stand-off between the government and African immigrants fighting expulsion when police on Thursday ejected supporters of the protesters who briefly occupied the Paris offices of France's ruling RPR party.</p>
<p>The centre-right coalition government's conciliatory offer to review the expulsion orders for 10 hunger strikers, and about 300 protesters backing them at a Paris church, failed to break the fast. The immigrants demanded residence permits for all 300, many of whom are from the west African state of Mali.</p>
<p>Police said 41 members of a separate movement were taken away after they occupied for an hour the headquarters of the Gaullist RPR, senior partner in the coalition, in central Paris. The protesters had shouted slogans from the upper floors.</p>
<p>Simultaneously, magistrates released one of the 300 protesters who had been detained on Wednesday during a routine police check. A few sympathisers had staged a demonstration outside the Paris law courts to demand his release.</p>
<p>Ababakar Diop, spokesman for the fasters and the protesters entrenched in a Paris church, said Malian Dembele Makan, whose demand for political asylum had earlier been rejected, was detained after leaving the church.</p>
<p>Diop accused the government of using carrot-and-stick tactics in making a conciliatory offer while detaining Makan.</p>
<p>&quot;He was already in custody before the Interior Minister (Jean-Louis Debre) said he was ready to study our situation case-by-case,&quot; Diop told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;This is doublespeak. We appeal to President Jacques Chirac so that Debre stops lying,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Debre promised earlier to re-examine expulsion orders for the Africans but the hunger strikers, determined to win more concessions, pledged to keep up their fast.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be no residence permits en masse, there will be no automatic right to stay but the government will study things on a case-by-case basis,&quot; Debre told RTL radio.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who have had their demands for (political) asylum rejected will not be granted permits. That is the law,&quot; he added, declining to put a number on how many of the protesters would be allowed to stay. An estimated 117 of them have been refused asylum, according to their spokesmen.</p>
<p>Signalling their determination to force the government into what would amount to a humiliating climbdown, the protesters called a new rally for next Wednesday after a march through Paris drew 5,000 demonstrators on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The hunger strikers have been drinking sweet tea and taking vitamin pills, but two are said to be in a serious condition.</p>
<p>An official of France's highest administrative court, the Council of State, said it would probably release its review of controversial immigration laws later on Thursday. The government requested it to help find a way out of the crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;We respect the law but in its enforcement we try to have a humane attitude so that we can stretch out a hand to the worst cases,&quot; Debre said.</p>
<p>The protesters say many of them enjoyed residence rights until they were plunged into illegality by the laws which tightened residence and citizenship regulations to drastically curb immigration.</p>
<p>The church, in the heavily immigrant Goutte d'Or district, is surrounded by hundreds of sympathisers, including celebrities like film star Emmanuelle Beart, determined to prevent any police raid.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
