<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9713" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Cimpor rises on BFE price hopes.</title>
<headline>Cimpor rises on BFE price hopes.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Portuguese cement group Cimpor rose on Lisbon bourse amid hopes that the privatisation price of Banco de Fomento e Exterior (BFE), in which Cimpor has a stake, could be above expectations, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The rise in Cimpor is based on the expected privatisation price,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;With expectations for the BFE share price now running at more than 2,500 escudos, this is good news for Cimpor.&quot;</p>
<p>Shares in Cimpor-Cimentos de Portugal, which has an 11.06 percent stake in BFE, stood at 3,405 escudos, up 15, in volume of 177,171 shares on Lisbon bourse at 1205 GMT.  </p>
<p>Trade in BFE shares was suspended in Lisbon on Thursday after the Finance Ministry called a news conference about its privatisation.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry may announce at the conference, set for 1300 GMT, which of three competing Portuguese financial groups will be awarded the state's 65 percent stake.</p>
<p>However, it was not certain that a clear-cut winner would have yet emerged from the complex bidding process.</p>
<p>BFE shares were suspended on the Lisbon bourse by the Financial Markets Committee at 2,545 escudos ($16.7) which would value the state stake at around 130 billion escudos ($850 million).</p>
<p>The ministry should announce the results of a report by a special jury set up to evaluate bids by rivals Banco Portugues de Investimento (BPI), Portugal's fifth largest bank, Banco Finantia and Banco Nacional de Credito Imobiliario (BNC).</p>
<p>Banco Finantia is allied to Swiss Bank Corp in the bid while BNC is controlled by cork magnate Americo Amorim.</p>
<p>-- Lisbon newsroom +351-1-3538254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
