<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9715" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: RTRS-Nuclear test ban talks fizzle out.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Nuclear test ban talks fizzle out.</headline>
<byline>Philippe Naughton</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Disarmament negotiators conceded defeat on Thursday as almost three years of talks on a treaty outlawing all nuclear explosions ended in failure.</p>
<p>The 61-nation Conference on Disarmament (CD), whose efforts for a landmark Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty (CTBT) were blocked by India, decided it could not even agree to report its failure to the U.N. General Assembly.</p>
<p>But major powers said they would work quickly to revive the draft treaty and have it approved and opened for signature in New York next month despite India's opposition.</p>
<p>&quot;The CD has now played out its string. There's nothing more this body can do on the treaty itself,&quot; said U.S. disarmament ambassador Stephen Ledogar.</p>
<p>&quot;But noone's interested here in consigning the treaty to the dustbin...The story now is in New York.&quot;</p>
<p>India blocked the treaty at a negotiating committee last week and confirmed its veto on Tuesday because it said the pact did not contain a clause committing the five declared nuclear powers to a timetable for nuclear disarmament.</p>
<p>One of three nuclear &quot;threshold states&quot; alongside Pakistan and Israel, India complained that the treaty would simply maintain the divide between the nuclear &quot;haves&quot; and &quot;have nots&quot;.</p>
<p>Conference member states had hoped that the negotiating committee's report, which only stated that no consensus had been reached on the pact, could still be forwarded to the General Assembly, which asked the conference last year for a CTBT.</p>
<p>But Iran and India both blocked that move, with Iran using complicated procedural manouevring to head off a clear decision in a first meeting on Thursday.</p>
<p>All five declared nuclear powers -- the United States, Russia, China, Britain and France -- support the idea of reviving the text and having it signed at the outset of the next session of the General Assembly as originally envisaged.</p>
<p>But they will not take the lead role in pushing through the resolution in New York, where the support of major non-aligned states is seen as crucial in getting the clear overall majority needed to have the treaty approved without any changes.</p>
<p>Australia signalled on Thursday that it was ready to sponsor the resolution, and diplomats said an Australian text was already circulating in Geneva. Canberra was expected to publicly announce its intentions on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot give up. The opportunity is here now, it will not last,&quot; said Australian ambassador Richard Starr.</p>
<p>&quot;We must grasp it or lose it and with it the whole critical step towards nuclear disarmament.&quot;</p>
<p>The idea of sending the negotiating report to New York was supported on Thursday by a number of influential non-aligned states including Pakistan, Mexico, Brazil, Egypt, Peru and Chile -- the states whose support will be crucial in New York.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
