<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9716" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: UN says Eritrea should pull out troops from islands.</title>
<headline>UN says Eritrea should pull out troops from islands.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The president of the U.N. Security Council on Thursday told Eritrea it should withdraw its troops immediately from a small Red Sea island as it had promised last weekend.</p>
<p>Ambassador Tono Eitel of Germany, this month's council president, said council members &quot;recalled the promise made by Eritrean authorities to withdraw their troops and they expect this withdrawal to take place immediately.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he was authorised to speak to Eritrean diplomats at the United Nations &quot;in order to convey the expectation of the council.&quot;</p>
<p>Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali in January was asked to mediate Eritrea's dispute with Yemen, which also claims the islands. He appointed French mediator Francis Gutman, who announced last weekend that Eritrea had agreed to withdraw its forces so that arbitration procedures could take place.</p>
<p>At least 12 people were reported killed last December when the two countries fought briefly over the Lesser Hanish and other disputed Red Sea islands. Both states claim the islands, which lie near tanker routes at the Red Sea's southern entrance.</p>
<p>Asked if any troop withdrawal had begun, Eitel told reporters after closed-door Security Council consultations: &quot;News about any withdrawal has not reached me.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ERTRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
