<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9717" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: UN relates another Iraqi arms inspection delay.</title>
<headline>UN relates another Iraqi arms inspection delay.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.N. official said on Thursday that Iraq last week had delayed another weapons inspection team searching for possible hidden arms.</p>
<p>Rolf Ekeus, the U.N. official in charge of ridding Iraq of weapons of mass destruction, told reporters that a team was stopped at road blocks while the Iraqi official accompanying it was allowed to go ahead.</p>
<p>The official was Lt-Gen Amir Muhammad Rasheed, Iraq's oil minister.  </p>
<p>Ekeus said the site his team wished to inspect, southwest of Baghdad near the airport, had been involved previously in moving some of the equipment or arms his inspectors were seeking.</p>
<p>Ekeus is leaving for Baghdad on Friday to confer with Iraq's deputy prime minister Tareq Aziz on the incident and previous ones involving the barring of his inspectors.</p>
<p>He briefed the Security Council, which will issue a statement, supporting his quest.</p>
<p>Ekeus said any concealed weapons or materials Iraq may still have are usually moved when they know inspectors are about to arrive.</p>
<p>&quot;They are put on railway cars and trucks and made mobile,&quot; he said. &quot;The site can be emptied if we cannot move without being hindered.&quot;</p>
<p>Ekeus again said Iraq needed to be clear on the sum of the weapons and materials it said it destroyed unilaterally.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't believe that is the full story. Some of it was no doubt destroyed but we believe more exists. The matter of concealment is undisputed and must be highlighted.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
