<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9720" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: SNB seen accommodative as Swiss franc stays strong.</title>
<headline>SNB seen accommodative as Swiss franc stays strong.</headline>
<byline>Alice Ratcliffe</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Swiss National Bank (SNB) left its key discount rate steady on Thursday but analysts said news of its latest additions to the money market show it is willing to steer a slightly easier monetary course for now.</p>
<p>Such action is expected to continue as long as the Swiss franc stays strong, and the Swiss economy remains weak.</p>
<p>The SNB said on Thursday, as expected, it was keeping its discount rate at 1.50 percent. But it also said in the afternoon that it was adding a &quot;significant quantity&quot; of liquidity to the Swiss money market.</p>
<p>&quot;Lowering the discount rate would not have had much impact on the economy. With this operation, effectively the SNB can influence the exchange rates. They are not going straight forward, but it can be interpreted as certain type of easing, especially in relation to the currencies,&quot; said Peter Jeggli, bond research analyst at CS Research, a division of Credit Suisse.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
