<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9725" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France's Juppe rejects African immigrants' demands.</title>
<headline>France's Juppe rejects African immigrants' demands.</headline>
<byline>Irwin Arieff</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe, backed by France's highest administrative court, on Thursday rejected a blanket demand for residence permits by 300 African immigrants including 10 hunger strikers who are holed up in a Paris church.</p>
<p>But he said the Council of State left the door open to case-by-case reviews and pledged the government would not expel people who were ill or use deportations to break up families.</p>
<p>&quot;Whenever none of these circumstances arise, expulsion orders will be enforced,&quot; Juppe said in a videotaped statement broadcast on LCI television.</p>
<p>The protesters' vowed to continue their 49-day-old fast until they win residence permits for all 300.</p>
<p>But they also called a meeting to discuss Juppe's statement amidst fears that police were preparing to eject them early on Friday although hundreds of sympathisers have surrounded the Saint-Bernard church to protect them.</p>
<p>Tension rose in the stand-off earlier in the day when protesters briefly occupied the Paris offices of the ruling RPR party. Police ejected and held them, along with eight press photographers, for four hours before releasing them.</p>
<p>&quot;This fascist-like behaviour cannot be tolerated,&quot; said RPR official Renaud Muselier, referring to the protesters.</p>
<p>But another potential flashpoint was defused when magistrates released on a technicality one of the 300 protesters who had been detained on Wednesday after leaving the church temporarily to visit his family.</p>
<p>A few sympathisers had demonstrated outside the Paris law courts to demand the release of the man, identified by the protesters as Malian Dembele Makan.</p>
<p>Juppe said the Council of State fully backed his view that none of the protesting immigrants had the right to stay in France under 1993 laws tightening conditions for residence.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be against the law to give blanket residence permits to this or that group. We are going to continue a review of individual situations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It never crossed our mind to expel someone who is seriously ill, separate a mother from her children, break up a couple, or expel parents of children who were born in France or are French citizens,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Many of the protesters say they once had residence rights and were plunged into illegality by the hardline 1993 laws pushed through by then-interior minister Charles Pasqua at a time of mounting anti-immigrant sentiment.</p>
<p>Lawyers say loopholes in the laws, which also tightened conditions for citizenship, had created a legal nightmare.</p>
<p>Juppe said the law would nonetheless be enforced.</p>
<p>But the far-right National Front party, which advocates sending home all immigrants, taunted Juppe for &quot;weakness&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Words yes, but where is the action?&quot; the Front said in a statement.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre declined to say how many protesters met the conditions that would allow them to stay.</p>
<p>But he said those whose demands for political asylum had been rejected would be expelled -- an estimated 117, according to a spokesman for the Africans.</p>
<p>Signalling their determination to force the government into what would amount to a humiliating retreat, the protesters have called a new rally for next week after a march through Paris drew 5,000 demonstrators on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The hunger strikers have been drinking sweet tea and taking vitamin pills, but two are said to be in a serious condition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFRICA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
