<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9727" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Non-nuclear states to salvage shelved nuke pact.</title>
<headline>Non-nuclear states to salvage shelved nuke pact.</headline>
<byline>Stephanie Nebehay</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The fate of a nuclear test ban treaty now lies in the hands of non-nuclear weapon states who have pledged to resurrect the shelved pact at the U.N. General Assembly, diplomats said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Australia is expected to announce on Friday it will sponsor a resolution seeking action from the world body after the Conference on Disarmament failed to agree on the treaty text.</p>
<p>The 61-nation Conference on Disarmament, whose efforts for a landmark Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty (CTBT) were blocked by India, decided it could not even agree to report its failure to the U.N. General Assembly.</p>
<p>Richard Starr, Australian ambassador, said his country hoped the treaty, which would prohibit all nuclear explosions used to test and refine nuclear weapons, could be salvaged after nearly three years of negotiation and &quot;decades of expectations&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a clear need for friends of the CTBT to consider action so that the whole international community will be able to consider, endorse and sign this valuable treaty.</p>
<p>&quot;We would not want to see a treaty text die in a pigeonhole in Geneva,&quot; Starr told Reuters.</p>
<p>But diplomats said the window of opportunity in New York was narrow if there was to be real hope of the 51st General Assembly opening the pact for signature at a ceremony in late September.</p>
<p>&quot;It is in the hands of the non-nuclear weapon states. They have to band together to carry this through to New York,&quot; one envoy told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The nuclear weapon states can't carry it into the New York arena,&quot; he added. &quot;No single country can do it alone.&quot;</p>
<p>Others feared that India and Iran, who strongly oppose the draft treaty text, would continue to put up procedural roadblocks in the New York debates. Each could count on support from other non-aligned states in the 185-member world body.</p>
<p>&quot;The procedural pettiness of the Iranians is as bad as that in New York or worse,&quot; said one envoy after Thursday's debate.</p>
<p>U.S. disarmament ambassador Stephen Ledogar expressed disappointment with the blockage in Geneva, but predicted the pact would be opened for signature in New York next month.</p>
<p>&quot;It will succeed,&quot; Ledogar told reporters. &quot;It has traditionally been on everyone's shopping list for arms control and disarmament. The instinct for support is enormous.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it appears as though the overwhelming choice is to put it before the General Assembly. That is the route that will be pursued,&quot; he added. &quot;There is a very little timeframe.&quot;</p>
<p>In particular, the Clinton administration hopes to avoid a damaging defeat on home turf on the eve of the presidential elections in early November, according to analysts.</p>
<p>There have been nearly 2,000 nuclear tests in the atmosphere, underground and under water since the end of World War Two, more than half of them by the United States.</p>
<p>India torpedoed the pact in Geneva after it became clear that the five declared nuclear powers (Britain, China, France, Russia and the United States) would not commit to a timetable for total nuclear disarmament.</p>
<p>All five declared nuclear weapon states made clear in closely coordinated speeches on Thursday they did not want the pact reopened for negotiation or fresh amendments in New York.</p>
<p>Washington and its allies want to avoid the text being dissected by the U.N.'s first committee which discusses disarmament matters and is to meet between October and November.</p>
<p>Ledogar said there was barely three weeks to act before the current 50th General Assembly closes on September 16.</p>
<p>Treaty backers hope the body will agree to hand over the text intact to the 51st General Assembly opening the next day.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States is not going to be the prime mover in this,&quot; Ledogar said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the sort of thing, I think, where it is best in order to achieve maximum support, for those who have historically wanted this the most should take the lead -- those are the non nuclear weapon states. They are the ones who will be exercising leadership,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;After all, this treaty is about getting us -- the nuclear weapon states -- to do something.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
