<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9729" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: CRH voted best Irish firm in fund manager survey.</title>
<headline>CRH voted best Irish firm in fund manager survey.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Building materials firm CRH Plc was named best Irish company for the third consecutive year in a poll of Irish and UK investment fund managers compiled by Finance magazine.</p>
<p>Ireland's two leading banks Allied Irish Banks Plc and Bank of Ireland came second and third respectively in the survey which was published on Thursday.</p>
<p>Fund managers were asked to rate Irish companies under seven separate criteria including strategic positioning, marketing strength, accounting information, acquisitions capability and investor relations.  </p>
<p>Fund managers said CRH's success in the investor survey was mainly due to good management strategy.</p>
<p>&quot;CRH make common sense decisions which are well thought out and they have become predictable, which markets like,&quot; one fund manager told Finance.</p>
<p>&quot;CRH put a lot of effort into their dealings with the fund management community and provide a lot of information in their accounts,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Finance magazine said a notable feature of the 1996 survey was the emergence of a number of small progressive companies like IAWS, United Drug, Kingspan, Grafton, DCC, Tullow Oil and Clondalkin.</p>
<p>--Dublin Newsroom +353 1 660 3377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
