<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9730" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French Finance Minister hails rate cut.</title>
<headline>French Finance Minister hails rate cut.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Finance and Economy Minister Jean Arthuis on Thursday welcomed a decision by the central bank to cut its intervention rate by 20 basis points to 3.35 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an unprecedented (low) level. This has been made possible because on a European level other central banks have made steps in the same direction,&quot; Arthuis told France Inter radio. &quot;That is the case for the Bundesbank, which reduced from 3.30 to three percent the repo rate.</p>
<p>&quot;The franc has reacted and rose and has found a parity with the mark which it had (lost) a few weeks ago,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It means that the cost of borrowing comes down and that means that those who borrow, notably companies and households which want to become house owners or want to buy consumer assets, for them money will be less expensive and therefore we will have more spending power, bigger operating margins,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;That is also true for public borrowers, the towns, the departments, the regions, also for the state. It is very good news, it means that real rates -- the difference between the nominal rate and inflation -- are being squeezed and that means that there can be investment and who invests creates growth and work and that's our pre-occupation,&quot; Arthuis said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
