<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9735" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Bundesbank slashes repo to historic low.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Bundesbank slashes repo to historic low.</headline>
<byline>Janet Northcote</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German Bundesbank slashed its main money market rate to an historic low on Thursday, triggering a wave of interest rate cuts across Europe and boosting European currencies and the dollar against the mark.</p>
<p>The central bank said after its regular council meeting it was cutting its securities repurchase rate, or repo, to three percent from 3.30 percent, a larger easing than any market players or economists had expected.</p>
<p>Its official discount and Lombard rates -- the floor and ceiling for German money market rates -- were held steady at 2.50 percent and 4.50 percent respectively.</p>
<p>Other European central banks, keen to cut credit costs to boost economic growth, quickly followed the Bundesbank's lead.</p>
<p>The Bank of France responded by immediately cutting its intervention rate to 3.35 percent from 3.55 percent.</p>
<p>Belgium, Austria and the Netherlands also loosened policy and analysts predicted a reduction in Finnish interest rates.</p>
<p>Outside Europe, Canada, one of Germany's partners in the Group of Seven rich nations, also seized the opportunity to lower credit costs.</p>
<p>In currency markets, the dollar surged about a pfennig to hit technical resistance at about 1.4950 marks, while the French franc jumped a centime to trade at 3.4090 per mark.</p>
<p>In a telephone statement made two hours after the rate cut was announced, Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer said a slowdown in German money supply growth and low inflation had allowed the move.</p>
<p>He made no direct comment on the future rate trend but said this decision had cleared the decks for the time being.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we intend to watch and await further developments for some time... We are waiting now to see in the rest of the year how the whole situation develops but we believe today's decision has created clarity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Back in April, when the Bundesbank last cut its discount and Lombard rates, Tietmeyer had promised the central bank would follow through with a repo easing when the time was right.</p>
<p>One key condition for that was a slowdown in M3 money supply growth -- its leading monetary policy indicator. M3 expansion has since slowed to an annualised 8.6 percent in July compared with double-digit growth rates in the first half of the year.</p>
<p>But the decision to lower the repo came despite data released this week which shows the German economic recovery is on a stronger footing that many economists had thought.</p>
<p>The Economics Ministry said on Thursday it estimated the German economy grew by one percent in the second quarter compared with a year earlier, outpacing expectations.</p>
<p>An upward revision in June manufacturing orders data and a stronger than expected business climate index from the respected Ifo economic institute, both issued on Wednesday had already led economists to scroll back rate cut hopes.</p>
<p>For German financial markets, the main question was whether this move meant interest rates had bottomed for this cycle, with the discount and repo rates now both at historic lows.</p>
<p>But the central bank, which likes to keep markets guessing, seemingly succeeded in doing so once again.</p>
<p>Analysts contacted by Reuters were divided on the likelihood of another cut, but said the Bundesbank had probably managed finally to stem the rate cut speculation which has preceded every Bundesbank meeting for the last several months.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the Bundesbank wanted to stop the hopes for more interest rate cuts once and for all, to stop the speculation and turn expectations towards constancy,&quot; said Gerhard Grebe, chief economist at Bank Julius Baer in Frankfurt.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
