<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9742" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: FOCUS-BFE deal to boost BPI's network.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-BFE deal to boost BPI's network.</headline>
<byline>David Brough</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The planned purchase of state bank Banco de Fomento &amp; Exterior (BFE) by Banco Portugues de Investimento (BPI) will enable BPI to broaden its retail network and cut costs, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>It could be some time before the price that BPI will pay for the state's stake in BFE becomes known, official sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;It will benefit greatly from acquiring BFE's extensive retail network -- Banco Borges &amp; Irmao,&quot; said Pedro Assuncao, analyst with Lisbon broker Central Investimentos.</p>
<p>&quot;It is another step that will boost concentration in Portuguese banking and will allow BPI to cut costs,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>It could be some time before the price that BPI will pay for the state's stake in BFE becomes known, official sources said.</p>
<p>BPI will become Portugal's fourth biggest banking group, combining its retail bank Banco Fonsecas &amp; Burnay, Portugal's eighth biggest bank, with BFE's BBI, Portugal's ninth biggest.</p>
<p>A selection jury chose BPI as the only candidate to continue to the final phase of the privatisation of BFE because its proposal was &quot;unarguably&quot; the best, Finance Minister Antonio Sousa Franco said.</p>
<p>The other candidates were  Banco Finantia, which was allied to Swiss Bank Corp, and  Banco Nacional de Credito Imobiliario, controlled by cork magnate Americo Amorim.</p>
<p>The final phase in the privatisation will be the opening of the envelopes containing the value of the bid which has to be above 1,980 escudos per share.</p>
<p>In February the Finance Ministry rejected a bid by BPI which valued BFE at 152 billion escudos.</p>
<p>Mark Howard of Cascais-based Lloyds Bank Fund Managers said the jury would have considered BPI's previous experience in absorbing then state owned bank Banco Fonsecas &amp; Burnay.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a good deal for BPI, which was the only candidate with a proven capacity to turn a state bank around,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>BPI shares soared 5.2 percent to close at a new high for the year of 2,115 escudos, up 105, on Lisbon bourse.</p>
<p>&quot;BPI could test higher levels, perhaps touching 2,150 escudos as the market reacts positively to its acquisition of BFE,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Another operator said: &quot;It is likely that BPI will gain more ground as there is plenty of demand for the stock and there are no sellers.&quot;</p>
<p>Shares in BFE were suspended by the Financial Markets Committee on Thursday at 2,545 escudos ($16.6). It was not known when trade would start again.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
