<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9756" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greece to hold snap elections on September 22.</title>
<headline>Greece to hold snap elections on September 22.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greece's socialist Prime Minister Costas Simitis announced on Thursday that early general elections will be held on September 22.</p>
<p>&quot;I will visit tomorrow the president of the republic to request the parliament's dissolution and ask for elections to be held on Sunday, September 22,&quot; Simitis told reporters after chairing a special cabinet meeting.  </p>
<p>Simitis cited as reasons for the early poll problems with the country's ailing economy and tense relations with neighbouring Turkey. Elections were originally scheduled to be held in October next year.</p>
<p>Simitis, 60, is one of Greece's most popular politicians and and poll analysts have said his PASOK socialist party has a slight edge over the conservative New Democracy main opposition party.</p>
<p>Simitis, who replaced late party founder Andreas Papandreou as premier in January, wants a public mandate to push on with tough economic decisions aimed to bring Greece in line with its European Union partners</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
