<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9760" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bunds firm, mkt sceptical on chance of more gains.</title>
<headline>Bunds firm, mkt sceptical on chance of more gains.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Uneasiness was the dominating theme among German bond traders at the end of a hectic day that saw a surprise cut in the repo rate down to 3.00 percent from 3.30 percent previously.</p>
<p>At 1604 GMT the September Bund future was up 36 basis points at 97.79 after rising as high as 98.03 earlier in the afternoon.</p>
<p>Dealers said they doubted whether Bunds would be able to hold on to their current levels. The upmove after the rate cut had not been strong enough to herald major gains, they said.  </p>
<p>Dealers said there was hardly any hope for further rate cuts. Some insisted that a Bund sell-off was imminent while the others said Bunds were likely to settle into range trading for the time being.</p>
<p>&quot;I see resistance at 98.06 for Bunds and support at 79.65,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Traders said the Bundesbank had wrong-footed them. The cut in the repo rate to an all-time low was well above forecast for a decline of five to 10 basis points at most.</p>
<p>The cut had wiped out hopes of a repo easing and thereby robbed the market of impetus for further gains, dealers said.  </p>
<p>With easing hopes gone, Bunds would become even more vulnerable to movements of U.S. Treasuries, dealers said.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
