<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9762" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Europe feeds buyers seeking Latam sun pellets - ASA.</title>
<headline>Europe feeds buyers seeking Latam sun pellets - ASA.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Compound feed producers and traders in northern Europe were actively seeking limited sunseed meal pellets supplies from Latin America, the German office of the American Soybean Association (ASA) noted.</p>
<p>An ASA newsletter said the Rotterdam price of $160 spot fob was up $15 from a month ago in generally firmer markets.</p>
<p>The feed industry still had some gaps in its raw materials cover for the autumn and winter, ASA said.</p>
<p>Pig and poultry feed prices trended higher while dairy cow feed prices remained steady as farmers bought less as they could afford to delayed buying and instead use on-farm feed.</p>
<p>German grain harvest pressure was expected to weigh on feed grain prices and to slightly reduce feeds prices in the very near future, ASA said.</p>
<p>But feed barley prices still exceed last year's by 10 marks and wheat offers are 20 marks above last year's levels as a by-product of high world market prices.</p>
<p>As feeds benefitted from high feedgrain levels, palmkernel expellers for 1996 shipment today cost $130-$133 cif North Germany versus $127-$130 a month ago in the Hamburg market.</p>
<p>Corngluten, a rival in dairy feed uses, rose $5 to $151 for fourth quarter shipment due to lower U.S. corn crop expectations which triggered price rallies.</p>
<p>Active global demand for tapioca boosted spot mark prices fob Rotterdam to 23.25 marks per 100 kilos compared with 22.75 marks in early August.</p>
<p>ASA also said the feed industry needed more rapemeal, where fourth quarter prices fob ex-Hamburg mills of 27.00-27.75 marks consolidated high July levels.</p>
<p>Prices of Peruvian fishmeal for September/October were priced at $540 (64 percent protein), up by $10 from early August, amid lower fish catches and lower stocks at origin.</p>
<p>Chilean fishmeal also rose $10 in August and had a $25 premium over Peruvian material.</p>
<p>-- Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
