<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9764" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: FOCUS-Swedish steelmakers take price hit in '96.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Swedish steelmakers take price hit in '96.</headline>
<byline>Trevor Datson</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish steel producers Avesta Sheffield and SSAB posted on Thursday sharply lower earnings for the first quarter and first half respectively, blaming the profit slump on tumbling steel prices and weak markets.</p>
<p>Avesta, which is 51 percent owned by British Steel, showed a pre-tax profit of 228 million crowns ($34 million) for the first quarter of its 1996/97 financial year, almost a billion crowns down on the 1.23 billion posted for the same period last year.</p>
<p>Sales fell to 4.58 billion crowns, a 25 percent drop on the 6.13 billion crowns reported in the first quarter of last year.</p>
<p>Although demand for stainless steel had been fair, prices of cold-rolled products had fallen sharply, Avesta said.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite an improvement in demand, the price scenario worsened dramatically in May and June as competitors attempted to increase market share,&quot; Avesta said, adding that prices were now almost 45 percent below mid-1995 levels.</p>
<p>Production volumes at the Avesta steel mill in Sweden had increased as teething troubles were overcome, and output from the British mill in Sheffield had been the highest ever, it said.</p>
<p>Although there was little in the first quarter report to cheer Avesta shareholders, group CEO Per Molin said the worst was behind the company.</p>
<p>&quot;During the second quarter, prices of cold-rolled materials will have bottomed out after the dramatic fall in prices in the first quarter of the financial year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the positive signs now discernible of price increases during the autumn remain, we expect a slight improvement in results compared with the very low level we expect for the current quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>Although rival SSAB's half-year profits were higher than expected, the company said it expected profits for the year to be just half 1995 levels.</p>
<p>SSAB's profit after financial net of 1.49 billion crowns was the second-best ever half year figure, but it was still 35 percent down on the 2.29 billion crowns reported for the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>Even so, the figure beat market expectations of a 1.42 billion crown profit, and the SSAB share gained 1.50 crowns in Stockholm to 84.50 immediately after the results were published.</p>
<p>Once again, falling steel prices bore much of the blame, SSAB said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Steel prices have fallen by more than 20 percent in the space of three quarters. Against that background, the result was strong,&quot; SSAB president Leif Gustafsson said.</p>
<p>Of the 800 million crown fall in profits, some 600 million was due to lower margins in the steel operation, and a stronger Swedish crown -- the bane of Swedish exporters during the first half of the year -- accounted for 250 million.</p>
<p>Falling steel consumption in combination with shorter delivery times and de-stocking on the part of customers meant lower prices in the first two quarters, and SSAB said its steel prices had fallen by five percent in the second quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;We are meeting the downturn in the steel cycle with a continued focus on our niche products...and by cost-cutting throughout the company,&quot; Gustafsson said.</p>
<p>Prospects for the rest of the year were gloomy, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In all, the current development of steel prices and currency exchange rates in combination with the traditionally weak third quarter is expected to lead a result after financial items about half that of last year's record of 3.83 billion crowns,&quot; he said. ($=6.6290 Swedish crown)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
