<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9772" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Elf says in talks on Ecuador oil block.</title>
<headline>Elf says in talks on Ecuador oil block.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Elf Aquitaine is discussing changes to one of its four oil contracts in Ecuador and is open to all ideas, a company spokesman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The discussions focus on block 14, located in the central- eastern part of the country, and have been going on for four months, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are open to all discussion and ways of revising the existing contract and we have been meeting regularly for four months,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Elf is one of a number of foreign oil companies active in Ecuador, which said on Wednesday it planned to revise all foreign oil operations and banned a U.S. firm, Maxus Energy Corp, from drilling for oil.</p>
<p>Maxus, owned by Argentina's YPF SA, does not have a production-sharing deal with the Ecuadorean government under a regulation requiring that foreign firms grant the state at least 12.5 percent of output.</p>
<p>The Elf spokesman said block 14 was currently run as a &quot;type of service contract&quot; but that discussions could change this.</p>
<p>Two other blocks, Shiripuno and block 18, were already set up as production participation deals, he said.</p>
<p>A fourth, block 17, is still at the exploration stage and Elf announced what it called a significant oil discovery there in July.</p>
<p>Elf has been in Ecuador since 1987 and produces 3,500 barrels per day (bpd), the spokesman said. Ecuador produced about 395,000 bpd last year.</p>
<p>The company made no comment on Ecuador's latest declarations on foreign oil company interests.</p>
<p>President Abdala Bucaram, who was elected in July and calls himself the &quot;president of the poor,&quot; ordered the drilling ban by Maxus until it agreed to joint ventures with the state oil firm.</p>
<p>Energy and Mining Minister Alfredo Adoum said he had issued orders for the army to take possession of the Maxus fields.</p>
<p>However in Buenos Aires, YPF president Nells Leon said its oil installations in Ecuador were operating normally and had not been taken over by the armed forces.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5146</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
