<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9774" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norway gives aid to developing oil nations.</title>
<headline>Norway gives aid to developing oil nations.</headline>
<dateline>STAVANGER, Norway 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Norwegian Agency for Development Cooperation (NORAD) will donate around 50 million crowns to developing oil producing nations in 1996, officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Norwegian Oil Directorate, NORAD and the International Programme for Petroleum Management and Administration (PETRAD) are working together to transfer competence in the oil industry to 20 developing nations.</p>
<p>Most of the money will go to Africa, where the directorate is supporting oil projects in Namibia, Tanzania, Mozambique, Angola, South Africa and Eritrea, officials told a press conference.</p>
<p>The initiative aims to provide Norwegian experience and expertise with country's striving to build up their oil industries.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that Norway ia a small land without an imperialistic past is important and creates goodwill,&quot; said Fredrik Hagemann, director at the directorate.</p>
<p>Hagemann said one project yielding prmising results was with Indian oil authorities, which had received advice on building up a directorate to monitor hydrocarbon exploration and production.</p>
<p>NORAD and the directorate are also sponsoring development of a gas pipeline in South Africa between Johannesburg and Maputo, as well as other projects in the Seychelles, Bangladesh, Vietnam and Nicaragua.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STAVANGER, Norway"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
