<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9777" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian bonds/futures.</title>
<headline>Italian bonds/futures.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy bond futures held around the day's highs in late afternoon trade after taking a boost from a repo rate cut from the Bundesbank and a surprise Bank of France intervention rate cut, dealers said.</p>
<p>They added that the Bundesbank move aided most European bond markets, and helped settle a nervous Italy bond market that had seen losses early this week.</p>
<p>The market's focus is now on the second round of preliminary August CPI data with four Italian cities reporting this afternoon. The first six cities on Wednesday showed Auugst CPI was likely to fall to 3.3/3.4 percent from July's 3.6 percent.  </p>
<p>The Bundesbank announced today said that it would set its next two repo tenders at a fixed interest rate of 3.0 percent cutting the rate from 3.3 percent currently, but it left its official Discount and Lombard rates unchanged.</p>
<p>Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer said that the slowdown in German money supply growth and low inflation had allowed the central bank to cut its main money rate.</p>
<p>&quot;The German rate move was just what the doctor ordered after a period of nervousness in the Italian market. Together with the fall in Italian inflation, it puts more pressure on the Bank of Italy for lower interest rates,&quot; said one dealer.  </p>
<p>In late trading, data from the last four Italian cities of Bologna, Naples, Florence and Perugia confirmed analysts' earlier expectation that official August Italian CPI should fall to 3.3/3.4 percent from 3.6 percent in July.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom 392 66129502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
