<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9778" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Montedison returns to limelight.</title>
<headline>Montedison returns to limelight.</headline>
<byline>David Jones</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's agro-industry and chemical giant Montedison SpA returned to the limelight on Thursday as its shares rose sharply with analysts saying the stock was now a good short-term investment after recent share stake sales.</p>
<p>Two major shareholders have been selling shares in Montedison, and analysts suspect the hand of Montedison's largest shareholder the newly-named Compart and Italy's top deal-making merchant bank Mediobanca behind the move.</p>
<p>Rebel shareholder Luca Padulli and U.S. investment bank Merrill Lynch have sold shares while the ex-Ferruzzi Compart has increased its hold over the group, signalling that Mediobanca's recovery plan for Compart/Montedison is back on track.</p>
<p>Montedison shares rose up 2.56 percent to 1,025 lire and Compart 4.64 percent firmer to 656 lire by mid afternoon with investors eyeing less volatile times for its recently rocky share price, and seeing further consolidation of the group's sprawling structure at top of the agenda.</p>
<p>Padulli, who heads hedge fund group Codelouf &amp; Co, rocked Italy's cosy business establishment in May by pushing for the break up the large conglomerate to unlock shareholder value. Padulli then held a 4.8 percent stake of Montedison.</p>
<p>After Montedison's top management rejected the break-up plan, analysts suspect Padulli was offered a way to get out of Montedison, and it was revealed late Wednesday that his shareholding had slipped to 0.12 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems Padulli was offered a way out, and the Mediobanca plan is back on the rails. Its good news for Montedison but shows that nothing changes in Italy and the old boy connection is still secure,&quot; said a head trader at leading Italian broker.</p>
<p>Over the last few months, Compart's holding in Montedison had risen to 33 percent from around 31 percent while the latest records show Mediobanca's share of Montedison at four percent.</p>
<p>Mediobanca led a group of Italian banks to rescue Ferruzzi and Montedison from the brink of collapse in 1993 and they now control 70 percent of Compart shares. The Mediobanca-led rescue plan was to sell off non-core business to cut debt and return both groups to profitable growth.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly, Compart and Mediobanca have increased their influence over Montedison. The question now is what is the next move,&quot; said one industry analyst in Milan.</p>
<p>Some suspect a Compart/Montedison merger is back on the agenda after a similar plan last summer called SuperGemina was adandoned after accounting fraud was unearthed at the merger vehicle Gemina SpA, but a more limited merger just between Compact and Montedison could be a simpler move, they suggest.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch held 3.8 percent of Montedison at the time of the Montedison's annual meeting in June, but then sold 1.7 percent a few days ago and was thought to have sold a 1.52 percent block of 60 million Montedison shares yesterday. Merrill have said only they have &quot;under two percent&quot; of Montedison.</p>
<p>Analysts pointed out that with two shareholders, not believed to be firm holders of Montedison, reducing their holdings the focus has returned to Montedison's warrants.</p>
<p>Montedison stands to gain 1,050 billion lire ($690 million) from the exercising of warrants held by the market by the end of this year, but only if the shares hold above 1,000 lire.</p>
<p>Dealers say Montedison is now a good short-term investment with the company eager to keep the shares above 1,000 lire to gain the financial benefits from the exercising of the warrants.</p>
<p>($1=1,519 lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
