<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9780" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital market closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital market closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ten-year bond futures and three-month PIBOR settled sharply higher after the Bank of France lopped 20 basis points of its key intervention rate following a decisive 30 basis point cut in the German repo rate.</p>
<p>The franc also jumped more than one centime against the mark on the surprise easing by the two central banks, trading at 3.4079 per mark in late afternoon compared with 3.4192 late Tuesday.</p>
<p>Analysts and economists said that the &quot;mini-crisis&quot; on the franc now appeared to be over but said tensions could resurface when the centre-right government presents its 1997 budget.  </p>
<p>The 10-year OAT-Bund spread briefly narrowed to parity from eight basis points on Wednesday before widening to two basis points. Analysts said they expected the gap to hover around parity but widen again in the run-up to the budget due September 18, with some saying it could reach the double-digit level.</p>
<p>&quot;This has had a very positive effect but it could be short term,&quot; said one economist. &quot;We are likely to see some more pressure on the franc before the budget on September 18.&quot;</p>
<p>By not matching the Bundesbank rate cut in full, economists said the French central bank had left itself a cushion for when events heat up with the 1997 budget.  </p>
<p>&quot;There could be more tension on the franc around budget time,&quot; said Jean-Louis Mourier, economist at Louis Dreyfus Finance. &quot;The franc weakness was not an interest rate story. It was about worries over the government.&quot;</p>
<p>Financial markets have been rattled by fears that a slowing economy will mean France will be unable to meet the Maastricht criteria for European monetary union.</p>
<p>But one economist at a major French bank said the Bundesbank's rate cut had been a decisive move to support France and other countries struggling to qualify for monetary union.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think it is going to be very difficult to have a big crisis on the French franc because they will not only face the Banque de France...they will have to engage in a struggle with the Bundesbank and this is something they can't win,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said it was too early to conclude that the Bundesbank reduction in the repo rate to 3.00 percent was the final rate German rate cut.</p>
<p>They expected the Bank of France to start nudging call money down again but believed it would hold off on any cut in the floor intervention rate, now at 3.35 percent, until the government was safely out of the woods on the budget.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is a new context that will support the front end of the mark, the BTAN area. The message for the next few weeks is to play further steepening of the yield curve and to play BTAN-Bobl spread compression,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;With further call money easing in the pipeline, we have to remain positive on the French market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The spread between call money and the German repo rate was at 20 basis points before the latest cuts, he said. &quot;We're now at 50. It will likely try to push back the spread to 20 over the next few months.</p>
<p>Call money has been at 3-1/2-5/8 since July 19.  </p>
<p>The long end of the curve would be supported by ongoing flows from French domestic investors, mainly insurers, one analyst said. But concrete signs of economic slowdown in the United States coupled with a stronger U.S. T-bond performance were needed to push the French 10-year bond future through its contract high of 124.10 hit today.</p>
<p>Some economists were dubious about longer-term prospects for the French market, doubting the government's ability to meet its fiscal targets and wary of angry union reaction to austerity plans. &quot;We would not say the franc is out of the woods especially as we move toward the budget,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>-- Penny MacRae, Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
