<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9782" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish bonds rise capped by credit growth concerns.</title>
<headline>Irish bonds rise capped by credit growth concerns.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish government bonds strengthened in busy late trade on Thursday but concerns about domestic interest rates put a lid on performance, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had an advance like everywhere else. All curves have tended to steepen with the short-end performing much better than the long-end after the Bundesbank's surprising 30 basis points cut in the Repo rate earlier,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the reaction in Ireland has been a little bit muted relative to core Europe largely because of concerns here about the pace of credit growth,&quot; the dealer added.  </p>
<p>Earlier, the Bundesbank cut its repo rate for the next two tenders to a fixed 3.00 percent from the 3.30 percent where the rate had been fixed since February but did not change its discount and Lombard rates, which were last cut in mid-April.</p>
<p>By 1525 GMT, the 8.00 percent bond due 2000 had risen 40p from Wednesday's close at 103.95 to yield 6.75 percent while the 8.00 percent bond due 2006 had risen 20p from the close at 103.05 to yield 7.41 percent.</p>
<p>The one-month money market rate, which has remained above the key 5.50 mark since early in August, was at 5.56/69 compared with 5.63/75 at the close.  </p>
<p>&quot;We saw an offical interest rates cut introduced in most of core Europe after the Bundesbank announcement whereas we are still looking at the possibility of a retail rate rise in Ireland,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very much up to the financial institutions in Ireland as to whether or not we see get a change. I don't think one month money will drop below 5.50 so we might be looking at a rates change some time next week,&quot; the dealer added.</p>
<p>-- Damien Lynch, Dublin Newsroom +353 1 6603377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
