<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9788" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish Permanent says to raise variable loan rate.</title>
<headline>Irish Permanent says to raise variable loan rate.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish Permanent Plc, one of Ireland's largest mortgage lenders, said on Thursday that it was raising its variable mortgage rate by 0.25 percent.</p>
<p>The move comes in the wake of a 30-basis point cut in the German Repo Rate by the Bundesbank earlier.  </p>
<p>&quot;We see this as a balance,&quot; general manager stratery Diarmuid Bradley told Reuters. &quot;The money market rates have been indicating half a percentage point increase for the last couple of weeks but slightly better news on the international front would indicate that the full half percent won't be necessary.&quot;</p>
<p>Bradley said the Bundesbank's 30-basis point cut in the Repo rate meant the difference between Irish Permanent raising rates by quarter of a percentage point rather than half a point.</p>
<p>Ireland's key one-month interbank rate has been trading close to 5.75 percent in recent weeks and was quoted at 5.56/69 percent by 1610 GMT.  </p>
<p>The official Short Term Facility Rate (STF) is currently 6.25 percent.</p>
<p>Irish Permanent said it will raise its variable annuity rate to 7.00 percent from 6.75 percent and its endowment rate by 0.25 percent to 7.15 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Market conditions have for some time warranted a 0.5 percent increase in general mortgage rates. The lower increase (0.25 percent) at this time reflects our hope that benign international conditions will lead in due course to lower Irish money market rates,&quot; general manager Treasury, Michael Torpey said in a statement.</p>
<p>-- Dublin Newsroom +353 1 676 9775</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
