<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9789" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch closing share market report.</title>
<headline>Dutch closing share market report.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares closed higher on Thursday, boosted by a 30 basis point cut in a key German money market rate which caught some in the market by surprise.</p>
<p>The AEX share index closed 5.47 points higher at 564.95, putting on around 4.00 points in direct response to news the Bundesbank was cutting its repo rate to 3.00 percent from 3.30.</p>
<p>&quot;We needed this incentive because the momentum in the index seemed to be running out, so the cut in the repo rate seems to have come just in time,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;There's some sentiment building up in the market, if not for lower rates, at least for no rise in (German) interest rates,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>News the Dutch central bank was cutting its special advances money market rate to 2.50 percent from 2.70 percent in line with the Bundesbank caused a late flurry of interest, dealers said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the Bundesbank move could open up the way for the AEX share index to push back up to the 572.50 all-time high reached in June.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we will head further towards the old high in the index especially if the (September) German bund future goes above 98.00 as looks likely now,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;The bund future is poised to attempt to go back above 100 after 94.50 in June and that would give our market a big push.&quot;  </p>
<p>Market sentiment before the Bundesbank move had been mixed, with a 28 percent rise in ING first half net to 1.51 billion guilders triggering profit-taking in the company's shares on the view that, while strong, the profit rise was unexciting.</p>
<p>&quot;ING results were quite good but expectations were high and it was difficult to beat (last week's) ABN AMRO result,&quot; a dealer said. ABN AMRO closed 1.20 up at 93.20 guilders.</p>
<p>ING shares closed 30 cents down at 53.90 guilders, bouncing up from a session low of 52.20 guilders after ING said it saw the second quarter rate of profit growth continuing in the third and fourth quarters.  </p>
<p>Insurer Aegon closed 3.10 guilders at 83.40 following a better than expected 15.7 percent rise in first half net profit to 711.1 million guilders.</p>
<p>&quot;That was a nice surprise from Aegon and it helped the market a bit too,&quot; said a dealer.</p>
<p>News of a 51 percent jump in Nutricia first half net profit to 107.1 million guilders was above expectations of 79-102 million guilders but too late to have any impact on the shares which had already closed 40 cents easier at 191.60 guilders.</p>
<p>Other leading issues saw Philips 1.80 guilders higher at 57.60 and Royal Dutch up 1.90 guilders to 256.90. -- Keiron Henderson, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
