<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9790" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: All Belgium grieves as child sex victims buried.</title>
<headline>All Belgium grieves as child sex victims buried.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>LIEGE, Belgium 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of Belgians turned out on Thursday to pay their last respects to two young girls who starved to death after abduction by a paedophile gang, and to support the courage and share the grief of the parents.</p>
<p>Young and old, rich and poor, from all walks of life... Belgians united in mourning eight-year-olds Julie Lejeune and Melissa Russo in a way that even the death of King Baudouin three years ago did not quite achieve.</p>
<p>A memorial service in the Saint Martin Basilica in Liege was relayed in sound and pictures to the thousands waiting outside in this east Belgian city and beamed live throughout the country. Liegoise France Collignon summed up the mood.</p>
<p>&quot;It is horrendous, unbelievable,&quot; she said, tears streaming down her cheeks as she stood in the crowd cradling her eight-week-old daughter Morgane in her arms.</p>
<p>Some in the crowd cried openly but silently. Others stood absorbed as the memorial service progressed.</p>
<p>Others still seemed lost in thought, stricken expressions on their faces as they and the rest of the country adopted the dead girls as a symbol of the determination never to let their fate be repeated.</p>
<p>&quot;I haven't got the words to describe these people,&quot; said Marie-Char Orgeret, 14. &quot;We should do the same thing to them as they did to Julie and Melissa.&quot;</p>
<p>Reporters and television crews circulated, posing the same questions to different people -- and getting the same answer.</p>
<p>The crowds were there to show support for the parents of Julie and Melissa -- Jean-Denis and Louisa Lejeune and Gino and Carine Russo -- and express their disgust at what had happened.</p>
<p>&quot;I am here for the poor parents of those martyred children. The people who did this must be made to suffer...&quot; said Anne-Marie Lamory of Bastogne in southern Belgium. &quot;They too should die suffering...they are monsters.&quot;</p>
<p>Friends Julie and Melissa disappeared in June last year from near their homes in the Liege suburb of Grace-Hollogne.</p>
<p>Last weekend convicted child rapist Marc Dutroux led police to the bodies of the two girls in the garden of one of his houses. He said they had starved to death early this year.</p>
<p>The discovery triggered an eruption of emotion throughout the country, amplified by the rescue of two other young girls and information about two others whom Dutroux admitted having abducted a year ago with two accomplices.</p>
<p>Some people have urged the reintroduction of the death penalty -- finally erased from the statute books in June after lying dormant for several years.</p>
<p>Others called for it to be made impossible for convicted child abusers to be released early from jail.</p>
<p>Dutroux, sentenced to 13 years in jail in 1989 for multiple child rape, was freed 10 years early in 1992 for good behaviour.</p>
<p>Police had expected up to 100,000 to gather for the memorial service. In the end only 5,000 turned up, police said, but the emotion they generated more than made up for the lack of numbers.</p>
<p>As the 18-car funeral cortege went by -- 13 cars loaded with hundreds of bouquets sent by well-wishers, one laden with soft toys donated by young children, one car each carrying the two small white coffins and one car each for the girls' parents -- people crossed themselves and clapped to show their support.</p>
<p>Many in the crowd also clutched pictures of the two girls, some weeping as they read the inscription underneath. It read:</p>
<p>&quot;We were eight years old and full of dreams. We believed life would be beautiful. You grown-ups, make us a better world.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIEGE, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
