<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9792" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares higher amid post rate-cut aftershock.</title>
<headline>German shares higher amid post rate-cut aftershock.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares were higher in afternoon trade on Thursday, although traders were still shell-shocked after the Bundesbank's decision to cut its money market rate by 30 basis points.</p>
<p>In late post-bourse trade, the IBIS DAX index stood at 2,564.56 points, up 30.12 points.</p>
<p>&quot;It's hard to know what to make of it really. There are two points of view -- that it's all over, all the expectation is gone, the interest rate cycle is complete, or that there is more room for further cuts,&quot; said a London trader.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that the cycle is probably complete,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>The Bundesbank cut the securities repurchase rate to a historic low of three percent, a far bigger cut than expected. The cut was interpreted by some as sign that the stint of German rate easing has come to an end.</p>
<p>In the afternoon the market easily digested U.S. jobless figures and took Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer's reasons for the repo rate cut very much in its stride.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer said the Bundesbank had decided to cut the repo rate after developments in M3 money supply and inflationary factors and pledged to monitor further developments.</p>
<p>Shares held their gains after the comments.  </p>
<p>Shares in the spotlight over the course of the day included BASF AG, which was nearly three percent higher at 43.50 marks in late post-bourse trade.</p>
<p>BASF was boosted by its first half figures, which saw pre-tax profits rise 14.7 percent to 2.32 billion marks.</p>
<p>Builder Hochtief AG was up one mark at 67.50 marks in afternoon trade after its first half results which showed an increase in incoming foreign orders of 191 percent.</p>
<p>Chemical group Merck KGaA fell 1.51 marks to 55.79 after Deutsche Morgan Grenfell lowered its EPS forecasts.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
