<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9793" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Nuclear test ban talks end in failure.</title>
<headline>Nuclear test ban talks end in failure.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Disarmament negotiators wrapped up almost three years of talks on a global nuclear test ban on Thursday with no pact agreed and without even agreement to report their failure to the United Nations General Assembly.</p>
<p>Opposition from Iran and India prevented the 61-nation Conference on Disarmament sending a negotiating report to the U.N., where major powers still hope to reintroduce the draft text and have it signed next month.  </p>
<p>India vetoed the draft treaty because it does not contain a clause committing the five declared nuclear powers to a timetable for nuclear disarmament.</p>
<p>But conference members had still hoped to send the negotiating report -- which merely stated that no consensus had been reached on the text -- to the General Assembly, which asked the Geneva body last year to negotiate a pact.</p>
<p>That was blocked on Thursday by Iran and India, making it slightly more difficult for major powers and some non-aligned states to reintroduce the treaty to the current session of the assembly as a resolution needing a simple majority rather than the consensus needed in Geneva.</p>
<p>Australia earlier signalled that it would be willing to take the lead role in proposing the resolution. Backers of the treaty hope it can be adopted and opened for signature by late September.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
