<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9796" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: BPI offer &quot;unarguably&quot; best for BFE - Finmin.</title>
<headline>BPI offer &quot;unarguably&quot; best for BFE - Finmin.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Banco Portugues de Investimento was chosen as the only candidate to continue to the final phase of the privatisation of Banco de Fomento &amp; Exterior because its proposal was &quot;unarguably&quot; the best, Finance Minister Antonio Sousa Franco said.</p>
<p>He told a news conference that this was the decision of the selection jury asked to evaluate the proposals of the three candidates to buy the 65 percent of BFE controlled by the state.</p>
<p>&quot;The jury believed that the BPI group (is) the solution that best satisfies the objectives of the privatisation,&quot; the ministry said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The other candidates were  Banco Finantia, which was allied to Swiss Bank Corp, and  Banco Nacional de Credito Imobiliario, controlled by cork magnate Americo Amorim.</p>
<p>&quot;With respect to the other two groups...(the jury decided they should be ranked) a long way behind the group led by BPI,&quot; the ministry statement said.</p>
<p>The statement said that whoever won the bidding would inevitably need to raise debt to cover the significant cost of buying BFE and the jury felt that BPI could do so with the least risk.</p>
<p>Sousa Franco said the decision to approve the sole candidacy of Banco Portugues for the final phase of the privatisation was taken unanimously by the cabinet at its meeting on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;It was unanimous,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Fernanda Pargana, Lisbon bureau 3511-3150035</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
