<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9801" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Small firms ask Quinn to dispel rate rise fear.</title>
<headline>Small firms ask Quinn to dispel rate rise fear.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Small Firms Association (SFA) called on Finance Minister Ruairi Quinn on Thursday to take action to dispel fears of a rise in Irish interest rates in the wake of the German repo rate cut.</p>
<p>&quot;An interest rate increase at this time will send very negative signals to our internatrs and the Minister should take the appropriate steps to protect our reputation,&quot; SFA director Brendan Butler said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Butler said Irish economic indicators did not necessitate an interest rate rise and that businesses and their employees were being &quot;kicked in the teeth&quot; by the government and Central Bank.</p>
<p>He said inflation was the lowest in Europe at 1.4 percent and there was no evidence of inflationary pressures in the key sectors of tourism or food production.</p>
<p>A rate rise would put further upward pressure on the Irish pound against sterling and other European currencies, he argued.</p>
<p>Irish exporters complain that the punt's strength against sterling weakens their competitiveness against Britain, Ireland's biggest trading partner.</p>
<p>--Dublin Newsroom +353 1 660 3377.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
