<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9803" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks end up, off best after BoF rate cut.</title>
<headline>French stocks end up, off best after BoF rate cut.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Paris bourse closed with sharp gains, cheered by a surprise interest rate cut by the Bank of France, which followed an equally unexpected easing by the Bundesbank.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank has once again taken the markets by surprise because since yesterday nobody was still expecting a cut,&quot; said Jacques-Antoine Bretteil, a director at brokers Leven.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index closed up 17.12 points or 0.86 percent at 2,017.76, after hitting a day-high of 2,026.54 after the French rate reduction. The CAC-40 futures contract was up at 2,025 from 2,003 on Wednesday's close.  </p>
<p>* Volume was a solid 4.29 billion francs.</p>
<p>* The French central bank cut of 20 basis points in the intervention rate to 3.35 percent caught some in the market off guard as they had thought the Bank would wait a while to see how the franc would react in the currency market.</p>
<p>* The franc firmed to trade at 3.4093 per mark in late afternoon compared to 3.4192 late Wednesday.</p>
<p>* One trader thought the CAC-40 index could hit the 2,030/50 range in the next few days.</p>
<p>* Financials rallied strongly on a view the rate reduction could help growth, credit demand and lower funding costs.  </p>
<p>* Total ends 1.81 percent higher at 377 francs. It posted a 20 percent increase in first-half sales to 8.6 billion francs</p>
<p>* Cie Generale des Eaux ended 0.79 percent down at 501 francs. Opeators pointed up financing concerns over a 400 million stg investment in new trains after its CGEA unit won a rail privatisation franchise.</p>
<p>Its possible entry into a bid by businessman Walter Butler for the loss-making French SFP fim studio also raised doubts.</p>
<p>The market shrugged off first-half sales, which were steady at 78.88 billion francs. -- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452  </p>
<p>* Banque Nationale de Paris (BNP) garnered several broker recommendations and closed up 7.0 francs at 180.80, or 4.03 percent. Since January BNP has fallen 18.5 percent.</p>
<p>Other financials to rise were Societe Generale, up 2.17 percent at 565 francs, Paribas up 1.91 percent at 315, Credit Commercial de France up 1.14 percent at 239, and Suez up 1.56 percent at 182.8.</p>
<p>* Cap Gemini stays firm, adds 3.73 percent to 219.80 francs on big first half sales increase.</p>
<p>* Seita weakens 2.85 percent to 207.90 francs, on fears for the tobacco sector looming from the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
