<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9804" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish navy detains first Japanese trawler.</title>
<headline>Irish navy detains first Japanese trawler.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish naval officers shadowed a Japanese trawler on Thursday and escorted another to port in a crackdown on illegal fishing in the nation's Western waters.</p>
<p>It was the first time the authorities had detained a Japanese vessel inside its 200-mile &quot;Irish box&quot; waters on suspicion of illegal fishing.</p>
<p>A senior naval official told Irish radio that officers were preparing to board an unnamed Japanese vessel found inside the Irish box on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are about 200 yards (metres) away from the vessel. We are going to carry out a routine search,&quot; Lieutenant Commander Brian Havers of the LE Deirdre told Irish radio.</p>
<p>He said he would not know until after a search of the hold and inspection of the trawler's documentation whether or not it would also be detained and escorted to port.</p>
<p>A second vessel, the Minato Maru, was being escorted to the coast of Cork, southern Ireland, after being found in the Irish box earlier this week.</p>
<p>Its captain is expected to be charged when he reaches land with fishing about 100 miles off the Galway coast inside Irish waters. Eight tonnes of tuna were found in its hold.</p>
<p>A further 30 Japanese vessels were grouped just outside Ireland's international waters, Havers said. He declined to be drawn on speculation of a standoff developing between the Japanese fleet and Irish fisheries protection vessels.</p>
<p>It took more than 10 hours for Irish naval vessels to retrieve the 70-mile long-line fishing gear thought to have been used by the Minato Maru to catch tuna.</p>
<p>Other long-line gear was also being retrieved from inside the area, which extends for 200 miles around the Irish coast and is more than 10 times the country's land area.</p>
<p>Long-lining is used to catch surface-feeding fish on kilometres (miles) of line tossed overboard by trawlers, marked by radio signal and picked up later.</p>
<p>Ireland detained several vessels, mostly Spanish, last year in a show of strength over the protection of its waters for Irish fishermen and licensed operators from other EU states.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I03000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
