<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9807" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek money rates drop sharply after Buba cut.</title>
<headline>Greek money rates drop sharply after Buba cut.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek depos and forex swaps dived 20 basis points on expectations that the central bank will cut its overnight intervention bid on Friday following Thursday's 30 bp reduction in the Bundesbank's repo rate, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Rates plunged after Buba cut its key repo rate,&quot; said a senior money dealer at a foreign bank. &quot;The Bank of Greece usually follows Buba and the market expects it to slash its overnight intervention rate on Friday.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said there was about the prospect of early elections.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets are fond of the short pre-election period and there is hope that a strong government will emerge from the ballot that will move aggressively to streamline the economy,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>The Greek socialist party's general secretary Costas Skandalidis said the party's executive bureau gave the green light for Prime Minister Costas Simitis to call snap elections.</p>
<p>He added Prime Minister Costas Simitis would make an official announcement after a cabinet meeting later on Thursday.</p>
<p>Based on Greece's constitution, elections must be held within a month from the time they are announced.</p>
<p>The mark was quoted at 159.92/97 drachmas from Wednesday's 159.850 fix, the dollar at 238.02/12 drachmas from 237.460 and the Ecu at 301.49/59 from 300.600 drachmas.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Greece, the domestic money</p>
<p>market's biggest player, quoted the following late rates:</p>
<p>** Overnight at 12.40-12.90</p>
<p>** T/N at 12.40-12.90</p>
<p>** S/N at 12.40-12.90</p>
<p>** One week at 12.45-12.95</p>
<p>** Two weeks at 12.50-13.00</p>
<p>** Three weeks at 12.55-13.05</p>
<p>** One month at 12.65-13.15</p>
<p>** Two months at 12.75-13.25</p>
<p>** Three months at 12.85-13.35</p>
<p>** Six months at 13.10-13.60</p>
<p>** Nine months at 13.35-13.85</p>
<p>** Twelve months at 13.40-14.00</p>
<p>--Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
