<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9812" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Deal with hardleft on Stet possible - Italy govt.</title>
<headline>Deal with hardleft on Stet possible - Italy govt.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Italian government should be able to reach an agreement with the hardleft Communist Refoundation over the privatisation of telecoms holding Stet, the undersecretary at the post ministry said.</p>
<p>&quot;From its latest statements, the position of Refoundation (over the Stet sale) seems calmer and more constructive than at first,&quot; Michele Lauria said in a statement.</p>
<p>Refoundation leader Fausto Bertinotti warned at the start of the week that he would be ready to bring the government down if it tried to push through the Stet sale, which is slated for early 1997.  </p>
<p>Refoundation holds the balance of power in the lower house of parliament and has ensured the survival of Italy's centre-left government since it took office in May.</p>
<p>Earlier on Thursday, Refoundation chairman Armando Cossutta wrote in La Repubblica newspaper that his party had a much more pragmatic and less ideological view of the privatisation of Stet than those people who were blindly calling for its sell-off.</p>
<p>&quot;Before selling Stet, the government, and above all parliament, must completely define rules for markets, like the telecommunications and electric energy sectors, which today are clear monopolies,&quot; Cossutta wrote in an article.</p>
<p>The undersecretary at the post ministry said in his statement: &quot;If the liberalisation of the sensitive multi-media sector is taken as the key concept of the operation...an agreement can be reached.&quot; -- Rome newsroom +396 6782501</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
