<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9816" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: SSAB sees '96 profits sharply down.</title>
<headline>SSAB sees '96 profits sharply down.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish steel producer SSAB posted on Thursday a higher than expected profit for the first half of the year, but said it expected profits for the year to be halved on 1995 levels.  </p>
<p>Although the steelmaker's profit after financial net of 1.49 billion crowns for the first half was the second best ever for that period, it was still a 35 percent fall on the 2.29 billion crowns reported for the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>Even so, the figure was slightly better than market expectations of a 1.42 billion crown profit after financial net, and the share gained 1.50 crowns in Stockholm to 84.50 immediately after the results were published.</p>
<p>Falling steel prices bore some of the blame for the earnings tumble, SSAB said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Steel prices have fallen by more than 20 percent in the space of three quarters. Against that background, the result was strong,&quot; SSAB president Leif Gustafsson said.</p>
<p>Of the 800 million crown fall in profits, some 600 million was due to lower margins in the steel operation, and a stronger Swedish crown -- the bane of Swedish exporters during the first half of the year -- accounted for 250 million.</p>
<p>Operating income for the period declined to 9.41 billion crowns from 9.99 billion in the first half of last year, and higher costs and depreciation resulted in a 40 percent drop in operating profit to 1.28 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Falling steel consumption in combination with shorter delivery times and de-stocking on the part of customers had resulted in weak order intake for the Western European steel industry, SSAB said.</p>
<p>This had resulted in falling prices for most products over the first two quarters, and SSAB said the group's steel prices had fallen by five percent in the second quarter.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are meeting the downturn in the steel cycle with a continued focus on our niche products ... strip and quenched steel in the heavy plate area and by cost-cutting throughout the company,&quot; Gustafsson said.</p>
<p>SSAB said it would invest a total of 350 million crowns in improving the production flow in its heavy plate operations and the contruction of a special line for thin hardened plate at its Swedish Oxelosund mill.</p>
<p>Even so, prospects for the rest of the year were gloomy, Gustafsson said.</p>
<p>&quot;In all, the current development of steel prices and currency exchange rates in combination with the traditionally weak third quarter is expected to lead a result after financial items about half that of last year's record of 3.83 billion crowns,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom,+46-8-700 1006</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
