<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9817" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Portugal Finmin calls news conference on BFE.</title>
<headline>Portugal Finmin calls news conference on BFE.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Portuguese Finance Ministry said it would hold a news conference about the privatisation of Banco de Fomento &amp; Exterior at 1300 GMT after a cabinet meeting on Thursday.</p>
<p>The ministry gave no further details but the government has in hand three offers to buy the state's 65 percent stake in the bank and is due to decide which to accept.  </p>
<p>The three candidates are Banco Portugues de Investimento, Banco Finantia and Banco Nacional de Credito Imobiliario which is controlled by businessman Americo Amorim.</p>
<p>The prices of the various bids have not been disclosed but the market is looking for over 2,500 escudos per share which would value the stake at some 130 billion escudos ($850 million).</p>
<p>But the winner will also have to guarantee an offer of some 3.5 percent to small investors and employees and eventually launch a public offer to buy (OPA) the remaining stock quoted on the market, all at the same price.</p>
<p>However, it is not certain that the name of the winner will emerge on Thursday.</p>
<p>The government has received the report of a special jury set up to evaluate the proposals of the three contenders on the basis of such elements as experience in the banking sector, synergies with existing operations and the promoting of competition within the Portuguese banking sector.</p>
<p>All three proposals could pass at the jury stage, leaving the final decision to rest solely on price.</p>
<p>Only if one of the offers is 10 percent higher than the others will an immediate winner emerge.</p>
<p>If not, then the battle moves to the floor of the Lisbon bourse where the candidates will bid directly against eachother for the stake.</p>
<p>--Lisbon bureau 3511-3150035</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
