<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9819" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India sees no arms race after nuclear pact blocked.</title>
<headline>India sees no arms race after nuclear pact blocked.</headline>
<byline>Hari Ramachandran</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>India said on Thursday that its opposition to a global nuclear test ban treaty did not mean New Delhi intended to enter into an arms race with neighbouring Pakistan and China.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister I.K. Gujral was asked at a news conference if India's decision to block adoption of the accord in Geneva would lead to an arms race with Pakistan and China.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not see that possibility because India is not entering into any arms race,&quot; he said. &quot;Our not signing a new treaty does not mean we are going in for any new kind of weapons, particularly nuclear.&quot;</p>
<p>China, along with Britain, France, Russia and the United States, is a declared nuclear power. India carried out a nuclear test in 1974 but says it has not built the bomb.</p>
<p>Experts believe both India and Pakistan could quickly assemble nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>Asked what stopped India from being an open nuclear power state Gujral said &quot;self-discipline.&quot;</p>
<p>Gujral said he did not expect India's veto of the Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty (CTBT) to damage bilateral ties with the United States or other nations.</p>
<p>&quot;We both value each other's friendship and this one issue on which we may differ should not affect and will not affect our bilateral relations,&quot; Gujral said.</p>
<p>But Gujral said India would re-examine its position if the treaty was modified.</p>
<p>Asked what India would do if the pact were forwarded to the United Nations General Assembly, Gujral said: &quot;That bridge I will cross when I come to it.&quot;</p>
<p>In a written statement released at the news conference, Gujral reiterated India's objections to the treaty, under negotiation at the Conference on Disarmament in Geneva.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a sad fact that the nuclear weapon states show no interest in giving up their nuclear hegemony,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Gujral said India had national security concerns that made it impossible for New Delhi to sign the CTBT.</p>
<p>&quot;Our security concerns oblige us to maintain our nuclear option,&quot; he said, adding that India had exercised restraint in not carrying out any nuclear tests since the country's lone test blast in 1974.</p>
<p>He said: &quot;We cannot accept constraints on our option as long as nuclear weapon states continue to rely on their nuclear arsenals for their security&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
