<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9827" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: PRESS DIGEST - Pakistan newspapers - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Pakistan newspapers - Aug 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main stories in Thursday's Pakistani newspapers.</p>
<p>DAWN</p>
<p>- Turkish Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan, who completed a tour of five Asian nations, announced major defence industry accords with Pakistan, Malaysia and Indonesia.</p>
<p>- Iranian Oil Minister Gholamreza Aqazadeh said Iran and Pakistan have finalised a $1.2 billion agreement for a joint oil refinery. The agreement was signed in Islamabad on Tuesday.</p>
<p>- A leader of the Mohajir National Movement (MQM), Osama Qadri, sought by authorities who have offered a reward of one million rupees for information on his whereabouts, was arrested. Qadri was in hiding since an army operation was launched against the MQM in June 1992.</p>
<p>- Stock exchanges of 13 Asian and European countries are discussing the possibility of starting cross-border listing and trading of companies registered in their respective exchanges, president of the Karachi Stock Exchange Arif Habib said.</p>
<p>BUSINESS RECORDER</p>
<p>- The State (central) Bank of Pakistan has allowed banks to offer 40 billion rupees as credit to the cotton sector in fiscal 1996/97 (July-June).</p>
<p>- The private sector has entered the field of sugar imports and eight shipments of 96,000 tonnes have so far been booked.</p>
<p>- The fiscal budget for 1996/97 (July-June) has weighed heavily on the stock market in Pakistan and share prices have flattened after initial gains, the International Finance Corporation said.</p>
<p>THE MUSLIM</p>
<p>- Pakistan needs two billion rupees to eradicate cultivation of the poppy plant in opium growing areas.</p>
<p>- Representatives of a Dutch-Indonesian-Pakistani consortium met officials of the Pakistani Privatisation Commission to discuss the sale of the state-run Pakistan Telecommunication Company Ltd.</p>
<p>- The Taleban have denied they had arrested six men to investigate the escape of seven Russian airmen from Kandahar.</p>
<p>-- Islamabad newsroom 9251-274757</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
