<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9832" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - August 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - August 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indian business and political stories in leading newspapers on Thursday prepared for Reuters by Business News and Information Services Pvt Ltd, New Delhi. Telephone: 11-3324842, 11-3761233; Fax: 91-11-3351006 Internet: biznis.news@forums.sprintrpg.sprint.com</p>
<p>		   -------oo0oo-------</p>
<p>			TOP STORIES</p>
<p>The Times Of India</p>
<p>CONGRESS PARTY EXPELS FORMER MINISTER AFTER RAIDS</p>
<p>The Congress party suspended former Communications Minister Sukh Ram from the party's primary membership, following recent raids on his homes by the Central Bureau of Investigation (CBI), which recovered an unaccounted sum of 36.6 million rupees. Sukh Ram, whose whereabouts have not been known since the raid, has been accused of unfairly favouring a private firm in a government purchase of radio equipment. Congress officials said the funds recovered did not belong to the party. Meanwhile, the CBI carried out another raid on one of Sukh Ram's houses. The former minister is variously said to be in London and the United States.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Hindustan Times</p>
<p>BJP ACCUSES GUJARAT GOVERNOR OF HELPING PARTY REBELS</p>
<p>The Bhartiya Janata Party (BJP) has asked the President to reprimand the Gujarat governor for trying to destabilise the BJP-ruled state government. The governor had taken advantage of the split in the ruling party (BJP) to create confusion and &quot;pollute the political atmosphare in the state,&quot; BJP alleged. The governor had recently said that a breakaway faction of the BJP had the support of a substantial number of lagislators</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Indian Express</p>
<p>PAY COMMISSION RECOMMENDS INTERIM RELIEF</p>
<p>The Fifth Pay Commission has recommended a third instalment of interim relief for the six million federal government employees in the country, pending a wage revision. The commission has recommended that 10 percent of the basic pay be paid as interim relief. The recommendation, suggested in the commission's interim report to the finance ministry, is likely to cost the exchequer about 15 billion rupees.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Economic Times</p>
<p>FOREIGN POWER COMPANIES TO GET EASY APPROVAL</p>
<p>The Power Ministry has decided to grant automatic approval to coal-based, hydro-electric and non-conventional energy-based power projects for 100 percent foreign equity holding. In the new set-up there would be no need for clearance from the Foreign Investment Promotion Board or the Cabinet Committee on Foreign Investment once the Reserve Bank of India, the central bank, approved the projects.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>HARRIS THREATENS TO SEVERE VENTURES WITH ARM</p>
<p>US-based Harris Corp contemplated snapping all its ventures with ARM (Advanced Radio Masts) Ltd in view of latter's alleged links in a corruption case investigated by the federal police. Harris said the future of its ties with ARM depended on whether ARM had adopted corrupt means to get telecommunications equipment contracts from the government. Harris is governed by the US Federal Corrupt Practices Act. The Act forbids US companies from indulging in corrupt practices or being associated with corrupt companies worldwide.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>SOUTHERN PETRO'S GDR ISSUE WILL RAISE FOREIGN STAKE</p>
<p>Foreign investment in Southern Petrochemical Industries Corp (SPIC) may go up to 58 percent following its $60-million (global depositary receipt) GDR issue. The government recently cleared SPIC's $60-million GDR issue. The company already has 28 percent equity placed with foreign investors. Once the warrants of its $60 million GDR issue are converted into shares, the foreign investors' stake may double to 58 percent.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Financial Express</p>
<p>BOMBAY BOURSE INDEX UP 90 POINTS</p>
<p>The Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) sensitive index recovered 90 points to close above the 3400-mark. The BSE received good buying support from local and foreign institutional investors, said sources. The BSE-30 scrips index, opening at the previous level, moved upwards to close at 3406.22 points, up 2.7 percent. Top gainers included  Reliance which moved up by 14.75 rupees to close at 215.75 rupees. The total turnover on BSE was 1.57 billion rupees. The National Stock Exchange's 50-share index gained 22 points over the previous close of 977. The net traded value stood at 9.20 billion rupees.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>MICHELIN PLANS FULLY-OWNED TYRE UNIT</p>
<p>French tyre giant Michelin plans to set up a 100 percent owned manufacturing subsidiary in India. Michelin does not rule out forging ties with an Indian company at a later stage. The company plans to invest $60 million as equity and set up a manufacturing plant with an initial capacity to produce 20,000 tonnes of tyres per year.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>TRACTOR MAJORS WOO MAHINDRA &amp; MAHINDRA</p>
<p>World tractor majors are planning to enter India to tap a growing market and use it as a potential sourcing point for global markets. Leading players like US-based Agco, Kubota of Japan and Same of Italy are exploring tie ups with India's automobile giant, Mahindra &amp; Mahindra (M&amp;M). M&amp;M is currently negotiating with US-based Case for a possible joint venture to manufacture high horsepower tractors. Sources said M&amp;M had plans to become a global player by tying up with multinational corporations in various segments of tractor manufacturing and exports.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business Line</p>
<p>PRIVATE SECTOR ALLOWED TO SET UP AIR CARGO COMPLEXES</p>
<p>The government has decided  to permit the private sector to set up air cargo complexes to ensure smoother movement of export cargo dispatched by air. The government, in its first-ever policy on cargo complexes, plans to allow such facilities to be located outside airports. The policy will help establish more than one air cargo complex to route exports through a airport. The policy aims to introduce competition from the private sector and ensure improvement in quality of services provided by the state-run Airports Authority of India, which now enjoys virtual monopoly, sources said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>SEVEN COMMITTEES TO EXPLORE INSURANCE REVAMP</p>
<p>The Insurance Regulatory Authority (IRA) has constituted seven working groups to review and recommend changes in the existing administrative and legal framework on critical insurance-related areas. The groups will have to submit their reports by an August 31 deadline set by the insurance authority. The setting up of the working groups to advise the IRA is one of the initial steps taken by the regulator towards restructuring the insurance sector.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business Standard</p>
<p>RESERVE BANK REJECTS GE CAPITAL SUBSIDIARY PLANS</p>
<p>GE Capital India's plan to start two wholly-owned subsidiaries has run into rough weather. The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has refused to clear proposals from the US-based GE Capital's Indian affiliate to establish the subsidiaries. RBI said GE Capital had failed to meet the bank's entry-level requirements. GE Capital had planned to set up two wholly-owned subsidiaries, one for hire-purchase and lease financing activities and the other for bill discounting.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>REFINERY MAJOR EARMARKS 105-BLN RUPEE INVESTMENT</p>
<p>Country's second largest refining company, Hindustan Petroleum Corp (HPCL), plans to invest 105 billion rupees in various projects over the next six years. HPCL's plans in the joint sector include setting up two more refineries, developing liquefied petroleum gas infrastructure facilities and power projects. HPCL is tying up with Saudi Aramco Oil Company to set up a six million-tonne refinery in Punjab.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Observer</p>
<p>MINISTRY RULES OUT SHORT-TERM INCENTIVES FOR BOURSES</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry has ruled out taking short-term measures to rescue the stock market from the current slump. Instead, the government plans to focus on institutional strengthening of the capital market. Setting up of depositories and reforming the company laws are some of the steps the Finance Ministry plans to undertake. The ministry fears that the slump in the share prices may adversely affect the realisation of the government's disinvestment targets. The ministry is therefore exploring alternatives to divest through measures like direct public offerings or tapping of the international market.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
