<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9840" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka seeks to rebuild image, attract tourists.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka seeks to rebuild image, attract tourists.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lanka will launch a $4 million campaign to attract investors and tourists by stressing that a 13 year-long ethnic war has been largely limited to the country's north and east.</p>
<p>Media and Tourism Minister Dharmasiri Senanayake told a news conference on Thursday the government had to counter moves by separatist Tamil guerrillas to tarnish Sri Lanka's image.</p>
<p>&quot;Presently we suffer from a problem of disinformation,&quot; he said. &quot;These reports are exaggerated.&quot;</p>
<p>Tourist arrivals to the Indian Ocean island dropped by 39.6 percent in April from a year ago, the Ceylon Tourist Board said. Sri Lanka had 403,101 tourists last year.</p>
<p>The armed forces have battled the Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam since 1983 in a war largely contained in the north and east and away from attractions such as the southern beaches, the central hill country and the ancient kingdoms in the north-central region.</p>
<p>The rebels, however, have also hit economic targets. A suicide bomb attack on the Central Bank in Colombo in January killed almost 100 people.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
