<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9844" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Britain says death of its citizen will sour ties.</title>
<headline>Britain says death of its citizen will sour ties.</headline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A British minister expressed his government's official disquiet on Thursday at the recent death of a British citizen of Bangladeshi origin at Dhaka airport.</p>
<p>&quot;I have told Bangladesh leaders that British goverment has attached serious importance to the resolution of the tragic death of Siraj Mia,&quot; Under-Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs Liam Fox Fox, told reporters.</p>
<p>Siraj Mia died at Dhaka airport on May 9 during interogation by customs officials after arriving from London. His body bore multiple injuries, and his relatives complained that he was murdered.</p>
<p>A post-mortem report suggested he might have been tortured. But customs authorities said the passenger was drunk and died of loss of blood from a deep cut in his wrist after he hit a glass sheet.</p>
<p>Fox, who arrived in Bangladesh on Tuesday on four-day visit, said Britain wanted Dhaka to act seriously on the case.</p>
<p>&quot;This is one of the reasons of my visit here... this is an important issue in our relationship&quot;, said Fox, who is due to leave for Nepal on Friday.</p>
<p>Fox said the incident had strained relations between the two governments. He said the Mia's issue had been raised in the House of Commons.</p>
<p>Fox said he had brought up the issue at every meeting he had had with government leaders in Dhaka. He said the Bangladesh government had assured him it was taking the matter seriously.</p>
<p>&quot;The British government wants a thorough investigation and a just outcome,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Fox said the British government wanted an end to the alleged harassment of its nationals at Dhaka airport by customs officials.</p>
<p>Bangladesh's Criminal Investigation Department has charged two immigration officials in connection with Mia's killing.</p>
<p>Mia, a father of five children, had a restaurant business in a London suburb.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
