<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9846" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: S. Asian nations vow to end child labour by 2010.</title>
<headline>S. Asian nations vow to end child labour by 2010.</headline>
<byline>Tahir Ikram</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seven South Asian nations vowed on Thursday to eliminate all forms of child labour by the year 2010 and to end child labour in hazardous occupations 10 years earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;Child labour, in bondage or otherwise, working in hazardous occupations should be eliminated by the year 2000,&quot; said a resolution adopted by a ministerial conference of the South Asian Association of Regional Cooperation (SAARC) in Rawalpindi.</p>
<p>It also said: &quot;SAARC member states should eliminate the evil of child labour from the SAARC region by the year 2010.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman said the resolution was unanimously adopted by ministers from the organisation's member-countries -- Bangladesh, Bhutan, India, Maldives, Nepal, Pakistan and Sri Lanka.</p>
<p>The resolution will be go before the ninth SAARC summit next year at Male, capital of Maldives, for endorsement.</p>
<p>SAARC Secretary-General Naeem Hassan told a news conference that it was the first time the issue of child labour had been collectively taken up by the seven-nation group. &quot;There is a general agreement that something has to be done about the issue.&quot;</p>
<p>Pakistan's Social Welfare Minister Sher Afgan said: &quot;It is now the responsibility of the governments and the people of all our countries to help translate the commitments into reality.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;It is our responsibility to eradicate child labour. It is our duty to provide food, health, education and clothing to our children.&quot;</p>
<p>South Asian countries have come under international criticism and faced threats of trade sanctions over alleged use of child and bonded labour.</p>
<p>In July the U.S. House of Representatives unanimously passed an appropriations bill amendment to fund inspections of plants suspected of employing child labour in India and Pakistan.</p>
<p>India's Labour Ministry officials say some 18 million children are at work there instead of going to schools.</p>
<p>But children's-rights activists say more than 55 million poor children work in labour-intensive industries in India such as match-making, quarrying, tanning, bangle-making, firework-manufacturing and carpet-weaving.</p>
<p>The Human Rights Commission of Pakistan says 10 million children there work in brick kilns, farms, carpet factories, workshops and restaurants for the same hours as adults but much less pay.</p>
<p>Islamabad denies unofficial estimates of the child workforce and has ordered its own study, in collaboration with the International Labour Organisation, which is due to be issued in September.</p>
<p>The SAARC resolution contains a commitment to move towards universal access to and completion of primary education by the year 2000.</p>
<p>The conference also resolved to combat trafficking in children and to help victims of violence caused by prostitution and sexual exploitation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BHUTAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALDR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NEPAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
