<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9847" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India fears attempts to disrupt Kashmir polls.</title>
<headline>India fears attempts to disrupt Kashmir polls.</headline>
<dateline>SRINAGAR, India 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's Home (interior) Minister accused Pakistan on on Thursday of planning to disrupt state elections in troubled Jammu and Kashmir state.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems that from across the border there is going to be a planned attempt to disrupt the elections,&quot; Inderjit Gupta told reporters in the state capital Srinagar.</p>
<p>The local polls next month will be the first since 1987 in the state, clamped under direct rule from New Delhi since 1990.</p>
<p>India has often accused Pakistan of abetting militancy in the valley, a charge Islamabad has always denied.</p>
<p>Gupta said there might be an increase in the number of people infiltrating the Kashmir valley to create disturbance in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;We noticed among the people who come from across the border, there is a growing number of foreign mercenaries,&quot; Gupta said.</p>
<p>India and Pakistan have fought two of their three wars over the troubled region of Kashmir since independence from Britain in 1947.</p>
<p>Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's centre-left government hopes the elections will help restore normality and democratic rule in Jammu and Kashmir, where more than 20,000 people have died in insurgency-related violence since 1990.</p>
<p>Over a dozen militant groups are fighting New Delhi's rule in the state.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SRINAGAR, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
