<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9855" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan wants U.N. to keep Kashmir on agenda.</title>
<headline>Pakistan wants U.N. to keep Kashmir on agenda.</headline>
<byline>Raja Asghar</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan said on Thursday it was seeking to reverse a U.N. Security Council decision to delete some 50 items from its agenda, including its dispute with India over Kashmir.</p>
<p>A Foreign Ministry spokesman told reporters the Council's decision this month to delete these items from September 15 was for what he called the &quot;very frivolous reason&quot; that its agenda was overcrowded.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto's government has come under attack from political opponents who see the Council's move as a failure for Islamabad's foreign policy.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the Security Council had agreed to review the decision after vigorous efforts by Pakistan and other concerned countries.</p>
<p>Pakistan has approached the Council's permament members and Bhutto had sent them messages, he said.</p>
<p>The Arab group in the United Nations and several other countries had taken up the matter, while a ministerial contact group of the Organisation of Islamic Conference on Kashmir had decided to write to the Security Council, he said.</p>
<p>Kashmir has been on the Council agenda since 1949 when it ordered a ceasefire in the first India-Pakistan war there and later called for a plebiscite to decide its future.</p>
<p>India is fighting a separatist revolt in the two-thirds of Kashmir it rules.</p>
<p>Pakistan, which wants the dispute to be resolved by implementing the U.N.-mandated plebiscite, controls the remainder of the region, over which the two countries have fought two of their three wars since independence from Britain in 1947.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision of the Security Council is procedurally flawed, was taken without prior consultation in a closed meeting and without any regard to the merits or substantive aspects concerned,&quot; the Pakistani spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have made it clear that if this decision is not rescinded, it would have a serious bearing on the working and the future role of the Security Council under the charter of the United Nations.&quot;</p>
<p>Under the present Security Council decision, an item due to be deleted will remain on the agenda for one more year if a country complains against deletion before September 15.</p>
<p>But the spokesman said Pakistan, which wants Kashmir to remain on the agenda until the dispute is settled, wished to reinstate the issue as a matter of principle.</p>
<p>&quot;Because of these irregularities (in the Council decision) and because Kashmir issue has been alive all this time -- so many people have died -- it is not an issue which can be just brushed under the carpet just like that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>More than 20,000 people have died in insurgency-related violence in Indian part of Kashmir since early 1990, hospital and police sources say. Pakistan denies Indian charges that it is training and arming the Kashmiri militants seeking independence or union with Pakistan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
