<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9856" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Cotton rates close higher in India, Pakistan.</title>
<headline>Cotton rates close higher in India, Pakistan.</headline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cotton rates closed higher in India due to limited supplies and in Pakistan on reports of a virus attack, dealers said.</p>
<p>Prices of Punjab cotton varieties rose last week on limited supplies towards the end of the 1995/96 (September-August) season and renewed demand from mills while Gujarat cotton was quoted lower, dealers said.</p>
<p>In spot deals Punjab saw-ginned rose from 1,620/1,650 rupees to 1,675/1,700 rupees per maund (37.32 kg) while Bengal-deshi moved up from 860/890 rupees to 880/950 rupees per maund.</p>
<p>Gujarat Kalyan (medium-staple) slid to 11,800/12,000 rupees from 12,400/12,500 rupees per candy (355.56 kg), while wagad cotton fell by 500 rupees to 10,500 rupees per candy.</p>
<p>Meanwhile traders estimated the cotton crop during the 1995/96 season at around 15.90-16 million bales (170 kg each).</p>
<p>&quot;Initial crop estimates for 1996/1997 season are about 17 million bales,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall progress of rain in the producing centre up to now is satisfactory but everything depends on rainfall in September,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Scattered new crop arrivals of cotton have already started from southern states which will gradually rise in September and will pick in October,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In Pakistan, daily cotton rates closed higher on Thursday on reports of a leaf curl virus attack to the new crop in Multan, the country's main cotton growing area in central Pakistan, dealers said.</p>
<p>Rates, which were falling sharply in the last few days on expectations of a bumper crop, closed 55 rupees higher on Thursday, compared to Wednesday but lower compared to last week, dealer Amir Merchant said.</p>
<p>Rates rose after a report, confirmed by an official agency, that leaf curl virus had affected 30 to 40 percent of the 1996/97 (July-June) crop in Multan region, the dealers said.</p>
<p>Rates might go up if the report was true, said one broker as he referred to Pakistan Agricultural Research Council report from Multan about the virus attack.</p>
<p>Before the virus report, brokers were expecting that rates would fall to 2,300 rupees per maund, the broker said.</p>
<p>In the kerb market, the rate for 1996/97 NIAB-78 variety rose to 2,650 rupees per maund from 2,600, the broker said.</p>
<p>The private Karachi Cotton Association said exports had reached 1.82 million 375-lb bales by July 31 since the 1995/96 season began on September 1, 1995.</p>
<p>Dealers had registered 2.33 million bales for export with the state-run Export Promotion Bureau, the KCA said.</p>
<p>KCA's official spot rates in rupees per maund:</p>
<p>				     Thursday Wednesday August 15</p>
<p>    NIAB-78 (1996/97 crop)   2,618    2,563     2,755.50</p>
<p>    K-68    (1995/96 crop)   2,508    2,453     2,656.50</p>
<p>    MNH-93  (1995/96 crop)   2,563    2,508     2,706</p>
<p>-- Bombay Commodities +91-22-265 9000</p>
<p>($1 = 35.61 Pakistani rupees) -- Ibrahim Khan 9221-5685192</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
