<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9859" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: RBI sets base of $17 bln for 96/97 India reserves.</title>
<headline>RBI sets base of $17 bln for 96/97 India reserves.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign currency reserves should not fall below $17 billion and the 1996/97 (April-March) current account deficit should be contained within two percent of GDP, RBI governor Chakravarty Rangarajan said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The current account deficit should stay at around two percent of GDP and there should be no fiurther drop in the foreign currency reserves from the level reached at the beginning of the current fiscal year of $17 billion,&quot; he said in an adress to business leaders in New Delhi.</p>
<p>Rangarajan said the financing requirements during the year would be much larger than what was required to meet the current account deficit becasue of certain lumpy repayment obligations.</p>
<p>Repayment of India Development Bonds, outflows under maturing foreign currency deposits and repayment to the IMF would come to around $6.2 billion, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;While there will be some increase in the net commercial borrowings and under non-resident deposits over the past year, there has to be a substantial increase in the inflows in foreign investments, both direct and portfolio.&quot;</p>
<p>Rangarajan said reserves at $17 billion, would provide import cover of four months, internationally accepted as a desirable level.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
