<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9868" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian rice prices fall despite Chinese inquiries.</title>
<headline>Indian rice prices fall despite Chinese inquiries.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian rice traders have received inquiries from Chinese firms for imports but no deals have been finalised and export prices are falling on a lack of foreign demand, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Prem Garg, managing director of a leading Delhi foodgrain export company, said some Chinese firms had made inquiries for the import of about 50,000 tonnes of rice but no deals have been finalised. &quot;It is still in the negotiation stage,&quot; Garg said.</p>
<p>Analysts said they did not expect the Chinese sales to be consumated as China insists on quality checks at the port of delivery -- a condition not agreeable to India exporters.  </p>
<p>&quot;Rice exports to China are not likely to materialise as China insists on delivered weight and quality whereas India wants to deal in shipped weight and quality,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>They said Indian rice exporters are not prepared to wait for payment until consignments are discharged at the port of delivery. Shipments to China normally take about 40 days.</p>
<p>Export rice prices have dropped between $10-$15 a tonne in past two weeks due to a fall in foreign demand, traders said.</p>
<p>Indian five percent broken was quoted at around $300 a tonne FOB, 10 percent broken at $280, 15 percent broken at $255 and 25 percent broken at $240.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
