<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9870" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan has Sept option on 75,000 T Indian sugar.</title>
<headline>Pakistan has Sept option on 75,000 T Indian sugar.</headline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The state-run Trading Corporation of Pakistan (TCP) said on Thursday it had an option with an Indian firm to import 75,000 tonnes of crystal white sugar in September.</p>
<p>&quot;We have received confirmation from the Indian Sugar and General Industry (ISGI) that it would promptly ship 75,000 tonnes in September at $389 per tonne C&amp;F at TCP's request,&quot; a TCP official said.</p>
<p>The TCP has already booked 225,000 tonnes of sugar for delivery by August 31.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not sure at the moment if there will be a need for more imports as sugar mills earlier this month reported a stock of about 400,000 tonnes,&quot; the official said. &quot;But we want to have an arrangement in place in case of any contingency.&quot;</p>
<p>The Food and Agriculture Ministry had asked the TCP to import 225,000 tonnes by September to halt a rise in domestic prices and offset lower domestic output of 2.47 million tonnes in fiscal 1995/96 (July-June) against 3.0 million in 1994/95.</p>
<p>TCP has bought a total of 175,000 tonnes from ISGI, 25,000 tonnes from a Turkish firm and another 25,000 tonnes from a Brazilian firm. All of it is due to reach Pakistan by August 31.  </p>
<p>The TCP official said a consigment of 12,000 tonnes of white sugar from India bought by a private firm at $394 per tonne C&amp;F was likely to reach Karachi port in the next few days.</p>
<p>He dismissed local newspaper reports that private firms planned to import about 100,000 tonnes from Brazil and Thailand, saying India was offering much cheaper rates and shipments from those countries could not reach Pakistan before October, when the domestic cane-crushing season normally starts.</p>
<p>The private Pakistan Sugar Mills Association (PSMA) said mills had stocks of about 300,000 tonnes on August 15.</p>
<p>&quot;With estimated consumption of 250,000 tonnes per month we have estimated a shortage of about 100,000 tonnes by October 15,&quot; PSMA secretary-general Ali Qazilbash told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said even when the crushing season gets under way there would be a shortage of about 200,000 tonnes by November.</p>
<p>He said TCP imports of 225,000 tonnes were unlikely to reduce local prices because there were no carryover stocks this year, compared to last year's 400,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>The official said that a decision on further imports would be taken after sugar already purchased reached Pakistan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
