<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9872" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistani IRRI-6 rice prices rise on Oman buying.</title>
<headline>Pakistani IRRI-6 rice prices rise on Oman buying.</headline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistani rice IRRI-6 variety export prices rose slightly on demand from Oman but Basmati variety fell because of dwindling sales abroad, dealers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Prices were mixed in the past week.</p>
<p>Oman has tendered for 6,000 tonnes of IRRI-6 rice for shipment in September, a dealer said. The tender will open on September 7.</p>
<p>IRRI-6 prices rose to $290 per tonne FOB in the past week from $280 a week earlier, the dealer said.</p>
<p>One official of the state-run Rice Export Corporation of Pakistan said Basmati prices fell because of low demand from abroad. Demand will rise on arrival of the new crop in October.</p>
<p>A three-member Japanese team, led by Kazumi-Koga, has shown interest in buying at least 500 tonnes of super Basmati variety rice in October or November, dealers said.</p>
<p>The team plans to introduce super Basmati at American food restaurants in Japan, they said. Japan imported 112 tonnes of Basmati rice in the past year.</p>
<p>Prices of IRRI-6 rice were likely to fall as the new crop would reach the market in September, a month earlier than Basmati crop, Khalid Ghori of Matco Rice Processing said.  </p>
<p>Exports in 1995/96 (July-June) fell 26.21 percent to 1.366 million tonnes worth $450 million, from 1.852 million worth $454 million in 1994/95.</p>
<p>Following are exporters FOB rates per tonne:</p>
<p>					    August 22     August 15</p>
<p>    Basmati				  $515	    $540</p>
<p>    IRRI-6				   $290	    $280</p>
<p>Prices in the domestic markets in rupees per 100 kg:</p>
<p>					     August 22     August 15</p>
<p>    Basmati (old)		     1,650/1,850   1,650/1,850</p>
<p>    Basmati (new)		     1,500/1,675   1,500/1,675</p>
<p>    IRRI-6				  825/850	 825/850</p>
<p>($1 = 35.61 rupees)</p>
<p>-- Ibrahim Khan 9221-5685192</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
