<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9894" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ share market rises 1.1 pct, hits 10-month high.</title>
<headline>NZ share market rises 1.1 pct, hits 10-month high.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>* NZ share market touches 10-month high, ends 1.1 pct up</p>
<p>* Fletcher Forests, Brierley gain after Forestry Corp news</p>
<p>* Demand generally strong, buoyed from offshore</p>
<p>---------------------------(Aug 22)---------------------------</p>
<p>Price movements at close</p>
<p>	    LAST CHG</p>
<p>  144  +3   * NZSE-40 cap index +23.78 at 2,199.53</p>
<p>  320  +3   * NZSC cap index +10.94 at 4,379.50</p>
<p>  286  nil  * NZSE-10 cap index +13.11 at 1,110.73</p>
<p>  373  nil  * Volume NZ$79.5 million. Futures +5 at 1,117</p>
<p>  682  +8   * Other movers - +8 +11</p>
<p>The New Zealand share market closed 1.1 percent higher on Thursday, having risen in the early afternoon to a 10-month high.</p>
<p>Brokers said the catalyst for the rise was feedback from the government's sale on Tuesday of Forestry Corp of New Zealand.</p>
<p>Two of the day's star performers were Fletcher Forests and Brierley Investments, the two New Zealand companies in the consortium which purchased FCNZ with China's Citic for $2.0 billion. BIL closed three cents up at $1.44 and Fletcher nine cents up at $1.95.  </p>
<p>&quot;There was a lot of offshore demand,&quot; said J.B. Were's Luke Koekoek. &quot;It's encouraging and I would have thought there was more upside in the short-term.&quot;</p>
<p>The benchmark NZSE-40 capital index closed 23.78 higher at 2,199.53 but peaked at 2,207.47, its highest since October 20 last year.</p>
<p>The focus of the market was on the leaders, with Telecom continuing its strong performance since last week's first quarter result, up eight to $6.82, and Carter Holt Harvey up three to $3.20.  </p>
<p>Notable laggard among the leaders was Fletcher Paper, steady on $2.86. Brokers said there is stock overhanging it.</p>
<p>Koekoek said it appeared that foreign investors were taking a general view of the New Zealand market.</p>
<p>&quot;It was not interest rate-driven at all today. Some of these guys are just taking a New Zealand view rather than stock-specific. Most of the gains are in the heavily weighted stocks, with Fletcher Paper the exception.&quot;</p>
<p>He said worries about the October 12 general election had dissipated. &quot;We have underperformed for such a long a time... people are taking the view that the worst is factored in.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
