<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9895" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia's new IR laws seen up in early 1997.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia's new IR laws seen up in early 1997.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Industrial Relations (IR) minister Peter Reith said the government's proposed IR reforms could be in place by early next year, after the release of a Senate Committee report on the bills on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Senate majority report proposed amendments to the bill, but Reith said this did not surprise him as the committee had been dominated by Labor Party Senators who oppose the reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;But irrespective of the majority report, I remain hopeful that the outcome of negotiations with the Democrats will be the passage of the bill and a new industrial relations system in the New Year,&quot; Reith said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The committee chairwoman, Labor Senator Jacinta Collins, said the inquiry had found workers would be worse off under the government's plan to change the industrial relations system.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall the findings in most areas would mean workers would be worse off,&quot; Collins told Reuters.</p>
<p>Later Reith told reporters that the committee had been Labor Party dominated and trade union orchestrated -- they were &quot;just using the Senate Committee for their own political purposes.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The fact is that, as we speak now already, this majority committee's report is dead, dead in the water,&quot; Reith said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The bill is going to pass, and we look forward to sensible discussions about the amendments.&quot;</p>
<p>Reith said negotiations would continue with the minority Democrat senators, who can provide the government with the votes it needs to pass the legislation in the upper house.</p>
<p>Democrats industrial relations spokesman Andrew Murray said they would reject some proposals and make sure that employers and employees needed to bargain fairly at an enterprise level.</p>
<p>But Murray said there was room for negotiation between both the Federal government and the Democrats.  </p>
<p>The Democrats were also prepared to support the thrust of new unfair dismissal laws, the establishment of an official employment advocate, ending union closed shops and preference clauses and quickening the pace of award system modernisation, he said.</p>
<p>Reith declined to nominate any areas of the legislation that he may be more inclined to amend to ensure passage, which he expected to occur in coming months.</p>
<p>&quot;The lines will be drawn when when the thing hits the Senate,&quot; Reith said.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
