<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9899" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Korea meat win Australia's biggest since 1994.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Korea meat win Australia's biggest since 1994.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's winning of the full grassfed section of the latest South Korean meat import tender gave it its largest tender award since October 1994, the Australian Meat and Livestock Corp (AMLC) said.</p>
<p>Gross prices obtained for grassfed quarter beef were up an average 14 cents per kg on an Australian currency free alongside (ACFAS) basis compared with the previous Livestock Products Marketing Organisation (LPMO) tender, held July 16, AMLC said.</p>
<p>Successful tender prices for grassfed fullsets were 298 cents per kg (360 tonnes), 292 cents per kg (360 tonnes) and 288 cents per kg (288 tonnes), on an ACFAS basis.  </p>
<p>Prices for grassfed quarter beef were 184 cents per kg (1,600 tonnes), 180 cents per kg (1,600 tonnes) and 175 cents per kg (800 tonnes), AMLC said.</p>
<p>Prices vary according to slaughter and shipping dates, with higher prices for closer dates.</p>
<p>Prices for grassfed fullset were similar to the previous fullset tender held in April, AMLC said.</p>
<p>&quot;The tender reflected widespread interest from Australian exporters, particularly at a time when other markets remain sluggish. Exporters from all three eastern (Australian) states featured in the results,&quot; AMLC said.</p>
<p>New Zealand was less competitive in this tender because of its reduced seasonal supply situation, it said.</p>
<p>The tender, for a total of 9,200 tonnes, included 4,000 tonnes of grassfed quarter beef, 1,008 tonnes of grassfed fullsets and 4,192 tonnes of boneless grainfed cuts. The U.S. won the grainfed section at unknown prices, AMLC said.</p>
<p>LPMO has now purchased 79,946 tonnes (boneless equivalent) which represents 91 percent of its 1996 quota, it said.</p>
<p>A further tender can be expected in September for LPMO to fulfil its minimum quota commitment of 88,200 tonnes, it said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
