<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9901" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Shell refinery operators to return to work.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Shell refinery operators to return to work.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shell Australia Ltd's striking refinery operators voted on Thursday to return to work at the 115,000 barrels-per-day (bpd) plant near Melbourne on Friday, a trade union official said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The members have voted to return to work at 7 p.m. (0900 GMT) tomorrow,&quot; Australian Workers' Union (AWU) negotiator Sam Wood said after the vote on Thursday afternoon.</p>
<p>Picket lines on the refinery's ocean tanker and LPG distribution facilities have been lifted, he said.</p>
<p>The 240 or so striking operators walked off the job on August 13 after shutting down the refinery, at Geelong southwest of Melbourne, in a dispute over wage practices.</p>
<p>The AWU had refused a Shell request for the operators to perform extra maintenance duties as part of a new wage deal.  </p>
<p>But the union and the company reached a compromise in talks held earlier on Thursday, Wood told Reuters.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, a limit has been put on the amount of time operators can spend performing maintenance tasks, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Only 20 percent of their time as an operatore could be spent on doing maintenance-type activities,&quot; he added. &quot;With those protections in there, we are now satisfied that our concerns are being addressed.&quot;</p>
<p>The refinery has been operating at partial production since late last week. Using non-union labour, Shell brought the refinery to around one third of normal output by this week.  </p>
<p>Shell welcomed the decision to return to work and said the agreement was consistent with the company's aim of keeping the refinery on an internationally competitive footing.</p>
<p>&quot;This has been a difficult dispute but there is now a genuine commitment to build a sound relationship for the future,&quot; Shell spokesman Warren Stooke said in a statement.</p>
<p>He did not say when the refinery might return to full capacity.</p>
<p>-- Melbourne bureau 613-9286-1421</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
