<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9913" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian dlr fades as samurai fails to show.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian dlr fades as samurai fails to show.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar drifted to a flat close Thursday as early buying enthusiasm faded when a much anticipated samurai issue failed to materialise.</p>
<p>Dealers said the dollar had been bid up toward US$0.7930 this morning as some samurai-linked demand appeared and talk swirled a big dual currency bond from IBM was on the way. A strong set of domestic business investment data bolstered the bullish sentiment, as did a fairly upbeat economic outlook from the Reserve Bank.</p>
<p>Profit-taking set in when the samurai failed to show, but traders expected US$0.7890 support to provide a solid floor.  </p>
<p>By 5.00 pm (0700 GMT) the local dollar had faded to US$0.7906/11 from an early US$0.7923/28 high, but was in line with Wednesday's US$0.7909/14 finish.</p>
<p>Further support was seen at US$0.7850 and key resistance was pegged at US$0.7935. The latter was expected to be a tough barrier, but the importance of a break would be all the greater and could see the currency re-test its July peak of 80 cents.</p>
<p>On the crosses, it nudged to 85.72/82 yen from 85.64/74 but idled at 1.1732/43 marks from 1.1736/47 as firmer than expected German economic data cast doubt on speculation the Bundesbank would trim its repo rate at today's council meeting.  </p>
<p>Analysts reckoned there was still a good chance the Bundesbank would trim 5-10 basis points off its 3.30 percent repurchase rate, which would confirm the bank was back in easing mode and widen the local dollar's yield advantage on the mark.</p>
<p>The prospects of another Australian easing were also much on the market's mind and again seemed pretty well balanced.</p>
<p>Today's report of a huge 16.0 percent rise in private capital expenditure in the June quarter -- that was eight times larger than the median forecast -- tended to lean against another cut, although analysts said the figures were rather historical given that Q2 GDP data had already been released.  </p>
<p>The third estimate for CAPEX in 1996/97 rose 9.7 percent to A$39.48 billion, which was 15.4 percent higher than the estimate for 1995/96, and made the government's forecast of a 14 percent investment rise look a little less like wishful thinking.</p>
<p>However, John Peters, a senior economist at Westpac, noted that if the five year average realisation ratio of business investment expectations was applied to the data it suggested investment was likely to grow by around 10 percent in 1996/97.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, we believe that moderating economic growth and further waning inflation and wage pressures will pave the way for another 0.50 point easing in the December quarter,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>An economic outlook in the Reserve Bank's annual report today offered nothing to contradict that view.</p>
<p>The bank said it expected growth to continue at a modest pace in 1996/97 and underlying inflation should remain in its 2-3 percent target band through the year.</p>
<p>Analysts noted the central bank emphasised the benefit of the dollar's appreciation in holding down inflation and expected the currency to contain consumer prices over the second half of 1996 and beyond. That in turn suggested the RBA had a bullish outlook for the currency and was comfortable with that prospect, they said.  </p>
<p>The only remaining domestic data are new motor vehicle registrations for July on Friday. Median foercasts are for a fall of around 10.0 percent in a correction from June's unexpectedly strong 18.5 percent jump.</p>
<p>Next week has a full schedule, which includes quarterly inventories, foreign debt and net exports, along with current account, retail trade and building approvals figures for July.</p>
<p>In trade weighted terms the local dollar was steady at 58.0.</p>
<p>-- Wayne Cole 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
