<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9917" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-WMC says to sell petroleum assets.</title>
<headline>RTRS-WMC says to sell petroleum assets.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold and nickel miner WMC Ltd said on Thursday it has decided to sell all its petroleum assets, excluding its share in the Goldfields gas transmission pipeline of Western Australia.  </p>
<p>The assets comprise operations in the United States, Western Australia and New Zealand, the company said.</p>
<p>WMC said that while its petroleum division has good strategic assests and skills, the requirement for exploration funds and capital at a time of major expansions of other projects led to the decision to sell, WMC said.</p>
<p>WMC said it intends to sell the businesses in Australasia and the U.S. as going concerns.  </p>
<p>WMC said it will retain its majority ownership of the 1,380 km Goldfields gas transmission pipeline, which is nearing completion.</p>
<p>The pipeline is designed to carry natural gas from the North-West coast of Australia through the middle of Western Australia state to supply mining operations.</p>
<p>&quot;The pipeline is still in development and we want to ensure it delivers the planned lower costs and cleaner energy that our nickel and gold operations need to continue to be competitive,&quot; the company said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the petroleum division was on track to earn about A$30 million in operating profits in 1996.</p>
<p>WMC has been focusing on building its metals businesses recently, with expansions planned for nickel, gold, uranium and copper in Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it will come as much of a surprise to the market,&quot; an analyst for an investment bank said.</p>
<p>&quot;Most people would agree that over the years that they've been rather dissapointing,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Australasian petroleum output in the fourth quarter was 399,056 barrels for a full-year result of 1.97 million barrels, down from 2.67 million barrels in 1994/95, the company said in its most recent production report.</p>
<p>WMC largely blamed the drop in full-year petroleum output on a continuing decline in production from its mature Western Australian fields.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
