<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9918" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Direct selling key to growth - Ashton.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Direct selling key to growth - Ashton.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian diamond miner Ashton Mining Ltd said on Thursday the world diamond market looked good for the company, but further strong earnings growth would depend on its ability to market its own diamonds.</p>
<p>Ashton chief executive John Robinson said the market showed encouraging signs of expansion, citing expectations of continued strong growth in the world jewellery market and the prospect of higher prices for diamonds over one carat for the rest of 1996.  </p>
<p>But asked if Ashton was likely to post strong profit growth for 1996, he said this relied on the success of Ashton's recent divorce from the Central Selling Organisation (CSO) diamond cartel operated by De Beers Consolidated Mines Ltd.</p>
<p>Earlier on Thursday, Ashton announced a 29 percent jump in interim profit to A$12.4 million for the six months to June 30, compared with the 1995 first-half.</p>
<p>Sales rose 23 percent to A$114.8 million.</p>
<p>Ashton, which expects to produce a total of about 38 million carats in 1996, sold most of its production to the CSO under a contract that ended on June 30.  </p>
<p>After failing to negotiate a new deal, Ashton said in June it would market its stones directly.</p>
<p>&quot;The market in which we operate is looking good but our ability to tap the strength of the market will be very much a function of how successful we are in getting out direct marketing operations up and running,&quot; Robinson told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously there are a lot of factors, including the extent to which the CSO becomes super competitive in the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Ashton owns 40.1 percent of the world's biggest diamond mine, the open-cut Argyle mine in Western Australia, which produces 40 million carats annually.  </p>
<p>Minerals house RTZ Plc-CRA Ltd owns the rest.</p>
<p>-- Melbourne bureau 613-9286-1421</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
