<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9920" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-RBA 95/96 net earnings rise to A$2.486 bln.</title>
<headline>RTRS-RBA 95/96 net earnings rise to A$2.486 bln.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Reserve Bank of Australia (RBA) said it made a net operating earnings of A$2.486 billion in 1995/96, up from A$1.772 billion the year before.</p>
<p>Underlying earnings, which reflect the margin between interest earned on assets and interest paid on liabilities less operating expenses, rose to A$1.784 billion from A$1.649 billion in 1994/95, the RBA said in its anual report.</p>
<p>Capital gains, and losses, on the bank's holdings of securities and foreign exchange resulted in a profit of A$702 million compared to a A$123 million gain the year before.  </p>
<p>The RBA said net profits, after accounting for a transfer of A$100 million to Reserves, amounted to A$2.386 billion up from A$1.772 billion in 1995/96.</p>
<p>A further A$50 million was transfered the the RAB Reserve Fund leaving A$2.336 billion payable to the government. An initial payment of A$200 million was made in June 1996 and the balance will be paid in August 1996.</p>
<p>The bank's balance sheet fell by A$900 million to A$36.0 billion, it said.</p>
<p>The bank said its holdings of gold totalled approximately 250 tonnes at end June, worth around A$3.8 billion.  </p>
<p>Gold lending activities continued to expand during the year, with the amount of gold on loan rising to 114 tonnes from 64 and the number of counterparties involved rising to 14 from 12, the RBA said.</p>
<p>Earnings on gold loans amounted to A$20.6 million in 1995/96, a rise of A$14.6 million, reflecting both the increased quantity and a significant increase in margins over much of the year, the bank said.</p>
<p>The RBA said active mangement of its foreign exchange protfolio produced added profits of A$40 million.  </p>
<p>The bank said it had been overweight of U.S. dollars against the mark and the yen for much of the year and for part of the year with an overweight position in German assets.</p>
<p>The RBA said it had made substantial purchases of foreign exchange over 1995/96, partly to cover the needs of the government for which it bought the equivalent of A$4.9 billion.</p>
<p>It also undertook purchases on its own account which were not intended to influence the A$ but to facilitate a run-off of outstanding swaps accumulated in 1992/93 when it intervened to protect the dollar. By June 1996, the oversold swap position had been cut to A$5.4 billion from A$8.8 billion a year earlier.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
