<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9922" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-St George calm about insurance move.</title>
<headline>RTRS-St George calm about insurance move.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>St George Bank Ltd said it did not expect to write large amounts of business during the establishment phase of its foray into the life insurance sector.</p>
<p>The regional bank's chief financial officer, Steve McKerihan, said the move into insurance from some time in the first half of 1997 would allow St George to gain more revenue from its existing customer base, already offered life insurance at each branch from Sun Alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not going to be in that order for some considerable time,&quot; he told Reuters, when asked if the bank could write hundreds of millions of dollars of business in the early days.  </p>
<p>&quot;Obviously it is going to take some time to build up. So I certainly would be wrong to say that the volumes would be anything like the hundreds of millions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>St George considered the acquisition of an established insurance company and had focussed on one company but pulled out before proceeding with a due diligence investigation.</p>
<p>McKerihan said an acquisition would have meant St George would be paying unnecessarily for a customer base and a distribution network. The move into the life insurance sector was complementary to the bank's expansion plans, which remained strong despite the rejection by Metway Bank Ltd.  </p>
<p>Brisbane-based Metway decided earlier this year to form a A$21 billion Queensland &quot;bancassurance&quot; group led by the state government rather than merge with St George. The merger would have given A$18 billion St George another A$4 billion in assets and made it safer from takeover, in particular from major shareholder National Australia Bank Ltd.</p>
<p>McKerihan said St George still wanted to achieve growth through internal expansion and acquisitions. &quot;We have to acknowledge that the opportunities for acquisition are limited,&quot; he said, referring to the dwindling number of non-major banks that remain independent. - Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
