<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9924" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Wool market prospects still positive - WI.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Wool market prospects still positive - WI.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The wool market outlook for 1996/97 continues to hold prospects of improved demand, particularly in the second half of the season, Australian statutory authority Wool International (WI) said.</p>
<p>There was also the prospect of a significant increase in trade clearances, it said in its Insight publication.</p>
<p>Economic growth forecasts and wool textile conditions in the Pacific region were strengthening, but economic, retail and wool business conditions in Western Europe were a concern, it said.  </p>
<p>Trade clearances of Australian wool were projected to rise by 18 percent in 1996/97 and apparel wool availability from the world's major wool exporters by nine percent, it said.</p>
<p>WI also said that at August 2 its September quarter sales totalled 158,957 bales or 87 percent of the 182,000 minimum legislated sales requirement.</p>
<p>The grower stockpile of greasy wool continued to be a major supply factor for 1996/97, it said.</p>
<p>At June 30, wool held in brokers' stores totalled 659,331 bales, about 368,000 bales higher than at the end of the 1994/95 season, it said.  </p>
<p>It was also about 2.5 times the average end-of-season level of the previous four years, it said.</p>
<p>Stocks held on farm were currently estimated to be about 226,000 bales.</p>
<p>Total grower stocks in store and on farm was estimated to be about 885,000 bales or 157 million kgs at the end of June, 81 million kg higher than a year ago, it said.</p>
<p>WI's own stockpile is now about 2.18 million bales.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
