<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9929" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Big Australian retailers face identity crisis.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Big Australian retailers face identity crisis.</headline>
<byline>James Regan</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>In an identity crisis of sorts, Australia's largest grocery retailer, Woolworths Ltd, wants to become more like a petrol (gasoline) station.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the nation's biggest petrol station chain, Australian Petroleum Ltd (Ampol), wants to be more like a grocer.</p>
<p>It's all about roping in customers.</p>
<p>Both companies are feeling the impact of higher costs, which are hitting the bottom line.  </p>
<p>Woolworths on Wednesday reported a steady profit in tough trading in 1995/96 of A$233.6 million, well down on the previous year's growth rates.</p>
<p>Profits of Ampol's 50 percent owner, Caltex Australia Ltd, although up nearly three-fold to A$30.31 million in 1995/96, still were constrained by high crude oil prices, the company said on Wednesday. Ampol's other owner is building products group, Pioneer International Ltd.</p>
<p>Ampol said margins on gasoline sales are too small on their own, so why not sell newspapers, pizza, milk and over-the-counter medications to boost revenues.  </p>
<p>In current conditions petrol stations earn only about one cent per litre after tax on petrol sales as opposed to often hefty premiums on grocery and convenience items.</p>
<p>Woolworth's says shoppers regularly fill up in supermarket parking lots in Europe and the United States and predicts they will do the same in Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;We announce today that Woolworths will embark upon the retailing of petrol,&quot; Woolworths managing director Reg Clairs told a news conference in Sydney on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Not surprisingly, Ampol thinks its idea is better.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think if you're modelling Europe and projecting whether or not those market conditions could eventuate in Australia, I think it's very unlikely,&quot; Ian Blackburne, managing director of Ampol said.</p>
<p>Blackburne said established pipeline systems for distributing petrol easily in Europe do not exist in Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;Somebody that is going to participate in petrol retailing has got to go through the mechanics of importing, of terminalling and of distribution,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Woolworths obviously see things differently and will spend A$4.5 million initially to build its first station in rural Dubbo, New South Wales, by October to get the ball rolling.</p>
<p>The outlet would be the first of many and up to half the 1,031 Woolworths stores in Australia could have petrol stations in their carparks in the next few year</p>
<p>For its part, Ampol is moving deeper into offering non-petroleum products and services at its retail stations.</p>
<p>It is in the process of extending trials into convenience retailing to a further 20 sites, Blackburne said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We've introduced new consumer offerings with 'Pizza Haven' and 'Muffin Break,' Blackburne said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
