<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9931" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ's ECNZ write-up to have no price impact - CFO.</title>
<headline>NZ's ECNZ write-up to have no price impact - CFO.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A $655 million revaluation of the Electricity Corporation's assets announced today will not be a driver in future power price rises, ECNZ chief financial officer Arun Amarsi told NZPA on Thursday.</p>
<p>The revaluation, which will lift the corporation's value to $3.3 billion, was disclosed in a commentary on the company by international ratings agency Moody's Investor Services.</p>
<p>ECNZ is currently tendering long-term power supply contracts with average reserve prices rising at 1.18 percent annually.</p>
<p>Mr Amarsi said that although those reserve prices figured in the sales assumptions underlying the valuation, they were not a big driver.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no price rise implications in that (valuation),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Amarsi said the revaluation, based on discounted future cashflows, was the first since 1987-88 and was really a catch-up to the company's existing cash-flows.</p>
<p>By increasing the value of the business, the Government's percentage returns on its equity would fall to a more reasonable level, he said.</p>
<p>ECNZ said it was likely to pay a special dividend to the Government in March as a result of the revaluation.</p>
<p>Amarsi declined to estimate the size of that dividend saying it was a board decision that would depend on the level of interest-bearing debt the company was carrying.</p>
<p>Moody's said the Government was likely to use a high dividend payout ratio and special one-off dividends to maintain a debt-to-total-capitalisation ratio of 40 percent.  </p>
<p>ECNZ expects to fund a $200 million, four-year upgrade of its Manapouri power station from retained earnings and existing credit lines, but Amarsi said the board might yet want to consider further capital expenditure.</p>
<p>ECNZ was split in two in February, with Contact Energy acquiring the other $1.6 billion in assets.</p>
<p>Contact Energy communications manager Bruce Thompson said the company was also revaluing its assets, but not for credit-rating purposes.  </p>
<p>Having received the power stations at book value, Contact considered a revaluation &quot;prudent&quot; and expected to publish those details in its first annual report.</p>
<p>Although the value of Contact's Clyde and Roxburgh hydro stations were likely to have increased, one industry observer said a downward valuation was possible for Contact.</p>
<p>It had a greater exposure to more expensive thermal generation and some of those stations were operating below installed capacity, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Don't assume that it would revalue up,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>In June Contact announced staff cuts at its thermal plants and in July announced plans to spend about $350 million building a new gas-fired power station at either Otahuhu or New Plymouth.-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
