<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9936" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Prices firm at Christchurch wool sale.</title>
<headline>Prices firm at Christchurch wool sale.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wool prices rose across the board at the sale in Christchurch on Thursday, Wools of New Zealand said.</p>
<p>Medium segment prices were up 10 cents at 510 cents while strong segment prices were up three cents to 444 cents and the market indicator rose two cents to 472 cents.</p>
<p>The total offering was 1078 clean tonnes comprising 10 percent halfbred fleece, two percent merino, 54 percent crossbred, seven percent second shear, nine percent bulky skirtings eight percent crutchings and three percent second shear bellies and pieces, with the balance in miscellaneous  </p>
<p>wools.</p>
<p>Twenty percent was passed in after failing to meet growers' reserve prices.</p>
<p>Compared with the August 15 Christchurch sale, merino fleece was slightly dearer. Halfbred 24 to 26 microns was unchanged while the remainder was up to 1.5 percent dearer. Crossbred fleece was 1.5 percent dearer on 33 to 35 micron and up to one percent dearer on 36 micron and stronger.</p>
<p>Bulky skirts and second shear bellies and pieces were up to 2.5 percent and five percent higher respectively and crutchings were slightly dearer.  </p>
<p>Main interest came from Western Europe, Iran, Turkey, India and Australia with limited support from China and local mills.</p>
<p>The next sale is in Christchurch on August 29.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
