<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9940" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Ridley to buy half of NZ salt group.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Ridley to buy half of NZ salt group.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Food group Ridley Corp Ltd said on Thursday it would buy 50 percent of New Zealand's Dominion Salt group from the Skellerup Group Ltd for NZ$36 million.  </p>
<p>&quot;The acquisition is being settled using debt funds with a down payment of just under NZ$6 million and a final payment of NZ$30 million due by year end,&quot; Ridley said.</p>
<p>&quot;The investment is expected to have returns similar to those realised from Ridley's joint venture investments in Salpak Pty Ltd and Western Salt refinery,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The acquisition involved the purchase of shares owned by Skellerup in three businesses, in which Skellerup was a joint venture partner with Cerebos Greggs Ltd, a subdidiary of Cerebos Pacific Ltd.  </p>
<p>The businesses involved were Dominion Salt Ltd, Dominion Salt (NL) Ltd and Cerebos Skellerup Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;For Ridley the purchase creates a new business relationship in New Zealand between itself and the Cerebos group,&quot; Ridley said, adding the two companies had successfully operated the Salpak Australian joint venture for the past 34 years.</p>
<p>&quot;The Dominion Salt business includes a salt field and refinery at Lake Grassmere near Blenheim in the South Island, a refinery at Mt Maunganui near Tauranga in the North Island as well as packaging, distribution and marketing operations,&quot; Ridley said.  </p>
<p>Dominion had annual sales of about 120,000 tonnes of salt, producing half of that in New Zealand and importing the rest from Ridley's Cheetham Salt business in Australia.</p>
<p>Ridley chief executive Gary Busenshut said the acquisition represented a logical geographic expansion of Ridley's salt interests into an established market with similar to Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;Dominion is a very sound business operating in a viable market which will deliver attractive returns,&quot; Busenshut said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Additionally, we believe there will be opportunities to explore operating synergies between Dominion and Cheetham in areas such as technology, processing, marketing and packaging,&quot; Busenshut said.</p>
<p>Ridley's share price was steady at A$1.60 at 3.50 pm (0550 GMT).</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
