<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9950" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-St George to establish insurance arm.</title>
<headline>RTRS-St George to establish insurance arm.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>St George Bank Ltd said on Thursday its St George Investment Services Ltd unit would apply for registration as a life insurance company.</p>
<p>The regional bank said earlier in 1996 that it was keen to establish an insurance arm and would consider external acquisitions or an internal start-up.  </p>
<p>The bank said it would initially offer products covering life protection, term life, trauma and disability cover.</p>
<p>It said it did not plan to introduce general insurance products and these would continue to be provided through an agency agreement with the Sun Alliance Group.</p>
<p>Insurance operations should begin in the first half of 1997, St George said.</p>
<p>Managing director Jim Sweeney said the decision was &quot;consistent with the bank's previously indicated intention to investigate opportunities to enter this market&quot;.  </p>
<p>&quot;By developing our own products we also protect the strength and integrity of the St George brand,&quot; Sweeney said.</p>
<p>&quot;By starting our own insurance business, we can enter the market in areas where we have a distinct advantage without having to fund the purchase of a broader insurance operation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>St George Bank shares were four cents lower at A$8.36 at 2.30 p.m. (0430 GMT).</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
