<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9953" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Greens to try to block some cuts.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Greens to try to block some cuts.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The minority Australian Greens said on Thursday they will try to block in the upper house of parliament social security cuts in the 1996/97 Federal budget handed down on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Greens Senators (Bob) Brown and (Dee) Margetts will move to block the government's harsh social security cuts in the Senate by opposing legislated changes to the Social Security Act (1991) needed to implement key parts of the government's budget,&quot; they said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The Greens said they would oppose budget measures valued at A$249 million in the fiscal year to June 1998, their first full year of operation:</p>
<p>--Making migrants wait longer for social security, which will save A$140 million</p>
<p>--Cutting rent assistance, worth A$33 million in 1997/98;</p>
<p>--Tightening entitlements where beneficiaries have been working part-time, A$76 million in 1997/98.</p>
<p>The value of another opposed measure, cutting fraudulent claimants' benefits for 13 weeks, was unclear.  </p>
<p>The Liberal-National government, which will need legislation for some of the deficit-slashing budget it announced on Tuesday, is two votes short of a majority in the Senate, the upper house of parliament.</p>
<p>Assuming the Labor opposition votes against a measure, the two votes can come from the seven Australian Democrats, either of the two Greens, who might not always vote together, or from either of two Independents, Brian Harradine and Labor defector Mal Colston.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
