<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9955" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian meat seen uncompetitive in Japan.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian meat seen uncompetitive in Japan.</headline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Japanese meat distributor on Thursday said the Australian industry should urgently re-examine its beef market strategy for Japan, saying Australian producers currently cannot compete against U.S. grain fed beef.</p>
<p>In a speech to be delivered later on Thursday to an Australian Meat Council (AMC) conference, Takatoshi Miyamoto, president of distributors Ryochiku Inc, wholly owned by Mitsubishi Corp, said a sharp drop in Japanese demand for beef had followed the British mad cow disease scare in May.</p>
<p>This had led Mitsubishi to suspend its feedlot operations in Australia, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;As a private company we cannot justify continuing at the huge losses we are experiencing in the current market, where demand is uncertain and we cannot compete cost-wise against U.S. beef,&quot; Miyamoto said.</p>
<p>Miyamoto said beef sales to Japan had been further severely damaged with the outbreak of the E.Coli bacteria in Japan, which produced a 30-40 percent drop in sales of beef products such as yakiniku and steak cuts.</p>
<p>&quot;The E.Coli problem should be short-term only but there is no doubt it has made a deep impression on consumer awareness as to the quality of sanitation of meat products,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Miyamoto said the U.S. meat industry had quickly moved to reassure Japanese supermarkets and distributors, a move not matched by the Australian Quarantine and Inspection Service.</p>
<p>&quot;Frankly speaking, the action taken by Australia was far too slow and this concerns the people handling Australian beef,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Miyomoto said a rapid increase in the chilled beef market in Japan, where imports rose to 367,000 tonnes in 1995 from 170,000 tonnes in 1991, had depressed market prices and seriously damaged distributors in Japan and exporters in Australia.  </p>
<p>Australia's market share began to decline in 1994 with a chemical residue problem and recent droughts which significantly increased production costs, and Australia began to lose its competitive edge to the U.S., he said.</p>
<p>Miyomoto said there were many uncertain factors in the Japanese market and the current destabilised condition was likely to continue for another few years, while the international grain market was likely to stay relatively firm.</p>
<p>&quot;Consequently the belief is that it will take another couple of years for Australian grain-fed beef to regain a competitive footing in the Japanese market,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Miyomoto said Australia should consider the promotion of value-added products in Japan but, with the enormous capital required, a consortium to establish a meat industry processing plant may be necessary.</p>
<p>He predicted total meat imports to Japan would rise to 800,000 tonnes in 2000, about 15 percent of the total world beef trade, up from the current 658,000 tonnes, and warned it would not be easy for Japan to maintain such a supply in the future.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
