<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9957" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: World's first voluntary euthanasia law survives.</title>
<headline>World's first voluntary euthanasia law survives.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The world's first voluntary euthanasia law survived a challenge in Australia's Northern Territory parliament on Thursday when opponents failed in a bid to repeal the assisted suicide legislation.</p>
<p>The territory's parliament defeated the &quot;Right to Human Life&quot; bill 14 to 11 in a free vote after a five-hour debate.</p>
<p>The law, which came into effect on July 1 but has not yet been used, survived a court challenge last month and still faces challenges in the national parliament and Australia's High Court.</p>
<p>The assisted suicide law allows terminally-ill patients to end their life by lethal injection or pill as long as they meet strict conditions.</p>
<p>Territory opposition backbencher Neil Bell, who introduced the right to life bill, said he was disappointed with the vote, but that the matter was far from resolved.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a lot of people out there who are concerned and a lot of other people who don't understand it,&quot; Bell told Reuters by telephone from Darwin, the territory's capital.</p>
<p>Doctors have been warned they may face murder charges if they assist a patient to die and the law is subsequently repealed.</p>
<p>The territory's Supreme Court last month rejected a challenge brought by a coalition of doctors, church and aboriginal leaders, ruling the law was within the territorial parliament's power.</p>
<p>The euthanasia law still faces a challenge in Australia's national parliament where a government backbencher intends to introduce legislation in the next few weeks to override the law.</p>
<p>A challenge is also expected in Australia's High Court with euthanasia opponents seeking a ruling on the legislation's constitutional validity.</p>
<p>Northern Territory Chief Minister Shane Stone said on Thursday he expected the challenge in the national parliament could succeed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
