<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9967" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: FROM THE HILL-Glimpses of new-style NZ politics.</title>
<headline>FROM THE HILL-Glimpses of new-style NZ politics.</headline>
<byline>Vernon Small</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand parliament next week says farewell to the Westminster-style first-past-the-post voting system.</p>
<p>But this week it sketched the shape of the future under the Mixed Member Proportional system to be ushered in at the October 12 election.</p>
<p>While the House will sit for two days next week to hear the last of the valedictories from MPs (voluntarily) leaving politics -- in some cases in horror of working under the consensus politics needed under coalition governments -- the  </p>
<p>final serious business of the House ended on Thursday.</p>
<p>Wednesday was the last private members' day of the session and saw the passage of the Teacher Registration Bill. Proposed by Labour's Trevor Mallard, it passed through its final stages in the teeth of government opposition and created history in the process.</p>
<p>National's seven-MP coalition partner United crossed the floor to help the bill through.  </p>
<p>In itself, that was no surprise. United's support for Labour was always assured. United education spokeswoman Margaret Austin had been an early promoter of teacher registration when she was Labour's education spokeswoman before switching party allegiance midway through 1995. Moreover United had written its support for the bill into the agreement which set up its coalition with National.</p>
<p>What was surprising was the behind-the-scenes horse trading that saw National turn down the chance to filibuster the measure past 10 p.m. and effectively sink it until the next parliament.  </p>
<p>In what was akin to the first cuckoo of the MMP Spring, it appears National did a number of deals with the &quot;enemy&quot; on the bill.</p>
<p>First it undertook to allow its smooth passage in exchange for a commitment from Labour that the balance of its own legislative programme could be cleared. Labour had threatened (or was it bluff?) to keep the House running for two more weeks without such an understanding.  </p>
<p>Secondly it struck a deal with New Zealand First to support their amendment to have teachers at Maori language immersion schools (kura kaupapa Maori) exempted from compulsory registration if in turn New Zealand First supported National's similar exclusion for independent schools. While New Zealand First was successful (much to Mallard's and Austin's annoyance), National's amendment was lost, leaving kura kaupapa alone outside the bill's ambit.</p>
<p>It was a working model of MMP compromise in action and it will be no surprise if similarly strange bedfellows fashion legislation after October 12.  </p>
<p>If the referendum supporting a change to MMP was largely motivated by disaffection with Labour and National for breaking manifesto promises, then deals such as this could cause some serious disillusionment among voters who believe a manifesto pledge is for life.</p>
<p>They are likely to find out later this year that, like marriage, manifestos can have trouble riding out the rough times.  </p>
<p>For those who believe the disparate voices in the House -- anything up to seven parties on some polling -- will lead to policy paralysis rather than an unwinding of the economic reforms of the past 12 years, there was also early evidence this week.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Jim Bolger is a strong advocate of the abolition of the Privy Council as New Zealand's final court of appeal, but faces some some conservative opposition within his own ranks. The minor parties crucial to National's majority in the House are keen to cling to the appeal, whose abolition some would see as a dangerous first step towards the republic which  </p>
<p>Bolger has also promoted.</p>
<p>So the broad support crucial for such a constitutional change is not there, and the Courts Structure Bill seems to have quietly atrophied at the select committee stage.</p>
<p>With the exception of bills of high ideological significance, that is likely to be the fate of many a proposal under the next government: death in the lobbies rather than on the floor of the House. -- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
