<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9968" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ inflation picture still murky after labour data.</title>
<headline>NZ inflation picture still murky after labour data.</headline>
<byline>Catherine McCaw</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lower than expected salary and wage growth will provide some comfort to the Reserve Bank of New Zealand (RBNZ), but the overall inflation picture remains murky, economists said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Earlier, Statistics New Zealand said its Labour Cost Index rose 0.3 percent in the June quarter and 1.9 percent in the year to June.</p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters had expected on average 0.53 percent and 2.2 percent rises respectively.</p>
<p>They said that while the weak data would encourage the RBNZ in its fight to dampen inflation, it needed to see more weak indicators before loosening its grip on monetary conditions.</p>
<p>Only last week the market was suprised by data showing June quarter employment growth of 0.9 percent, against economists' expectations of a 0.37 percent rise.</p>
<p>Doyle Paterson Brown economist Stephen Toplis cautioned against reading too much into Thursday's figures as there was still too much uncertainty in the overall inflation picture.</p>
<p>&quot;If you get a whole swag of these numbers coming in below expectations, then you are going to see the Reserve Bank bring forward the easing (rather) than put it back,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been a significant number of bits of information that are now suggesting the economy is slowing down more than people may have anticipated,&quot; he said. &quot;The problem is, we are still getting the odd statistic out there which is showing a slightly different picture.&quot;</p>
<p>Toplis said on top of the surprisingly strong employment growth, recent building consents data, remained substantially higher than a year ago, despite falling month to month.</p>
<p>Bank of New Zealand economist Peter Jolly said a low labour cost number was a prerequisite for any monetary easing, but while the weak quarterly rise was &quot;very positive&quot; it was not enough in itself.</p>
<p>&quot;It goes part of the way. I think they (the RBNZ) felt they needed a weaker housing market and some alleviation in wage pressures, and they have got it a little bit in both but not entirely.&quot;</p>
<p>Jolly said the RBNZ would not signal an easing in its September economic forecasts, due on September 13.</p>
<p>&quot;They will need the weight of evidence and I don't think the weight of evidence is quite there yet,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The data was seen as mildly positive for the market. Rates on the 90-day bank bills rose about three basis points, and the shorter government bond yields slipped around two basis points.</p>
<p>&quot;In our view, it is supportive and consistent with earlier anecdotal evidence that the economy slowed in May, June and July,&quot; said Roger Kerr, executive director of merchant bank Bancorp Treasury Services.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
