<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9969" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia expects record 1996/97 rice crop.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia expects record 1996/97 rice crop.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian rice industry is embarking on a major investment in upgraded storage facilities in anticipation of a record 1996/97 crop.</p>
<p>Gerry Lawson, rice marketing chairman of the Rice Growers Association, said at the annual conference at Griffith in the state of New South Wales (NSW) that the construction programme would provide sufficient capacity to handle expected record production in 1996/97 of 1.3 million tonnes of paddy from anticipated sowings of 150,000 hectares.  </p>
<p>This would be up from the previous record crop of 1.18 million tonnes in 1994/95 and well ahead of the 1995/96 crop which was hit by cool weather in January and February.</p>
<p>Production in 1995/96 amounted to only 950,000 tonnes from a potential of 1.28 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The NSW industry would invest A$10.6 million over the next 12 months to increase capacity and intake at paddy storage sites in the Riverina area, NSW Minister for Agriculture Richard Amery said in a statement issued from the conference.  </p>
<p>Amery told the conference that a new 16,000 tonne storage and receival facility would increase capacity at Benerembah depot to a total static storage capacity of 53,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>The development, which will include a 200 tonne per hour paddy intake, will cost A$6.9 million.</p>
<p>The second project, a A$3.7 million extension to storage capacity at Hay, will increase capacity by 16,000 tonnes to a total of 32,000 tonnes of paddy, Lawson said.</p>
<p>This would increase the industry's storage capacity to 930,000 tonnes which would assist the efficient receival of an anticipated record crop for the season, he said.  </p>
<p>NSW produces almost all of Australia's rice.</p>
<p>Australia's rice is sown between September and November with the harvest beginning in February.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
