<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9974" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-INSTANT VIEW - Australian June quarter capex.</title>
<headline>RTRS-INSTANT VIEW - Australian June quarter capex.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian private new capital expenditure (capex) rose 8.8 percent in the June quarter, the Australian Bureau of Statistics said.</p>
<p>Economists median forecast had been for a 2.0 percent rise.</p>
<p>Within the total rise, investment in equipment, plant and and machinery was up 16.0 percent and building and structures expenditure rose 37.3 percent.</p>
<p>The third estimate for 1996/97 capex was A$39.478 billion, which was 9.7 percent higher than the second estimate for 1996/97 in the March quarter report.</p>
<p>A selection of economists reactions to the data follow:</p>
<p>CRAIG JAMES, SENIOR ECONOMIST, STATE BANK NSW:</p>
<p>&quot;It is significant that the survey estimate of capital expenditure differs very significantly from the national accounts estimate, so this makes it difficult in terms of interpretation. One thing to come out of this was the estimate of growth of only nine percent compared with the government's hope for 14 percent in 1996/97. This may mean the budget could have some difficulties down the line because the government relies heavily on business investment.&quot;  </p>
<p>JOHN KYRIAKOPOULOS, SENIOR ECONOMIST, MACQUARIE BANK:</p>
<p>&quot;The data for the June quarter is ancient history now and the most important figures are the expectations for this financial year. They are quite strong, particulary buildings and structures, which makes us more confident the government will meet its forecast of business investment this year.&quot;  </p>
<p>AKIS HARALABOPOULOS, CHIEF ECONOMIST, GIO AUSTRALIA:</p>
<p>&quot;It's up very strongly which is just as well because the government looking for strong growth in private investment. so its consistent with their view on private investment generally.&quot;</p>
<p>ANTHONY THOMPSON, ECONOMIST, HONGKONGBANK AUSTRALIA:</p>
<p>&quot;The latest expectations for 1996/97 ... compared to last year gives you a nominal increase of 15.4 percent, and when you knock out inflation it gives you around a 13 percent real increase, a bit below the government's budget forecast. These numbers are supportive of a rate cut.&quot;  </p>
<p>TONY MEER, ECONOMIST, BAIN AND COMPANY:</p>
<p>&quot;Although the (budget) forecast looks a bit strong ... Treasury has the track record on it. A conservative reading of of realisation ratios from a comparable period, say the mid 1980s ... say that you will be able to get around A$42 odd billion in nominal capital spending, given that your third estimate is A$39.5 billion ... which is a value number you need to actually get the real growth of 14 percent.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
