<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9977" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Qantas plans A$330 mln of cost cuts.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Qantas plans A$330 mln of cost cuts.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Qantas Airways Ltd said on Thursday it forecast lower revenue growth for the year to June 30, 1997 and planned to increase its cost cutting targets for the year to A$330 million from A$230 million.  </p>
<p>Qantas said current seat prices and an outlook of lower revenue did not justify investment in new aircraft at Qantas' current level of operating cost.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook for the 1996/97 year presents the same issues encountered in the year just completed,&quot; Qantas said in a statement with its annual results. &quot;Lower revenue growth and a stronger Australian dollar are again forecast.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;To compensate for this revenue prediction and to deliver profit growth in line with market expectations, cost reduction targets for new initiatives in the coming year have been increased to A$230 million to A$330 million.&quot;  </p>
<p>Qantas said that growth in parts of Asia was strong, but at prices which did not provide a sufficent profit margin.</p>
<p>&quot;Additional cost reduction initiatives are therefore an essential requirement for any further significant expansion of the business,&quot; Qantas said.</p>
<p>Qantas said that while the early indications were that this higher cost cutting target was achieveable, a further softening of market conditions may impact on the evenutal outcome.  </p>
<p>&quot;Passenger numbers will continue to grow, but international market share will decline further due to the allocation of Australian international rights to other Australasian carriers, and deliberate decisions by Qantas not to invest in growth which does not generate acceptable additional returns,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Profits will continue to be more important than market share,&quot; the airline said.</p>
<p>Qantas said its priorities were the management of the balance sheet to reduce gearing.  </p>
<p>Qantas earlier reported a 25.3 percent rise in pre-tax operating profit to A$401.4 million for the year to June 30, 1996 and a net profit of A$246.2 million, up 37 percent over the previous year and four percent higher than its prospectus forecast.</p>
<p>Analysts had on average forecast a pre-abnormal net profit of between A$237 million and A$249 million. There were no abnormals.</p>
<p>Qantas' share price was unchanged at A$2.17 at 12.00 p.m. (0200 GMT). Qantas is 25 percent owned by British Airways Plc .  -- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
