<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9980" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Pasminco mine to yield 2,500 T zinc.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Pasminco mine to yield 2,500 T zinc.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reopening of the long-idled Hercules mine in Tasmania will increase output at Pasminco Ltd's Risdon zinc smelter by about 2,500 tonnes a year, a company officials said told Reuters on Thursday.</p>
<p>Pasminco Ltd said earlier on Thursday the mine would be reopened under a sub-lease agreement with mine contractor firm Mancala Pty Ltd.</p>
<p>The mine, which was closed in 1986, is expected to resume ore production in October this year at an initial rate of 50,000 tonnes in the first year rising to 80,000 tonnes in the second year, Pasminco said.  </p>
<p>Bryan Davis, Pasminco's executive general manager of mining, said the project was too small for Pasminco to get involved in directly. Mancala was better equipped to restart the mine because it would focus exclusively on the project, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're miners in bulk mining and Mancala is an expert in remnant mining,&quot; Davis said.</p>
<p>Pasminco has agreed to purchase the entire output of the mine, which will be processed at its Roseberry treatment plant before being smelted at the 215,000-tonnes-a-year Risdon smelter, Davis said.  </p>
<p>The arrangement is initially for two years but can be extended if the economic returns are attractive to both parties, Pasminco said.</p>
<p>Pasminco has about 200,000 tonnes of exceeds treatment capacity at the Roseberry plant, caused by the closure of the Que river Zinc mine in the 1980s, Davis said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22471">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
