<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9981" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: FEATURE - Aborigines mark 30 years of land struggle.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Aborigines mark 30 years of land struggle.</headline>
<byline>Michael Perry</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The red ochre dirt poured out of a politician's manicured white hands and into the weathered black hands of an aboriginal tribal elder, spilling back into the dry outback earth from which it came.</p>
<p>The symbolic image of former Australian prime minister Gough Whitlam returning land to a group of Aborigines in 1975 remains one of the most poignant in the history of aboriginal land rights in Australia.</p>
<p>This week, Whitlam returns to the site, Daguragu in the Northern Territory, to celebrate with Aborigines the beginning of the aboriginal land rights movement 30 years ago.</p>
<p>But three decades later, indigenous land rights still divide Australians. Aborigines say perceptions are the major obstacle to progress. To black Australia, land is spiritual. To the white community, it is a commodity.</p>
<p>&quot;Land is the Mother Earth to aboriginal people. We believe the land is all life,&quot; said Galarrwuy Yunupingu, chairman of the Northern Land Council in the Northern Territory.</p>
<p>&quot;So it comes to us that we are part of the land and the land is part of us. It can not be one or the other. We can not be separated from it by anything or anybody,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On August 23, 1966, a small, sinewy aboriginal stockman named Vincent Lingiari led 200 of his Gurindji tribe off Wave Hill Station, a sprawling cattle property on Gurindji land owned by the British Vestey group of companies.</p>
<p>Lingiari was fed up with the poor work and living conditions his people suffered on their traditional land. He demanded not only better conditions, but the return of Gurindji land to the people. Aborigines call that day, Gurindji Freedom Day.</p>
<p>&quot;We were treated like dogs. We were lucky to get paid the 50 quid (sterling) a month we were due. We lived in tin humpies (shelters) and we had to crawl in and out of on our knees,&quot; said Billy Bunter Jampijinpa, then a 16-year-old Gurindji stockman.</p>
<p>&quot;The food was bad, just flour, tea, sugar and bits of beef like the head or feet of a bullock. The Vestey mob were hard men. They didn't care about blackfellas,&quot; Jampijinpa said.</p>
<p>Lingiari led his people to a bush camp at nearby Wattie Creek, which they renamed Daguragu. Here they stayed for seven years, despite being threatened with violence and starvation. They would never return to work at Wave Hill.</p>
<p>In 1968, the then Australian government decided to build a township at Wave Hill for the Gurindji and in 1975 provided funds to buy 90 sq km (35 sq miles) of land from Lord Vestey.</p>
<p>The Gurindji struggle led to the introduction of the Aboriginal Land Rights Act in 1976, but it took five more years after the law passed for the Gurindji to win their claim to 1,290 sq km (498 sq miles), still only a fraction of their land.</p>
<p>&quot;The strike at Wave Hill three decades ago was one of the turning points in the struggle...for recognition of our rights of land,&quot; said Aborigine Marcia Langton, a professor in aboriginal studies at the Northern Territory University.</p>
<p>Forty percent of the territory, 538,000 sq km (207,721 sq miles), is now aboriginal land, hosting a billion dollars worth of mineral operations and major tourist attractions like Uluru, formerly Ayers Rock, and the Kakadu wetlands.</p>
<p>Aborigines have created 600 homeland centres, supporting themselves with mineral royalties, tourism, 26 cattle projects and ventures such as crocodile farming.</p>
<p>But the struggle for land rights continues. Australia's first land rights law remains valid only in the territory, and even there, Aborigines warn that land gains remain under threat from miners, pastoralists and politicans.</p>
<p>Aborigines say they are still locked out of ancestoral lands because the territory's law does not cover pastoral leases, towns or sacred sites. &quot;Many of these people live in fringe camps in Alice Springs, Katherine or Darwin, severely economically disadvantaged...,&quot; said Yunupingu.</p>
<p>Australia's 300,000 Aborigines are the most disadvantaged of the country's 18 million population.</p>
<p>Aborigines have a 60 percent unemployment rate, are 18 times more likely to be in prison and to die 18 years to 20 years earlier because of poor health. Some 38 percent of aboriginal communities do not meet World Health Organisation standards.</p>
<p>Northern Territory's Minister for Aboriginal Development Mick Palmer said many communities are &quot;land rich but income poor&quot; and called on land councils to become land managers.</p>
<p>The 1993 introduction across Australia of Native Title, a law recognising aboriginal ownership of land before white settlement in 1788, was called a new dawn in the land rights struggle. But no land has yet been handed back as Native Title.</p>
<p>&quot;I am worried about what might happen in the future if aboriginal people don't keep fighting,&quot; Yunupingu said.</p>
<p>&quot;Loss of our land rights would leave us powerless as the scavenger birds in Australian cities. If we lose our land, we will end up eating crumbs from the whitefellas' table,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
