<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9983" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Santos to develop Stag oil field.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Santos to develop Stag oil field.</headline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil and gas producer Santos Ltd said on Thursday the WA209-P joint venture had committed to the A$200 million development of the Stag oil field in the Carnarvon basin, offshore Western Australia.  </p>
<p>Santos has a 54.17 percent stake in the venture, the other participants being the operator, Apache Corp with 33.33 percent and Globex Mining Enterprises Inc 12.5 percent.</p>
<p>Santos said its share of the development was A$117.9 million including its requirement to fund Globex's interest through a portion of the development.</p>
<p>&quot;Stag is a significant field with an expected life of at least 13 years - it will provide a solid foundation for future growth of the company,&quot; Santos managing director Ross Adler said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The Stag field, discovered in June 1993, is located in 46 metres of water, 30 km north west of Dampier.</p>
<p>The company said gross proved and probable reserves in the field were estimated to be 43.8 million barrels of oil of which Santos' share is 23.7 million barrels.</p>
<p>&quot;The first full year of production is expected to average 26,200 barrels of oil per day,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>The development scheme for the field involves the fabrication and installation of a fixed central production platform.  </p>
<p>Santos said the oil would be exported from the production platform through a subsea flow line connected via a mooring buoy to a floating storage facility about two kilometres away.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
