<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9985" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTR-Australians see meat problems for some time.</title>
<headline>RTR-Australians see meat problems for some time.</headline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian Meat Council (AMC) said on Thursday that recovery of international market confidence in meat would be neither easy nor short term following recent contamination problems.</p>
<p>AMC chairman George Gilbertson told a council conference in Adelaide that the E.Coli food contamination outbreak in Japan had caused a nationwide reaction to meat.</p>
<p>While no Australian meat product was involved, the Australian industry had suffered consequences, he said.  </p>
<p>Similarly the worldwide consumer reaction to meat following Britain's Mad Cow disease outbreak had hit Australian meat exports, Gilbertson said. &quot;The recovery of market confidence will be neither easy nor happen in a short duration,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gilbertson said the last 12 months for the Australian industry had been its most tumultuous with offshore origins to all its difficulties.</p>
<p>Trading conditions worldwide were extremely tight with intense competition from the United States in many of Australia's strategic growth markets, particularly Japan and Korea, he said.  </p>
<p>U.S. market share in Japan had risen to 47 percent in 1996 first quarter compared to 41 percent in 1995 first quarter while Australia's market share in Korea had dropped to 30 percent from 53 percent in 1991. &quot;At this time the U.S. industry is particularly focused on export markets and there is little likelihood of change until well into the next century,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gilbertson said industry rationalisation in Australia would accelerate over the next few years, with most industry players acknowledging an over-capacity in the processing sector.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
