<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9986" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: ECNZ revaluation lifts assets $655 million.</title>
<headline>ECNZ revaluation lifts assets $655 million.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>NZ government-owned electricity generator Electricity Corp of New Zealand said on Thursday it had revalued its assets by NZ$655 million to $3.3 billion.</p>
<p>The likelihood of a revaluation was made public by Moody's Investor Service on Wednesday, but was not due to be released by the company until its annual report in October.</p>
<p>ECNZ media relations manager Karen Jones confirmed the level of revaluation.</p>
<p>Moody's said it was concerned at the the New Zealand government's aggressive financial management of ECNZ.  </p>
<p>But Finance Minister Bill Birch told Reuters he did not think the government was &quot;any more aggressive with ECNZ than state owned enterprises generally&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Our policy is to work with the commercial board to develop a dividend policy. But that is not inflexible. If they make a good case to retain earnings the government takes that into account.&quot;</p>
<p>Birch said he had no comment to make on a likely special dividend from ECNZ forecast by Moody's.  </p>
<p>He said the ratio of 40 percent debt to total capitalisation mentioned as likely by Moody's &quot;we regard as a benchmark across the state owned enterprises and Crown-owned entities, but it is not inviolate.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;But we don't encourage Crown companies to build up cash reserves without good reason.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if there would be a similar revaluation of Contact Energy, split from ECNZ in February, Birch said &quot;we will wait and see&quot;.  </p>
<p>He said &quot;valuations were going in all directions&quot; and pointed to the downward revision of Forestry Corporation's assets prior to its sale.</p>
<p>Contact Energy's media relations manager Bruce Thompson confirmed the company was revaluing its assets, set at $1.693 billion in February, and said the results would be in the annual report for the year to September.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
