<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9987" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: PRESS DIGEST-HK newspaper headlines - Aug 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-HK newspaper headlines - Aug 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>-- ALL PAPERS -- Beijing cancels a mission to Ukraine by Politburo member and senior economic reform minister Li Tieying, and attacks Taiwan Vice-President Lien Chan's visit to Ukraine as a move against China's reunification.</p>
<p>-- Beijing-funded WEN WEI PO and TA KUNG PAO -- Beijing issued details of rules on direct cargo and transport links between China and Taiwan.</p>
<p>-- SOUTH CHINA MORNING POST -- A Democratic Party trip to Taiwan during which party leader Martin Lee would probably have met President Lee Teng-hui has been canceled amid signs of a thaw in relations between the party and Beijing. The trip was considered too sensitive at a time when the party was awaiting Beijing's response to calls for dialogue.</p>
<p>-- MING PAO -- Chinese leader Deng Xiaoping's family have prepared a party at home, just for family members and the head of Deng's Office. Deng only wanted to celebrate his 92nd birthday on Thursday with his family. It said Deng seemed to have lost interest in the world, because he rarely asked his assistant to read newspapers to him nowadays.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG ECONOMIC TIMES -- according to its own sources, China's central bank, the People's Bank of China, would cut interest rates by a big margin at the end of the week, which showed Beijing's determination to boost its economy.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG ECONOMIC JOURNAL -- The mayor of Guangzhou, Li Zeliu, said that the city would lower land prices by 25 per cent and the transaction fees and taxes by 20 per cent. Property experts said local developers who had projects in Guangzhou, including Lai Sin Group, would benefit.</p>
<p>-- HONGKONG STANDARD -- China's plan to establish direct shipping links with Taiwan could help the island wrest U.S.-bound shipping business from Hong Kong.</p>
<p>-- SOUTH CHINA MORNING POST -- Xiamen International Bank, the first Sino-foreign bank widely considered a trailblazer in China's drive to reform its financial sector, was seeking mainland approval for a listing in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>-- TA KUNG PAO -- About 1,000 overseas students graduated from the latest mandarin Chinese language course at the Beijing Language and Culture University. Last year about 40,000 foreign students went to learn the language in China. It said short courses lasting from one to five months were most popular.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG ECONOMIC TIMES -- Local businessmen have dreamed up a new promotion method using movie stars as label designers. Singer Andy Lau was invited to design a series of sunglasses targeted at professionals, while singer Amanda Lee, who is known for her trendy and stylish outfits, had designed an Amanda Lee Collection for Lee jeans.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong News Room (852) 2843 6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
