<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9988" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia seeks negotiated end to unrest.</title>
<headline>Indonesia seeks negotiated end to unrest.</headline>
<byline>Lewa Pardomuan</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian authorities and the country's leading opposition figure signalled on Thursday they are trying to negotiate an end to a row that has sharply raised political tensions.</p>
<p>Lawyers for the government and for Megawati Sukarnoputri, ousted chief of the Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI) and daughter of late founding president Sukarno, said they would discuss their differences.</p>
<p>However, political analysts said chances for an agreement were remote.</p>
<p>Central Jakarta District Court chief judge I Gde Ketut Suarta, who was hearing a lawsuit filed by Megawati against her removal, said an out-of-court settlement was in progress and he would give both sides one week to negotiate.</p>
<p>Megawati, who was not present in court, declined to comment on the development, which comes after months of political unrest in Indonesia capped by riots in Jakarta last month and a subsequent government crackdown.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't have any comment at the moment. I have given everything to my lawyers,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Aides said she planned to meet her legal team later on Thursday to discuss the case. They said no immediate political strategy was expected to be announced and there were no details on what shape a settlement might take.</p>
<p>Megawati is suing the government and the military for backing a rival PDI faction which deposed her from the leadership in June. Members of the rival faction, including its leader Surjadi, were also named as defendants.</p>
<p>&quot;The offer for an out-of-court settlement is the best. We will do it if the defendants share our perceptions,&quot; said Megawati's chief lawyer, R.O. Tambunan, at the court.</p>
<p>However, a lawyer for the national police chief, who has been cited as a defendant, said: &quot;We agreed with the offer, but only on one condition -- the suit must be dropped. We are also ready to face it because we have nothing to do with the PDI.&quot;</p>
<p>Muchtar Buchori, a political commentator who is close to Megawati, said she would at least demand reinstatement as the party chief in exchange for dropping the case.</p>
<p>&quot;I think her reinstatement will be very difficult,&quot; said independent analyst Dewi Fortuna Anwar. &quot;Since the president has accepted Surjadi as (PDI) chairman, it will be difficult to wriggle out of that.&quot;</p>
<p>Megawati has been at the centre of a political storm since her ejection from the PDI's top post. Her removal led to some of the most severe protests in the three-decades rule of President Suharto and riots broke out in Jakarta on July 27 after police cleared the PDI headquarters of her supporters.</p>
<p>At least four people died and scores of buildings and vehicles were set on fire during the violence, the worst in the city for more than 20 years.</p>
<p>The government has since cracked down on dissent and taken over 200 people into custody. Some have been charged with subversion, a crime punishable by death.</p>
<p>Megawati has been questioned twice by police in connection with the riots but has not been charged.</p>
<p>Political analysts have said the government backed the move to depose Megawati because it feared she could cut into the ruling Golkar party's votes in next year's parliamentary elections and perhaps stand against Suharto in the 1998 presidential elections.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
