<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9990" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Media say Taiwan, Ukraine agreed office exchange.</title>
<headline>Media say Taiwan, Ukraine agreed office exchange.</headline>
<byline>Alice Hung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan media on Thursday revealed the prize that Vice-President Lien Chan snared during a mysterious mission to Ukraine that has incensed China -- an exchange of unofficial representative offices.</p>
<p>Taiwan and Ukraine agreed to exchange offices after Lien met Ukraine President Leonid Kuchma in a secretive trip to the former Soviet republic, Taiwan newspapers reported.</p>
<p>Taiwan officials would not comment on the reports, maintaining the secrecy that has cloaked Lien's trip since he dropped from sight on Sunday during a New York stopover.</p>
<p>The Central Daily News, the ruling Nationalist Party's mouthpiece, said on its front page that Lien and Kuchma reached the agreement in a meeting on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Ukraine, already bearing the brunt of China's scorn over the Lien's visit, has flatly denied that the two leaders met.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no meeting. Neither official, nor private nor non-official,&quot; a Kuchma spokesman said on Wednesday. &quot;There is no point at all for the president to meet him. The Chinese are even angry over his private stay in Ukraine.&quot;</p>
<p>The Central Daily News and other papers said the two leaders also agreed to bolster cultural and technology exchanges between Taiwan and Ukraine, which do not have diplomatic ties.</p>
<p>Taiwan and Ukraine were expected to set up economic and cultural representative offices in each other's territory within six months, the independent Liberty Times reported.</p>
<p>None of the reports identified the sources of their information.</p>
<p>Ukraine recognises Beijing, which has regarded Taiwan as a renegade province since a civil war split them in 1949.</p>
<p>Beijing says Taiwan is a Chinese province not entitled to foreign ties and has scorned even allies whom it sees as giving political or diplomatic quarter to the island's leaders.</p>
<p>Furious over the welcome Kiev accorded Lien, Beijing scrapped a high-level visit to the former Soviet republic that was to have begun on Wednesday.</p>
<p>On Wednesday the Chinese Foreign Ministry summoned Ukraine's ambassador to express Beijing's displeasure over Ukraine's decision to allow Lien to visit.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese expressed displeasure over this action in Ukraine that this person from Taiwan has got permission to visit the country,&quot; an embassy spokesman said.</p>
<p>The spokesman confirmed that Chinese State Councillor Li Tieying, a member of the Politburo of the ruling Communist Party, had postponed his Ukraine visit.</p>
<p>Lien surfaced in Kiev on Tuesday, two days after vanishing on a European mission. He made a secret detour to Ukraine after making a state visit to the Dominican Republic.</p>
<p>Taiwan state television showed Lien with his wife and other Taiwan and Ukraine officials posing at the University of Kiev, where the announcer said Lien had received an honorary degree.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
