<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9991" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia's Megawati may have deal with government.</title>
<headline>Indonesia's Megawati may have deal with government.</headline>
<byline>Lewa Pardomuan</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian opposition figure Megawati Sukarnoputri is discussing a possible settlement with the government in the row over her ejection as leader of the Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI), a judge said on Thursday.</p>
<p>It was the first sign that the political upheaval which followed her removal from the PDI in June could be coming to an end, but there were no immediate details on what a settlement would entail.</p>
<p>Jakarta District Court chief judge I Gde Ketut Suarta, who was hearing a lawsuit filed by Megawati against her ouster from the party post, said the two sides were working on an out-of-court settlement.</p>
<p>Megawati is suing the government and the military for backing a rival PDI faction which deposed her from the leadership. Members of the rival faction, including its leader Surjadi, were also named as defendants.</p>
<p>Suarta adjourned the hearing after a brief statement that the court would reconvene on August 29 to hear the outcome.</p>
<p>More than 100 supporters thronged the court complex and chanted &quot;Megawati Will Win&quot; as the proceedings ended. Riot police and armed police later dispersed them peacefully.</p>
<p>&quot;The offer for an out-of-court settlement is the best. We will do it if the defendants share our perceptions,&quot; said Megawati's chief lawyer, R.O. Tambunan.</p>
<p>However, a lawyer for the national police chief, who has been cited as a defendant, said: &quot;We agreed with the offer, but only on one condition -- the suit must be dropped. We are also ready to face it because we have nothing to do with the PDI.&quot;</p>
<p>Megawati, the daughter of Indonesia's late founding president Sukarno, has been at the centre of a political storm since her ejection from the party post.</p>
<p>Her removal led to some of the most severe protests in the three-decades rule of President Suharto. Riots broke out in Jakarta on July 27 after police cleared the PDI headquarters of her supporters.</p>
<p>At least four people died and scores of buildings and vehicles were set on fire during the violence, the worst the city has seen for more than over 20 years.</p>
<p>The government has since cracked down on dissent and taken over 200 people into custody. Some have been charged with subversion, a crime punishable by death.</p>
<p>Authorities blame the riots on a small activist group, the People's Democratic Party, and say its members infiltrated the PDI during the protests against Megawati's ouster.</p>
<p>Megawati has been questioned twice by police in connection with the riots but has not been charged.</p>
<p>Political analysts have said the government backed the move to depose Megawati because it feared she could cut into the ruling Golkar party's votes in next year's parliamentary elections and perhaps stand against Suharto in the 1998 presidential elections.</p>
<p>In contrast, Surjadi, the man who succeeded her as PDI chief, earlier this week agreed to support Suharto and not criticise Golkar and the other recognised political party, the United Development Party, in the campaign.</p>
<p>Suharto, one of the longest-ruling leaders in the world, has won six five-year terms as president unopposed. He has not said if he will stand in 1998, but analysts say it is likely.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
