<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9996" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - August 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - August 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indonesian political and business stories in leading newspapers, prepared by Reuters in Jakarta. Reuters has not checked the stories and does not guarantee their accuracy. Telephone: (6221) 384-6364. Fax: (6221) 344-8404.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>KOMPAS</p>
<p>Jakarta police say they have for the moment finished questioning Catholic priest Father Ignatius Sandyawan as part of their investigation into the July 27 riots in the capital. Police say Sandyawan, who has been accused of sheltering criminals, would not be detained while they gather further information.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>JAKARTA POST</p>
<p>Garuda Indonesia plans to begin diverting flights through Hang Nadim International Airport on Batam Island to develop the special zone's potential as a freight transit point.</p>
<p>New housing regulations governing foreign ownership will limit the occupancy by foreigners to 40 percent for any particular area to stop them having a dominant presence in a particular neighbourhood.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>REPUBLIKA</p>
<p>The leader of the People's Democratic Party, Budiman Sudjatmiko, and his colleagues, currently in detention and facing subversion charges after last months riots, will be represented by a team of 33 lawyers.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BISNIS INDONESIA</p>
<p>Housing Minister Akbar Tanjung has issued more detailed regulations governing the types of houses which can been owned by foreigners as businessmen in the property sector called on the government to open up the commericial sector to foreign ownership.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
