<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="9998" id="root" date="1996-08-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks end weaker on profit-taking, politics.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks end weaker on profit-taking, politics.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-08-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks ended lower in thin trade on Thursday as some investors took profits and uncertainty over the future of the government kept others on the sidelines, brokers said.</p>
<p>The SET index ended 4.32 points down at 1.090.71 on slim 2.7 billion baht trade. Decliners beat gainers 202 to 105 with 116 unchanged. The SET-50 index was 0.32 points off at 82.23</p>
<p>&quot;We saw a bit of profit taking after the sharp rise yesterday on foreign specualtive buying and politics is still keeping many investors away,&quot; said a local analyst.  </p>
<p>Politics has cast gloom over the jittery bourse since last week when one of the partners in Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa's seven-party coalition quit. Earlier this week the opposition filed a censure motion against Banharn for debate on September 11, compounding the unease.</p>
<p>Japanese funds entered the market on Wendesday hoping to ride a wave of buying as the first portion of a 21 billion baht local support fund was invested.</p>
<p>But brokers said the low volume on Thursday showed that foreigners had again retreated and the local support fund was not actively trying to push the market higher.  </p>
<p>&quot;The support fund just cushions the market when it declines,&quot; said an analyst at Adkinson Securities.</p>
<p>The finance sector ended 1.14 percent lower on 590 million baht and the bank sector finished 0.68 percent off on 493 million baht turnover.</p>
<p>Bangkok Bank was most active, two baht down at 210. Thai Farmers Bank gained one to 173 and Finance One lost two to 108.</p>
<p>-- Robert Birsel (662) 252-9950</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
